<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>纽约客</title><description>纽约客全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.newyoker.com <item><title><![CDATA[“A Haunting in Venice” and “El Conde,” Reviewed]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/09/25/a-haunting-in-venice-movie-review-el-conde]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65032ad1e8cb5056481b283f/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/230925_r42990.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt; div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2. 95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/s vg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存这个故事&lt;/ span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span>;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d= “M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d =“M23 3” H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;阿加莎·克里斯蒂 (Agatha Christie) 于 1969 年出版的《万圣节派对》主要以虚构小镇 Woodleigh Common 为背景，“一个普通的地方”，距离伦敦三十或四十英里。感谢导演肯尼思·布拉纳 (Kenneth Branagh) 和编剧迈克尔·格林 (Michael Green)，这本书已成为一部新电影《威尼斯闹鬼》，故事发生在 1947 年的意大利。现在，这是一部改编作品——比布拉纳和格林在《东方快车谋杀案》（2017 年）或《尼罗河惨案》（2022 年）中所论述的任何内容都更加大胆的变形。我已经开始期待他们对克里斯蒂的下一次重制：《图书馆里的尸体》，也许会搬到沃尔玛的冷冻室。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布拉纳回归饰演赫尔克里·波洛，他已经退休到一家威尼斯牢度。在那里，他无视那些纠缠不休的人的恳求，用他们的私人秘密来烦扰他，他照料着他的花园，用放大镜检查他的植物，仿佛要揭露任何有罪的蚜虫。当地的重量级人物Portfoglio（里卡多·斯卡马西奥饰）听起来像是股票经纪人，但实际上是一名前警察，充当看门人的角色。他允许进入的唯一一个局外人是阿里阿德妮·奥利弗（蒂娜·菲饰），一位崭露头角的犯罪小说家。她敦促侦探陪她去参加降神会，在那里，著名的灵媒雷诺兹夫人（杨紫琼饰）将与彼岸世界取得联系。阿里亚德涅的计划是，波洛作为一个极端理性主义者，将揭穿超自然现象的说法。作为一个狡猾的电影制片人，布拉纳的计划是彻底揭穿他们的谎言。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因此，请为所有的伎俩做好准备。这座宫殿据说充满了鬼魂，目前住着一位歌剧女高音罗威娜·德雷克（凯莉·蕾莉饰），自从她的女儿艾丽西亚（罗温·罗宾逊饰）掉进运河淹死后，她就再也没有唱过一个音符。一只名叫哈利的鹦鹉出于同样的原因一直闭着嘴。一位习惯说拉丁语的管家（卡米尔·科廷饰）只能进入女儿的房间。一位英国医生（杰米·多南饰）因战时经历而受到创伤。一个英俊可靠、空虚的混蛋（凯尔·艾伦饰），曾经与艾丽西亚订婚，但后来抛弃了她，显然是为了钱，这对我来说似乎很公平。一个隐蔽的地下室，里面全是骷髅。一只针织兔子。失踪的蜜蜂。一台打字机，其按键会自动按下。一场猛烈的夜间风暴，当死亡降临时，警察无法到达现场，这意味着波洛必须把所有人都锁起来，并——&lt;em>;老天爷&lt;/em>;——在早餐前解决犯罪问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;我记得小时候读到《万圣节派对》时被吓到了，因为第一个受害者&lt;em>;是&lt;/em>;一个孩子：一个十二岁或十三岁的女孩，她的头被强行放进水桶里她在捡苹果的时候喝了水。 （如果克里斯蒂愿意的话，在乐趣出错的问题上，她可以很残忍。）仿佛作为一种救赎，《威尼斯鬼魂》中最有趣的人物是另一个孩子——由裘德扮演的医生的儿子利奥波德希尔是布拉纳执导的《贝尔法斯特》（2021 年）中的无赖小混蛋。在这里，希尔不再有任何可爱之处。相反，他向我们展示了一种早熟的小波洛，庄重地穿着深色西装，打着领带。埃德加·爱伦·坡读到利奥波德关心他颤抖的父亲，当被问及他对死者的同情时，他回答说：“他们中的一些人是我的朋友。”他和《第六感》（1999）中的男孩有很多话可聊。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于像利奥波德这样的体质病态的人来说，没有任何地方比威尼斯更阴暗。亨利·詹姆斯称其为“最美丽的坟墓”，而我总是对它作为浪漫避难所的声誉感到困惑。你怎么能在一个被解体和衰败所定义的城市里度蜜月呢？想想约瑟夫·洛西吧，他把好莱坞的烂片《夏娃》拿来，像布拉纳一样，把情节搬到了威尼斯。结果是《伊娃》（1962），一部对幻灭的纪念，其中让娜·莫罗作为一个漫不经心的享乐主义者，让她的爱人的尊严被浸透，他的心变成了废墟。影片的部分情节在冬天的托尔切洛岛上展开，远离耀眼的大运河。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt; div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;如果每一个威尼斯故事都被讲述，那么，每一个观点都被详尽地记录在印刷品或绘画中，那么《威尼斯闹鬼》还能为这个故事增添什么呢？混合？距离海莉·阿特维尔和丽贝卡·弗格森在最新的《碟中谍》中忙于在这座城市的一座桥梁上与恶棍作战才几个月，而对于威尼斯溺水女儿的哀悼，没有什么可以与《唐》相媲美。现在看”（1973）。然而，布拉纳的电影却有着荒唐可笑的魅力：华丽的风格被高高地堆放在哥特式阵营的宝库中，无论受到何种挑衅，镜头都以最令人震惊的角度倾斜——业内所称的“荷兰角度”。波洛先生，如果你真的想有宾至如归的感觉，就忘掉威尼斯吧。前往阿姆斯特丹！&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据历史记载，50年前军事政变后在智利上台的奥古斯托·皮诺切特出生于1915年，逝世于2006年。据《El Conde》报道，另一方面，智利导演巴勃罗·拉腊恩（Pablo Larraín）的一部新电影《皮诺切特》（Pinochet）已经流传了几个世纪。他一开始是克劳德·皮诺什，路易十六军队中的一名年轻法国军官，他近距离观察了法国大革命的暴行——距离如此之近，以至于在玛丽·安托瓦内特被处决后，他偷偷走到断头台上舔了她的血。从刀片上。你看，这不是普通的野蛮人。他是一个吸血鬼。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;这就是推动这部不寻常电影的自负。本书追踪皮诺切特的罪行，跳转到现代，迅速穿越他的独裁统治时期，并在他入眠时落在他的灵柩上。一扇小窗户显示出死者平静的面容，他睁开眼睛，偷偷看了一眼，显然不耐烦地再次站起来，继续他干渴的工作。我们了解到，单纯的血统并不能满足皮诺切特挑剔的口味。相反，他会挖出受害者的心脏，将它们放入搅拌机中，然后喝下液化的液体。除了最后一刻的尾声外，《El Conde》——《伯爵》——完全是黑白的。血迹像焦油一样黑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;故事的大部分故事发生在一个偏远的智利牧场。唯一的居住者是皮诺切特（海梅·瓦德尔饰）、他的妻子露西娅·希里亚特（格洛丽亚·蒙奇梅尔饰）和他们的仆人费奥多尔（阿尔弗雷多·卡斯特罗饰），费奥多尔对自己在军政府统治期间施虐的经历感到非常自豪。 。皮诺切特的五个孩子来到了这个荒凉的地方，他们声称对父亲有微弱的爱，但主要是为了他的钱。一位名叫卡门西塔（保拉·鲁辛格饰）的会计师到来，负责整理家庭财务状况，尤其是那些像松鼠坚果一样藏起来的资金。然而，卡门西塔有一个秘密计划：她是一名修女，乔装打扮，她的手提箱里装满了驱魔人的工具。赌注很高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管有吸血鬼，但电影中没有人比 Luchsinger 产生更引人注目的影响。短发、五官锐利、圆眼睛、笑容满面的她散发着一种好战的天真无邪。然而她的角色的目的变得危险地模糊，并且情节的核心有些松懈和不集中。当皮诺切特家族为不死族的遗产争吵时，拉雷恩越是试图用道德怪诞来吸引你的注意力，你就越不愿意屈服。我怀疑《El Conde》是一个只有一招的故事。暴君作为真正的吸血鬼的形象，而不是作为同胞的严厉征服者，对于政治漫画家来说将是肉和饮料，尤其是饮料，但它没有与其讽刺性相匹配的叙事力量。很少有笑话，无论多么恶心和强烈，可以一遍又一遍地讲而不会开始消失。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这部电影以玛格丽特·撒切尔（斯特拉·戈内特饰）明显的语气叙述，她屈尊客串。后期出现。确实，1998 年皮诺切特被指控侵犯人权并在英国被软禁后，撒切尔夫人（和乔治·H·W·布什）主张应该释放他。然而，任何看过《孔德》的人，对那个时期知之甚少，都会留下这样的印象：她与其说是皮诺切特的盟友，不如说是他的可怕伴侣——甚至可能是他的上级——有着自己的野蛮品味。和他一样，她平静地飞过广阔的灰色天空，她的斗篷像蝙蝠的翅膀一样展开。作为一位女士，她从瓷杯里啜饮着血，就像喝格雷伯爵茶一样。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;事实上，撒切尔夫人与皮诺切特不同，是公平选举产生的，而且她统治着一个你可以称之为的国家。总理是一个吸血鬼，没有被从直升飞机上扔下来，也没有被打成肉泥，这种区别可能太细了，也太乏味了，不值得困扰拉雷恩。他的情况很奇怪：随着他的成熟，他的工作变得更加愚蠢，而不是更加明智。 《Jackie》（2016）、《Spencer》（2021）和《El Conde》的巴洛克式偏执，充满了阴谋的噩梦，不如《NO》（2012）的紧迫性那么有说服力。这是拉雷恩最好的电影，以 1988 年公投中击败皮诺切特的运动为背景，片中的普通智利人已经忍受了足够多的痛苦，并聚集起来进行反击。 《El Conde》中这样的人在哪里？谁需要一部几乎全是掠食者的电影，而猎物几乎一言不发？ ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;l44469&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; >;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;rsez7o&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt; div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ side>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live= “礼貌” aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/文章>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 18:06:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hasan Minhaj’s “Emotional Truths”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/news/annals-of-communications/hasan-minhajs-emotional-truths]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6501dc8d2120abde4bd6899a/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/Malone_final.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt; div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2. 95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/s vg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存这个故事&lt;/ span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span>;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d= “M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d =“M23 3” H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;喜剧演员哈桑·明哈吉 (Hasan Minhaj) 在 9/11 事件后的美国的一个印度家庭中长大，成为一名虔诚的穆斯林。他的 Netflix 系列剧《爱国者法案》是一部模仿《每日秀》和《上周今夜秀》的喜剧新闻节目，以那个时代的定义性法律命名。该剧在播出两年期间荣获艾美奖和皮博迪奖。他作为一名单口喜剧演员的舞台作品在 Netflix 上制作了两部喜剧特别节目，明哈吉将自传式故事讲述和社会正义评论融为一体，赢得了赞誉。他最近与巴拉克·奥巴马进行了一次长时间的&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=jAYVKZSWXhY&quot;>;静坐采访&lt;/a>;，是继任的领先候选人&lt;a href=&quot; https://www.newyorker.com/culture/on-television/how-the-daily-show-squandered-the-opportunity-that-was-trevor-noah&quot;>;特雷弗·诺亚&lt;/a>;作为下一任主持人“每日秀”。 2019 年，Minhaj 被选为《时代》杂志最具影响力的人物之一。在随附的文章中，诺亚&lt;a href=&quot;https://time.com/collection/100-most-influenceial-people-2019/5567704/hasan-minhaj/&quot;>;写道&lt;/a>;，“我们需要自从唐纳德·特朗普走下金色自动扶梯并将移民和穆斯林变成他的目标以来，哈桑就发出了这样的声音。”他接着说，明哈吉的“精明的评论、魅力和真诚”“不断提醒人们，哈桑就是美国。”美国就是哈桑。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在明哈吉的喜剧手法中，他很大程度上依赖于自己作为亚裔美国人和穆斯林美国人的经历，讲述了执法部门陷入困境和个人威胁的悲惨故事。对于他的许多粉丝来说，他已经成为娱乐界代表力量的化身。但是，经过几周的尝试，我无法证实他在台上讲述的一些故事。最近的一个下午，当我们在西村的一家喜剧俱乐部见面时，明哈吉第一次承认，他在 Netflix 特别节目中讲述的许多轶事都是不真实的。不过，他表示他坚持自己的工作。 “我风格中的每个故事都是围绕真理的种子建立的，”他说。 “我的喜剧《阿诺德·帕尔默》百分之七十是情感真实——这件事发生了——然后百分之三十是夸张、夸大和虚构。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;明哈吉 2022 年 Netflix 单口喜剧特辑《国王的小丑》——一部传记反思他讲述了一个关于名誉、虚荣和明哈吉对社交媒体影响力的痴迷的故事——2002 年，一名联邦调查局线人潜入了他家位于萨克拉门托地区的清真寺，当时明哈吉还是一名高中三年级学生。正如明哈吉所说，埃里克修士是一位肌肉发达的白人，自称是伊斯兰教的皈依者，他赢得了清真寺社区的信任。他去明哈吉家吃晚饭，甚至主动提出向社区的十几岁男孩教授举重训练。但明哈吉从一开始就盯住了埃里克弟兄。最终，埃里克修士试图引诱男孩们谈论圣战。明哈吉决定惹恼埃里克兄弟，告诉他他想获得飞行员执照。很快，警察就赶到了现场，将明哈吉撞到了一辆汽车的引擎盖上。多年后，明哈吉和父亲一起看新闻时，看到了克雷格·蒙泰尔 (Craig Monteilh) 的故事，他以私人教练的身份成为南加州穆斯林社区的联邦调查局 (FBI) 线人。 “好吧，好吧，好吧，爸爸，看看这是谁，”明哈吉回忆道他告诉他的父亲。 “这是我们的好朋友埃里克兄弟。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;舞台上，明哈吉身后的大屏幕上播放着半岛电视台英文版关于蒙泰尔的报道的新闻片段。看来，明哈吉青少年时期的预感被证明是正确的。这个时刻是为了搞笑，但这个故事强调了美国穆斯林在反恐战争初期所带来的威胁。 Minhaj 继续访问 &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.sfchronicle.com/projects/2022/hamid-hayat/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot; ;outgoingURL”：“https://www.sfchronicle.com/projects/2022/hamid-hayat/”}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.sfchronicle.com/projects/2022/hamid-hayat/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;哈米德·哈亚特 (Hamid Hayat) 案&lt;/a>;，一名来自萨克拉门托地区另一个城镇的年轻人，他成年后的大部分时间都在监狱里度过，他的律师称，他的供词是被迫的。 “他今年六月刚刚出狱，”明哈吉说道，语气变得挑衅。 “伙计，他和我同龄——他三十六岁了。我一直在想哈米德。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在特别节目的后面，明哈吉谈到了&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/in-netflixs- 《爱国者法案》中贾迈勒·卡舒吉被杀和纳伦德拉·莫迪的印度教民族主义片段造成的“审查-哈桑-明哈吉-金钱比谋杀更重要”的后果&lt;/a>;。大屏幕上显示着发送给明哈吉的威胁推文。最令人不安的是，他讲述了一封寄到他家的信，里面装满了白色粉末。里面的东西不小心溅到了他年幼的女儿身上。孩子被紧急送往医院。结果证明它不是炭疽病，但它清醒地提醒人们，明哈吉的喜剧行为对现实世界产生了影响。那天晚上晚些时候，他的妻子愤怒地告诉他，她怀上了他们的第二个孩子。 “‘你可以在台上说任何你想说的话，而我们必须承担后果，’”明哈吉回忆起她的话。 “‘我根本不在乎《时代》杂志认为你是一个“影响者”。如果你再让我的孩子陷入危险，我会立刻离开你。” ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这两件事都没有真正发生在 Minhaj 身上，这重要吗？&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;之前我与明哈吉·蒙泰尔（又名“埃里克兄弟”）的会面告诉我，明哈吉的故事纯属捏造。 “我不知道他为什么要这么做，”蒙泰尔说。蒙泰尔于 2002 年入狱，直到 2006 年才开始为联邦调查局 (FBI) 从事反恐措施工作。他的卧底行动细节记录在一个已提交最高法院的法律案件中。 Monteilh 说他只在南加州工作过，而不是萨克拉门托地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;纽约警察局负责调查可能存在炭疽杆菌的事件，但没有像明哈吉描述的那样的事件记录，地区也没有医院。明哈吉故居的前台和收发室员工不记得这样的事件，参与演出安保的《爱国者法案》员工或当时明哈吉的保安也不记得。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在我们的谈话中，明哈吉承认他的女儿从未接触过白色粉末，也没有住院。他说，他打开了一封送到他公寓的信，里面装有某种粉末。明哈吉说，他跟妻子开了个玩笑，说：“天哪。如果这是炭疽怎么办？”他说，他从未向节目中的任何人透露过这封信，尽管当时有人担心他的安全，而且 Netflix 已经为明哈吉聘请了保护人员。明哈吉说，埃里克兄弟的故事是基于他年轻时在一场篮球比赛中受到的严重犯规。明哈吉和其他十几岁的穆斯林与男孩们怀疑是军官的中年男子玩游戏。其中一人做出了将明哈吉推倒在地的表演。明哈吉坚称，尽管这两个故事都是编造的，但它们都是基于“情感真相”。更广泛的观点是，他试图编造合理的故事来表达这些观点。 “其中的妙语值得虚构的前提，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人们不一定会在观看单口喜剧节目时期待无懈可击的真相。他们期待笑声，也许还有一些尖锐的观察。在今年早些时候 John Heilemann 的播客中，Minhaj &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://shows.acast.com/612830d1407ad60013fa691a/episodes/hasan-minhaj&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot ;ExternalLink”,“outgoingURL”:“https://shows.acast.com/612830d1407ad60013fa691a/episodes/hasan-minhaj”}&quot; href=&quot;https://shows.acast.com/612830d1407ad60013fa691a/episodes/hasan- minhaj&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;将&lt;/a>;他的作品描述为“戏剧、讲故事和喜剧可以让你探索的动态范围。”这是否意味着观众应该期待他在台上所说的话严格遵守实地事实？当回忆录在人群面前播放以取笑时，它的狡猾性找到了新的维度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在我们的会议期间，明哈吉在他的《爱国者法案》主持职责和他的舞台作品之间划出了一条强硬的界限。他说，在他的 Netflix 特辑中，他被允许创造角色和事件来服务于讲故事，以提高他的社交观点。他反复告诉我，“情感上的真相”更重要。但在《爱国者法案》中，他的喜剧表演让位于所传达的信息。他似乎回避了这样一种可能性，即大多数人可能无法解析他们在特定时刻正在观看的哈桑·明哈吉 (Hasan Minhaj)。&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;明哈吉 (Minhaj) 在采访中讨论了白粉事件，但没有借此机会澄清他在台上描述的事件，包括他女儿的住院治疗，并没有像所描述的那样发生。 2022 年，他对《每日野兽报》表示：“我记得那一刻，天哪，有时信封会推倒。”我问他是否觉得自己操纵了观众。 “不，我不认为我在操纵，”他告诉我。 “我认为他们是来体验情感过山车的。”他接着说，“对于那些说‘哟，这太疯狂了，不可能发生’的人，我不在乎，因为是的，操，是的——这就是重点。”但是，考虑到这些事情的道德分量以及其他人实际上经历过这些事情的事实，他编造的与孩子或执法人员陷入困境的创伤经历是否令人厌恶？ “这是基于事实的，”明哈吉说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“但这并没有发生在你身上，”我回答道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我认为我最终想做的是突出所有这些故事，”他说。 “建立我认为尖锐的论点”，而不是“毫无意义的即兴重复”的笑话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;明哈吉在他的故事中省略或炮制了其他细节，通常是为了将自己更明确地置于中心位置的行动。 “我还没有公开谈论过这件事，”明哈吉在《国王的小丑》中谈到他在 2018 年试图采访穆罕默德·本·萨勒曼时说道。沙特王储正在做一个 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker .com/magazine/2018/04/09/a-saudi-princes-quest-to-remake-the-middle-east&quot;>;美国公关闪电战&lt;/a>;，与迈克尔·布隆伯格和奥普拉等人会面，明哈吉在沙特驻华盛顿大使馆安排了一次会议，讨论与他坐下来的可能性。他说，明哈吉的妻子不同意他对抗沙特的企图，因此他对她隐瞒​​了这次访问。 （特别节目的一个主题是她对他的专制诱饵喜剧风格的抵制。）在海勒曼的播客上，明哈吉说他的喜剧“让我的婚姻经历了很多，而《国王的小丑》是对我的婚姻的探索。愿意开个玩笑。”&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;在特别节目中，明哈吉将沙特大使馆的会议描述为隐约充满敌意。沙特人表示，他们不想被喜剧演员嘲笑，他们会看着他。明哈吉乘火车返回纽约，他回忆道，抵达后，“办公室里的每个人都给我发短信——‘你还好吗？’ &#39;你没事儿吧？&#39; “你在看新闻吗？”据 Minhaj 称，有关 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/the-khashoggi-body-doubleand-mounting-evidence-of-a-premeditated- 的消息刚刚传出。记者贾迈勒·卡舒吉在伊斯坦布尔沙特领事馆内被谋杀。 “感谢上帝，你没有见到沙特人。”他的妻子告诉他。&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto; height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;uzp75g&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-隐藏=“true”>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;cq4ufv&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Minhaj 承认他对自己没有对妻子更加直率感到内疚，但他也喜欢这种关注，“ 《爱国者法案》在谋杀案发生后不久播出了适时的一集，获得好评。他受邀参加《时代 100》晚会，他说他看到贾里德·库什纳 (Jared Kushner) 走进房间，粗鲁地坐在为一名被监禁的沙特活动人士空出的座位上。明哈吉警告唐纳德·特朗普的女婿在人权问题上不采取行动。明哈吉的名气上升，威胁激增，最终我们听说了炭疽事件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，据了解明哈吉日程安排的制片人称，明哈吉在沙特大使馆的会面至少发生在卡舒吉被谋杀前一个月，电子邮件确认的事情。明哈吉说，他将时间线混为一种讲故事的手段，以“让它感受到它的感觉”。明哈吉说，他的“日常生活不是很有趣或引人注目”。 “我的喜剧讲故事当然必须如此。”而且，尽管明哈吉在《时代 100》晚宴上非常公开地批评库什纳特朗普政府对沙特侵犯人权行为的软弱反应，但并没有为一位活动人士留出礼仪席位，更不用说库什纳了明哈吉说，这是另一个捏造的事实，目的是为了让人们了解当时的“情感真相”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当喜剧演员被要求评论另一​​个人的艺术时，他们会感到明显的不适——一种&lt;em>;omertà&lt;/em>; 代码。但与我交谈的一些作家和表演者对明哈吉的说教姿态感到愤怒。一位前《爱国者法案》员工表示：“他从语气上表现出自己是一个总是在推翻世界上的暴君和独裁者，总是对权力说真话的人。” “这太刺耳了。”一位曾为《每日秀》工作过的喜剧作家表示，大多数漫画的表演都不会通过严格的事实核查，但是，如果一个节目建立在分享一些个人的东西之上，而这些东西不一定是令人捧腹大笑的，发明重要细节可能会让观众觉得自己被欺骗了。 “如果他对真实的人和真实的事件撒谎，那就是一个问题，”作者说。 “这些故事的吸引力很大程度上在于‘这真的发生了’。” ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Minhaj 的项目模糊了娱乐和舆论新闻之间的界限。普及喜剧新闻主流形式的乔恩·斯图尔特一直坚称自己不是记者，但无法否认&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2015/08/ 10/exit-stage-left&quot;>;他的《每日秀》&lt;/a>;提供了固执己见的观点，这些观点为该剧的主要年轻观众提供了信息。约翰·奥利弗 (John Oliver) 也否认自己是一名记者，尽管他的 HBO 节目的每一集都深入探讨了公共话题——人工智能、单独监禁、科技垄断。这不是舆论新闻。喜剧演员可能不愿意称自己为喜剧演员，但他们中的一些人，包括明哈吉，已经尖锐地介入了政治对话。他们已经成为我们这个时代古怪的公共知识分子，并且在向公众通报情况时，他们承担了道德仲裁者的某种地位。当撒谎是为了证明社会观点而不是为了引起轻松的笑声时，他们的道德分量会改变吗？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;曾在《爱国者法案》编剧室工作的喜剧演员伊斯梅尔·卢特菲（Ismael Loutfi）为明哈吉辩护，尤其是涉及联邦调查局线人的故事时。卢特菲在佛罗里达长大，是一名穆斯林，他提到了他听说的坦帕地区清真寺在 9/11 事件后遭到渗透的故事。 “也许他只是将三四个事实合二为一，”卢特菲说。 “你看到的每一个讲笑话的脱口秀都有一定的真实性，但引起笑声的却是不诚实的。我可以理解你会觉得它有点名誉扫地，但同时我不认为这是我听过任何人谈论过的故事。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;事实上，清真寺的院长明哈吉在成长过程中参加过的活动记得 9/11 后时代发生的一件事，一名男子周五来到清真寺，行为十分可疑，以至于伊玛目打电话给美国伊斯兰关系委员会的一名律师，后者反过来，这名男子再也没有出现在清真寺，但很容易看出这样的事件会给明哈吉留下怎样的印象。谈到炭疽病的故事，卢特菲说，他在观看《国王的小丑》时觉得这个故事非同寻常，但它却让明哈吉在《爱国者法案》的演出中感受到了真挚的感受。 “确实存在明显的恐惧，”卢特菲说。明哈吉在网上收到了死亡威胁，据他的保安、前纽约警察局官员称，有人向 Netflix 发送了一封威胁明哈吉的信，但信中没有任何粉末。明哈吉还向我承认，《国王的小丑》中大屏幕上显示的威胁性推文并不真实，而是为了达到喜剧效果而增强的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《爱国者法案》因其喜剧性而受到赞誉。 -一个目的，在大流行期间取消它引起了粉丝的哀悼。 “&lt;em>;Patriot Act&lt;/em>; provided biting comedy and cultural analysis with an eye to the South Asian diaspora, a population that has historically suppressed such discourse,” one &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vulture.com/2020/08/patriot-act-wasnt-perfect-but-it-was-ours.html&quot;>;eulogy&lt;/a>; for the show read. Many stories on the cancellation also mentioned a series of tweets from former female employees of color alluding to their poor work experience behind the scenes. A document reviewed by &lt;em>;The New Yorker&lt;/em>; revealed that three women had hired an attorney and threatened litigation against Netflix and “Patriot Act” &#39;s production company, alleging gender discrimination, sex-based harassment, and retaliation. Prashanth Venkataramanujam, Minhaj&#39;s creative partner and the show&#39;s co-creator, said that he had been “surprised” by the tweets. “Clearly, some people who worked at the show did not enjoy their experience, which is painful to hear,” he said in a statement. “We tried very hard to make &#39;Patriot Act&#39; one of the most inclusive and diverse spaces in all of late-night, and it was.” (The legal matter settled out of court.)&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;According to former “Patriot Act” employees, members of the research department felt that Minhaj could be dismissive of the fact-checking process. “[Minhaj] just assembled people around him to make him appear different and much smarter and more thoughtful,” a female researcher said. “But those people—the smart people and hardworking people—were treated poorly for bringing the perspective that he is celebrated for.” Like other comedy news shows, “Patriot Act” hired journalists to write briefing memos—based on reporting and research—that were meant to serve as the factual basis for twenty-five-minute episodes on topics such as Amazon, protests in Sudan, and corruption in cricket. In one instance, Minhaj grew frustrated that fact-checking was stymying the creative flow during a final rewrite, and a pair of female researchers were asked to leave the writers&#39; room. They sat in the hall for more than an hour, listening to the meeting continue without them, and later had to scramble to insert factual revisions. Later in the show&#39;s run, researchers were no longer invited into the writers&#39; room for rewrites—only the male head of the research department was allowed in. Women researchers said that they felt shunted to the side.Venkataramanujam said that the decision was meant to streamline the show&#39;s process and was not designed to exclude individual researchers. He also said that researchers being sent out of rewrites was standard practice and that the researchers chose to stay in the hall. “Fact-checking at Patriot Act was extremely rigorous,” Minhaj said in a written statement. “A team of news producers fact-checked every line of every draft of every script at least 8-10 times before I ever said anything on camera.”&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Minhaj often talks about his immigrant upbringing and the social alienation that sometimes came with being a racial minority in his home town. The central story of his first Netflix special, “Homecoming King,” which was released in 2017, is about his crush on a friend, a white girl with whom he shared a stolen kiss and who accepted his invitation to prom but later reneged in a humiliating fashion; Minhaj showed up on her doorstep the night of the dance, only to see another boy putting a corsage on her wrist. Onstage, Minhaj says that his friend&#39;s parents didn&#39;t want their daughter to take pictures with a brown boy, because they were concerned about what their relatives might think. “I&#39;d eaten off their plates,” Minhaj says. “I&#39;d kissed their daughter. I didn&#39;t know that people could be bigoted even as they were smiling at you.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;But the woman disputed certain facts. She told me that she&#39;d turned down Minhaj, who was then a close friend, in person, days before the dance. Minhaj acknowledged that this was correct, but he said that the two of them had long carried different understandings of her rejection. As a “brown kid in Davis, California,” he said, he&#39;d been conditioned to put his head down and “just take it, and I did.” The “emotional truth” of the story he told onstage was resonant and justified the fabrication of details. “There are so many other kids who have had a similar sort of doorstep experience,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;c3r188&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;The woman also said that she and her family had faced online threats and doxing for years because Minhaj had insufficiently disguised her identity, including the fact that she was engaged to an Indian American man. A source with knowledge of the production said that, during the show&#39;s Off Broadway run, Minhaj had used a real picture of the woman and her partner, with their faces blurred, projected behind him as he told the story.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The woman said that Minhaj had invited her and her husband to an Off Broadway performance. She had initially interpreted the invitation as an attempt to rekindle an old friendship, but she now believes the move was meant to humiliate her. Later, she said, when she confronted Minhaj about the online threats brought on by the Netflix special—“I spent years trying to get threads taken down,” she told me—Minhaj shrugged off her concerns. Minhaj said that he didn&#39;t recall that interaction, and pointed to the fact that he had been in touch with her prior to the airing of the special, recommending she scrub social-media posts that might indicate her relationship to him. Minhaj also noted that the tone of their texts and e-mails was always friendly.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;What is the truth in this instance? “Homecoming King” offers a broader observation about the often insidious nature of racism in American suburbs. But what duty does the storyteller have to the real person who is on the other side of his tale, whether it be a high-school crush or a felon turned FBI informant? (Minhaj said that he owed nothing to Monteilh, based on his behavior toward the Muslim community.) The nature of storytelling, let alone comedic storytelling, is inventive; its primary aim is to make an impression, to amuse or to engage. But the stakes appear to change when entertainers fabricate anecdotes about current events and issues of social injustice. In 2015, the comedian Steve Rannazzisi, who appeared on all seven seasons of FX&#39;s “The League,” admitted that he had lied about evacuating from the Twin Towers on the morning of 9/11, narrowly escaping death when the second plane hit. In interviews, he had used the story to explain his motivation for abandoning a corporate job in Manhattan to pursue an entertainment career in Hollywood, a trajectory that would have seemed remarkable enough without any embellishment. The writer and monologuist &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/mike-daiseys-pride&quot;>;Mike Daisey&lt;/a>; faced blowback for making up details in his story for “This American Life” about Apple&#39;s Foxconn plant in China, but his point about poor working conditions was an important one to make. In a blog post titled “Some Thoughts After the Storm,” Daisey wrote, “When I said onstage that I had personally experienced things I in fact did not, I failed to honor the contract I&#39;d established with my audiences over many years and many shows.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;When Minhaj appeared on the comedian Marc Maron&#39;s podcast, in 2021, the two had a &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://podcasts.apple.com/md/podcast/hasan-minhaj/id329875043?i=1000539601592&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://podcasts.apple.com/md/podcast/hasan-minhaj/id329875043?i=1000539601592&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://podcasts.apple.com/md/podcast/hasan-minhaj/id329875043?i=1000539601592&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;conversation&lt;/a>; about how comedians portray themselves and their emotional lives onstage. The comedian, Minhaj said, must guide the audience to a particular emotional takeaway: “Bring it home, what is the point?” Maron seemed to raise the idea that, in “Homecoming King,” Minhaj had constructed an onstage emotional history that wasn&#39;t entirely honest. “Your show was tight, it was effective, it had a message, the punch line at the end was very clever. It was good, the story was good—you lucked out with these life things and you organize them,” he said. “I&#39;m not criticizing that. I&#39;m just saying that there is a big difference between what you put out in the world and who you are personally.” He went on, “When you talk about your father or that woman that jilted you in high school or whatever, you&#39;re going to have to weigh the repercussions. Either you respect them or you don&#39;t. And then you have to balance that out. At what point is this disrespectful, and at what point do I not give a shit anymore?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Minhaj seems unconflicted about his choices. “You have got to take the shots you are given in life, even if they&#39;re built on a lie,” Minhaj says during a bit in “The King&#39;s Jester.” When we spoke, I asked, were he to get “The Daily Show” hosting job, if his fabrications could put him in a compromised position when commenting on someone such as George Santos. Minhaj brushed the question off. “I think, when George Santos says he&#39;s on the volleyball team, it&#39;s a pointless story,” he responded. Minhaj&#39;s “fiction” was always in service to a bigger point, putting him in a different moral category than Santos. He appeared unwilling to engage with the idea that his position in the comedic landscape is unique, or that the host of a comedy news show might be held to more stringent standards of accuracy across his body of work. When it came to his stage shows, he told me, “the emotional truth is first. The factual truth is secondary.” ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;7rt1oj&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 18:06:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Goings On]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/goings-on/new-york-city-ballet-celebrates-seventy-five-years-of-mr-b]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65009e4fb315a844d53ab9be/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/230925_r42972.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/molly-fischer&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Molly Fischer&lt;/strong>;&lt;/a>;&lt;br/>;Staff writer&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;external-link-embed--inline&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;a aria-label=&quot;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;You&#39;re reading the Goings On newsletter, a guide to what we&#39;re watching, listening to, and doing this week. &amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;Sign up to receive it in your in-box.&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt;&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://newyorker.com/newsletter/goings-on&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://newyorker.com/newsletter/goings-on&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;span >;&lt;em>;You&#39;re reading the Goings On newsletter, a guide to what we&#39;re watching, listening to, and doing this week. &lt;strong>;Sign up to receive it in your in-box.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/em>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;September, that traditional time of abundance!&lt;/strong>; I am thinking, of course, of fashion magazines. They used to greet autumn with a cornucopia of advertising: &lt;em>;Vogue&#39;s&lt;/em>; September issue was once a thing of such awesome bounty that it inspired a movie—RJ Cutler&#39;s documentary “The September Issue,” from 2009. Now the advertisers have decamped for the Internet, and magazines are much skinnier.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Eckhaus Latta Spring 2024 Ready To Wear Runway Show in NYC&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650098793b75385eeae319f4/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/GettyImages-1655450444_for%2520Go.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650098793b75385eeae319f4/master/w_120,c_limit/GettyImages-1655450444_for%20Go.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650098793b75385eeae319f4/master/w_240,c_limit/GettyImages-1655450444_for%20Go.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650098793b75385eeae319f4/master/w_320,c_limit/GettyImages-1655450444_for%20Go.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650098793b75385eeae319f4/master/w_640,c_limit/GettyImages-1655450444_for%20Go.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650098793b75385eeae319f4/master/w_960,c_limit/GettyImages-1655450444_for%20Go.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650098793b75385eeae319f4/master/w_1280,c_limit/GettyImages-1655450444_for%20Go.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650098793b75385eeae319f4/master/w_1600,c_limit/GettyImages-1655450444_for%20Go.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Eckhaus Latta, Spring/Summer 2024.&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Photograph by Giovanni Giannoni / WWD / Getty&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Two books published this fall, which I review in next week&#39;s issue, out on Monday, explore how social commerce has blossomed in the past decade or so. &lt;strong>;“&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Extremely-Online-Untold-Influence-Internet/dp/1982146869&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Extremely-Online-Untold-Influence-Internet/dp/1982146869&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Extremely-Online-Untold-Influence-Internet/dp/1982146869&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Extremely Online&lt;/a>;,”&lt;/strong>; by &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/taylorlorenz/?hl=en&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.instagram.com/taylorlorenz/?hl=en&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/taylorlorenz/?hl=en&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Taylor Lorenz&lt;/a>;, breaks down the many ways influencers and other online-content creators have found to make a living. “Fashion was one of the first industries to recognize the usefulness of bloggers and social media power users,” Lorenz points out. Back in 2009, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/tavi-gevinson&quot;>;Tavi Gevinson&lt;/a>;—a thirteen-year-old fashion prodigy with a blog called Style Rookie—was a novelty in the front rows of New York Fashion Week. But even if some magazine editors raised their eyebrows at Internet interlopers, brands and retailers were quick to recognize their commercial potential—and, more broadly, the potential of having so many iPhones trained on the runway. Fashion weeks quickly became social-media spectacles. Now the observers best equipped to make sense of this shift manage to take part in the effervescent online scene while grounding it in history; the fashion writers &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/theprophetpizza/?hl=en&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.instagram.com/theprophetpizza/?hl=en&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/theprophetpizza/?hl=en&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Rachel Tashjian&lt;/a>; and &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://emiliapetrarca.substack.com/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://emiliapetrarca.substack.com/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://emiliapetrarca.substack.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Emilia Petrarca&lt;/a>; are two of my favorites.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;“&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Glossy-Ambition-Beauty-Inside-Glossier/dp/1982190604&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Glossy-Ambition-Beauty-Inside-Glossier/dp/1982190604&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Glossy-Ambition-Beauty-Inside-Glossier/dp/1982190604&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Glossy&lt;/a>;,”&lt;/strong>; by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/marisa-meltzer&quot;>;Marisa Meltzer&lt;/a>;, offers a case study in Instagram-era branding. It tells the story of Glossier, a beauty company founded by Emily Weiss, in 2014. When the line first appeared, the attitude and aesthetic conjured by Weiss and her team easily overshadowed the products themselves. The brand&#39;s style—carefully effortless, with lots of pale pink—would eventually become synonymous with Instagram as a whole. Lorenz&#39;s book focusses on paid influencers who&#39;ve made a living off advertising and sponsored content; Meltzer notes that Glossier, at the start, relied on an unpaid army of fans, who tagged the brand in their selfies and posted photos of its stores. Either way, the result was an online landscape where brands posted like people and people posted like brands—a cacophony of hype that endures.&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;align-center&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:align-center&quot;>;&lt;h2 >;Spotlight&lt;/h2>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Goings On&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65009e4fb315a844d53ab9be/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/230925_r42972.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65009e4fb315a844d53ab9be/master/w_120,c_limit/230925_r42972.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65009e4fb315a844d53ab9be/master/w_240,c_limit/230925_r42972.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65009e4fb315a844d53ab9be/master/w_320,c_limit/230925_r42972.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65009e4fb315a844d53ab9be/master/w_640,c_limit/230925_r42972.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65009e4fb315a844d53ab9be/master/w_960,c_limit/230925_r42972.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65009e4fb315a844d53ab9be/master/w_1280,c_limit/230925_r42972.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65009e4fb315a844d53ab9be/master/w_1600,c_limit/230925_r42972.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Photograph by Erin Baiano&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;6&quot; >;Dance&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;In 1948, the nascent &lt;strong>;New York City Ballet&lt;/strong>; found its footing, becoming the company-in-residence at City Center. Before then, the future of Lincoln Kirstein&#39;s vision for a troupe centered on the works of George Balanchine had looked iffy. Seventy-five years later, the company is still kicking. The fall season, with nineteen ballets, is dedicated to Balanchine; it starts with the three-act “Jewels” (1967), set to music by Fauré, Stravinsky, and Tchaikovsky. Other performances include “Serenade” (pictured), and the program that opened NYCB&#39;s first season at City Center, a showcase of Mr. B.&#39;s range: the rigor of “Concerto Barocco,” the emotional depth of “Orpheus,” and the luminosity of “Symphony in C.”—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/marina-harss&quot;>;&lt;em>;Marina Harss&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>; &lt;em>;(David H. Koch Theatre, Sept. 19-Oct. 15.)&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;An illustration of the New York City skyline.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ad7fea3f0ea61101b7b5aa/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/header-2023.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ad7fea3f0ea61101b7b5aa/master/w_120,c_limit/header-2023.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ad7fea3f0ea61101b7b5aa/master/w_240,c_limit/header-2023.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ad7fea3f0ea61101b7b5aa/master/w_320,c_limit/header-2023.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ad7fea3f0ea61101b7b5aa/master/w_640,c_limit/header-2023.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ad7fea3f0ea61101b7b5aa/master/w_960,c_limit/header-2023.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ad7fea3f0ea61101b7b5aa/master/w_1280,c_limit/header-2023.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ad7fea3f0ea61101b7b5aa/master/w_1600,c_limit/header-2023.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;align-center&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:align-center&quot;>;&lt;h2 >;About Town&lt;/h2>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;6&quot; >;Podcast&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Like its mock-heroic title, the splashy new Spotify podcast &lt;strong>;“Strike Force Five,”&lt;/strong>; accented by mock-majestic thunderclaps, has a frisson of the Super Friends at the Hall of Justice: five big late-night TV hosts—Stephen Colbert, Jimmy Fallon, Jimmy Kimmel, Seth Meyers, and John Oliver—unite to do good, by raising money for their shows&#39; staffers during the ongoing WGA strike, and enjoy the glory that comes with it. It&#39;s an amiable, loosely structured gab, in which their interpersonal dynamic—mutually respectful, with liberal chops busting—provides some intrigue as they riff about strike-era news stories that they&#39;re sad to have missed (three of Trump&#39;s indictments, the Prigozhin saga, a virally slow Somalian sprinter), swap show-biz anecdotes, and, occasionally, discuss the importance of the strike.—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/sarah-larson&quot;>;&lt;em>;Sarah Larson&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;6&quot; >;Classical Music&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Franz Schubert wrote hundreds of lieder before his death, at the age of thirty-one. The last ones, collected and published posthumously as the “Schwanengesang” (“Swan Song”), build on archetypes of Romantic passion: red roses, treetops rustling in the moonlight, Atlas bowed beneath a world of sorrows. The German tenor Jonas Kaufmann, who performs those works with his adept accompanist, Helmut Deutsch, is renowned for his gorgeous voice. Is the music enough? &lt;strong>;“Doppelganger,”&lt;/strong>; a new, staged version—directed by Claus Guth and billed as “part performance and part installation art”—adds a narrative (a fallen soldier sees his own ghost) to the eponymous finale, and plumps Schubert&#39;s songs with video projections, and a soundscape composed by Mathis Nitschke. Romance isn&#39;t dead yet.—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/fergus-mcintosh&quot;>;&lt;em>;Fergus McIntosh&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>; &lt;em>;(Park Avenue Armory Drill Hall; Sept. 22-28.)&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;6&quot; >;House Music&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Portrait of Uncle Waffles&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ff26a72fd41dd8ef9fb2ea/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/IMG_3022.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ff26a72fd41dd8ef9fb2ea/master/w_120,c_limit/IMG_3022.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ff26a72fd41dd8ef9fb2ea/master/w_240,c_limit/IMG_3022.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ff26a72fd41dd8ef9fb2ea/master/w_320,c_limit/IMG_3022.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ff26a72fd41dd8ef9fb2ea/master/w_640,c_limit/IMG_3022.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ff26a72fd41dd8ef9fb2ea/master/w_960,c_limit/IMG_3022.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ff26a72fd41dd8ef9fb2ea/master/w_1280,c_limit/IMG_3022.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ff26a72fd41dd8ef9fb2ea/master/w_1600,c_limit/IMG_3022.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Photograph by Pedro Ridwan&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;In the past few years, African pop has been infiltrated by the sounds of amapiano, a subgenre of house music born in South Africa which features an elastic, percussive digital bass known as the log drum. One of amapiano&#39;s defining practitioners, and perhaps its greatest ambassador, is the Swazi-born dj and producer Lungelihle Zwane, who performs as &lt;strong>;Uncle Waffles;&lt;/strong>; since 2021, she has spread its gospel internationally, earning signal boosts from Drake and Beyoncé in the process. The two EPs she released this year—“Asylum,” from March, and “Solace,” from August—display her range as a mood-setter, with tracks spanning shuffling dance-floor movers and softer, more R. &amp;amp; B.-adjacent wind-downs. In either state, her grooves are so infectious that even she can&#39;t resist dancing.—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/sheldon-pearce&quot;>;&lt;em>;Sheldon Pearce&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>; &lt;em>;(Avant Gardner; Sept. 22.)&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;6&quot; >;Television&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Misery&#39;s the only wanted company in Hulu&#39;s &lt;strong>;“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/on-television/how-this-fool-became-the-summers-best-comedy&quot;>;This Fool&lt;/a>;,”&lt;/strong>; a bawdy, laugh-out-loud comedy that riffs on Black-Latinx tensions and delves into depression and its absurdities. In the first season, Julio (Chris Estrada) is a case manager at a Los Angeles nonprofit called Hugs Not Thugs—run by the righteous but unhinged Minister Payne (Michael Imperioli)—that helps former gang members reintegrate into society. Julio takes on his cousin Luis (Frankie Quiñones), just out of prison, who moves in. In the looser and more experimental new season, Hugs Not Thugs has gone under, and the men squabble over who&#39;s unhappier—with some competition from a now dissolute Minister Payne. When Julio opens a coffee shop called Mugs Not Thugs, run by ex-felons, it reactivates his savior complex, Luis&#39;s knee-jerk defensiveness, and Minister Payne&#39;s itch for redemption.—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/inkoo-kang&quot;>;&lt;em>;Inkoo Kang&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;6&quot; >;Movies&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;zpe96nj&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Shailene Woodley and Paul Dano star in “Dumb Money.”&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ff5c76fbe5b1290e51cec6/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/DF-01550_r_2000x1333.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ff5c76fbe5b1290e51cec6/master/w_120,c_limit/DF-01550_r_2000x1333.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ff5c76fbe5b1290e51cec6/master/w_240,c_limit/DF-01550_r_2000x1333.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ff5c76fbe5b1290e51cec6/master/w_320,c_limit/DF-01550_r_2000x1333.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ff5c76fbe5b1290e51cec6/master/w_640,c_limit/DF-01550_r_2000x1333.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ff5c76fbe5b1290e51cec6/master/w_960,c_limit/DF-01550_r_2000x1333.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ff5c76fbe5b1290e51cec6/master/w_1280,c_limit/DF-01550_r_2000x1333.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64ff5c76fbe5b1290e51cec6/master/w_1600,c_limit/DF-01550_r_2000x1333.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Shailene Woodley and Paul Dano.&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Photograph by Claire Folger / Courtesy Sony&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p >;The financial drama &lt;strong>;“Dumb Money”&lt;/strong>; is based on the true story of retail investors&#39; rush, in 2021, to purchase shares in GameStop, contradicting big Wall Street firms and putting several of them at risk. A Massachusetts-based financial analyst named Keith Gill (Paul Dano), who&#39;s also a social-media influencer called Roaring Kitty, prompts the buying frenzy, partly as a rebuke to institutional investors such as Gabe Plotkin (Seth Rogen), who&#39;d been shorting the stock. When it skyrockets, Gabe risks losing billions—and Keith and the many small investors who&#39;ve joined him (such as a nurse, played by America Ferrera) stand to win big. The movie, directed by Craig Gillespie, is better at explaining financial abstractions than at developing characters; it&#39;s nonetheless a gleeful romp through strange and treacherous territory.—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/richard-brody&quot;>;&lt;em>;Richard Brody&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;6&quot; >;Movies&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;There&#39;s a fascinating quasi-documentary aspect to &lt;strong>;“Cassandro,”&lt;/strong>; a heartfelt but largely methodical bio-pic about the &lt;em>;lucha libre&lt;/em>; wrestler Saúl Armendáriz, who competed under the stage name of the title. The film, directed by Roger Ross Williams, shows Saúl (played with fierce purpose and lacerating wit by Gael García Bernal) crafting the character of Cassandro, an &lt;em>;exótico&lt;/em>;, a wrestler who performs in drag. Working hard with a new trainer (Roberta Colindrez), Saúl decides to become the first &lt;em>;exótico&lt;/em>;—traditionally the sport&#39;s patsy—who wins. The movie reveals the athleticism and unscripted danger of a spectacle often considered mere showmanship. Saúl is a gay man who has had to face prejudice in his family and in the world, and his battle for respect in the ring is depicted as a crucial part of his wider quest.—&lt;em>;Richard Brody&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Goings On&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64b58b3399c75b29bf38350d/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/GOAT-PickThree-web.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64b58b3399c75b29bf38350d/master/w_120,c_limit/GOAT-PickThree-web.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64b58b3399c75b29bf38350d/master/w_240,c_limit/GOAT-PickThree-web.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64b58b3399c75b29bf38350d/master/w_320,c_limit/GOAT-PickThree-web.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64b58b3399c75b29bf38350d/master/w_640,c_limit/GOAT-PickThree-web.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64b58b3399c75b29bf38350d/master/w_960,c_limit/GOAT-PickThree-web.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64b58b3399c75b29bf38350d/master/w_1280,c_limit/GOAT-PickThree-web.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64b58b3399c75b29bf38350d/master/w_1600,c_limit/GOAT-PickThree-web.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;align-center&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:align-center&quot;>;&lt;h2 >;Pick Three&lt;/h2>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;align-center&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:align-center&quot;>;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;The staff writer&lt;/em>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/naomi-fry&quot;>;&lt;em>;Naomi Fry&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>; &lt;em>;on the most stylish documentaries.&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;1.&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;“Unzipped”&lt;/strong>; (1995). One of the best and most amusing fashion docs of all time. Directed by Isaac Mizrahi&#39;s then boyfriend, Douglas Keeve, it follows the designer as he prepares for his Fall 1994 show, on the heels of crushing reviews of a previous collection. This movie has it all: Linda Evangelista and Naomi Campbell singing along to Culture Club&#39;s “Miss Me Blind,” Mizrahi sitting down with the irrepressible Eartha Kitt and her poodles (“It&#39;s almost impossible to have any style at all without the right dogs!” he says), Veronica Webb&#39;s leg getting stuck in a thigh-high stiletto boot.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;2.&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;“Heavy Metal Parking Lot”&lt;/strong>; (1986). This documentary short is an ode to the kind of style that binds a subculture together. By shooting tailgaters as they wait to enter a Judas Priest and Dokken double bill, in a Maryland arena, John Heyn and Jeff Krulik present a perfect glossary of eighties hard-rock fashions, from bandannas to teased-up mullets and wispy mustaches. Watching this doc always reminds me that, to borrow the words of one of the hard-partying concertgoers, heavy metal rules!&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;People recording a scene of a woman in a dress meeting with a man with a beer bottle.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6501eacc0b1c28a73777a40d/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/230925_r42974.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6501eacc0b1c28a73777a40d/master/w_120,c_limit/230925_r42974.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6501eacc0b1c28a73777a40d/master/w_240,c_limit/230925_r42974.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6501eacc0b1c28a73777a40d/master/w_320,c_limit/230925_r42974.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6501eacc0b1c28a73777a40d/master/w_640,c_limit/230925_r42974.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6501eacc0b1c28a73777a40d/master/w_960,c_limit/230925_r42974.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6501eacc0b1c28a73777a40d/master/w_1280,c_limit/230925_r42974.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6501eacc0b1c28a73777a40d/master/w_1600,c_limit/230925_r42974.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Illustration by Jackson Gibbs&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;3.&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;“Cracked Actor”&lt;/strong>; (1975). This BBC production, directed by Alan Yentob, follows David Bowie during part of his “Diamond Dogs” tour, in 1974. We see the singer in Los Angeles, both onstage and off, a wraith done up in slim suits in powder blue and slate gray, his hair a shocking orange-and-gold swoop. A segment in a limo as it makes its way through the California desert, with Bowie, in a wide-brimmed hat, humming along to Aretha Franklin&#39;s “Natural Woman,” is a highlight.&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;PS Good stuff on the Internet:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;ul >;&lt;li>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gq.com/story/the-race-to-catch-the-last-nazis&quot;>;“The Race to Catch the Last Nazis”&lt;/a>;&lt;/li>;&lt;li>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=kozH2NeGX6A&quot;>;David Byrne, Kimbra, and the Roots perform “Fame”&lt;/a>;&lt;/li>;&lt;li>;&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://annekadet.substack.com/p/playground&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://annekadet.substack.com/p/playground&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://annekadet.substack.com/p/playground&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;“Only in NYC: A Home for Retired Playground Animals!”&lt;/a>;&lt;/li>;&lt;/ul>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 18:06:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Friendship and Gender Rebellion in Nineties San Francisco]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/photo-booth/friendship-and-gender-rebellion-in-nineties-san-francisco]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e409d49c7c04e6d8ec/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-14.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;In “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Chloe-Sherman-Renegades-Francisco-1990s/dp/3775755179&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Chloe-Sherman-Renegades-Francisco-1990s/dp/3775755179&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Chloe-Sherman-Renegades-Francisco-1990s/dp/3775755179&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Renegades&lt;/a>;,” a new collection by the photographer Chloe Sherman, even a largely unpopulated image evokes a rich social atmosphere. The book, published by Hatje Cantz, draws from Sherman&#39;s archive of thousands of pictures that she took in the nineties among the queer community in San Francisco&#39;s Mission District, a site where rebels of gender and sexuality coalesced and cross-pollinated. In “Dinner at Fountain St. House,” taken in 1995, long tables set with mismatched plates and silverware stretch across and nearly fill a living room. The space is exuberantly busy, with walls painted mint green and scarlet red, a patterned curtain over the window, multicolored lanterns hanging from the ceiling, a fern placed on a bench in front of a wooden piano, and an alluring array of weathered chairs. Glass candlestick holders (a tiny drink umbrella teeters from one of them), breezily arranged flowers, and pieces of produce decorating the tables suggest an unfussy but intentional hominess.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A long table set for many people.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e06a22f972c10db1c6/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-01.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e06a22f972c10db1c6/master/w_120,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-01.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e06a22f972c10db1c6/master/w_240,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-01.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e06a22f972c10db1c6/master/w_320,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-01.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e06a22f972c10db1c6/master/w_640,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-01.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e06a22f972c10db1c6/master/w_960,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-01.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e06a22f972c10db1c6/master/w_1280,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-01.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e06a22f972c10db1c6/master/w_1600,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-01.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Dinner at Fountain St. House,” 1995.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;feature-large-callout&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GroupCalloutWrapper&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A woman taking a self portrait in an airplane bathroom.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0f7614bb9cc793c83/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-02.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0f7614bb9cc793c83/master/w_120,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-02.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0f7614bb9cc793c83/master/w_240,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-02.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0f7614bb9cc793c83/master/w_320,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-02.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0f7614bb9cc793c83/master/w_640,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-02.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0f7614bb9cc793c83/master/w_960,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-02.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0f7614bb9cc793c83/master/w_1280,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-02.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0f7614bb9cc793c83/master/w_1600,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-02.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Self-Portrait Flying Home,” 1997.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A person sitting at a messy desk in the 1990s.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337dfebce12b0b0432db6/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-03.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337dfebce12b0b0432db6/master/w_120,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-03.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337dfebce12b0b0432db6/master/w_240,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-03.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337dfebce12b0b0432db6/master/w_320,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-03.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337dfebce12b0b0432db6/master/w_640,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-03.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337dfebce12b0b0432db6/master/w_960,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-03.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337dfebce12b0b0432db6/master/w_1280,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-03.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337dfebce12b0b0432db6/master/w_1600,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-03.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“The Desk,” 1996.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Women wearing vintage clothes in the cab of a pickup truck.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0a06f534d5c0b2579/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-04.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0a06f534d5c0b2579/master/w_120,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-04.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0a06f534d5c0b2579/master/w_240,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-04.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0a06f534d5c0b2579/master/w_320,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-04.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0a06f534d5c0b2579/master/w_640,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-04.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0a06f534d5c0b2579/master/w_960,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-04.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0a06f534d5c0b2579/master/w_1280,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-04.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0a06f534d5c0b2579/master/w_1600,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-04.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“The Mission,” 1996.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;“People did not fit around that table,” Sherman told me when I spoke with her about “Renegades.” “We&#39;d sit down, but then there&#39;s overflow to the couches, in the kitchen, and walking around, and someone stood up, and someone sat in their spot, and you sat on laps.” She took the photo when she was living at the house with a rotating cast of four or five people who would extend a general invite to gaggles of friends and acquaintances for events: holidays, birthday parties, memorials, “Pride Christmas” in June. The book is replete with the faces, the outfits, the environments, and the attitudes of people who hung around the house on Fountain Street and the many nearby businesses owned and patronized by queer people.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;feature-large-callout&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GroupCalloutWrapper&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Two women talking at a bar one with a bright pink wig and the other wearing duct tape as a shirt.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e46a22f972c10db1c9/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-15.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e46a22f972c10db1c9/master/w_120,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-15.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e46a22f972c10db1c9/master/w_240,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-15.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e46a22f972c10db1c9/master/w_320,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-15.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e46a22f972c10db1c9/master/w_640,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-15.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e46a22f972c10db1c9/master/w_960,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-15.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e46a22f972c10db1c9/master/w_1280,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-15.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e46a22f972c10db1c9/master/w_1600,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-15.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Pink Wig and Duct Tape at Hole in the Wall,” 1999.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Young people in the 1990s.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e409d49c7c04e6d8ec/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-14.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e409d49c7c04e6d8ec/master/w_120,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-14.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e409d49c7c04e6d8ec/master/w_240,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-14.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e409d49c7c04e6d8ec/master/w_320,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-14.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e409d49c7c04e6d8ec/master/w_640,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-14.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e409d49c7c04e6d8ec/master/w_960,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-14.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e409d49c7c04e6d8ec/master/w_1280,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-14.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e409d49c7c04e6d8ec/master/w_1600,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-14.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Before the Gig,” 1997.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Looking back on that era, Sherman describes the atmosphere as similar to that of a college campus, where close proximity permits spontaneity and exchange. The small size of San Francisco proper—and, crucially, the cheap real estate that permitted her and her friends to live and own businesses there—meant that the Mission, the Castro, and Dolores Park could serve as their bohemian playground. People tended to have three housemates or more, and a typical day might start with heading to one of the places where friends could reliably be found. One hub was the Bearded Lady café, which shared a patio with Black &amp;amp; Blue Tattoo. “People just began to congregate there throughout the day and socialize and make plans,” Sherman said. “You end up at happy hour at the Lexington bar, you make your way to the Stud or the Cat Club or Josie&#39;s Cabaret.” There was a general agreement that, if there were a big earthquake, everyone would meet at the Bearded Lady.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Two of the owners of the Bearded Lady, Harry Dodge and Silas Howard, who would go on to make the experimental film “By Hook or by Crook” together and pursue fruitful artistic careers, were among the many luminaries of the scene who dot the photos. The writer Anna Joy Springer, the musician Lynn Breedlove, and the photographer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2017/03/13/catherine-opie-all-american-subversive&quot;>;Catherine Opie&lt;/a>;, all members of Sherman&#39;s circles, wrote introductions to “Renegades” that invoke not only nostalgia but a sense of the generative nature of the time and place. “We turned to each other,” Springer writes, “for the kind of protection that would allow us to explore varieties of creative play and risk that few women-centered populations had ever been safe enough to try publicly.”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;feature-large-callout&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GroupCalloutWrapper&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A woman in the shower shaving her legs.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0ebce12b0b0432db8/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-05.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0ebce12b0b0432db8/master/w_120,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-05.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0ebce12b0b0432db8/master/w_240,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-05.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0ebce12b0b0432db8/master/w_320,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-05.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0ebce12b0b0432db8/master/w_640,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-05.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0ebce12b0b0432db8/master/w_960,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-05.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0ebce12b0b0432db8/master/w_1280,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-05.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e0ebce12b0b0432db8/master/w_1600,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-05.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Lightwell,” 1997.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A person sleeping on a bed in a pink room.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e06a22f972c10db1c7/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-06.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e06a22f972c10db1c7/master/w_120,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-06.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e06a22f972c10db1c7/master/w_240,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-06.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e06a22f972c10db1c7/master/w_320,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-06.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e06a22f972c10db1c7/master/w_640,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-06.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e06a22f972c10db1c7/master/w_960,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-06.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e06a22f972c10db1c7/master/w_1280,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-06.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e06a22f972c10db1c7/master/w_1600,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-06.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Sleeping in Pink Room,” 1997.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;feature-large-callout&quot; >;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A person looking back from the front seat of a vintage car.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3fd47431d5e50a597/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-10.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3fd47431d5e50a597/master/w_120,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-10.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3fd47431d5e50a597/master/w_240,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-10.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3fd47431d5e50a597/master/w_320,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-10.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3fd47431d5e50a597/master/w_640,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-10.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3fd47431d5e50a597/master/w_960,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-10.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3fd47431d5e50a597/master/w_1280,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-10.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3fd47431d5e50a597/master/w_1600,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-10.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“View from the Backseat,” 1997.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;feature-large-callout&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GroupCalloutWrapper&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A person with slicked back hair and eyeliner.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3022245bfd8760611/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-11.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3022245bfd8760611/master/w_120,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-11.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3022245bfd8760611/master/w_240,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-11.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3022245bfd8760611/master/w_320,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-11.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3022245bfd8760611/master/w_640,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-11.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3022245bfd8760611/master/w_960,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-11.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3022245bfd8760611/master/w_1280,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-11.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3022245bfd8760611/master/w_1600,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-11.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Daniel Sea,” mid-nineties.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A person in the front seat of an older model car with their hair flying in the wind.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3ebce12b0b0432dba/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-12.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3ebce12b0b0432dba/master/w_120,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-12.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3ebce12b0b0432dba/master/w_240,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-12.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3ebce12b0b0432dba/master/w_320,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-12.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3ebce12b0b0432dba/master/w_640,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-12.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3ebce12b0b0432dba/master/w_960,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-12.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3ebce12b0b0432dba/master/w_1280,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-12.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3ebce12b0b0432dba/master/w_1600,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-12.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Elitreo in the Desert,” 1998.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Though the idiosyncratic fashions in the photos are undeniably of their age, their magpie referentiality makes the pictures seem contemporary. The images abound with vintage cars, suits, and dresses, rescued from old-timeyness by their juxtaposition with the punk aesthetics of brightly colored hair, tattoos, piercings, leather, and spikes, and by a general sense of gender anarchy. There is subversion afoot in campy iterations of butch and femme archetypes, a sense that exaggerating and remixing femininity and masculinity past the point of recognition is more fun than any futile attempt to discard them. In one image, someone in a voluminous pink wig, blue lipstick, and a leopard-print dress chats at a bar with someone in leather pants, a leopard-print collar and wrist cuffs, and a backless bustier made of duct tape. In another, called “The Dodge Brothers,” Dodge and Howard, with two other friends, gaze with ironic defiance at the camera while wearing purposefully unkempt suiting—including tuxedo shirts with ruffles—and playfully sleazy pencilled-on facial hair.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Four people standing in front of a gate.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e1a06f534d5c0b257b/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-07.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e1a06f534d5c0b257b/master/w_120,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-07.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e1a06f534d5c0b257b/master/w_240,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-07.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e1a06f534d5c0b257b/master/w_320,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-07.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e1a06f534d5c0b257b/master/w_640,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-07.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e1a06f534d5c0b257b/master/w_960,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-07.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e1a06f534d5c0b257b/master/w_1280,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-07.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e1a06f534d5c0b257b/master/w_1600,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-07.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“The Dodge Brothers,” 1997.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;feature-large-callout&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GroupCalloutWrapper&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A person on a payphone surrounded by friends.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e2022245bfd876060f/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-08.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e2022245bfd876060f/master/w_120,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-08.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e2022245bfd876060f/master/w_240,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-08.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e2022245bfd876060f/master/w_320,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-08.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e2022245bfd876060f/master/w_640,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-08.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e2022245bfd876060f/master/w_960,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-08.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e2022245bfd876060f/master/w_1280,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-08.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e2022245bfd876060f/master/w_1600,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-08.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“The Phone Call,” 1996.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Two people relaxing on a picnic blanket.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e2e8cb5056481b2841/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-09.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e2e8cb5056481b2841/master/w_120,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-09.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e2e8cb5056481b2841/master/w_240,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-09.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e2e8cb5056481b2841/master/w_320,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-09.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e2e8cb5056481b2841/master/w_640,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-09.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e2e8cb5056481b2841/master/w_960,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-09.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e2e8cb5056481b2841/master/w_1280,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-09.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e2e8cb5056481b2841/master/w_1600,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-09.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Picnic near Mission Dolores,” 1996.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Shot from the perspective of one thoroughly immersed in the subculture, the photos draw much of their energy from the easy intimacy between photographer and subject. The people featured lean on one another, nestle together, and seem to relate assuredly, both in their bedrooms and out in the lively streets, to Sherman&#39;s lens. In “Anna Joy Post Surgery at Home,” Springer peers at the ceiling from her bed, in red lipstick and a satiny burgundy robe, with a cigarette in one hand and a phone receiver in the other. Her high style and look of mild exasperation simultaneously evoke and undermine the latent melodrama of the convalescent scene. Under the gaze of a confidante, she shapes her natural gestures into a kind of pose. For Sherman and her community, self-presentation was a sacred tongue, a method of banding together in solidarity against a broader culture that was hostile to their existence. Their canny affectation is evidence not of their struggle to be legible but of the mutual knowingness shared by friends.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;feature-large-callout&quot; >;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A woman wearing a red satin dress lying on a bed on the phone holding a cigarette&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3f7614bb9cc793c85/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-13.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3f7614bb9cc793c85/master/w_120,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-13.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3f7614bb9cc793c85/master/w_240,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-13.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3f7614bb9cc793c85/master/w_320,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-13.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3f7614bb9cc793c85/master/w_640,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-13.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3f7614bb9cc793c85/master/w_960,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-13.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3f7614bb9cc793c85/master/w_1280,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-13.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650337e3f7614bb9cc793c85/master/w_1600,c_limit/Long_Chloe-Sherman-13.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Anna Joy Post Surgery at Home,” 1997.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 18:06:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Anti-Aging Secrets of the Mega-Rich]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/humor/daily-shouts/anti-aging-secrets-of-the-mega-rich]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-15T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6501e69f9f77ee8796168eeb/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Shouts-Katsir-Anto-Aging.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;A growing number of the world&#39;s richest entrepreneurs are using their wealth to fight aging. They&#39;re taking supplements, abiding by austere fitness routines, and investing millions into longevity research. —Business Insider&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;Over the two-day [Longevity Investors Conference] event, scientists and biotech founders made the case for various approaches to prolonging the number of years we might spend in good health. And the majority of them were trying to win over deep-pocketed investors. —&lt;em>;MIT Technology Review&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;How old would you guess I am? No need to say it out loud, just picture the number in your head. Now take that number (I&#39;m no mind reader, but it&#39;s fifty-nine), bump it up by a college sophomore, and you&#39;ve got my true chronological age: seventy-eight. Shocked? Of course you are. These sure don&#39;t look like a septuagenarian&#39;s earlobes: zero droop, no unsightly hair. I&#39;m not too humble to say it—you might be looking at the youngest “old man” on God&#39;s big blue orb. And it&#39;s all thanks to technology that you&#39;ll learn about today, because you made the smart decision to be wealthy enough to be invited to this year&#39;s Prolongitek VIP Investors&#39; Cruise. Give yourselves a round of applause. No hard claps, just finger taps—you don&#39;t want to end up with workman&#39;s knuckle.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I hope you enjoyed today&#39;s Longevity Lunch of 2.5 ounces of low-oxygen air and a high-altitude gooseberry. Now that you&#39;ve super-activated your spine methyl, it&#39;s time to get to the dilemma that has plagued philosophers for centuries: Why should man be cursed to age and decay, while his money remains immortal? Well, many high-net-worth visionaries have been seeking the answer, and they&#39;ve found it in Prolongitek.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;So, what is this breakthrough? Don&#39;t listen to the anti-prosperity crowd—it&#39;s far more than a protein-rich pudding. And, trust me, it goes way beyond blood transfusions from a teen-age gibbon. I&#39;m going to say some powerful words to you now: AI, crypto, telomeres, cell rejuvenation, &lt;em >;CRISPR&lt;/em>;, skin juice, meta-shirt. Prolongitek is pouring research into all of these, and, I promise you, not a drop of that research is woke.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;This is your time. You&#39;ve given so much to earn your wealth, and now you&#39;re ready to give future generations the incredible gift of more of you. The years you add to your life will be vital and fulfilling. You will be surrounded by loved ones who admire your dedication to spending nineteen hours a day in a trough of omega-3-nutrient jello.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;But we can&#39;t get to the future if we accept the old, conventional wisdom that people die. No, sir. That&#39;s why you must act now. Please direct your attention to Mr. Flintock Feister, one of our Infinity Tier investors. Flin, give us a blink. There he is, right next to the Crown Prince&#39;s attaché, looking as robust as the day he founded the Caldera Group. Would you believe that Flintock is still CEO at the chronological age of a hundred and six? That number even makes &lt;em>;him&lt;/em>; laugh, or produce some sort of noiseless joyful scream. I see the outgoing-message light flashing on Flin&#39;s communication pad. Folks, he just sent this to me: “I may be a hundred and six, but, thanks to Prolongitek, my biological age is ninety-one!” followed by a bunch of pornographic &lt;em >;GIFs&lt;/em>;. And they say bone mass peaks at age twenty-nine! I&#39;m joking, because laughter is the best medicine, which is why tonight&#39;s Endurance Dinner is an IV drip of distilled macaw laughter.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Our friend Flintock has already put a significant sum of Swiss francs behind Prolongitek, and he&#39;s not alone. I can&#39;t divulge our other big-name backers, but let&#39;s just say one of them runs a major social-media company and has already replaced his skin with a sun-resistant polymer. Another is a leader in generative computing who wants to live to see the AI revolution that he paid for. As do I. In fact, I do this work because I hope to be around when machine intelligence rules supreme, and treats humanity with the same sympathetic dignity that we show lesser creatures. Which reminds me—it&#39;s time to end the rumor that Prolongitek is just packets of powdered dolphin scrotum.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Now let&#39;s bring out the infant. Don&#39;t be alarmed—his parents signed a very generous NDA This little guy is teaching our scientists about the youthful microbiome, in between scheduled fun in the Stimulation Atrium. Be honest, everyone, who&#39;s got smoother cheeks, me or him? OK, OK, I&#39;m not quite there yet. But with Prolongitek I&#39;m catching up, baby! Great, back to the cryonics play lab with you.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Ah, I see it&#39;s time for my evening life-enhancement regimen of two hours on the stair-climber in lunar atmospheric conditions. It&#39;s not easy, but it&#39;s worth it. Much like the decision you&#39;re about to make regarding your personal fortune. Before you do, I urge you: imagine your millions of fellow-citizens, of every race, creed, and social status, who stand to benefit from your choice today. They get your estate tax only if you die. Don&#39;t let them have it—invest in tomorrow now! ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;z3oeh&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;bwcx0q&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 18:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Mitch McConnell Is Fully Cognizant It’s Only Rock and Roll]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/cartoons/blitts-kvetchbook/mitch-mcconnell-is-fully-cognizant-its-only-rock-and-roll]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14T22:59:24.999Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65037ea309d49c7c04e6dacc/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/blitt_kvetchbook_mitch_stones.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt; div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;标题>;保存&lt;/标题>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22。 1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>; &lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot; 0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2 .95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/ svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存&lt;/span >;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-内容&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >; &lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;图片 >;&lt;img alt=&quot;米奇·麦康奈尔 (Mitch McConnell) 与滚石乐队一起演奏鼓。&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65037ea309d49c7c04e6dacc/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/blitt_kvetchbook_mitch_stones.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65037ea309d49c7c04e6dacc/master/w_120,c_限制/ blitt_kvetchbook_mitch_stones.jpg 120w，https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65037ea309d49c7c04e6dacc/master/w_240,c_limit/blitt_kvetchbook_mitch_stones.jpg 240w，https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65037ea309d49c7c04 e6dacc/master/w_320,c_limit/ blitt_kvetchbook_mitch_stones.jpg 320w，https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65037ea309d49c7c04e6dacc/master/w_640,c_limit/blitt_kvetchbook_mitch_stones.jpg 640w，https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65037ea309d49c7c04 e6dacc/master/w_960,c_limit/ blitt_kvetchbook_mitch_stones.jpg 960w，https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65037ea309d49c7c04e6dacc/master/w_1280,c_limit/blitt_kvetchbook_mitch_stones.jpg 1280w，https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65037ea309d49c7c 04e6dacc/主控/w_1600，c_limit/ blitt_kvetchbook_mitch_stones.jpg 1600w&quot;sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;http:// www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;, “outgoingURL”：“http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545”}&quot; href=&quot;http: //www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;购买 &lt;em>;纽约客漫画 »&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data- testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;mzrrsh&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div 角色=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;krfhg9&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot; true&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>; &lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 08:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[The Rage of the Toddler Caucus on Capitol Hill]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/news/letter-from-bidens-washington/the-rage-of-the-toddler-caucus-on-capitol-hill]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14T22:53:05.426Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65037b2d6a22f972c10db24a/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/Glasser-Biden-Impeachment.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >; &lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox= &quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312 L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4 H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存这个故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width =&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>; &lt;路径 d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M 23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt; /svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt; div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;如果要从过去几年的美国政治中吸取任何教训的话，那就是事情总是会变得更糟。这一点值得记住，因为华盛顿开始了另一场白手起家却又令人痛苦的真实危机——2024 年竞选季的政治序幕与以往不同，前总统变身刑事被告唐纳德·特朗普在挑战后威胁要返回白宫。我们民主的核心原则。 “前所未有”这个词已经不够了。我们已经用完了同义词、类比和摆脱混乱的时间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在的问题是不同类型的，关于我们将面临什么以及何时面对的确切细节。也就是说，随着国会结束漫长的夏季休会，特朗普化、激进的众议院共和党会议正准备在本月底资金耗尽时关闭联邦政府，并准备弹劾拜登总统，两者都没有明显的理由。议长凯文·麦卡锡的多数席位如此微弱，以至于他实际上成为了党内最鲁莽的极端分子的俘虏。周二，他实际上是在寻求讨价还价——为了收买他们对保持政府开放的措施的默许，议长同意了他们对拜登及其儿子亨特的海外金融交易进行可疑弹劾调查的要求。但到了周四，麦卡锡完全没能安抚那些折磨他的人，他只能向他们扔脏话，挑衅他们兑现威胁，提出罢免他的动议。据报道，他在一次核心小组闭门会议上愤怒地说：“如果你认为你吓到了我，”&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com/live-updates/2023/09/14/congress /mccarthys-profane-dare-00115873&quot;>;移动他妈的动议&lt;/a>;。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;毫无疑问：这是一场因软弱而产生的危机。想象一下，任何其他议长同意启动弹劾调查，只是作为讨价还价的筹码——而且是失败的——在他控制自己党员的斗争中。共和党人谈论最近管理自己的虚无主义者派系的不成功努力的方式非常能说明问题。一位参议院共和党人表示：“也许这只是凯文给人们带来的宾基酒来度过政府关门” &lt;a href=&quot;https://thehill.com/homenews/house/4200161-senate-gop-unhappy-with-mccarthy-on -impeachment-inquire-its-a-fools-errand/&quot;>;向&lt;em>;国会&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;透露了麦卡锡的弹劾公告。我立即想到了也许是 2020 年大选后时期最臭名昭著的一句话，当时华盛顿集体否认特朗普正在做他正在做的事情来推翻拜登的胜利。匿名“&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://twitter.com/AshleyRParker/status/1326024025777246208&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot; ;https://twitter.com/AshleyRParker/status/1326024025777246208&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/AshleyRParker/status/1326024025777246208&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;高级共和党人&lt;/ a>;”告诉《华盛顿邮报》：&lt;/p>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;在这一点时间里迁就他有什么坏处？没有人认真地认为结果会改变。 。 。 。这个周末他去打高尔夫球了。他并不是在密谋如何阻止乔·拜登在 1 月 20 日掌权。他在推特上说要提起一些诉讼，这些诉讼将会失败，然后他会在推特上发布更多有关选举如何被窃取的推文，然后他就会离开.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;p>;很快就证明了宾基不会安抚众议院幼儿核心小组。佛罗里达州共和党人马特·盖茨 (Matt Gaetz) 对麦卡锡的威胁促使议长突然决定启动弹劾调查，尽管就在 11 天前他还表示，如果没有众议院全体投票，他不会采取这一步骤。说没关系。盖茨坚称，这只是“&lt;a href=&quot;https://apnews.com/article/mccarthy-biden-impeachment-shutdown-house-republicans-b187202be8814f7acbdd6e2e937e23d4&quot;>;一小步&lt;/a>;”。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;因此，幼儿的愤怒现在有可能让整个政府垮台。为了什么？再次证明这些人不是我们赋予伟大权力的严肃人物？周四早上，麦卡锡告诉记者，他自己也不知道为什么会发生这种情况。他的一些共和党人拒绝通过一项国防拨款法案，但对其中的内容并不表示反对。他们还反对麦卡锡首选的通过一项持续决议以保持政府开放的选择，同时与拜登政府和参议院共和党人继续进行谈判。他们也不想达成一项大型综合交易。 “我不太确定他们想要什么，” &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://twitter.com/jakesherman/status/1702300497175056748&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot; ExternalLink”，“outgoingURL”：“https://twitter.com/jakesherman/status/1702300497175056748”}“href =“https://twitter.com/jakesherman/status/1702300497175056748”rel =“nofollow noopener”目标=&quot;_blank&quot;>;他得出结论&lt;/a>;。他很快就宣布众议院休会一周，但没有取得任何进展。与此同时，议长因自身弱点而启动的弹劾程序可能会持续到 2023 年剩余时间，为特朗普提供了一个可以向拜登抛出的竞选问题，并使国会陷入更多困境。&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>;目前，拜登和他的支持者正在对这一事态发展给予最积极的粉饰。尽管很难看到有人欢迎弹劾调查，但无论有多么可疑或赤裸裸的党派偏见，在民主党占多数的参议院中，定罪的风险基本上为零。总统的捍卫者认为这可能会给他带来一些好处，这一点并没有错。共和党控制的众议院中不断发生的混乱似乎加剧了将国家托付给“让美国再次伟大”共和党人变幻无常的统治的愚蠢行为。周三晚上，在弗吉尼亚州的一次筹款活动上，拜登甚至还拿这个开玩笑。 “首先他们只是想弹劾我，” &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://twitter.com/mkraju/status/1702113207119233149&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot; ,“outgoingURL”:“https://twitter.com/mkraju/status/1702113207119233149”}&quot; href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mkraju/status/1702113207119233149&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot; _blank&quot;>;他说&lt;/a>;。 “现在，据我所知，他们想要弹劾我，因为他们想要关闭政府。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，民主党也面临着自己的软弱危机，最终屈服于半公开的统治。人们对拜登的年龄和不受欢迎的恐慌进入了选举阶段，因为一系列令人震惊的新民意调查显示他与特朗普基本上是紧密相连的。 （事实上​​​​，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/2024-election/biden-trump-tied-polls-rcna103893&quot;>;特朗普目前的民意调查显示&lt;/a>;对拜登的支持率比以往任何时候都高是在 2020 年。）机构类型，例如选举障碍 &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.cookpolitical.com/analysis/national/national-politics/case-biden-step-aside&quot; data- event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://www.cookpolitical.com/analysis/national/national-politics/case-biden-step-aside&quot;} “ href=&quot;https://www.cookpolitical.com/analysis/national/national-politics/case-biden-step-aside&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;查理·库克&lt;/a>;和《华盛顿邮报》专栏作家&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/2023/09/12/biden-trump-election-step-aside/&quot;>;David Ignatius&lt;/a最近几天，他们呼吁拜登下台，希望民主党在 2024 年成为对抗特朗普和特朗普主义的更强大的旗手。然而，没有迹象表明拜登会听取这一建议；也没有明显更强大的候选人可供民主党联合支持。许多政党战略家认为，拜登的记录既重要又受欢迎。对自己年龄的疑虑只是民主党常见的“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2023/sep/06/biden-reelection-democrats-jim-messina-obama”的另一个例子>;尿床者&lt;/a>;”，他们每四年就会对党的前景感到惊慌。其他白宫捍卫者则采取“他在竞选时闭嘴并处理它，否则就有可能在与特朗普的战斗中损害他”的方法，正如民主党策略师大卫·阿克塞尔罗德&lt;a data-offer-url =“https://twitter.com” /davidaxelrod/status/1702037239541166301&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://twitter.com/davidaxelrod/status/1702037239541166301&quot;}&quot; href= “https://twitter.com/davidaxelrod/status/1702037239541166301” rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;把它&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这周关于“早安乔”的交流伊格内修斯和该节目的联合主持人乔·斯卡伯勒之间的对话，捕捉到了人们对总统地位的真正担忧。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mediaite.com/news/joe-scarborough-reveals-every-single-democrat-he-speaks-to-off-air-admits-biden-is-too-old-to -run/&quot;>;斯卡伯勒告诉伊格内修斯&lt;/a>;，在他最近进行的“每次政治讨论”中，当拜登再次参选的话题再次出现时，“人们会说，‘伙计，他太老了，不能参选了。’” ”而且，斯卡伯勒补充道，“当我说每一次讨论时，我并不是指百分之九十九的讨论。 &lt;em>;每一次&lt;/em>;讨论。”这当然也是我的经历。而且，对白宫来说不幸的是，这些轶事得到了实际数据的证实：在最近的独立民意调查中，不仅有共和党人强烈反对拜登，甚至有多达 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/ politics/2023/09/05/biden-age/&quot;>;三分之二的民主党人&lt;/a>;表示，他们认为拜登太老了，无法连任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在我看来，受访者认为拜登太老了，无法连任。这么说不是因为他们希望特朗普获胜，而是因为他们希望他输——并且不相信拜登能够实现这一目标。 2024 年初选的提交截止日期即将到来，内华达州初选将于 10 月中旬开始。如果拜登要退出，他将不得不非常非常快地退出；最后的决定时刻即将到来。这仍然不是不可避免的，但美国似乎害怕的拜登与特朗普的复赛已接近确定。 ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;u0v07&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; >;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;v484iq&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt; div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ side>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live= “礼貌” aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/文章>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 07:06:01 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Theatre Kids Find Their Place in “Theater Camp”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/culture-desk/theatre-kids-find-their-place-in-theater-camp]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14T20:12:47.089Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65021c36d0e490b583bb2a78/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/Stahl-Theater%20Camp.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >; &lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox= &quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312 L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4 H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存这个故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width =&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>; &lt;路径 d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M 23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt; /svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt; div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;戏剧孩子是一个奇怪的品种。我知道，因为我就是其中之一。在我青少年时期的大部分时间里，我在周六晚上听一个名为“小镇之夜”的广播节目，该节目播放百老汇表演歌曲并讨论制作。如果有人问我为什么如此着迷，我不会有一个连贯的答案。我只是发现舞台有无穷无尽的魅力；在这里，你可以成为任何人，去任何地方。当像 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-new-yorker-interview/stephen-sondheim-final-interviews&quot;>;Stephen Sondheim&lt;/a>; 这样的歌曲时你们一起做的小事”来自“公司”，或&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2018/03/12/did-andrew-lloyd-webber-ruin-the-musical- or-rescue-it&quot;>;安德鲁·劳埃德·韦伯&lt;/a>;和蒂姆·赖斯在《万世巨星》中扣人心弦的“我不知道如何爱他”在广播中播出，这种体验变得超凡脱俗。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;电影《剧院营》（该片于 7 月在电影院上映，目前仍在部分影院上映，并且刚刚开始在 Hulu 上播放）中的青少年也同样着迷。事实上，他们非常热爱戏剧，以至于在一个名为 AdirondACTS 的营地度过了暑假，在那里他们学习表演、舞蹈和舞台设计课程。它的创始人是深受喜爱的琼·鲁宾斯基（艾米·塞德丽丝饰），我们在训练营经理丽塔·科恩（卡罗琳·亚伦饰）的旁边见到了她，当时他们正在为中学制作的《再见小鸟》寻找像一对足球球探。 （他们是通过标题卡介绍的，这是构成电影框架的伪纪录片装置的一部分。）演出中的闪光灯使琼癫痫发作，使她住院，基本上没有出现在画面中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;琼住院后，她的儿子、有抱负的企业家特洛伊（吉米·塔特罗，因&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@LifeAccordingToJimmy&quot;>;他的 YouTube 频道&lt;/a>;而闻名）突然接管了营地。他将积极进取的金融兄弟精神带入了新的行政职责中。 AdirondACTS 亏损数千美元；为了平衡收支，特洛伊解雇了几位长期担任教练的教练，并用一名资质严重不足的新手珍妮特（Janet）取而代之（&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/persons-of-interest/how- ayo-edebiri-从一个不舒服的孩子变成了熊明星&quot;>;Ayo Edebiri&lt;/a>;），他的废话超出了他的理解范围。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这部电影的主要乐趣之一是观看特洛伊突破商学院模式，了解营地里的人们并学习他们的语言。当常驻舞台技术人员格伦（诺亚·加尔文饰）宣布他们必须优先考虑音乐剧而不是正剧时，特洛伊问什么是正剧。 “有音乐剧，也有戏剧，”格伦解释道。 “那么什么是同性恋戏剧呢？”特洛伊问道。在一个小演员的手中，特洛伊的花花公子可能会变得令人讨厌，但塔特罗却给他赋予了一系列的情感：当戏剧老师告诉他他不属于营地时的受伤；当戏剧老师告诉他他不属于营地时的受伤；内疚，因为他被刺痛的自尊驱使他采取鲁莽的行动；当他表明也许他毕竟属于营地时，他脸上洋溢着自豪感。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;影片的其他主角一开始看起来也很熟悉，但逐渐显露出内心的复杂性。热情、有精神倾向的音乐总监丽贝卡-黛安（莫莉·戈登饰）向珍妮特提供了她的能量治愈天赋，她直觉地认为珍妮特的氛围“非常混乱”。阿莫斯 (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/03/20/ben-platt-parade-broadway-skinheads&quot;>;Ben Platt&lt;/ a>;)，表演老师，恰好是她儿时暗恋的人，后来变成了最好的同性恋朋友。他们是在 AdirondACTS 营员时期认识的。自从成为辅导员以来，他们每年都负责编写和导演一部音乐剧，作为该营的旗舰作品。 （今年夏天，这是向昏迷的琼致敬。）如果说丽贝卡-黛安有点迷人，那么阿莫斯就有点像天后了，尽管与舞蹈老师的宏伟（内森·李·格雷厄姆，&lt;em>;生活&lt; /em>; 对于这个角色，亲爱的）和服装教练（欧文蒂勒）的狡猾，他是万宝路男人。技术人员格伦总是结结巴巴、谦虚——直到特洛伊在自己的成熟过程中发现了更深层次的东西。&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;加尔文、戈登和普拉特与这部电影以及对彼此来说远远超出了他们的角色。他们三人共同撰写了剧本，戈登与尼克·利伯曼共同执导。丽贝卡-黛安和阿莫斯之间的友谊类似于戈登和普拉特现实生活中的友谊，至少在起源上是这样。两人小时候在一个戏剧节目中相识。高尔文接替普拉特成为百老汇作品《&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2016/12/19/pop-psychology-onstage-in-dear-evan-汉森“亲爱的埃文·汉森&lt;/a>;”现在是他的未婚夫。 《戏剧营》是他们三人长期热衷的项目，最初是 2020 年发布的短片，多年来一直在努力寻找资金，最终在圣丹斯电影节上被探照灯影业广泛发行。一月。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;戈登、高尔文和普拉特对他们的素材的喜爱在影片的善意和幽默中都体现出来。 《戏剧营》有一种笑话书的感觉，从不同的角度取笑它的主题：一位年轻的演员因用催泪棒在舞台上哭泣而感到羞耻（“给演员服用兴奋剂”）；一位老师为他的任何可能考虑从事表演艺术职业的青少年学生设定了期望。 “你需要知道，只有百分之三的人能成功，”他告诉他们。 “其余的人最终会被关进精神病院或地狱厨房的走动盒子里。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不乏智慧，但在某些情况下缺乏性格发展。以格雷厄姆的舞蹈老师为例，他表演得很华丽，但观众永远不会发现他崇高情感背后的原因，也无法看到他的成长。格伦这个角色是一个更大的错失机会。在特洛伊的帮助下，他在最后一刻从幕后出现，在营地的原创音乐剧中饰演琼，展现出的才华甚至让难以打动的阿莫斯惊叹不已。然而我们不禁要问：格伦只是隐藏了他巨大的天赋吗？或者他的表演是否表明了某种更深层次、更复杂的东西，也许是一种不同的性别认同？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;格伦的明星转变也许是对 2003 年邪教经典《夏令营》的致敬，这是另一部关于暑期项目的电影。年轻的表演者。在那里，安娜·肯德里克 (Anna Kendrick) 饰演的弗里茨 (Fritzi) 从一个安静的跟班变成了一个地狱般的首席女主角，她那令人震惊的《吃午餐的女士》(The Ladies Who Lunch) 的表演将让人们&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/culture-desk/ ill-miss-her&quot;>;伊莱恩·斯特里奇&lt;/a>;畏缩在桌子底下。但弗里茨转变的力量很大程度上来自于看到她在整部电影中都被欺负；格伦的内心女主角在他的突破时刻之前只被瞥见一次，所以突破更像是一个特技，而不是一个角色弧线的完成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，真正落地的是电影对冲突的描述。艺术与商业之间存在着矛盾，前者以营员和辅导员为代表，对他们来说，戏剧是一种生活方式，后者以财务顾问卡罗琳·克劳斯（帕蒂·哈里森饰）为代表，她的公司想接管营地。她的公司已经吞并了湖滨区，这是附近富家子弟的度假胜地。富有商业头脑的特洛伊负责 AdirondACTS，卡罗琳感觉到了机会，年轻人的希望和梦想都被诅咒了。当戏剧类型受到深情讽刺时，卡罗琳被彻底妖魔化为焦土企业泼妇。认真对待她是不可能的，但她所代表的威胁是真实的。每个艺术企业，无论是青年营还是专业表演场所，都必须在忠于其使命与财务必要性之间取得平衡。有时，正如百老汇塞尔温剧院“重新命名”为美国航空剧院所证明的那样，这意味着需要权衡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;剧透警告：AdirondACTS 最终幸存下来，这要归功于来自一位富有的观众。这种幸运的干预被视为一种胜利，是艺术感动人们的力量的一个例子。但这也凸显了剧院和其他艺术机构对富裕顾客的依赖。今年夏天营地可能已经勉强度过了，但明年呢？话又说回来，也许这种挣扎的因素——不仅是电影角色面临的，也是其创作者在多年来寻找资金的过程中面临的——也是献身于戏剧的意义的一部分。没有一个理智的人会为了钱而进入艺术领域；他们的驱动力类似于那些年来让我听“小镇之夜”的东西。 “戏剧营”是对这种理想主义艺术精神的庆祝；它可能会错过一些线索，但它永远不会缺乏内心。 ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;nn5u3&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; >;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;2hj3j&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt; div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ side>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live= “礼貌” aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/文章>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 05:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[The 2023 National Book Awards Longlist: Nonfiction]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/books/page-turner/the-2023-national-book-awards-longlist-nonfiction]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14T19:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6500d2069f77ee8796168e2e/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/non-fiction%20v1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >; &lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox= &quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312 L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4 H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存这个故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width =&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>; &lt;路径 d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M 23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt; /svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt; div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;&lt;em>;本周，《纽约客》将公布 2023 年国家图书入围名单奖项。到目前为止，我们已经列出了&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/books/page-turner/the-2023-national-book-awards-longlist-young-peoples-literature&quot;>;的列表青少年文学&lt;/a>;、&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/books/page-turner/the-2023-national-book-awards-longlist-translated-literature&quot;>;翻译文学&lt;/ a>; 和&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/books/page-turner/the-2023-national-book-awards-longlist-poetry&quot;>;诗歌&lt;/a>;。明天早上回来看看小说。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大约三十年前，作家克里斯蒂娜·里维拉·加尔萨 (Cristina Rivera Garza) 的妹妹莉莉安娜 (Liliana) 在墨西哥城被前男友杀害，但从未被绳之以法。在《莉莉安娜无敌的夏天：姐姐寻求正义》中，里维拉·加尔萨利用警方报告、笔记本、手写信和采访来重现围绕她姐姐被谋杀的事件。这本书从墨西哥城开始，里维拉·加尔萨前往那里取回未解决的案件档案。 “There is something obscene about the beauty of the city—its boutiques, gazebos, poplars—and something frightening in Rivera Garza&#39;s ability to narrate this beauty in light of her terrible quest,” Merve Emre writes, in an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2022/07/11/cristina-rivera-garzas-bodies-politic&quot;>;essay&lt;/a>; on Rivera Garza&#39;s work. “When she finally finds the file and opens it, voices rise from its pages—the voices of Liliana, her parents, her friends, and the friends of her murderer. They are testimonies not to Liliana&#39;s death but to her life.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“Liliana&#39;s Invincible Summer” is on this year&#39;s Longlist for the National Book Award in Nonfiction. It is one of several works that mine documents from the past in order to forge new meaning. Jonathan Eig&#39;s “King: A Life” draws on newly declassified FBI files to create a groundbreaking biography of Martin Luther King, Jr.; Christina Sharpe&#39;s “Ordinary Notes” collects personal and public artifacts to bear witness to the legacy of white supremacy and create a “Dictionary of Untranslatable Blackness.” “I Saw Death Coming: A History of Terror and Survival in the War Against Reconstruction,” by Kidada E. Williams, uses archival records and oral history to construct a history of the Reconstruction-era South from the perspective of the formerly enslaved.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The titles on the list were selected from six hundred and thirty eight submissions from publishers. Viet Thanh Nguyen, whose memoir, “A Man of Two Faces,” was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-weekend-essay/a-departure-from-reality-viet-thanh-nguyen&quot;>;excerpted&lt;/a>; in &lt;em>;The New Yorker&lt;/em>;, is the only honoree on this list who has been previously recognized by the National Book Awards. The full list is below.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Ned Blackhawk&lt;/strong>;, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fthe-rediscovery-of-america-native-peoples-and-the-unmaking-of-us-history-ned-blackhawk%2F18722854&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fthe-rediscovery-of-america-native-peoples-and-the-unmaking-of-us-history-ned-blackhawk%2F18722854&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fthe-rediscovery-of-america-native-peoples-and-the-unmaking-of-us-history-ned-blackhawk%2F18722854&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;The Rediscovery of America: Native Peoples and the Unmaking of US History&lt;/a>;”&lt;br/>;Yale University Press&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Jonathan Eig&lt;/strong>;, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fking-a-life-a-life-jonathan-eig%2F18775295&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fking-a-life-a-life-jonathan-eig%2F18775295&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fking-a-life-a-life-jonathan-eig%2F18775295&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;King: A Life&lt;/a>;”&lt;br/>;Farrar, Straus &amp;amp; Giroux / Macmillan Publishers&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Viet Thanh Nguyen&lt;/strong>;, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fman-of-two-faces%2F19729620&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fman-of-two-faces%2F19729620&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fman-of-two-faces%2F19729620&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;A Man of Two Faces: A Memoir, A History, A Memorial&lt;/a>;”&lt;br/>;Grove Press / Grove Atlantic&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Donovan X. Ramsey&lt;/strong>;, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fwhen-crack-was-king-a-people-s-history-of-a-misunderstood-era%2F18859945&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fwhen-crack-was-king-a-people-s-history-of-a-misunderstood-era%2F18859945&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fwhen-crack-was-king-a-people-s-history-of-a-misunderstood-era%2F18859945&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;When Crack Was King: A People&#39;s History of a Misunderstood Era&lt;/a>;”&lt;br/>;One World / Penguin Random House&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Cristina Rivera Garza&lt;/strong>;, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fliliana-s-invincible-summer-a-sister-s-search-for-justice-cristina-rivera-garza%2F18485508&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fliliana-s-invincible-summer-a-sister-s-search-for-justice-cristina-rivera-garza%2F18485508&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fliliana-s-invincible-summer-a-sister-s-search-for-justice-cristina-rivera-garza%2F18485508&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Liliana&#39;s Invincible Summer: A Sister&#39;s Search for Justice&lt;/a>;”&lt;br/>;Hogarth / Penguin Random House&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Prudence Peiffer&lt;/strong>;, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fthe-slip-the-new-york-city-street-that-changed-american-art-forever-prudence-peiffer%2F19258109&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fthe-slip-the-new-york-city-street-that-changed-american-art-forever-prudence-peiffer%2F19258109&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fthe-slip-the-new-york-city-street-that-changed-american-art-forever-prudence-peiffer%2F19258109&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;The Slip: The New York City Street That Changed American Art Forever&lt;/a>;”&lt;br/>;Harper / HarperCollins Publishers&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Christina Sharpe&lt;/strong>;, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fordinary-notes-christina-sharpe%2F18411133&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fordinary-notes-christina-sharpe%2F18411133&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fordinary-notes-christina-sharpe%2F18411133&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Ordinary Notes&lt;/a>;”&lt;br/>;Farrar, Straus &amp;amp; Giroux / Macmillan Publishers&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Raja Shehadeh&lt;/strong>;, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fwe-could-have-been-friends-my-father-and-ia-palestinian-memoir-raja-shehadeh%2F18531026&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fwe-could-have-been-friends-my-father-and-ia-palestinian-memoir-raja-shehadeh%2F18531026&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fwe-could-have-been-friends-my-father-and-ia-palestinian-memoir-raja-shehadeh%2F18531026&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;We Could Have Been Friends, My Father and I: A Palestinian Memoir&lt;/a>;”&lt;br/>;Other Press&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;John Vaillant&lt;/strong>;, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Ffire-weather-a-true-story-of-survival-and-community-in-our-new-century-of-fire-john-vaillant%2F18751510&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Ffire-weather-a-true-story-of-survival-and-community-in-our-new-century-of-fire-john-vaillant%2F18751510&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Ffire-weather-a-true-story-of-survival-and-community-in-our-new-century-of-fire-john-vaillant%2F18751510&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Fire Weather: A True Story from a Hotter World&lt;/a>;”&lt;br/>;Knopf / Penguin Random House&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Kidada E. Williams&lt;/strong>;, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fi-saw-death-coming-a-history-of-terror-and-survival-in-the-war-against-reconstruction-kidada-e-williams%2F17306273&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fi-saw-death-coming-a-history-of-terror-and-survival-in-the-war-against-reconstruction-kidada-e-williams%2F17306273&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fi-saw-death-coming-a-history-of-terror-and-survival-in-the-war-against-reconstruction-kidada-e-williams%2F17306273&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;I Saw Death Coming: A History of Terror and Survival in the War Against Reconstruction&lt;/a>;”&lt;br/>;Bloomsbury Publishing&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;The judges for the category this year are the &lt;em>;New Yorker&lt;/em>; contributing writer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/hanif-abdurraqib&quot;>;Hanif Abdurraqib&lt;/a>;, whose book “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fa-little-devil-in-america-notes-in-praise-of-black-performance-hanif-abdurraqib%2F9568081&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fa-little-devil-in-america-notes-in-praise-of-black-performance-hanif-abdurraqib%2F9568081&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fa-little-devil-in-america-notes-in-praise-of-black-performance-hanif-abdurraqib%2F9568081&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;A Little Devil in America: Notes in Praise of Black Performance&lt;/a>;” was a finalist for the National Book Award in 2021, Ada Ferrer, the author of “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fcuba-an-american-history-ada-ferrer%2F17597864&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fcuba-an-american-history-ada-ferrer%2F17597864&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fcuba-an-american-history-ada-ferrer%2F17597864&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Cuba: An American History&lt;/a>;,” James Fugate, a co-founder of Eso Won Books, Sarah Schulman, a novelist and a historian of the &lt;em >;AIDS&lt;/em>; epidemic, and Sonia Shah, the author of “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fthe-next-great-migration-the-beauty-and-terror-of-life-on-the-move-sonia-shah%2F8554511&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fthe-next-great-migration-the-beauty-and-terror-of-life-on-the-move-sonia-shah%2F8554511&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fthe-next-great-migration-the-beauty-and-terror-of-life-on-the-move-sonia-shah%2F8554511&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;The Next Great Migration: The Beauty and Terror of Life on the Move&lt;/a>;.” ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;rcdckh&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;qmqgmc&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 03:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[The 2023 National Book Awards Longlist: Poetry]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/books/page-turner/the-2023-national-book-awards-longlist-poetry]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14T14:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6500d0f7bdc63c42b32021cd/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/poetry%20v3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;&lt;em>;This week, The New Yorker is announcing the longlists for the 2023 National Book Awards. On Wednesday, we presented the lists for&lt;/em>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/books/page-turner/the-2023-national-book-awards-longlist-young-peoples-literature&quot;>;&lt;em>;Young People&#39;s Literature&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>; &lt;em>;and&lt;/em>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/books/page-turner/the-2023-national-book-awards-longlist-translated-literature&quot;>;&lt;em>;Translated Literature&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;em>;. Check back this afternoon for Nonfiction.&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“Study of Two Figures (Dr. Seuss / Chrysanthemum-Pearl),” a sequence of poems by Monica Youn, considers the fraught legacy of the children&#39;s-book author Theodor Geisel, or Dr. Seuss. The sequence, which was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/books/poems/study-of-two-figures-dr-seuss-chrysanthemum-pearl&quot;>;published&lt;/a>; in this magazine in 2021, is one of Youn&#39;s “double portraits,” Kevin Young writes, placing a beloved Geisel creation alongside anti-Japanese political cartoons he created during the Second World War. “Youn finds humanity in the inhumane and a poetry in the make-believe world of a child whom Dr. Seuss could only dream of, but was surely writing for.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Youn&#39;s collection “From From,” in which the sequence appears, is on the longlist for this year&#39;s National Book Award for Poetry. It is one of several contenders to reckon with the violence of imperialist ambitions. Paisley Rekdal&#39;s “West: A Translation” memorializes a Chinese migrant who died by suicide at a detention center in San Francisco. Charif Shanahan&#39;s “Trace Evidence” turns a story about a calamitous bus accident in North Africa into an examination of anti-Blackness and colonialism. Craig Santos Perez&#39;s “from unincorporated territory [åmot]” explores the wounds of the militarization of the western Pacific island of Guåhan, or Guam.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The list was drawn from a total of two hundred and ninety-five submissions from publishers. Youn is the only nominee who has been previously recognized by the National Book Awards; the other nine contenders are being honored for the first time. The full list is below.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;John Lee Clark&lt;/strong>;, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fhow-to-communicate-poems-john-lee-clark%2F18138837&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fhow-to-communicate-poems-john-lee-clark%2F18138837&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fhow-to-communicate-poems-john-lee-clark%2F18138837&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;How to Communicate&lt;/a>;”&lt;br/>;WW Norton &amp;amp; Company&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Oliver de la Paz&lt;/strong>;, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Diaspora-Sonnets-Oliver-Paz/dp/132409298X&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Diaspora-Sonnets-Oliver-Paz/dp/132409298X&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Diaspora-Sonnets-Oliver-Paz/dp/132409298X&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;The Diaspora Sonnets&lt;/a>;”&lt;br/>;Liveright / WW Norton &amp;amp; Company&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Annelyse Gelman&lt;/strong>;, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fvexations%2F18842799&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fvexations%2F18842799&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fvexations%2F18842799&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Vexations&lt;/a>;”&lt;br/>;University of Chicago Press&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;José Olivarez&lt;/strong>;, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fpromises-of-gold-jose-olivarez%2F18415902&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fpromises-of-gold-jose-olivarez%2F18415902&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fpromises-of-gold-jose-olivarez%2F18415902&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Promises of Gold&lt;/a>;”&lt;br/>;Henry Holt &amp;amp; Company / Macmillan Publishers&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Craig Santos Perez&lt;/strong>;, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Ffrom-unincorporated-territory-amot%2F18846316&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Ffrom-unincorporated-territory-amot%2F18846316&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Ffrom-unincorporated-territory-amot%2F18846316&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;from unincorporated territory [åmot]&lt;/a>;”&lt;br/>;Omnidawn Publishing&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Paisley Rekdal&lt;/strong>;, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fwest-a-translation-paisley-rekdal%2F18625819&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fwest-a-translation-paisley-rekdal%2F18625819&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fwest-a-translation-paisley-rekdal%2F18625819&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;West: A Translation&lt;/a>;”&lt;br/>;Copper Canyon Press&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Brandon Som&lt;/strong>;, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Ftripas-brandon-som%2F19517374&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Ftripas-brandon-som%2F19517374&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Ftripas-brandon-som%2F19517374&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Tripas&lt;/a>;”&lt;br/>;Georgia Review Books / University of Georgia Press&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Charif Shanahan&lt;/strong>;, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Ftrace-evidence-charif-shanahan%2F18584310&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Ftrace-evidence-charif-shanahan%2F18584310&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Ftrace-evidence-charif-shanahan%2F18584310&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Trace Evidence&lt;/a>;”&lt;br/>;Tin House&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Evie Shockley&lt;/strong>;, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fsuddenly-we-evie-shockley%2F18605418&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fsuddenly-we-evie-shockley%2F18605418&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fsuddenly-we-evie-shockley%2F18605418&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;suddenly we&lt;/a>;”&lt;br/>;Wesleyan University Press&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Monica Youn&lt;/strong>;, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Ffrom-from-poems-monica-youn%2F18406690&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Ffrom-from-poems-monica-youn%2F18406690&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Ffrom-from-poems-monica-youn%2F18406690&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;From From&lt;/a>;”&lt;br/>;Graywolf Press&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;The judges for the category this year are Rick Barot, whose collection “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fthe-galleons-poems-rick-barot%2F8997649&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fthe-galleons-poems-rick-barot%2F8997649&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fthe-galleons-poems-rick-barot%2F8997649&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;The Galleons&lt;/a>;” was long-listed for the National Book Award in 2020; Heid E. Erdrich, a writer from North Dakota; Jonathan Farmer, the author of “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fthat-peculiar-affirmative-jonathan-farmer%2F7317582&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fthat-peculiar-affirmative-jonathan-farmer%2F7317582&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fthat-peculiar-affirmative-jonathan-farmer%2F7317582&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;That Peculiar Affirmative: On the Social Life of Poems&lt;/a>;”; Raina J. León, a founding editor of &lt;em>;The Acentos Review;&lt;/em>; and Solmaz Sharif, the author of “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fcustoms-poems-solmaz-sharif%2F16807514&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fcustoms-poems-solmaz-sharif%2F16807514&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Fcustoms-poems-solmaz-sharif%2F16807514&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Customs&lt;/a>;” and “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Flook-poems%2F8234229&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Flook-poems%2F8234229&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://go.skimresources.com?id=100106X1555758&amp;amp;xs=1&amp;amp;url=https%3A%2F%2Fbookshop.org%2Fp%2Fbooks%2Flook-poems%2F8234229&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Look&lt;/a>;,” which was a finalist for a National Book Award in 2016. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;fx5qk&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;34nozq&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 23:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Republicans Demand Biden Tell Them Why They Are Impeaching Him]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/humor/borowitz-report/republicans-demand-biden-tell-them-why-they-are-impeaching-him]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-14T14:19:49.854Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650314c3e8cb5056481b280b/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Boro-MacCartney-09-14023-social.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;WASHINGTON (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/humor/borowitz-report&quot;>;The Borowitz Report&lt;/a>;)—In an irate letter to the White House, Kevin McCarthy and other congressional Republicans have demanded that President Biden reveal why they are impeaching him.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The letter claims that, after Republicans announced their impeachment inquiry, “the White House has stubbornly refused to provide us with any reasons for our doing so.”&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;The Republicans go on to demand that Biden reveal the rationale for his ouster “immediately, or face the consequences.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“The American people are waiting, Mr. President, for you to explain to us why we are impeaching you,” the letter concludes. “Your silence will not be forgiven.”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;fkrp5&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;8uqb2&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 23:06:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>