<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>纽约客</title><description>纽约客全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.newyoker.com <item><title><![CDATA[Inside the Israeli Crackdown on Speech]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/news/annals-of-human-rights/inside-the-israeli-crackdown-on-speech]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08T19:28:24.338Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654aa8b5d37fa267bd40e193/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/Gessen_Peace_site_Social.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt; div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2. 95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/s vg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存这个故事&lt;/ span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span>;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d= “M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d =“M23 3” H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023 后一周/11/06/israel-gaza-war-hamas&quot;>;10月7日哈马斯袭击以色列南部&lt;/a>;，以色列·弗雷，36岁的正统派记者，关注巴以冲突，刚回到位于特拉维夫东部以极端正统派为主的布内布拉克小镇郊区的公寓时，他开始听到外面有噪音。那是晚上 10 点以后，距离安息日结束还有几个小时。有人——他不记得是谁——给他发消息说，他的地址在网上流传，并呼吁加入 La Familia，这是一个极右翼组织，最初是耶路撒冷最大的英超足球队的球迷俱乐部，袭击弗雷的家。当弗雷试图检查公寓门外是否有人时，他发现有人挡住了取景器。街上的声音越来越大。他能听到人们大喊“叛徒”。他们似乎在向大楼投掷鞭炮。他将妻子和两个分别为八岁和十三岁的孩子从有大窗户的客厅里冲了出来，并疯狂地给朋友们发短信：“人们正在攻击我的房子。请过来做点什么。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位邻居走近人群，为弗雷的家人协商安全通道。在孩子们离开公寓之前，弗雷用围巾遮住了他们的脸，以免人群看到他们。他呆在里面，听着聚会的声音变得越来越疯狂和吵闹，直到凌晨三点左右警察来到他家门口并告诉他需要离开。一枚鞭炮击中了弗雷楼下邻居的窗户，玻璃碎裂了。当三名警察护送弗雷出去时，其中一名警察抓住弗雷的手臂并向他吐口水。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;弗雷被一辆警车赶出布内布拉克，然后开着自己的车继续前行，这辆车是另一名警察驾驶的。但是，弗雷很快意识到，另外两辆车仍在追随他。他开车前往特拉维夫的一家大型医院伊奇洛夫并躲藏起来。最终，他得以前往一位朋友的公寓，几周后我们通过视频进行交谈时，他仍然住在那里，并由一位熟人担任翻译。据弗雷所知，在针对他的大楼的袭击中尚未逮捕任何人。 “警察保护我的生命只是因为他们阻止人们进入大楼并护送我出去，”他说。 “我不知道什么时候才能回家，如果我能回家的话。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;弗雷身材瘦小，戴着眼镜，留着传统的胡须和侧鬓。极端正统派人士认为，以色列和加沙的最新一轮暴力源于他在给我的信息中所说的以色列“镇压地中海和约旦河之间一半居民的全面计划”。在推特上表达这样的观点似乎让弗雷失去了两次工作。去年，他被警方带走审问。导致上个月袭击的事件似乎是 10 月 7 日后几天在特拉维夫举行的烛光守夜活动。在聚会上，弗雷被要求念卡迪什语，即哀悼者的祈祷词。他为当时在以色列对 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/the- line-after-gaza-and-america&quot;>;加沙&lt;/a>;。弗雷祈祷的视频片段经过编辑，看起来像是只提到了巴勒斯坦儿童，并与他的家庭住址一起发布。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;弗雷是至少三位著名的左翼以色列人之一。过去几周被人肉搜索。领先人权组织 B&#39;Tselem 的执行董事尤莉·诺瓦克 (Yuli Novak) 在社交媒体上公布了她的电话号码后，她觉得自己必须带着妻子和刚出生的婴儿暂时离开以色列。人肉搜索的另一个目标是电影制作人和活动家古尔·利特曼（化名），多年来，他在 Facebook 上发表了许多批评以色列武装部队的帖子，他认为以色列武装部队犯有战争罪。他还表示，与经常重复的以色列是中东唯一民主国家的说法相反，该国从来就不是一个民主国家，主要是因为其国家计划始终将其控制的土地上近一半的人民排除在外。 “我是一个男人——犹太人、白人、德系犹太人，”利特曼告诉我，他列出了使他在以色列社会享有特权的特征。 “在如此黑暗的时期生活在这样的地方而不发声，这几乎是不道德的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10 月 7 日之后，利特曼发布了大量帖子。遇难平民中包括他高中时的一位老朋友和一位朋友的父母。他写道，无论巴勒斯坦的解放斗争多么重要，没有任何理由可以为谋杀辩护。他写道，一些国际左翼人士没有意识到以色列悲剧的严重性。他还写道，一想到加沙正在发生的事情，他的心就碎了。利特曼与加沙的一位朋友保持联系，他告诉我，“每天我醒来都害怕她第二天可能无法生存。” 10 月中旬，朋友们提醒利特曼，他的姓名、照片和家庭住址已被 Telegram 上的极右团体散布。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt; /div>;&lt;p>;利特曼离开家前往朋友家。尽管他的电话一直在响，但他不再接听未知号码的电话。他删除了自己的 Facebook 帐户——他知道任何浏览他个人资料的人都会发现展示巴勒斯坦国旗的帖子或他在纪念大灾难（1948 年以色列将巴勒斯坦人暴力驱逐出新成立的以色列国）时的照片。用他的话说，他已经“沉迷于”Facebook，但戒掉它还有一个可取之处。在他离开网站之前，一位朋友转发了一项行动呼吁，建议以色列应对巴勒斯坦人使用核武器。 “我确信，如果我现在在 Facebook 上，我的心也会破碎，因为我会看到有多少我认识和我爱的人在说可怕的话，”利特曼告诉我。 “我宁愿盲目。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我为这篇报道采访的以色列犹太活动人士无一例外地指出，与他们的政府对巴勒斯坦人施加的惩罚相比，他们的麻烦就显得黯然失色了——当然，在加沙，在巴勒斯坦人也是如此。占领&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/q-and-a/the-gaza-ification-of-the-west-bank&quot;>;西岸&lt;/a>;，但也在以色列境内。虽然犹太活动人士成为右翼暴徒的目标，似乎得到了政府的默许，但巴勒斯坦人却感受到了政府镇压机构的全部力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前对言论的镇压包括逮捕、警察审讯以及安全部门 Shabak 进行的所谓警告谈话主要是由国家安全部长今年早些时候成立的一个特别工作组执行的。 com/magazine/2023/02/27/itamar-ben-gvir-israels-minister-of-chaos&quot;>;Itamar Ben-Gvir&lt;/a>;，以确定社交媒体上煽动恐怖主义的案件。在担任部长之前，本格维尔是一名极右翼活动家。 2007年，耶路撒冷一家法院因他携带写有“驱逐阿拉伯敌人”等标语和海报而被判煽动种族主义罪。巴勒斯坦人经营的法律中心阿达拉的负责人哈桑·贾巴林告诉我，“本格维尔的工作是保护我的安全，他被称为以色列历史上最种族主义的官员。”贾巴林补充道：“我们知道以色列犹太社会正在经历一段非常非常艰难的时期。但这个紧急时刻是在这个国家历史上种族主义最严重的政府之一的领导下发生的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>; &lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;10月7日之后，在以色列代表巴勒斯坦囚犯五十多年的传奇人权律师Lea Tsemel开始看到前所未有的事情：人们因社交媒体帖子甚至点赞而被捕。我们谈话的那天，采梅尔刚刚从一名以色列公民巴勒斯坦律师的案件听证会回来，这名律师在 10 月 7 日之后的几天里发帖称，“我度过了一个美妙的夜晚。” （采梅尔并不代表被告，但与其他几名律师一起出席了听证会，以示声援。）这名年轻女子刚刚通过了律师资格；一群犹太律师提出申诉，声称她的帖子表明了对哈马斯的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;10 月 30 日，拿撒勒的一家法院审理了巴扬·哈提布 (Bayan Khateeb) 的案件，他是一名第四次袭击者。海法以色列理工学院一年级学生，因 10 月 8 日发布的 Instagram 故事而被捕。这篇帖子的特色是一个煎锅，里面有一个沙克舒卡在炉子上煮，鸡蛋几乎凝固了，标题是“我们很快就会吃到胜利的沙克舒卡”，还有一个巴勒斯坦国旗表情符号。一群犹太学生向以色列理工学院投诉，声称卡提卜表达了对哈马斯的支持，结果她被捕并被关押过夜。当警方试图将 Khateeb 的拘留延长六天时，她作证称自己不是一名称职的厨师，并为一小群将要在厨房品尝她的胜利的朋友发布了这张照片。法官裁定有合理理由，并下令将她再关押一天；经过上诉，该措施被减少为五天软禁，并禁止使用社交媒体。 Khateeb 也已被以色列理工学院停职。&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node -id=&quot;ea4mcz&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>; &lt;div >;&lt;p >;目前，以色列平民的大部分生活都处于暂停状态。大学推迟了学年的开始；除逮捕等紧急事项外，法院不审理案件。许多因涉嫌不忠而被拘留的人可能永远不会受到指控，但法院正在通过逮捕来有效地实施惩罚。阿达拉法律中心正在监测一百七十多个案件，其中大多数涉及以色列的巴勒斯坦公民，约占以色列公民的百分之二十。这些人在教育、就业和公共服务方面受到系统性的歧视。尽管如此，他们中的许多人就读于希伯来语大学，并在以犹太人为主的以色列机构工作。在过去的几周里，数百名以色列巴勒斯坦公民被大学停职或解雇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10 月下旬，我与以色列巴勒斯坦公民莱拉（化名）进行了交谈。他在一家以色列大公司担任销售主管。她讲述了一次与一位客户的会面，这位客户试图让她参与讨论 10 月 7 日的袭击事件。莱拉没有说什么表明她为这些袭击辩护，但她显然也没有表达令人满意的谴责。莱拉的雇主举行了听证会，两天后决定继续雇用她，条件是她向客户和出席会议的一名犹太同事道歉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥马尔（不是他的真实身份）姓名）是一名大学生。和许多阿拉伯年轻人一样，他维护着一个主要由宗教诗句组成的 Facebook 帐户。 10 月 7 日袭击事件发生几天后，他发布了一首关于在困难时期保持耐心的诗句。一名陌生人发表评论，指责奥马尔支持哈马斯。奥马尔阻止了这个陌生人。随后，该帖子的截图出现在奥马尔系学生的 WhatsApp 聊天中。有人写道：“我不仅仅是把他锁在这个群体之外，我还要确保他每次靠近大学时都会感觉很糟糕。”奥马尔感到害怕，向警方报案，然后通知大学，并发送了他的帖子截图来说明事件的荒谬性。作为回应，该大学给他发了一封信，通知他已被停职，等待纪律听证会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 Zoom 上举行的听证会包括该大学的律师和校长。奥马尔得知，一群学生，其中包括他视为朋友的人，对他提出了投诉。该大学收集了奥马尔一年多前的一些帖子。其中一张照片是一个男孩坐在自家房屋的废墟上，旁边是一只被以色列火箭弹击中村庄的猫。 “在我们看来，你在支持恐怖主义，”校长说。奥马尔在律师的陪同下试图解释说他没有这样做。但是，奥马尔对我说，“就像如果你是以色列的阿拉伯人，他们认为你&lt;em>;应该&lt;/em>;支持恐怖主义。”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;8pe459&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;“这就像一台正在工作的机器，”奥马尔和莱拉的律师 Sawsan Zaher 说道。扎赫目前代表数十名其他失业或被大学停学的以色列阿拉伯人。她告诉我，特别是在大学方面，镇压力量似乎势不可挡。甚至推迟的请求也被拒绝，因为她被告知，教育部已指示各大学和学院迅速果断地采取行动。她所见过的绝大多数案件并不涉及实际煽动恐怖主义或支持哈马斯。相反，她说，人们因为自己的帖子给他人带来的感受而受到惩罚。 “普通民众声称受到了伤害，他们不希望任何人表达其他感受。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10月17日，以色列警察局长科比·沙卜泰宣布，他不会允许任何人表达其他感情。反对战争的示威活动。 “欢迎任何希望认同加沙的人——我将把他送上现在开往那里的巴士，”他说。第二天，在海法，警察制止了针对加沙战争的抗议活动。约阿夫·海法维 (Yoav Haifawi) 是一名六十多岁的计算机程序员和活动家，他正拿着一个小横幅参加抗议活动，上面用英文写着“这是种族灭绝！”当他和其他大约一百名抗议者到达时，他们看到广场上挤满了警察。只有极少数人敢冒险进入广场。他们都没有举起横幅，但坐在栏杆上的海法维允许他的横幅展开到足以拍照的程度。他立即被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Haifawi 的法定姓名为 Yoav Bar，他在监狱里过夜。第二天，他和另外四名在抗议活动中被捕的人（另一名男子和三名女子）挤在一个小房间里，通过 Skype 参加逮捕听证会。由于房间太拥挤，海法维没有看到太多的过程，但到了当天结束时他被释放了。然而十天后，警察在早上八点三十分出现在他家。他们没收了电脑、手机以及任何显示阿拉伯文字的物品，包括帽子和围巾。他们将海法维带去审问。海法维患有多种慢性病，无法服药。下午四点三十分，他不得不住院。第二天下午，他被锁在病床上，通过看守他的警察手机上的 WhatsApp 视频参加了第二次逮捕听证会。针对海法维的证据包括从他家中查获的材料：巴勒斯坦旗帜和呼吁释放被以色列关押的巴勒斯坦囚犯的海报。法官恰好是以色列的巴勒斯坦公民（海法维有犹太血统，尽管他反对分类），他裁定这些材料不构成可能扰乱公共秩序的行为，因为它们被保存在他的私人住宅中。 &lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;当天晚些时候，本-格维尔 (Ben-Gvir) 发推文称，“在恐怖分子支持者约阿夫·巴尔 (Yoav Bar) 的家里，‘一个中央“支持和同情哈马斯的抗议活动中的积极分子”，被发现了大量煽动材料，例如与安全囚犯和恐怖组织有关的海报、标语、旗帜和媒体。警方逮捕了他，并向法庭声称巴尔涉嫌“可能危害公共和平的行为”。然而，这一切对于伊赫桑·卡南法官来说还不够，他决定在战时释放他。这就是内部敌人的样子。耻辱。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;海法维又在医院呆了一天半。他被释放后，我问他今后是否打算减少冒险。 “我仍然是我，”他说。 “周日，我只是在家无所事事，事实证明这样做是有风险的。” ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>; &lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 04:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How Would a Humanitarian Pause Work in Gaza?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/how-would-a-humanitarian-pause-work-in-gaza]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08T18:24:31.648Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a699dc9f8111c64255807/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/Coll-Humanarian-Corridors-11-07-23.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article- body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height =&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot; M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H 20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/ span>;&lt;span >;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >; &lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存这个故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot; >;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid =&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;作为 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www .newyorker.com/tag/gaza&quot;>;加沙战争已进入第五周，巴勒斯坦平民的死亡人数创下了以色列与哈马斯之间严峻冲突的所有先例。加沙地带的街区、公寓楼被夷为平地，以及救援人员在废墟中搜寻幸存者的日常画面让人想起 2017 年摩苏尔的场景，当时美国领导的摩苏尔针对&lt;em>;ISIS&lt;/em>;进行了猛烈轰炸。 。自从以色列在 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/dispatch/waking-to-an-attack-from-hamas&quot;>;10 月 7 日暴行&lt;/a>;之后对哈马斯进行反击以来，超过四​​次据哈马斯控制的卫生部称，加沙已有数千名儿童死亡。这个数字是加沙所有与战斗有关的儿童死亡人数的三倍多 &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.ochaopt.org/data/casualties&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;元素&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://www.ochaopt.org/data/casualties&quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ochaopt.org/data/casualties&quot; rel=联合国自 2008 年开始统计以来就记录了“nofollow noopener” target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;/a>;。 （联合国尚未核实加沙卫生部公布的伤亡数字，但&lt;em>;联合国儿童基金会&lt;/em>;发言人&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov /05/gazas-children-face-catastrophe-as-death-toll-nears-4000-un-warns&quot;>;告诉&lt;/a>;《卫报》，该部的数据总体上经得起审查.）红十字国际委员会支持的加沙医院的医生“从未见过如此大规模的伤亡”，红十字国际委员会总干事罗伯特·马尔迪尼告诉我。据估计，加沙超过 200 万人中的三分之二已经流离失所。马尔迪尼说：“没有一个地方能幸免于敌对行动。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五，以色列总理本杰明·内塔尼亚胡拒绝了暂时停火的呼吁，直到哈马斯及其盟友归还 200 多名士兵。武装分子在 10 月 7 日的袭击中扣押了 30 名人质，其中许多是平民。以色列驻联合国大使吉拉德·埃尔丹告诉美国有线电视新闻网，战斗中的人道主义中断是不必要的，因为以色列允许“现在运载食品和药品进入加沙的卡车数量达到每天近百辆”。 （10 月 7 日之前，每天约有 500 辆卡车向加沙运送物资。周日，国务卿安东尼·布林肯表示，目前向加沙的供应速度“不错，但严重不足。”）埃尔丹还表示，“我们不应该相信或相信来自加沙的任何数字的表面价值”，因为“一切都在哈马斯恐怖分子的控制之下。”在采访中，大使一度表示，“加沙不存在人道主义危机。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登政府试图通过发展总统和布林肯所说的“人道主义危机”来改变这种惨淡的现状。 “暂停”，一个模糊的、技术官僚的术语，显然是为了避免“停火”而选择的，世界各地的反战和亲巴勒斯坦抗议者都将这个词贴在海报上。 “人道主义停火”也是联合国秘书长安东尼奥·古特雷斯阐述的目标。布林肯上周从耶路撒冷跳到安曼，再到拉马拉，再到巴格达，再到安卡拉，试图推进华盛顿关于暂停的想法。周一，内塔尼亚胡在接受美国广播公司新闻采访时提到了他可能接受的内容：“战术上的小停顿——这里一个小时，那里一个小时。”布林肯在旅行期间&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.state.gov/secretary-antony-j-blinken-remarks-to-the-press-16/&quot;>;对记者讲话&lt;/a>;解释说他的外交挑战的核心是：“以色列提出了关于人道主义暂停如何运作的重要问题。我们必须回答这些问题。”他说，美国和以色列官员的“团队”正在解决这个问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人道主义“走廊”和临时安全区或停火一直是战区（包括最近在乌克兰）提供援助的一个有争议的特征和叙利亚。停止战争以向受困平民提供人道主义援助的这一概念提出了一个问题：“如果停火没有发生，会发生什么？”弗吉尼亚大学专门研究人道主义政策的学者克尔斯滕·盖尔斯多夫（Kirsten Gelsdorf） ， 告诉我。 “这可能是虚假的安全承诺吗？还是说这实际上让更多的人处于危险之中？”她说，临时协议可能脆弱或不稳定，并且可能会造成“这种复杂的环境，你不知道何时、如何以及是否可以提供援助。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就加沙而言，等式哈马斯及其盟友劫持人质的行为使情况变得更加复杂。内塔尼亚胡和布林肯的最新言论似乎明确表明，以色列为允许暂时停火做出的任何让步都必须与人质释放挂钩。 （布林肯在巴格达表示，暂停行动可以提高“人质获救的前景”，这一点“很重要”。）卡塔尔和埃及在之前两次释放总共四名美国和以色列人质的行动中发挥了作用，红十字国际委员会也在其中发挥了作用。周日，卡塔尔外交部发言人 Majed Al Ansari &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wsj.com/livecoverage/israel-hamas-war-gaza-strip-2023-11-04/card/qatar- Calls-for-period-of-calm-in-gaza-to-facilitate-hostage-release-DDbx1oVKwCGwXet2r21E&quot;>;表示&lt;/a>;“任何人质释放都必须与一段平静时期挂钩。”&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;迄今为止发布的情况说明了原因。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?app=desktop&amp;amp;v=qkyq5WCA0lI&quot;>;哈马斯发布的视频&lt;/a>;描绘了 10 月 23 日该武装组织释放了两名以色列人的场景人质——七十九岁的努里特·库珀（Nurit Cooper）和八十五岁的约切维德·利夫什茨（Yocheved Lifshitz）——护送他们前往红十字国际委员会工作组。交火在黑暗中进行，两名戴着黑色滑雪面罩、手持突击步枪的哈马斯武装分子将俘虏交给身穿白色安全背心、手无寸铁的红十字国际委员会代表。该视频展现了手无寸铁的人道主义者在这种情况下所需要的毅力。如果要扩大人质释放规模，释放哈马斯及其盟友所扣押的数十名（如果不是数百名）其他俘虏，或许以换取以色列扣押的巴勒斯坦囚犯，那么几乎肯定需要达成一项完善的停火协议。尽管如此，马尔迪尼告诉我，迄今为止释放的人质表明，释放加沙人质“是可以实现的”。 “技术细节——我并不是说这很容易。有时即使双方同意条款，也需要多次尝试。”但是，他说，“这是可能的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;上周，以色列外交部长埃里·科恩要求红十字国际委员会探视哈马斯及其盟友扣押的人质，并且&lt; a href=&quot;https://www.timesofisrael.com/liveblog_entry/israeli-fm-demands-red-cross-visit-hostages-in-gaza-says-it-has-no-right-to-exist-otherwise/ ”他补充说，如果该慈善机构不这样做，它就“没有权利存在”。当我向马尔迪尼询问科恩的评论时，他回答说：“我们所有的努力都是不可见的。这并不意味着我们的努力没有发生。其次，红十字国际委员会无法在任何地方强制执行冲突各方的决定。我们唯一的工具是对话并说服各方履行国际人道法规定的义务。”&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >; &lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;他继续说道：“我们从不把自己强加为中间人。我们说应该无条件释放平民人质。我们要求探望他们，检查他们的健康状况，确保他们得到药物，确保他们与家人交换信息，这是他们的权利。”他说，所有这些请求“今天仍然有效。我们了解人质及其家人的困境。我们知道其中的痛苦、不耐烦和沮丧。”&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;正如布林肯所说，人道主义暂停的第二个目的周末的任务将是帮助“为加沙需要的人提供更多人道主义援助”。由于数十辆援助卡车已经在以色列同意的情况下进入该领土，因此通过停火实现大规模援助注入似乎是可以实现的。但也存在一些并发症。其中一项争议是关于燃料供应的。 10 月 7 日袭击后，以色列关闭了通往加沙的电线，该地区自己的发电厂也已停止运转。医院和面包店现在依赖发电机，而发电机又需要燃料。 &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://reliefweb.int/report/ocpied-palestinian-territory/hostilities-gaza-strip-and-israel-flash-update-30-enarhe&quot; data-event-click=&quot; {“element”：“ExternalLink”，“outgoingURL”：“https://reliefweb.int/report/occupied-palestinian-territory/hostilities-gaza-strip-and-israel-flash-update-30- enarhe&quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://reliefweb.int/report/ocpied-palestinian-territory/hostilities-gaza-strip-and-israel-flash-update-30-enarhe&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot; _blank&quot;>;据联合国&lt;/a>;称，加沙超过三分之一的医院和一半以上的初级保健诊所“因损坏或缺乏燃料而关闭”。援助组织表示，如果要在未来几天或几周内认真解决加沙的人道主义灾难，燃料供应将至关重要。但自10月7日起，以色列也禁止向加沙运送所有燃料。以色列国防军表示，哈马斯向医院和其他援助接受者施压，要求他们交出燃料，然后该组织用这些燃料发动战争。上周，以色列国防军&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.timesofisrael.com/idf-says-gaza-photos-show-half-million-liters-of-fuel-held-by-hamas/&quot;>;发布了照片&lt;/a>; 据称，其中似乎是哈马斯控制的储存罐，可容纳约 50 万升燃料。&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position :absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;in7igj&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>; &lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;84et2&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;与此同时，在加沙工作的援助组织已经不堪重负。对于联合国援助人员来说，这场战争已经是有记录以来最严重的一场战争。据一份报告称，自 10 月 7 日以来，在为巴勒斯坦难民提供服务的联合国主要机构工作的至少 92 人在加沙死亡，这一数字几乎与 2022 年全球 116 名援助人员死亡人数一样多。 data-offer-url=&quot;https://www. humanarianoutcomes.org/AWSR_2023&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://www. humanarianoutcomes.org/AWSR_2023&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.人道主义outcomes.org/AWSR_2023&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;有关援助人员安全的年度报告&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p >;&lt;p >;The Washington narrative about President Biden&#39;s efforts to achieve a temporary ceasefire in Gaza often focusses on his “leverage”—or his apparent lack of it—over Netanyahu and the Israeli war cabinet. In this telling, Biden&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/10/30/bidens-israel-policy-gets-put-to-the-test&quot;>;embrace of Israel&lt;/a>; after the attacks has not given him as much influence in Jerusalem as he might have hoped. There is obvious truth in that framing, but it is reductive. The President is trying to moderate Israel&#39;s war, but the US is also acting willingly as a lightning rod for criticism about the human costs of Israel&#39;s campaign against Hamas, a role that the US has long played in the alliance. And the recent public back-and-forth about a temporary ceasefire—including Netanyahu&#39;s qualified rejections of the proposal—should be considered in light of the ongoing secret negotiations over the fate of Israeli and international hostages. The public statements of leaders engaged in such high-stakes private bargaining cannot always be taken at face value.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Bringing a successful, negotiated end to any mass hostage-taking is an excruciating high-wire act in the best of circumstances, never mind in a case such as this one, in which Hamas and its allies are apparently holding their captives in tunnels beneath Gaza&#39;s apocalyptic war zone. To free those victims while also delivering food, water, and medical care sustainably and at scale to Palestinian civilians would be a miraculous achievement. Yet these are the imperatives of statecraft and aid work when confronted by a crisis of Gaza&#39;s dimensions. “At the end of the day, everything boils down to carving out space for humanity in the worst of circumstances,” Mardini said. “Our only option is to always try harder.” ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;gsz8p&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 03:06:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Furious Ohio Republicans Report Widespread Incidents of Women Voting]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/humor/borowitz-report/furious-ohio-republicans-report-widespread-incidents-of-women-voting]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08T16:06:24.615Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654bab8bcd3f944494927adb/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Boro-Ohio-11-08-23%20copy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;OHIO (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/humor/borowitz-report&quot;>;The Borowitz Report&lt;/a>;)—Irate Republican officials in Ohio have been crying foul over Tuesday night&#39;s election results, claiming that there were “widespread cases” of women voting across the state.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Harland Dorrinson, a GOP operative in Lake County, said that he had “eyewitness accounts” of “swarms of women” standing in long lines outside of polling places.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;“Many of our poll workers spotted women going into voting booths and literally casting votes,” he said. “These were not isolated incidents.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Dorrinson said the “nightmare scenario” that unfolded on Tuesday has dire implications for both Ohio and the nation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“There is every indication that women meddled in this election,” he said. “What&#39;s to stop them from doing it again in 2024?”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;izgod&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;xc7pgo&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 01:06:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Daily Cartoon: Wednesday, November 8th]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/cartoons/daily-cartoon/wednesday-november-8th-sackler-family]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08T15:22:41.026Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654ba10c93bb47845fbd1ea0/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/A28402.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Buy &lt;em>;New Yorker&lt;/em>; Cartoons »&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;vd8i2&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;zj0lp&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 00:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[The Novelist Who Inspired Elena Ferrante]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/books/under-review/the-novelist-who-inspired-elena-ferrante]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08T14:47:37.427Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65491c9e0f9c64038d931037/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/Virginia%20Gabrielli_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508 V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>; &lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存这个故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span>;&lt;svg width=&quot; 24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg >;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >; &lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;1943 年 9 月，艾尔莎·莫兰特 (Elsa Morante) 和她的丈夫、小说家阿尔贝托·莫拉维亚 (Alberto Moravia) 逃离了位于罗马除了背上的衣服和一些沙丁鱼罐头之外什么也没有。贝尼托·墨索里尼被他自己的大议会废黜，德国军队占领了意大利首都，开始了为期九个月的占领。这两位作家有很多值得担心的事情：他们都是犹太血统，而摩拉维亚是法西斯主义的直言不讳的批评者，他得知自己即将被捕。这对夫妇的旅程最终将他们带到了丰迪城外山坡上建造的一间单间小屋。他们只带了两本书：《圣经》和“&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Brothers-Karamazov-Fyodor-Dostoevsky/dp/0374528373&quot; data-event-click=&quot; {“element”：“ExternalLink”，“outgoingURL”：“https://www.amazon.com/Brothers-Karamazov-Fyodor-Dostoevsky/dp/0374528373”}&quot; href=&quot;https://www .amazon.com/Brothers-Karamazov-Fyodor-Dostoevsky/dp/0374528373&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;卡拉马佐夫兄弟&lt;/a>;，”&lt;a href=&quot;https://www. newyorker.com/magazine/2023/07/31/the-cacophonous-miracle-of-the-brothers-karamazov&quot;>;后者&lt;/a>;他们将其用作卫生纸。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在随着天气开始变冷，莫兰特需要更暖和的衣服，十月份，莫兰特回到罗马的公寓，收拾了一箱补给品。 Her courageous errand had an ulterior motive: when the couple ran, she had left a manuscript of a novel she was writing in the hands of a friend, the filmmaker Carlo Ludovico Bragaglia, and she wanted to insure its safety.她对所发现的东西感到满意，回到了小屋，她和摩拉维亚一直躲在那里，直到第二年春天被一名美国中尉释放。四年后，莫兰特一直在创作的小说以“Menzogna e Sortilegio”或“&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Lies-Sorcery-Elsa-Morante/dp /1681376849&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Lies-Sorcery-Elsa-Morante/dp/1681376849&quot; }&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Lies-Sorcery-Elsa-Morante/dp/1681376849&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;谎言与巫术&lt;/a>;。”&lt;/ p>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;external-link-embed--inline&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;a aria-label=&quot;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;本周我们阅读的最佳书籍&amp;lt ;/强>;” data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/best-books-2023&quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https:// www.newyorker.com/best-books-2023&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;span >;&lt;strong>;本周我们阅读的最佳书籍&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt; p >;&lt;em>;阅读我们每周三更新的著名小说和非小说类新书评论。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;a aria-label=&quot;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;本周我们读过的最佳书籍&amp;lt; /强>;” data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/best-books-2023&quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https:// www.newyorker.com/best-books-2023&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;图片>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/63c800e4e99d89b838ada996/ 1:1/w_200%2Cc_limit/undefined&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/63c800e4e99d89b838ada996/1:1/w_120,c_limit/undefined 120w&quot; 尺寸=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/图片>;&lt; /a>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;现在，《谎言与巫术》首次推出完整英文版，由珍妮·麦克菲 (Jenny McPhee) 进行了令人兴奋的新译本。 （莫兰特认为这是“残害”的英文删节版，于 1951 年出版，名为“House of Liars”。）乍一看，它几乎没有留下其制作历史条件的痕迹。小说出版时，意大利文学文化以新现实主义为中心。这种风格的实践者，包括摩拉维亚，摒弃了法西斯宣传的优雅、诡计和浮夸，用平实的语言来传达战争的破坏和战争留下的支离破碎的社会。 《谎言与巫术》在很多方面都是新现实主义的反面。这部小说是一部关于社会攀登和注定的浪漫的情节剧传奇，其主题和风格都是故意不合时宜的。其美好时代的背景、广泛的人物阵容、频繁的旁白以及夸张的言辞，使其牢牢地继承了十九世纪小说的传统。它关心的不是真相，而是谎言：闪闪发光的表面、隐藏的身份和愚蠢的伪装。​​&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，正如莫兰特一再提醒我们的那样，外表往往具有欺骗性。尽管表面上是十九世纪，但《谎言与巫术》只能写于二十世纪。莫兰特对她在同胞中看到的自私和肤浅的仇恨使这部小说充满活力。书中的人物对等级制度的受虐崇拜、偶像崇拜倾向和对媚俗的敏感，体现了她认为使墨索里尼崛起的特征。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫兰特的小说由年轻女子埃莉莎叙述，她声称自己一直是墨索里尼的成功者。由一个“对小玩意疯狂偏爱”的家庭编写了一个“充满谎言的剧本”。尽管她出生时没有财富或地位，但她的母亲和祖母仍然对自己的社会重要性抱有悲惨的妄想信念，并顽固地执着于旨在排除他们的阶级制度。这种信念以各种方式折磨着他们，破坏了他们的思想以及他们与他人的联系。它也折磨着埃莉莎，她没有继承她祖先的崇高地位，但却继承了他们与真理的不安关系。从很小的时候起，她就更喜欢与自己编造的故事为伴，而不是与其他人的故事为伴。这开始是一种虚幻的闲散习惯，最终转变为一种消耗一切的平行幻想生活，使她与现实隔绝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这本书以一种矛盾的巫术开始，一种魔术行为，也是驱魔。 Elisa has recently been orphaned for a second time by the death of her guardian, Rosaria, a minor courtesan who took her in after her parents&#39; untimely deaths.这次失去亲人的经历引发了埃莉莎关于她亲人的大量回忆，其中充满了她无法亲眼观察到的细节。她将自己新发现的洞察力解释为“像忠实的秘书一样”记录这些故事的必要条件。但对于莫兰特来说，写作是一门融合了背叛和奉献的艺术。 Elisa 的目标不是保存。相反，她希望通过追溯这段家族历史，消灭摧毁她祖先生活的“疯狂的贪婪”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;小说中众多幻象受害者中的第一个是艾丽莎的祖母塞西拉，她是一名引诱的家庭教师。当地一位名叫特奥多罗的贵族想要超越自己的地位。塞西拉被特奥多罗奢华的外表所迷惑，没有注意到他放荡的明显迹象，比如他衣衫褴褛、醉酒的车夫，直到为时已晚。结婚后，他的家人与他断绝了关系，债权人也胆大包天。这对夫妇原本计划住在科尔索的一栋别墅里，但很快就只剩下铁轨旁的一间小公寓。塞西拉被逐出天堂，站在橱窗前，陈列着她再也买不起的物品，“就像夏娃在伊甸园紧闭的大门前一样。”&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;莫兰特对这种唯利是图的愿望的蔑视是显而易见的。塞西拉的处境可能很可怜，但她的性格却并非如此。当特奥多罗失去了等级特权时，她的怨恨如此之大，导致她的情感和身体毁容。莫兰特散文中巴洛克式的极端主义放大了她由此产生的怪物：“她似乎被这种毒药陶醉了，细细的蓝色静脉在她娇嫩的皮肤下肿胀，她的瞳孔放大，仿佛被她自己的仇恨形象所迷惑。”&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;艾丽莎的母亲安娜继承了塞西拉的仇恨和对卓越的渴望。尽管她是“父系血统的完美女性典范”，但她的特权却被系统性地剥夺——像她母亲一样，她觉得这种有辱人格的处境是无法忍受的。这种共同的不满并没有使他们成为盟友；而是让他们成为盟友。塞西拉让女儿成为她压抑愤怒的目标，经常挤压她的手指或将指甲插入安娜的手腕。与此同时，安娜认为她的母亲是她父亲毁灭的原因，而不是受害者。她梦想着有一天，她的贫困得到补救，她将“进入那些乘坐马车在科尔索大道上、住在豪宅里的女士们和先生们的超人领域”。正如埃莉莎从一开始就警告我们的那样，这个故事是“一个怪诞且不确定的案件”，而不是一个救赎案件，安娜注定要下降——但不是在与她的表弟爱德华多发生婚外情之前，驱逐特奥多罗的显赫家族的后裔，激发了她命运多舛的显赫希望。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;莫兰特对意大利阶级制度的描述同样源于她对左派的同情和抵制教条。 《谎言与巫术》中的可怜人物并不是浪漫的英雄，而是几乎都是悲惨、粗俗和贪婪的。富人都是虐待狂，爱德华多尤其如此。他由近乎乱伦的溺爱母亲抚养长大，他内化了一种与生俱来的至高无上的感觉。他的“统治本能常常导致他去爱那些比自己地位低的人”：小狗、家庭教师、像安娜这样的女孩。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt; /div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;安娜将爱德华多的浪漫关注视为她自己崇高地位的证明。但他无意通过婚姻，或者任何其他方式来提高她在公众心目中的地位。相反，他渴望她“在精神上吸收她的卑微，这样他就能看到那个骄傲的人在他面前顺从和颤抖”。在一个令人痛苦的镜头中，他用卷发棒烫伤了她的脸颊，这样其他男人就无法欣赏她完美无瑕的美丽。比这种随意的残忍行为更令人不安的是安娜从他手中的“灼热的疼痛”中获得的近乎色情的快感。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当爱德华多不可避免地厌倦了安娜，将她抛弃到不幸的女人的垃圾堆中时，想象自己是他的情人，她就完蛋了。无奈之下，她同意嫁给弗朗西斯科，一位来自农村的贫困学生，她被她那假装的贵族冷淡所迷惑。他只想“证明自己配得上她，并促进她为之而生的荣耀”。但这对夫妇对安娜的显赫地位的共同信念注定了他们的不幸福。安娜无法原谅弗朗西斯科出身低微，也无法原谅他不是爱德华多。她嫁给的男人和她想要的生活之间的差异最终让她发疯。弗朗西斯科在对安娜的崇拜中，拒绝了一个不关心他不光彩的出身的女人的爱：埃莉莎的最终监护人罗莎莉亚。弗朗西斯科和安娜沉浸在各自的幻想中，很少关注他们唯一的女儿。&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >; &lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;godjk&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;莫兰特所描述的累积的愚蠢行为所产生的影响远远超出了家庭范围。它与任何形式的团结背道而驰。莫兰特通过弗朗西斯科这个人物，对政治理想在自利面前的脆弱性提出了尖刻的评论。在与安娜纠缠之前，他在酒馆里度过了空闲时间，向任何愿意倾听的人传播马克思主义。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于莫兰特来说，弗朗西斯科缺乏决心就是一个症状。 1945 年，墨索里尼被暗杀几天后，她在日记中写道，他的权力取决于这样一个事实：如果要在彼此的责任和个人利益的机会之间做出选择，意大利人每次都会选择后者。直到父亲去世后，母亲患病，埃莉莎才意识到家人自我孤独的真正代价。 “为了让自己与她所处的简陋社区区分开来，我母亲在我们周围竖起了一堵冰冷而充满怨恨的墙，”她想。 “如果大楼里的另一个家庭发生了类似的悲剧，熟人的朝圣活动就会立即开始，我们的房间里就会响起悲伤的哀嚎。”莫兰特的观点很明确：她所描绘的人物渴望得到永远不会接受的机构或个人的接受，从而排斥了那些可能与他们有共同事业的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在莫兰特的作品中，这种孤独感贯穿其中。女性的体重往往最重。通常，孤立感会驱使他们做出一些让读者难以理解的行为。莫兰特对女性，尤其是母亲的描绘，引起了批评者的分歧。一些人认为她小说中的“坏”母亲表现出对其他女性的低评价，另一些人则认为她试图揭示女性气质和理想化的母性作为社会结构。 《谎言与巫术》在这个问题上通常是模棱两可的。小说中的女性大多是母亲，她们都遭受苦难，但她们的不幸并没有使她们更倾向于同情其他女性。相反，他们会愤怒、生闷气；他们陷入否认；他们忽视自己的女儿，迷恋自己的儿子。也许并不奇怪，莫兰特与她自己的母亲艾尔玛的关系很困难。据报道，莫兰特曾经在她母亲的门下塞了一张纸条，称她为&lt;em>;maledetta&lt;/em>;（“被诅咒的人”），但后来又带着第二张纸条回来，称她为&lt;em>;benedetta&lt;/em>; >;（“有福的人”）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;渗透到她生活和工作中的对母亲的矛盾心理并没有阻止一些意大利女权主义者声称莫兰特是“我们所有人的母亲”之一，用一位意大利人的话说米兰妇女书店集体于 1982 年出版的有影响力的书。她最具象征意义的女儿中最著名的无疑是&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2020/08/31/what-brings-elena -ferrantes-worlds-to-life&quot;>;Elena Ferrante&lt;/a>;，其笔名通常被认为是向莫兰特致敬。费兰特曾说过，《谎言与巫术》是“通过这本书，我发现一个完全女性的故事——完全是女性的欲望、想法和感受——可能会引人入胜，同时具有巨大的文学价值。”她似乎从莫兰特那里得到了许可：雄心勃勃地写关于女性的长篇大论，而不需要道歉或担心丑陋。在 &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/The-Neapolitan-Novels-Boxed-Set/dp/1609455053&quot; data-event-click 中不难找到她前任的踪迹=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/The-Neapolitan-Novels-Boxed-Set/dp/1609455053&quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https ://www.amazon.com/The-Neapolitan-Novels-Boxed-Set/dp/1609455053&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;那不勒斯四重奏&lt;/a>;。费兰特对“邻居”中的暴力和贫困的坦率描述让人回想起莫兰特在《谎言与巫术》中对埃莉莎及其家人的肮脏生活、他们破烂的衣服和花哨的小玩意的严格关注。这两部作品都反映了物质匮乏条件下仿制奢侈品的吸引力，以及长期缺乏的社会和情感影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/ div>;&lt;p>;费兰特臭名昭著的隐居也可能要归功于莫兰特，莫兰特反对对她的作品进行传记式阅读，尽管她的作品随意借鉴了生活。在 1972 年的一次采访中，莫兰特坚称“作家的私生活就是八卦，无论谁冒犯了我”；她留下了很少的个人文字，仿佛是为了先发制人地阻止任何窥探。尽管她并不否认小说中有她自己的元素，但她坚持认为“生活中的事实如何发生并不重要，重要的是如何讲述这些事实。在书中，事实总是有意识或无意识的伪装，但这种伪装就是事实。 。 。 。就我而言，我不想被视为一个活着的人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这句话让艾丽莎在《谎言与魔法》中的命运有了不同的看法。逃避小说，将其理解为比现实更诚实——小说将其呈现为一种心理应对策略，会带来严重的个人和政治后果。但是，正如莫兰特所知，奇幻也是文学的基础。埃莉莎的母系遗传——她称之为她的“疯狂”——正是迫使她写作的原因。 “成为欺骗的奉献者和弟子！把你的每一个想法和你所有的知识都固定在谎言上！ 。 。 。这就是我的存在！”她在书的开头几页中哀叹道。发明是她从未真正摆脱的一种强迫。但哪个坚定的小说家愿意这样做呢？ ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>; &lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 23:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Preparing to Fly in “Puffling”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-new-yorker-documentary/preparing-to-fly-in-puffling]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08T11:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654ac1cd06d899e375d104ce/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/PUFFLING_THUMB_3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt; div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2. 95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/s vg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存这个故事&lt;/ span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span>;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d= “M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d =“M23 3” H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid =&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;feature-large-callout&quot; >;&lt;figure >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;script-container&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/图>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;一个女孩是她从雾蒙蒙的车窗往外看，环视着黑暗、安静的道路，这些道路标志着一座已经入睡的小镇。外面，唯一出现的颜色是朦胧的黄色和橙色路灯。她正在夜空中寻找小海雀，或“海雀”，它们从悬崖上掉进小镇。少年环顾四周，寻找白色的飞舞——因为在黑暗中可以看到鸟儿明亮的肚子。在迁徙高峰期，在崎岖的冰岛韦斯特曼纳群岛上，鸟类的数量超过了人类的数量。她是 Vestmannaeyjar 岛上的年轻人之一，在夏天的几周里，她带着仍在适应飞行的海雀宝宝，从陆地飞向它们所属的海洋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;这一传统历史悠久。当韦斯特曼纳亚尔引入电力后，依靠月光导航的海雀变得困惑，并跟随人造光进入内陆而不是出海。 Jessica Bishopp&#39;s meditative short documentary, “Puffling,” which was produced by Alice Hughes and Gannesh Rajah, shows the increasingly vital rescues against a backdrop of local environmental concerns, such as losses in biodiversity.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;external-link-embed--inline&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;a aria-label=&quot;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;The New Yorker Documentary&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-new-yorker-documentary/watch-the-new -yorker-documentary&quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-new-yorker-documentary/watch-the-new-yorker-documentary&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank &quot;>;&lt;span>;&lt;strong>;《纽约客》纪录片&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;查看最新影片或提交您自己的影片。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div >;&lt;a aria-label=&quot;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;纽约客纪录片&lt;/strong>;&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-new-yorker-documentary/watch-the-new -yorker-documentary&quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-new-yorker-documentary/watch-the-new-yorker-documentary&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank &quot;>;&lt;图片>;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/5daf63ccaae3dd0008e7fd38/1:1/w_200%2Cc_limit/undefined&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com /photos/5daf63ccaae3dd0008e7fd38/1:1/w_120,c_limit/undefined 120w&quot;sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;而且雏鸟并不是唯一的那些从救援中受益的人。这部短片让我们沉浸在两个十几岁女孩塞尔玛和比尔塔的生活中，跟随她们寻找海雀的旅程，反思她们与自己称之为家的岛屿的联系。韦斯特曼纳亚尔的年轻人寻找掉在街道、院子和社区中的丢失的海鹦鹉，并将它们运送到水里。毕肖普告诉我，女孩和海鹦鹉之间的关系是“内在的、与生俱来的，这就是我感兴趣的原因”。 “他们如此热衷于拯救鸟类，因为他们担心未来，他们希望保护和保护现有的东西。”&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;这部电影包括几个片段Birta 和 Selma 在夜晚最黑暗的时刻（通常是凌晨 11 点到 3 点）与朋友开车兜风的镜头。车上充满了期待，女孩们和她们的朋友们仔细地审视着外部环境，向外张望，甚至在她们互相交谈的时候也是如此。在许多对青少年的电影描绘中，半夜开车意味着即将发生的恶作剧，但这些场景颠覆了对叛逆的期望，取而代之的是一种责任感：寻找并收集纸箱里的海雀。开车时，青少年很安静；他们的平静常常被有人惊呼“噗噗！”的声音所打破。当汽车急刹车停下来时，一行人冲出去进行调查。 “我不知道如果我们不救他们会发生什么，”塞尔玛一边说着，一边听着挡风玻璃雨刷器的节奏。 “但我认为他们只会死。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在令人费解的搜索中穿插着日常生活中的短暂时刻：我们看到塞尔玛与她的朋友谈论丙烯酸指甲，还给她妹妹编辫子。这些场景说明了青少年的环保行动只是更广泛的日常护理的一部分，揭示了一个环境保护既正常又必要的世界。 “我认为我们讲述少女时代的另类故事很重要，而且它不是由创伤或浪漫主导的，”毕肖普说。女孩们表现出自己是负责任的管家。他们也正处于自己的成年期，他们意识到自己的经历与与父母分离的鸟类的经历之间有相似之处。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;毕肖普花了很长时间与他们相处比尔塔、塞尔玛和他们的家人远离镜头，想要制作一部以个人、亲密的方式讲述气候行动力量的电影。 “我们看过很多从专家主导或激进主义角度出发的电影，但人们不一定能看到它与他们的关系，”毕肖普说。 “[Birta and Selma] are not activists or experts. They&#39;re young people—they have their own dreams and hopes that don&#39;t necessarily relate directly to the environment.它向我们展示了我们之间的相互联系以及我们如何成为野生动物的一部分。”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >; &lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/ div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>; &lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best “ style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 19:06:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[The Incredible Adventure of the Fortitude, by Herbrerm Pinkleton: Part 2]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/humor/daily-shouts/the-incredible-adventure-of-the-fortitude-by-herbrerm-pinkleton-part-2]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08T11:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65441ac7f9309101ece46ab5/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/O&amp;#x27;Brien-Shouts-Part-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article- body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot; 24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12. 5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4 H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;保存&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot; 24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存&lt;/title>;&lt;path d= “M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d =“M23 3” H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;保存&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt; div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;&lt;em>;这是三部分序列化的第二部分。阅读&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/humor/daily-shouts/the-incredible-adventure-of-the-fortitude-by-herbrerm-pinkleton-part-1&quot;>;第 1 部分&lt;/a >;.&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;三． LOST&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;As my crew and I watched the provisions float away on the Thames, I wondered whether my power would diminish as the men&#39;s hunger grew.就像读懂了我的心思一样，Teehy McGann 宣布他找到了一桶面粉，这桶面粉在一阵风中没有被抛到海里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;配给很重要，所以我宣布每个人都可以“一爪子满了，一点也没有”。我坚持要求船员们在指挥官面前用餐。但我们很快发现面粉被污染了，对一个男人来说，他们呕吐的力量如此之大，以至于一些呕吐物溅到了岸上妻子的衣服下摆上。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot; presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;我没有生气，而是对呕吐的人感到同情。我用了一种古老的水手技巧，把一块死猪的脂肪绑在一根绳子上，让每个船员吞下它，然后把它拉回来——以安顿他的胃。但任何善行都会受到惩罚。他们会立即要求喝一口水来冲洗呕吐物和猪油，而我则把所有的淡水桶都扔到了船上。 “我不知道该对你说什么！”我会大喊大叫，然后命令他们在背上抽二十下。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;McGann 问我是否感觉良好关于我们目前的方向。我没有受过很深的导航技术教育，但我通过观察父亲了解了基本知识。我眯着眼睛看着太阳，然后把一根打结的绳子浸入水中，低声自言自语着数字。我告诉麦甘，“我们已经在航线上了，明天这个时候我们将穿越赤道——那个肮脏的妓女！”麦甘似乎很怀疑，但其他一些人欢呼雀跃，那感觉很棒。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自我们推出以来，第一次士气高昂。我们失去了一些好人，但我的计算使我们比计划提前了几周。麦甘指出，你仍然可以在威尔斯街上看到敦刻尔克的服装店，这将使我们距离码头不到一海里。 （确实，大约两百英尺。）&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我一边听着他的观点，一边抚摸着我的小黑胡子。如果麦克甘是对的，那我就是个傻瓜。我又把绳子浸入水中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你不对，我也不对，”我说。 “我们只是迷路了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;McGann 看起来很害怕或沮丧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“队长！”有人哭了。 “来看看这个！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“讨厌的”奥尼尔（后来我给他起了个绰号）指出，许多船员的胳膊和腿上都有深紫色的斑点。事实上，三分之二的人上船时都患有坏血病。尽管生活在陆地上，他们已经几个月没有吃过橙子了——三分之二的人没有吃过！ Not one orange in the past few months.或者甚至在他们的饮料中喷一点酸橙。他们只是不知道这是一件好事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;患者遭受关节疼痛、牙齿脱落和眼睛出血。 Broken bones that had healed years ago snapped again, collectively causing a steady bone-popping sound that was admittedly distracting to me as I looked over the weird maps and tried to identify how close we were to the Tahitian women. (I was starting to wonder whether we should abandon the South Pole of it all and just head straight to Polynesia.)&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;kqrm0m&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;x1wio4&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;We soon found that randomly snapping bones was one of the more desirable manifestations of the brutal affliction. Some unfortunate men had their brains swell and pop inside their skulls. Thankfully, the cerebral mush often settled in such a way that the sailor could still walk around and do basic tasks (and no longer remember their name or who they were related to, which made me jealous!). But some pieces of the shattered brain would become lodged in the nasal canals and have to be discharged. Hence the modern-day expression “He&#39;s so dumb, he could blast his brain out in one sneeze.”&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;The stress of the situation began to wear at the mental stability of the healthy men. Shorty McMolty pranced around the deck, singing, “I&#39;m a prince and it&#39;s my birthday!” Moments later, Pally MacMurter marched around with a mop on his head, saying that he was a Jamaican woman and it was Christmas. The men accused Pally of basically doing what Shorty had done but changing it a little bit. He pointed out that he really had been to Jamaica and it had come from that, but then threw up and died.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;The scurvy-ridden men below deck began to succumb as well. Although the deaths were coming more rapidly, I treated each one equally. Every fallen crewman was wrapped in the Union Jack and lowered into the water with prayers and a full gun salute. Their wives then waded into the Thames and dragged them ashore, sometimes nobly heaving the wet flag back on deck so it could be used on the next fallen hero.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;One can only imagine their horror when they unwrapped their husbands to find that rats, shipworms, and ratworms had eaten much of their beloveds&#39; faces, regardless of how recently they&#39;d passed. The hungry buggers lacked patience and tact. Indeed, it was a very lucky woman who was able to gaze upon her husband&#39;s full dead face as she dragged it ashore.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I started to unravel a bit myself. Apparently, I was heard saying that I “never really wanted this job” and that I was “really scared of big waves.” This was said to be bad for morale. But, worst of all, my sob-screams were heard by my father. He furrowed his brow in disappointment. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;gu083i&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 19:06:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Women Played an Unprecedented Role at the Pope’s Synod. Will It Make Any Difference?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/women-played-an-unprecedented-role-at-the-popes-synod-will-it-make-any-difference]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-08T00:36:12.702Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654950b83dec6c0188b499dc/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Elie-Synod-Rome-Women.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Last month, some four hundred and fifty Catholic leaders from around the world—cardinals, archbishops, bishops, priests and nuns, professors and students, laymen and women—came together in Rome for four weeks of structured conversations. It was one phase of an effort that began with national surveys of Catholics, in 2021, and will conclude in Rome next fall. The whole thing is known as the Synod on Synodality, after a Greek term for coming together.. Pope Francis, who called for the synod, opened and closed the proceedings with Masses at St. Peter&#39;s&#39;s Basilica and, on many days, joined the conversations, which were held in the Vatican audience hall.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The daily sessions were off limits to the media, but during the last week of talks I spoke with participants at nearby coffee bars and pilgrim houses. By that point, although the conversations had been going on for three weeks, it seemed that no one was yet sure what, exactly, the Synod on Synodality was meant to be. Was it a formal synod of bishops, as defined in the early nineteen-sixties, at the Second Vatican Council, or an informal assembly? Was it about the state of the Church, or about Church governance, or about a renewal in the everyday lives of Catholics—which, in the United States, involve issues such as marriage, sexuality, gender and economic inequality, and the climate emergency? And could it have any real effect, given that a synod is convened not to set policy but to make recommendations to the Pope? None of that was clear. One participant noted that it was hard to know whether the synod was being over-managed, or not managed enough.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;What was clear going in was that this synod could have been a capstone to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/how-a-decade-of-pope-francis-has-changed-the-church&quot;>;Francis&#39;s first decade&lt;/a>; as Pope. More than his recent predecessors, Francis has used interviews and one-to-one meetings to communicate his prerogatives. Shortly after his election, in March, 2013, he struck a note of progressive reform, asking, in reference to Vatican II, “Have we done everything the Holy Spirit was asking us to do during the Council?” He answered no and warned, “We don&#39;t want to change, and, what&#39;s more, there are those who wish to turn the clock back.” A few months later, speaking with the Jesuit Antonio Spadaro, the Pope spelled out his sense of what synodality is. Formally, it is a third leg of the Church&#39;s authority structure, along with primacy (papal authority) and collegiality (the obligation of the Pope, as bishop of Rome, to work with other bishops). Informally, it is a way of going about things. “It seems to me that the current method is not dynamic,” Francis said. “We must walk united with our differences—there is no other way to become &#39;one.&#39; ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Other synods during his tenure—on the family, in 2014 and 2015, and on the Pan-Amazon region, in 2019—foundered because of resistance from traditionalists. The cardinals who organized this one—Mario Grech, of Malta, and Jean-Claude Hollerich, of Luxembourg—saw to it that the more than two hundred voting delegates nominated regionally were joined by about a hundred and twenty others chosen by Francis, a move that some saw as a papal effort to outmaneuver his traditionalist adversaries. Notably, nearly a fifth of the voting delegates were women, a proportion without precedent. In an interview with the Argentinean news agency Télam (given in late September, and published during the synod), Francis highlighted his hopes for the proceedings, saying, “John XXIII had a very clear perception: the Church has to change. Paul VI agreed, just like the succeeding Popes. It&#39;s not just about changing ways, it&#39;s about a change of growth, in favor of the dignity of people.” So there was widespread expectation that this synod might address issues which have been simmering for the past decade, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/pope-francis-speaks-out-on-homosexuality-and-further-angers-traditionalists&quot;>;the rights of LGBTQ people&lt;/a>; and the role of women in the Church, and that the tensions between traditionalists and progressives &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/the-popes-coming-vatican-showdown-with-american-conservatives&quot;>;might finally rise&lt;/a>; to open confrontation.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;They didn&#39;t. The gathering proved to be a meta affair, more about process than substance. For several hours most mornings, the participants sat in groups of about a dozen at round tables and discussed topics derived from preparatory sessions, organized by themes such as including Communion, participation, and mission. The sessions followed a process meant to foster discernment, through listening and “Conversation in the Spirit,” which usually included brief remarks by the participants; responses; and several rounds of silent prayer. The groups produced a series of statements, which were consolidated into a summary report that was then presented to the assembly for amendments (more than twelve hundred in all) and approval. The process was circular: through listening, the participants strove to make Catholicism a “listening” Church rather than a commanding and demanding one; through the synod, they would learn how to proceed more synodally.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;What did they talk about? Only the participants know. At the start, Francis enjoined them to undertake a “fasting from speaking in public”—that is, to maintain confidentiality. Nevertheless, some particulars trickled out. One participant spoke about a young LGBTQ person who was made to feel unwelcome by Church officials and died by suicide. Cardinal Gerhard Müller, a German traditionalist who has tilted against Francis again and again, broke the fast by giving an interview in which he claimed that the synod had been rigged. “All is being turned around so that now we must be open to homosexuality and the ordination of women,” he said. A traditionalist cleric walked out of a session, lest he be photographed sitting next to James Martin, an American Jesuit who advocates for LGBTQ Catholics. During week two, a briefing indicated that the synod had affirmed opposition to homophobia, but a participant told me that the sessions on the topic had been “brutal.” (After the synod, Archbishop Andrew Nkea Fuanya, of Cameroon, said, “In Africa, we understand marriage as a union between a man and a woman, and anything short of that is witchcraft,” adding, “This is something we said very strongly.”)&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;One justification offered for the “What happens in the Vatican stays in the Vatican” approach was that details shared by individual participants would undermine the clarity of the synod&#39;s summary report. “It&#39;s going to be flat, which is a shame, because the conversations were not,” one of the report&#39;s drafters, Bishop Shane Mainlay, of Sandhurst, Australia, told me near the end of the synod, adding that he wished that he and colleagues could devote another week to it. The report, which was released on the final day, is opaque and unspecific, but it&#39;s not apparent that more time would have helped. The real flaw is that it generally records only matters on which there was majority agreement, omitting any true notes of conflict. Although the report rightly touts the presence of women at the synod—calling for the Church to “adopt a more decisive commitment to understand and accompany women from a pastoral and sacramental point of view”—there isn&#39;t a word about the prospect of ordaining women to the priesthood (only a question about how the Church can “include more women in existing roles and ministries”), and the question of ordaining women as deacons (a role involving both a presence at the altar and leadership in the community) is answered with a gesture toward “deeper study.” The word “divorce” never appears (just “complicated marital situations”), nor do the terms “homosexual,” “gay,” or “LGBTQ” (just matters of “identity and sexuality”), with the explanation that “sometimes the anthropological categories we have developed are not able to grasp the complexity of the elements emerging from experience or knowledge in the sciences and require greater precision and further study.”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;po60y&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;xo1con&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Female participants I spoke with felt that the report&#39;s avoidance of hot-button issues made sense, because it foregrounded the process of fostering a “synodal” Church in which people can “walk together” despite their differences. That&#39;s an appealing idea, but it also calls to mind the Vatican&#39;s long-established practices of silence or circumlocution on vexed topics, a stress on outward unity over internal criticism, and a perspective distant from life as it is actually lived. It also leaves out that, no matter how many women take part in proceedings like the synod, the exercise of Church authority is largely reserved for the ordained—that is, for men.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;The combination of a conflict-averse summary report and a restriction on further comment makes it unlikely that the synodal process will renew the Church prior to next year&#39;s session, much less help ordinary Catholics face conflicts in their lives. Perhaps this should be no surprise, though, because the question of what a synod ought to do has been unclear for sixty years.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Shortly after Pope John XXIII was elected, in 1958, he decided to call for a grand ecumenical council, hoping to renew Catholicism through an encounter with modernity. First, in 1960, he convened a one-week Synod of Bishops, in Rome, where he began to set out the upcoming Second Vatican Council&#39;s agenda. Vatican II, held in four autumnal sessions beginning in October, 1962, defied all expectations, changing the Church&#39;s liturgy (from Latin to local languages, and from a rite performed by the priest on behalf of the people to one “celebrated” by the priest with them), its stance toward other faiths (Jews, long calumniated as descendants of those who had killed Jesus, were recognized as bearers of the “spiritual patrimony” shared by Christianity, and looked to as partners in “fraternal dialogues”), and its approach to democracy and nuclear war. And it gave new emphasis to the understanding of the Pope as the bishop of Rome—not so much an absolute ruler as a kind of first among equals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Vatican II dealt at length with synods and synodality. Paul VI, elected Pope after John&#39;s death, in 1963, envisioned the synod as a crucial element of the post-Vatican II Church, both in Rome and regionally. The approach soon thrived in Latin America, where bishops in Medellín, Colombia, in 1968, sought to apply Vatican II&#39;s reforms in the region: controversially, they affirmed support for the liberation of the region&#39;s poor, recognized lay-organized “base communities” (which critics called Marxist cells), and deemed the élites&#39; grip on wealth and power as “institutionalized violence.” But such initiatives were largely suppressed after John Paul II took office, in 1978. In the Polish Pope&#39;s world view, anti-Communism and traditionalism were inextricably combined; for him, renewal had spread out of control, and the regional synods were part of the problem. To reduce their role, paradoxically, he called for a synod on the topic of Vatican II which would reassert traditionalist Catholicism, rooted in papal authority.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;That synod, held in Rome in 1985, had profound consequences over the next thirty years. National churches were made subservient to Rome, and theologians subject to supervision by bishops and Vatican officials. Contested issues—contraception, in-vitro fertilization, the ordination of women and married men, homosexuality—were considered closed to further discussion. The bishops and archbishops appointed by John Paul and his successor, Benedict XVI, took on the role of traditionalist culture warriors. Prominent Catholics who held stances different from theirs were derided as heretics or seen as captive to a “dictatorship of relativism.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Francis has spent his pontificate trying to dig the Church out from the effects of the 1985 synod. (“He is hitting the reset button on synodality,” Myriam Wijlens, a Dutch theologian and canon lawyer, told me.) So the fact that a synod which he himself called, shaped, and joined evidently didn&#39;t begin to bring about any recognizable changes (through the “development of doctrine,” as it&#39;s referred to) is discouraging to many Catholics. Sure, involving lots of women in a Vatican synod is a giant step forward. But the new approach presumes that women broadly will be willing to join the Church or stick with it while waiting for a far-off day when their descendants will be allowed to assume full leadership roles. And the refusal of a “listening” Church even to acknowledge hard questions and the discord they involve suggests that Francis&#39;s openness to change may have turned out to be no match for the conflict-suppressing forces of the Vatican. At this point, is the Church that Francis leads being over-managed by his subordinates, or under-managed by the Pope himself? That seems to be a question that requires further study. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;mdfire&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 09:06:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[These Photos Are “Pure Fiction”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/photo-booth/these-photos-are-pure-fiction]]><description>&lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07T20:40:22.986Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a5a1cd92c5eda2e5bf/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-02-TC.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Talia Chetrit wants you to know that her partner, Denis, doesn&#39;t normally bottle-feed their son while wearing a Gucci bondage harness. Nevertheless, she understands the confusion. Chetrit is a photographer who has often made herself and her family the subjects of her work, which would seemingly situate her in a lineage of diaristic artists such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/photo-booth/the-color-of-humanity-in-sally-manns-south&quot;>;Sally Mann&lt;/a>; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/photo-booth/a-photographers-intimate-self-portrait-of-womanhood-in-middle-age&quot;>;Elinor Carucci&lt;/a>;. But she told me recently, when I visited her studio, in upstate New York, that she considers all of her work “pure fiction.”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GroupCalloutWrapper&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A tank top hanging.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a76bf5247c1c0a571606f/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-03-TC-updated.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a76bf5247c1c0a571606f/master/w_120,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-03-TC-updated.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a76bf5247c1c0a571606f/master/w_240,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-03-TC-updated.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a76bf5247c1c0a571606f/master/w_320,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-03-TC-updated.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a76bf5247c1c0a571606f/master/w_640,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-03-TC-updated.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a76bf5247c1c0a571606f/master/w_960,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-03-TC-updated.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a76bf5247c1c0a571606f/master/w_1280,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-03-TC-updated.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a76bf5247c1c0a571606f/master/w_1600,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-03-TC-updated.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Boob Top,” 2023.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A man biting a chain link fence.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a393bb47845fbd1c74/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-06-TC.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a393bb47845fbd1c74/master/w_120,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-06-TC.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a393bb47845fbd1c74/master/w_240,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-06-TC.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a393bb47845fbd1c74/master/w_320,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-06-TC.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a393bb47845fbd1c74/master/w_640,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-06-TC.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a393bb47845fbd1c74/master/w_960,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-06-TC.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a393bb47845fbd1c74/master/w_1280,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-06-TC.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a393bb47845fbd1c74/master/w_1600,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-06-TC.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Breaker (Chain),” 1997/2023.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Chetrit, whose first solo museum show in the United States is now on view at the Wadsworth Atheneum, in Hartford, Connecticut, has had what appears at first glance to be a peripatetic career in photography. In addition to her self-portraits and pictures of her family, she has done moody, telephoto street photographs, optically tricky still-lifes, and slick fashion shoots. She has even dived into heady conceptual waters, exhibiting photos that she made in high school, which take on poignant layers of meaning in retrospect. Ultimately, however, her disparate work is part of a unified quest to pick apart and play with photographic conventions and, by extension, to poke holes in our expectations of what an image can reveal or hide.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A man and a woman seated.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67565247c1c0a5715fff/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-10-TC.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67565247c1c0a5715fff/master/w_120,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-10-TC.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67565247c1c0a5715fff/master/w_240,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-10-TC.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67565247c1c0a5715fff/master/w_320,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-10-TC.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67565247c1c0a5715fff/master/w_640,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-10-TC.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67565247c1c0a5715fff/master/w_960,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-10-TC.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67565247c1c0a5715fff/master/w_1280,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-10-TC.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67565247c1c0a5715fff/master/w_1600,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-10-TC.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Mom and Dad,” 2023.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;Born and raised in Washington, DC, Chetrit recalls that she was “out of the womb calling myself an artist.” She started making pictures as a teen-ager, setting up a darkroom in her parents&#39; laundry room and taking over a custodial closet at her high school. But she claims, in characteristically elusive fashion, that she was “never interested in other people&#39;s photography.” It was only later, while studying at the School of the Art Institute of Chicago, that she came to the conclusion that her ideas were better suited to the medium. The pictures that she made in high school, and later repurposed, were by no means virtuosic. They were, for the most part, exactly what you would expect. There is a pouty self-portrait in a short tennis skirt that radiates both childish petulance and budding sexual awareness. In her photographs of friends, some subjects practically vibrate with adolescent awkwardness, and others melodramatically perform their angst. A nude portrait of two female friends strikes a tenuous balance between discomfort and half-understood sensuality. Seen now, the power and the charm of this early work spring directly from its guilelessness. Other photographers have attempted to capture the essence of girlhood directly—Mann, for instance, in her stunning, controversial series “Immediate Family,” or Justine Kurland in her more allegorical, cinematic “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/photo-booth/justine-kurland-captures-the-lawless-energy-of-teen-age-girls&quot;>;Girl Pictures&lt;/a>;.” But Chetrit&#39;s novel act of self-appropriation delivers truths by way of her younger self&#39;s ham-fisted attempt to conceal them.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A woman appearing topless wearing makeup looking directly into the camera.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a51cefd4de85494324/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-01-TC.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a51cefd4de85494324/master/w_120,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-01-TC.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a51cefd4de85494324/master/w_240,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-01-TC.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a51cefd4de85494324/master/w_320,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-01-TC.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a51cefd4de85494324/master/w_640,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-01-TC.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a51cefd4de85494324/master/w_960,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-01-TC.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a51cefd4de85494324/master/w_1280,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-01-TC.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a51cefd4de85494324/master/w_1600,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-01-TC.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Self-Portrait (Corey Tippin Makeup #1),” 2017.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;Another group of images from those days presaged Chetrit&#39;s interest in photographic fiction. In them, her friends play dead, the victims of made-up murders that look simultaneously grisly and unconvincing. (In one, a victim is pictured slumped against a door, her bloodied hand resting on a piece of paper so as not to dirty the floor.) The pictures make me think of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2018/05/28/weegee-the-famous-the-voyeur-and-exhibitionist&quot;>;Weegee&lt;/a>;&#39;s sensationalized crime-scene photos, and of our culture&#39;s ghoulish obsession with true crime. I think of the horrors of school shootings, and the pictures of their aftermath that never reach the public eye. I think of the images of children killed in warfare, pushed onto our social-media feeds. For a teen-age Chetrit, however, the constructed scenes were mostly a way to make pictures that weren&#39;t boring. She told me, “ I had this breakthrough moment in high school where I was, like, &#39;Oh, I don&#39;t need to wait until my life becomes interesting.&#39; ”&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A mother holding her new born baby.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a5a7ba8515418d27f3/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-15-TC.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a5a7ba8515418d27f3/master/w_120,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-15-TC.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a5a7ba8515418d27f3/master/w_240,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-15-TC.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a5a7ba8515418d27f3/master/w_320,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-15-TC.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a5a7ba8515418d27f3/master/w_640,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-15-TC.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a5a7ba8515418d27f3/master/w_960,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-15-TC.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a5a7ba8515418d27f3/master/w_1280,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-15-TC.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a5a7ba8515418d27f3/master/w_1600,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-15-TC.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Hard to Title,” 2019.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;Chetrit has never let go of the idea that photography can be used to create an illusory world outside of our humdrum day-to-day. In her mature pictures, she almost seems to be daring you to believe that she is telling the truth. Some of them, like an image on view at the Wadsworth of Chetrit holding her son to her chest immediately after giving birth, have the unmistakable flavor of intimacy. They are what you might expect from a photographer who is intent on bringing the viewer close and getting “real.” But others, like her series of deadpan “bottomless” self-portraits, for which she poses for the camera nude from the waist down, or a pair of lighthearted pictures of her and Denis having sex in a bucolic field that are intruded upon by the sinuous black line of the camera&#39;s cable release, feel more like a burlesque of intimacy. Chetrit seems to be mocking our desire for self-exposure without actually divulging much. She told me that she started making her sex pictures soon after she and Denis began dating, as a kind of “test” to see if he would be “willing to be there in my work.” She went on, “That wasn&#39;t our sex life. That was our sex life with a camera, and what the camera did to our sex life and our relationship at the time.”&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A child and a nude man.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a6177905dd1db97b5a098/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-08-TC.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a6177905dd1db97b5a098/master/w_120,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-08-TC.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a6177905dd1db97b5a098/master/w_240,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-08-TC.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a6177905dd1db97b5a098/master/w_320,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-08-TC.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a6177905dd1db97b5a098/master/w_640,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-08-TC.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a6177905dd1db97b5a098/master/w_960,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-08-TC.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a6177905dd1db97b5a098/master/w_1280,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-08-TC.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a6177905dd1db97b5a098/master/w_1600,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-08-TC.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Buckle (Pam Hogg),” 2023.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;Chetrit&#39;s editorial work has allowed her to play around with designer clothing, like that Gucci harness, which she gets on loan from various stylist friends and collaborators. She takes obvious pleasure in dressing Denis in an array of high-end womenswear and edgy, bondage-inspired kit, and in the provocative strangeness of, say, juxtaposing the legs of her infant son with a pair of glossy, thigh-high stiletto boots. For a series of photographs, she invited the makeup artist and Andy Warhol associate Corey Tippin to do her up in his signature clownish style. In an image, Chetrit appears with a stocking stretched over her garish face, like some perverse mashup of a china doll and a bank robber. You get the sense that she views making a photograph the same way a child views playing dress-up: as a chance to stretch the boundaries of the possible.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GroupCalloutWrapper&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Jean shorts on the ground.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67565247c1c0a5715ffe/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-13-TC.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67565247c1c0a5715ffe/master/w_120,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-13-TC.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67565247c1c0a5715ffe/master/w_240,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-13-TC.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67565247c1c0a5715ffe/master/w_320,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-13-TC.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67565247c1c0a5715ffe/master/w_640,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-13-TC.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67565247c1c0a5715ffe/master/w_960,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-13-TC.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67565247c1c0a5715ffe/master/w_1280,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-13-TC.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67565247c1c0a5715ffe/master/w_1600,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-13-TC.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Jean Shoe,” 2021.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Black garbage bags.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a4b1954b6ed6771e66582/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-04-TC.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a4b1954b6ed6771e66582/master/w_120,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-04-TC.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a4b1954b6ed6771e66582/master/w_240,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-04-TC.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a4b1954b6ed6771e66582/master/w_320,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-04-TC.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a4b1954b6ed6771e66582/master/w_640,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-04-TC.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a4b1954b6ed6771e66582/master/w_960,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-04-TC.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a4b1954b6ed6771e66582/master/w_1280,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-04-TC.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a4b1954b6ed6771e66582/master/w_1600,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-04-TC.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Shoe / Trash,” 2022.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Even if Chetrit considers her work “pure fiction,” her images sometimes betray the eye of a documentarian. A picture of her son, adorably flailing on Denis&#39;s chest, with a foot pressed against his father&#39;s stubbled chin, is a stirring, unfakeable portrait of family life. In her pictures of Denis, no matter how ludicrous or stagy, it is impossible to conceal that he is her willing, often joyful, accomplice. (She told me that his reaction to her more outlandish requests is always: “What? No! OK”) Similarly, her pictures of her parents exude their supportive gameness, and touchingly expose their affection for each other. Her self-portraits, which stray intentionally into self-objectification, have a sneaking air of defiance, like one she took while pregnant, naked and straddling a mirror with her camera pressed to an eye. Chetrit&#39;s photography asks us to reflect on the imaginary worlds that images create. But sometimes, even through the fun-house lens, small truths, like love or self-love, can be glimpsed.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A naked pregnant woman squatting.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a3eba4644f6b508f9d/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-12-TC.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a3eba4644f6b508f9d/master/w_120,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-12-TC.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a3eba4644f6b508f9d/master/w_240,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-12-TC.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a3eba4644f6b508f9d/master/w_320,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-12-TC.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a3eba4644f6b508f9d/master/w_640,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-12-TC.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a3eba4644f6b508f9d/master/w_960,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-12-TC.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a3eba4644f6b508f9d/master/w_1280,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-12-TC.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a67a3eba4644f6b508f9d/master/w_1600,c_limit/Wiley-Talia-Chetrit-12-TC.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Self-Portrait (Downward),” 2019.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 05:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Where Does Antisemitism Come From?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/news/q-and-a/where-does-antisemitism-come-from]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07T19:27:32.733Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a47eca1cd92c5eda2e5bd/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Chotiner-David-Feldman-11-07-23.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Since the Hamas attack on Israel on October 7th, and Israel&#39;s subsequent bombing and invasion of Gaza, antisemitic incidents have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/how-surge-antisemitism-is-affecting-countries-around-world-2023-10-31/&quot;>;rising&lt;/a>; across the world. Governments and civil-society groups in the United States, Europe, Latin America, and Africa have reported a significant increase in attacks against Jewish people and their property. To try to understand these hate crimes, and the historical forces behind antisemitism, I recently spoke by phone with David Feldman, the director of the Birkbeck Institute for the Study of Antisemitism, at Birkbeck College, University of London. During our conversation, which has been edited for length and clarity, we discussed how different ideological strains of antisemitism coexist and overlap, what makes the latest wave of incidents so disturbing, and whether there are dangers in focussing too much on the Middle East when talking about hatred in America.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;We&#39;ve seen upsurges in antisemitism before. Does this feel similar or different to you?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;From the UK, at least, it feels different, and it feels different in two ways. One is that I think the rise in antisemitic incidents recorded by the police over the last three weeks or so, since the 7th of October, has been more dramatic than anything we&#39;ve experienced in the past. And also, as you&#39;ll know, in recent years we&#39;ve had—and not just in the UK but in other countries in Europe as well—debates and arguments about how to talk about Israel, the lines between antisemitism and anti-Zionism, and what definitions are helpful. This has been happening since the war in Gaza in 2006. But this war is on a much greater scale, and of course was preceded by a massacre in Israel. Whereas previous instances were chiefly about how we should talk about events going on in Israel-Palestine, the current moment is about responses to dreadful slaughter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;What are the different definitions of antisemitism that you alluded to, and how have they featured in these prior debates?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The International Holocaust Remembrance Alliance adopted its definition of antisemitism in 2016. It was an attempt to distinguish antisemitism from legitimate criticism of Israel—although it spoke about other things, that is what was at its core. I would argue that in its design it narrowed the possibilities for speech. It&#39;s a rather unclear and complicated document. It says that context is important, but it has often been invoked by people in debate to accuse others of antisemitism without reference to context. But it was widely adopted. [&lt;em>;The IHRA definition states that “antisemitism is a certain perception of Jews, which may be expressed as hatred toward Jews.” Seven of the eleven examples given make reference to Israel.&lt;/em>;]&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Then, in 2019, a group of people, myself included, began working on what became the Jerusalem Declaration on Antisemitism, which was a response in many ways to the IHRA definition. The Jerusalem Declaration sought to be clear that anything which denied Jews&#39; individual or collective rights was antisemitic, and identified narratives and stereotypes which are antisemitic, and which are sometimes invoked in the context of discourse in Israel-Palestine. However, it tried to be much more clear about distinguishing what was antisemitic and what were legitimate criticisms of Israel and claims made in the cause of justice for Palestinians.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;The background to our conversation is what happened on October 7th, and Israel&#39;s response to it. On a basic level of cause and effect, some of these incidents would not have happened without the bombing of Gaza. That being said, I do not want to excuse people committing hate crimes by tracing it back to a cause. After 9/11, there were a lot of people in America who committed hate crimes against Muslims, but I don&#39;t want to blame Osama bin Laden for, say, someone in Wisconsin burning down a mosque.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;No one makes anyone act in an antisemitic way. There&#39;s a difference between comprehending the circumstances in which people act and which lead them to act in particular ways and excusing hate crimes, and I would simply draw the line there. I do think that one of the problems in the current debate, whether it&#39;s over hate crimes outside of Israel or in responses to what happened on the 7th of October, is that some people who seek to explain are then accused of condoning. And, of course, that is what happened to the Secretary-General of the United Nations, in which he both condemned Hamas&#39;s actions but said that those actions did not emerge from a vacuum. So there&#39;s a difference between trying to talk about cause and effect and excusing an action.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Hamas arose in a political context of a long-term conflict between Israelis and Palestinians. There&#39;s definitely a context for Hamas, even if we&#39;re horrified by the way they behave. I don&#39;t know what the context is for someone yelling slurs at British Jews in London.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;I think that the issue we reach here is the way in which events in Israel and Palestine reverberate and divide people beyond Israel and Palestine. So obviously, as you will know, Jews in the UK and elsewhere don&#39;t speak with one voice on this, but mainstream Jewish institutions have lined up quite solidly behind Israel&#39;s actions and policies since the 7th of October. So there is a way in which mainstream Jews in the diaspora identify with Israel and are then identified by others with Israel, which I think is simply providing a context in which Jewish buildings are attacked.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Something awful just happened, which is that the word “Gaza” was daubed in red paint outside the Wiener Holocaust Library, which is a library and archive dedicated to the study of the Holocaust. There&#39;s no way in which that is a legitimate action, but clearly whoever was performing that action identified the building as one associated with Jews, and he associated Jews with the support for the State of Israel. This is me speaking, if you like, as an academic. And in that context, it seems to me that either we give up or we try to understand why people are acting the way they&#39;re acting. Otherwise, the humanities are not really serving a useful purpose.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;a3ka6h&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;32n5cj&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;I&#39;m just not sure the type of people who commit hate crimes really care that mainstream Jewish organizations do or do not line up with Israel. I feel like hate crimes may be happening separately from that context, that those may be two trains running on parallel tracks, but they&#39;re not actually connected.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yeah.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Especially with something like antisemitism or any sort of bigotry, I do wonder if looking at proximate causes misses something.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Yeah. In a sense, the answer to your question is that we don&#39;t know. But, in some ways, I suggest the reverse of what you said is likely to be the case. In normal times, there are a good deal of hate crimes which take place, and which are akin to hooliganism. Someone sees a person looking visibly Jewish in the street and they pick on them. This is a known phenomenon. But if one looks at the example that I just gave of someone daubing “Gaza” on the wall of a library and archive dedicated to the Holocaust, if one looks at people throwing Molotov cocktails at a synagogue, for example, then I think one does need to look at the immediate context.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;It&#39;s telling when people choose to focus on root causes and when they don&#39;t, and it often shows where their sympathies lie.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Sure, I can understand that. And it&#39;s certainly very important to use the same criteria and approaches for all hate crimes across the board. One wouldn&#39;t want to try to explain hate crimes against Jews in the ways that we&#39;ve been discussing but not do so for hate crimes against the other groups. And I agree with you that on some occasions people pick and choose.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;But hate crimes aren&#39;t really what I do and what I think about, as perhaps is a bit obvious. Fundamentally, I&#39;m a historian, and I can place what we&#39;re thinking about today in terms of antisemitism in some sort of historical context. I&#39;m not particularly comfortable with the focus on the causality of hate crimes. That&#39;s not because it&#39;s not a set of legitimate questions; they are, and I think you are raising important issues, but it&#39;s not really what I do.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Going back to the different definitions of antisemitism, and a way of putting the present moment in some sort of context—I think Jews arguing over what is and what is not antisemitism is not new, and what Jews mean by antisemitism is something which has changed over time. These debates are the latest iteration of a long history, which goes back to when the word antisemitism came into common usage, which was in the eighteen-eighties.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;When it first came into common usage, certainly in Western Europe, it had a much more restricted meaning than it&#39;s come to have since. Then, the antisemitic movement was a real German movement, which called itself the Anti-Semitic League. And they brought into question civil equality for Jews. Antisemitism was widely understood to be about that. It was about the idea that Jews should not enjoy equality with other subjects.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;e80c2d&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Now, one of the extraordinary consequences is that the pogroms in Russia were not spoken of as antisemitic in the West. They were barbaric, they were medieval, they were uncivilized. But because Jews in Russia did not have rights to be taken away from them, those pogroms didn&#39;t fit the meaning of antisemitism. The point of talking about that is to say that the meaning of antisemitism has changed over time, and our recent debates are just the latest stage in a long history.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;So much of it today is based on Israel, which is not to say that there wouldn&#39;t still be antisemites if there were no Israel. Do you see the post-1948 period as its own period of antisemitism?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;OK, so that&#39;s a really big question.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;You have thirty seconds to answer it.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I&#39;ll do it in the form of a haiku. There are different dimensions to this question. I have written about antisemitism as a reservoir in the culture, something there to be drawn on. And this is a reservoir which has built up over centuries, even over millennia. There are three key elements in this: one is the idea that Judaism has been superseded by Christianity (the notion that Jews have a particularistic and narrow morality is one consequence of that idea); second, the idea that Jews are forever conspiratorial and up to something against the common good; and, third, the connection of Jews with money. These ideas have been repurposed over centuries in multiple political contexts. And we see them repurposed in some of the antisemitic attacks on Israel.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;One thing shown by multiple opinion surveys in the United States, Germany, and in the UK and elsewhere, is that the percentage of committed ideological antisemites is relatively small, but the diffusion of negative stereotypes and narratives about Jews through the culture is much higher and much wider. At certain moments, people draw on these, especially at political flash points when these ideas appear to be useful, and when they appear to explain something. Yes, there are antisemites, sort of ideologically committed individuals and groups who have an antisemitic world view, but much more commonplace are individuals who draw on the well of antisemitism within the culture. And that&#39;s what we see in antisemitism around Israel.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Today, there is what I think people would perceive as right-wing antisemitism that you see from Donald Trump&#39;s online followers, and whomever else. There&#39;s left-wing antisemitism, too. And then you have the antisemitism of certain groups in the Middle East, such as Hamas, which I think in an American political context are associated more with the left, but if you actually look at their ideas about, say, gay people, they appear right-wing. Do you think of these different strands of antisemitism as very distinct in some way?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I would want to think about them as being distinct. You have distinct political traditions which draw on a common culture. There is a tradition of writing about antisemitism which simply emphasizes these long continuities. And I think that as a historian, that doesn&#39;t help one understand the particular instances when they arise, and they also can lead one to misunderstand the present moment.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;xfpgo&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;wluoe&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;For example, look at the very understandable description of the events of the massacre of the 7th of October as a pogrom. It&#39;s easy to understand why people draw on Jewish collective memory to describe these events. However, pogroms in Russia and later in Poland took place where Jews were a racialized minority, relatively powerless, vulnerable, and the violence meted out against them was an attempt to put them in their place. The violence meted out against the Israelis was awful. But calling them pogroms does not see the very different context in which they took place, in a state in which Jews are a majority, in which they have state power. In those terms, if one did want to speak about pogroms, one would be looking at the events in the West Bank in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cnn.com/2023/06/15/middleeast/huwara-west-bank-settler-attack-cmd-intl/index.html&quot;>;Huwara&lt;/a>; earlier this year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Maybe this gets to something that&#39;s been complicated about the current rise in antisemitism. After October 7th, all the major Western powers have lined up pretty solidly behind Israel, with the political support for the Jewish people and the Jewish state being incredibly strong. That is one reason that people have trouble grasping the extent of antisemitism. They say, “You&#39;ve got people of both political parties in America supporting Jews, supporting Israel,” and so on and so forth.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;It&#39;s not only that the Western powers have lined up solidly behind Israel—it&#39;s that Western powers in their internal policies are very clear about combating antisemitism. Biden produced his strategic plan to combat antisemitism. In the UK, the government helps fund security of buildings which house Jewish institutions. It&#39;s helping fund a Holocaust memorial project next to the Houses of Parliament. The German government is very strong in seeking to prevent any recurrence of antisemitism in German society.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;This, historically, is unprecedented. If one goes back to the interwar years, governments in Europe were either explicitly hostile to Jews or largely indifferent to them as they faced persecution. One of the things which this points to are the ways in which mainstream Jewish communities in the United States and in Europe have very often made alliances with governments, and with those in power. And it&#39;s not that there are no alliances with other racialized minorities, but these have often suffered and frayed. And the vertical alliances, which Jews have made, in some ways leave them vulnerable to radical groups who sympathize with the Palestinians and who have little sympathy either with Israel or with its supporters. These vertical alliances offer some rewards and some safety to Jewish people outside of Israel, but they also bring dangers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Why does it bring danger necessarily to be protected?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;It brings danger if people think that Jews are being protected in ways that the other groups are not. And it brings danger because it angers people who are against the state or against the system, however they conceive it. That can be and sometimes is understood by people on the left in conspiratorial ways. And many people who are engaged in the movement for Palestinian rights are also engaged in wider political activities around race and social justice. Although there are points of solidarity between Jews and other racialized minorities, it&#39;s also the case that the impact of Israel-Palestine has been to make those other solidarities harder and harder to build.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;It feels a little bit like a Catch-22 to suggest that Jews in the twentieth century faced widespread antisemitism, faced the Holocaust, and then in response sought political alliances, and now they&#39;re disliked for doing that. I guess my concern about focussing on any stated cause of antisemitism is it seems a little bit like you are damned if you do and damned if you don&#39;t.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;This is not about causality. It&#39;s about thinking through how a dynamic arises. People are making political choices. And alliances are made and alliances are broken. It&#39;s trying to understand that dynamic. It&#39;s not trying to say, “Well, these vertical alliances are a cause of antisemitism,” but I am saying that these vertical alliances in a time of heightened anti-racist mobilization across society reveal the different strategies being taken by Jews and by other racialized minorities. That speaks to your question about the paradox of the position of Jews in many countries, because they are fearful, and at the present moment antisemitic incidents are rising dramatically. What I&#39;ve been trying to talk about is how to understand this. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;d9b04v&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 04:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Daily Cartoon: Tuesday, November 7th]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/cartoons/daily-cartoon/tuesday-november-7th-sad-pumpkin]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-07T16:56:15.459Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654a62ebd37fa267bd40e10b/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/A28401.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt; div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22。 1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>; &lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot; 0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2 .95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/ svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存&lt;/span >;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-内容&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content =daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-银行?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp; ;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;购买《纽约客》漫画 »&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >; &lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;q5tewk&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div 数据-node-id=&quot;fjyay&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; >;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 01:06:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>