<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>纽约客</title><description>纽约客全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.newyoker.com <item><title><![CDATA[George C. Wolfe Would Not Be Dismissed]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-new-yorker-interview/george-c-wolfe-would-not-be-dismissed]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05T11:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542ad2305eb91fba6e6b116/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/Cunningham-George-C-Wolfe-social.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot; 24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508 L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H1 6V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>; &lt;span >;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d =“M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z”>; &lt; /path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot; ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;“如果那玩意不起作用，我就不穿上个月我们交谈时，导演兼编剧乔治·C·沃尔夫 (George C. Wolfe) 告诉我。他谈论的是童年的包袱，以及他早年在一个偏僻的南方小镇生活的后果，但他也可能很容易谈论他的艺术态度。沃尔夫，六十九岁，美国戏剧界的泰斗，他充满活力地编写和导演戏剧和电影，感觉像是不受义务束缚的自由的产物。从他的作品来看，他似乎总是很开心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;八月，在玛莎葡萄园非裔美国电影节上，我在观众席上看到沃尔夫穿着沙色西装和运动鞋，与 MSNBC 记者乔纳森·卡普哈特 (Jonathan Capehart) 谈论了他的新片《鲁斯汀》(Rustin)，该片以伟大但不太知名的民权领袖贝亚德·鲁斯汀 (Bayard Rustin) 为主题。在舞台上，沃尔夫轻松地坐在椅子上，就像朋友客厅里的双人沙发一样。他满怀自我接纳，在播放电影片段时微笑着，显然对结果感到满意，并将他的答案锐化成俏皮话，他知道这些俏皮话会引起卡普哈特和观众的笑声。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沃尔夫是一个美国表演艺术界的泽利格。他出生于肯塔基州法兰克福，早年凭借《有色人种博物馆》和音乐剧《天堂！》等戏剧赢得了作家的赞誉。他的第一部热门作品是《Jelly&#39;s Last Jam》，这是一部关于爵士钢琴家兼乐队领队 Jelly Roll Morton 的音乐剧。那部早期的作品充满了尖刻的智慧和一种疯狂的、略带做作的智慧——这是沃尔夫此后风格的标志。与此同时，这位不安分的多才多艺的人——当然是多才多艺的，也许是因为他早期在音乐剧方面的学术训练——作为戏剧导演获得了更大的声誉。他执导了&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2005/01/03/after-angels&quot;>;托尼·库什纳&lt;/a>;的划时代作品《&lt;a href= “https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/1992/11/23/beyond-nelly&quot;>;天使在美国&lt;/a>;”，库什纳的音乐剧“卡罗琳，或改变”，以及&lt;a href=&quot;https: //www.newyorker.com/magazine/2006/10/30/the-show-woman&quot;>;Suzan-Lori Parks&lt;/a>; 的普利策奖获奖杰作“Topdog/Underdog”。沃尔夫担任公共剧院的艺术总监后，创作并导演了流行音乐剧“Bring in &#39;da Noise, Bring in &#39;da Funk”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2004年，沃尔夫开始了另一个平行的职业生涯，作为一名电影导演，他从改编自鲁本·圣地亚哥-哈德森同名自传剧的《拉克瓦纳布鲁斯》开始。从那时起，他执导了《亨利埃塔·拉克斯的不朽生命》和《&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2020/12/21/reimagining-august-wilsons-ma-raineys -black-bottom-on-the-small-screen&quot;>;Ma Rainey 的 Black Bottom&lt;/a>;”，经常为媒介带来节奏、热情、表演技巧和强度，这些似乎是从他的初恋音乐剧中借来的。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;他的新电影讲述了&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/1963/09/07/march-on-washington-i-have-a-dream&quot;的故事>;从拉斯汀（由神秘的科尔曼·多明戈饰演）的角度来看华盛顿游行&lt;/a>;，他构思了这次游行并将其组织到最细微的细节。这部电影的基调令人惊讶地轻松——它常常让人感觉像是一个雀跃的故事，而不是这个国家历史上最庄严的公民事件之一。它以一个长而充满活力的画面开头，介绍了广泛的历史人物，包括国会议员亚当·克莱顿·鲍威尔（杰弗里·赖特饰）和民权活动家菲利普·伦道夫（格林·图尔曼饰）和罗伊·威尔金斯（克里斯·威尔金斯饰）。洛克），并以马丁·路德·金（阿米尔·阿米恩饰）对拉斯汀的暂时背叛而达到顶峰——拉斯汀因性取向而被其他几位领导人视为该运动的累赘。 《Rustin》是一部着迷于组织和过程的电影，对诸如种族平等大会 (&lt;em>;CORE&lt;/em>;) 等机构的运作感兴趣，因为它处于个人人物投下的长长的阴影中，例如饰演 Rustin、King 和 Ella Baker（奥德拉·麦克唐纳）。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;你可能会认为“Rustin”是沃尔夫数十年职业生涯中许多爱好和知识潮流的结合——民权运动及其来世、同性恋经历以及帮助它生存的伪装，一个计划如何几乎音乐般地组合在一起，并在一场盛大的表演中达到高潮。我和沃尔夫谈论了这部电影、他成长的轮廓，以及如何在娱乐和艺术世界中继续前进。为了清晰和长度，我们的对话已经过编辑。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;观看“Rustin”时，我开始思考你与传记叙事的关系，回到《果冻的最后果酱》。这是最喜欢的形式吗？你是如何处理我们所说的传记片，并按照生命的时间线进行创作的？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我讨厌传记片的概念。对我来说，戏剧是关于想法的。因此，在《果冻的最后果酱》中，我对这样一个想法很感兴趣：一个在文化和行为上似乎都是南方人、黑人的人不断地说：“我的祖先直接来自法国海岸。”这种矛盾让我感到惊讶，我想对此进行探索。我越深入这个世界，我对探索新奥尔良就越感兴趣。杰利·罗尔·莫顿 (Jelly Roll Morton) 的职业生涯非常有趣，因为他从南方来到芝加哥，但当他到达纽约时，路易斯·阿姆斯特朗 (Louis Armstrong) 也到了，所以新奥尔良最好的部分已经融入到了场景中。我对出现在这座城市却事业起步晚的人很感兴趣。这个人变成了一个想法。&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>; &lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;7x13br&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>; >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt; div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;acfuo&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client- content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;和 Bayard 一起，我对 1963 年的夏天着迷。三个月后，肯尼迪去世了。到了 64 或 65 年，&lt;em >;CORE&lt;/em>; 变成了 &lt;em >;CORE&lt;/em>; East，并且变得更加激进。因此，从历史上看，存在这样一个门口，非暴力将受到质疑。这个国家将会变得更加暴力。然后就有了这位才华横溢的组织者，他是同性恋——在 1963 年他是同性恋，毫无歉意——他在八周内组织了这次游行。这部电影让我有机会不仅生活在角色内部，而且生活在这个时期，并探索这个国家团结在一起的重大事件。它聚集在一起，然后在很长一段时间内发生破裂。这对我来说很有趣。另外，贝亚德只是一个非凡的案例研究。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我变得对人着迷。我很迷恋艾拉·贝克，所以我想，让我把她放在这里并确保她很重要。鲁比·多丽丝（Ruby Doris）——我对她很着迷——也是民权运动中的人物，她去了斯佩尔曼学校，然后被开除，并且是&lt;em>;SNCC&lt;/em>;的重要人物，最后她有了一个孩子成为一名黑人民族主义者，并在她二十六岁时去世。我开始着迷于某些人的生活，以及他们在如此短的时间内所取得的辉煌。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;你的想法之间是否存在任何紧张关系？试图提出人们有时希望从有关历史人物的电影中得到的东西——也许是一种真实感，就好像他们从历史书中得到了一小段页面一样？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;我从纽约大学获得了双硕士学位，一个是戏剧写作，一个是音乐剧，每天项目中的其他人都会说，“我喜欢这个角色吗？这个角色可爱吗？”我说：“他他妈就是个人类。”这些品质将尽我所能在旅途中延续，因此我对这种“讨人喜欢”的方程式感到厌恶——尽管我认为贝亚德·鲁斯汀是一个非常讨人喜欢的人。因为，如果角色是人，他们就更像我，也更像我们。这就是为什么我喜欢马丁·路德·金的第一个场景，因为他做了一件糟糕的事情：他背叛了他的亲密朋友。他后来救赎了自己，但我喜欢这一切——因为那时他们就是人。我可以看着它，然后想，让我找到进入这个故事的方式，如果他们能克服他们的狗屎，我也能。纪念碑的事——我对此不感兴趣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;在这部电影中，你有一个明显有魅力的人，人们蜂拥而至，他也蜂拥而至其他人，但你确实看到了他的缺点总是回到前台。作为一名导演，您如何引导像科尔曼·多明戈这样的演员走过这条弧线？是否关注档案内容，拉斯汀实际上是如何移动和说话的？你依赖日记吗？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科尔曼踏上了自己的旅程。他自己进行了技术研究。就像，贝亚德是男高音，科尔曼是男中音，所以他对自己的演讲进行了所有调整。然后，工作就发生在人际动态中——比如他和艾拉·贝克之间的动态。这里的权力动态是什么？菲利普·伦道夫是谁？此时此刻，马丁·路德·金是谁？你觉得你比他聪明吗？&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;dcxv7&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;拍摄前我会排练两周，拍摄前每天都会排练我有一个排练期。我清理了整个场景，演员和我开始探索场景的内容——阻止它并做所有这些事情，但也创建一个安全结构，以便演员能够承受最大的脆弱性。你会了解角色的真实情况以及他们所做的所有工作，然后你坐在一张桌子旁，看着科尔曼·多明戈，以及权力动态和变化。她在推动什么？她说了什么别人不能说的话？这有什么影响？您正在暴露角色，因此，当某个紧张时刻发生时，演员会以惊人的方式接受它，而您正在观看一个自发的时刻。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor= “inline-recirc”>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;我的赞歌之一是，观众可以分辨出演员何时在做一些专门为这部电影而发现的事情，以及何时从另一部电影中回收一些垃圾。我们的目标是制作一部充满无尽赤裸裸发现的电影。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;并不是每个电影导演都像您一样专注于排练。这是来自你的戏剧背景吗？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是其中的一部分。但这也是你如何与演员一起发展词汇的方式——这也是你如何让他们踏上旅程的方式。你问问题。有时我问问题不是为了得到答案，而是为了看看演员在他们的过程中处于什么位置。当我们每天表演《雷尼妈妈的黑屁股》时，查德维克·博斯曼每天都会走到我面前说：“感谢上帝，我们进行了两周的排练。”这是一个扎根的时期，然后就会让位于未知的、脆弱的、令人惊讶的事情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;梅丽尔·斯特里普告诉我，当她表演《苏菲的选择》时，他们每天早上都会排练，然后他们下午就去拍它给演员一种指挥感，而这种指挥使他们能够自由地面对素材和角色的脆弱性。因此，这不是模仿戏剧的问题，我认为，这是一个精心设计场景的过程，使出色的作品成为可能。那些不能移植到屏幕上的东西？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我把这一切都简化为讲故事。有时我讲一个故事，最后故事发生在一座古老的维多利亚式建筑中，人们坐得太近，有时有一台小机器记录着一切。亲密的等式以及你捕捉到这种亲密的程度各不相同，但你和演员总是在寻找绝对的真相。这就是你的使命，我认为这超越了一切。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在戏剧排练中，你正在帮助演员锻炼肌肉，这样你作为导演就变得无关紧要，这样他们每天晚上都可以出去并负责自己的表演。在电影中，你试图捕捉尽可能多的不同时刻，以及这些时刻的尽可能多的变化，这样当你最终进入剪辑室时，你就有了可以挖掘的大量词汇，并且可以分辨你想讲的故事。这有意义吗？&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;uoa5ml&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;5cfj3b&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;确实如此。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;我一直认为您的电影生涯特别依赖于您在音乐剧方面的经验。你的电影不仅在某种程度上经常与音乐有关，而且其中的节奏、节奏和动态也是音乐性的。在《鲁斯汀》中，人们唱着自由之歌，这些场景有一个音乐逻辑。当然，贝亚德·鲁斯汀也录制了自己的音乐。您如何看待这些时刻？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;导演音乐剧培养了我拍电影的精神力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;真的吗？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;音乐剧是野兽。他们是野兽。电视节目“&lt;em>;M&lt;/em>;*&lt;em>;A&lt;/em>;*&lt;em>;S&lt;/em>;*&lt;em>;H&lt;/em>;”的联合编剧拉里·格尔巴特 (Larry Gelbart) 说道， “如果希特勒还活着，我希望他能带着音乐剧出城。”当你在预览时，你正在管理一个城镇；当你在预览时，你正在管理一个城镇。然后你停下来，人群进来，他们要么充满敌意，要么很兴奋，这取决于你所做的工作的质量。有时，如果你巧妙地改变某件事，就会改变他们的看法。这是一个很好的训练场，可以培养人们对材料以及什么有效、什么无效的分析能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在很早的时候，在与布兰福德·马萨利斯交谈时，我就设想了这个 1963 年的爵士四重奏。 。对我来说，爵士乐除了打响指之外，还很理智，而且我正在和非常聪明的男人和女人打交道。我希望观众确切地知道他们在哪里，并捕捉到我正在与一个黑人知识分子打交道——在很多方面，不仅仅是——一个黑人知识分子。我希望他们能够理解那种节奏。另外，有了这个四重奏（结果不是四重奏，它比四重奏大得多），你将拥有主要独奏者贝亚德。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在开场序列中，音乐将你推向背叛。你被扔到那里是因为这些角色被扔到那里。在帕萨迪纳的场景中，贝亚德是主要的独奏者，突然之间“帕萨迪纳”这个词就具有了力量，这让他沉默了。然后有一个新人接管了房间，他觉得这应该是他的电影，那就是亚当·克莱顿·鲍威尔，他正在独奏。然后，在缺席的情况下，安娜·赫奇曼博士看到贝亚德处于危险之中，这件事一直困扰着她，所以她接管了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些人试图争先恐后地推动音乐，直到 A. 菲利普·伦道夫，他热情、友善、进化、爆发，结束了亚当·克莱顿·鲍威尔(Adam Clayton Powell)对当下的掌控。因为亚当·克莱顿·鲍威尔在历史上与马丁·路德·金有过问题。这就是他对贝亚德的看法：他是纽约人。我认为亚当并不关心谁与什么发生了性关系，只是他来自纽约，所以无论如何。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;鲍威尔认为他应该负责。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;正是如此。他是一个政治家，一个非常聪明的人，而且非常成功——他会不择手段地得到他想要的东西。但 A. Philip Randolph 介入并结束了整个作品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;爵士乐组合的复杂性对我来说非常重要，因为它结合了这些才华横溢的人类的思维过程和语言。民权运动歌曲的所有语言都来自奴隶制。 “我不会让任何人让我转身，我会继续走下去，继续说话，向自由之地进军。”有一个经典的美国黑人词汇正在发挥作用。然后是这种不断发展和具有挑战性的现代声音，它寻找真相并质疑以前的一切。这样，爵士乐和这种传统声音就可以协同工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;n9oukm&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;然后我有兴趣探索，因为缺乏更好的词语，正如许多同性恋者所做的那样，躲在众目睽睽之下。因此，在贝亚德被殴打后，你会听到这种尖叫声，而某些电影制作人员不喜欢它，但我说，“我喜欢那种尖叫声。”当南方的一个黑人被殴打时，没有人听到那声尖叫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;所以就有了尖叫声，下一个节拍开始，继续前进，继续到下一页，你记得痛苦的时刻，现在你，贝亚德，去恢复与你的朋友马丁的关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;这部电影中不止一个时刻，有人必须放下自己的骄傲，因为有更大的事情要做线;时间如此紧迫，使命如此重大。这与其说是一个电影制作问题，不如说是一个个人问题，但这种痛苦去哪儿了？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是一个非常有趣的问题。我对贝亚德最亲密的回应可能是这样的想法：当你负责时，没有人关心你是否感冒，没有人关心你是否累了——你只需要交付。 “我的未出柜男友已经有妻子了，他刚刚和我分手了。斯特罗姆·瑟蒙德刚刚在广播中出卖了我。好吧，必须处理，继续，继续，继续。”因为你正在建造比你更大的东西。对我来说最感人的时刻之一是拉斯汀与马丁·路德·金对峙，然后回到办公室。可以想象所有这些孩子都会逃跑，因为与贝亚德这个同性恋男子联系在一起可能会在他们脸上爆炸。但他看到它们在起作用，这就是尽管面临如此惊人的逆境仍继续工作的理由——你创造了比你的怀疑或恐惧更大、更好、更强的东西。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;问题是损失会发生什么和痛苦。这是一个非常现实的问题。我在经营公共剧院时接受了肾脏移植手术，因为我工作得要死。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;你有机会停下来思考一下吗？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;如果我不这样做，我今天就不会在这里。这是一个让我意识到我的身体不仅仅是服从我的意志的东西，我也必须服从我的身体的机会。因为那是我对身体的概念——就像，好吧，让我去移动这堵墙，来吧，身体。我的身体在说：“对不起？”这些时刻的发生是为了让你可以重新定义和重新评估，这样你就可以继续做你正在做的事情，希望以一种更聪明、更富有同情心的方式，不仅对别人更有同情心，而且对自己更有同情心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;在我看来，这部电影在某种程度上是关于民权运动未完成的工作的。你提到安娜博士开口说道：“嘿，你知道这里没有女性，对吧？”当然，整部电影中也充满了对同性恋的恐惧，并且是针对贝亚德的。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt; div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;nr123l&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node- id=&quot;mlrfqk&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt; div >;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;如果我没有问你，你自己在肯塔基州长大时是否也有这种感觉，那就是我的失职了。你去了一所黑人大学，你去了一所罗森沃尔德学校——你是许多这些运动的受益者和产物。而且你也是一个出柜的同性恋者。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为这个令人难以置信的社区的一员，我受益匪浅，然后我必须跑步才能成为我自己。这是一个非常有教养的社区，但它也有。 。 。有一个人，我一直提到他，一个叫杰克逊·罗伯的人。马丁·路德·金在法兰克福举行了一次游行，金住在杰克逊·罗伯的家里。杰克逊·罗伯是一名殡仪员，而且他是同性恋。如果他们希望埋葬自己的亲人，难道没有人会抱怨杰克逊·罗伯吗？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，就我的职业抱负和我是谁而言，我必须离开。我去了加利福尼亚州，去了波莫纳，然后，在加利福尼亚州之后，我搬到了纽约，这样我就可以拥有我的全部了。但我必须离开那里。我回去后，他们为我感到骄傲，我很高兴他们为我感到骄傲。但你必须继续旅行，你必须服从你的好奇心，你需要发现，需要知道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有一次，我在玛莎葡萄园岛，我正在谈论这个年轻的女孩，她大概二十多岁，她说：“我父亲是一名传教士，而我是一名女同性恋。”我说：“看看那个世界，认领并拥有你可以使用的东西，然后在后视镜中与它的其余部分挥手告别。如果你不能使用它，就不要声称它，但不要让它阻止你成为你需要成为的最令人惊讶的自己。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我是，非常如此，我是谁——我来自肯塔基州法兰克福。但如果那玩意不起作用，我就不穿它。贝亚德离开宾夕法尼亚州西切斯特，成为这个黑人社区的一部分，他抗议当地电影院的种族隔离，然后他来到纽约，开始了一段旅程，并成为了他自己。我们都会踏上旅程，去完成和探索我们尚未探索过的事物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;当时的飞行是有意识的吗？或者，后来您是否认为，哦，哇，我只需要 -&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;否六岁时，我就要走了，我必须离开。然后，当我十二岁或十三岁的时候，我母亲来到纽约，来到纽约大学，从事一些高级学位的工作，我和她一起去了。我想，好吧，明白了，就在这里，明白了，明白了。这样我就可以回家，在高中时感到可怕和痛苦，因为我知道，稍后我会来这里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;那是你高中时的吗？您只是在等待出去吗？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不。我就读的学校有点像罗森沃尔德学校，但它与镇上的布莱克学院有某种联系。当我进入这所以白人为主的公立高中时，他们认为我很愚蠢，他们打电话给我母亲，讨论让我参加补习班——尽管我当时不知道，但我知道我很蠢。被评判。我变成了伊娃庇隆：“当我离开这所学校时，我将管理它！”我站在阳台上说：“这将是我的！”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/ div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;bg3cj5&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;我是报纸的编辑，鼓手、文学杂志的编辑等等——我已经是一个成绩优异的人了，但它放大了。这个想法是：我不会被忽视或解雇，我来自的社区不会允许这种情况发生，我来自的家庭不会允许这种情况发生，我不允许被疏远，并且你不会那样做的。这是训练的一部分——首先是出来，然后只是到达不同的地方并说：“不，我不会被忽视。我还有工作要做，你对我来说是一个障碍，那是微不足道的。”这是培训的一部分，而且是非常具体的基于社区的培训。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;在您的成长过程中，社区的所在地是什么？是教堂环境吗？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;可以是很多东西——学校、教堂、社区。我的祖母住在街上，她是一个凶猛的、保护性的人物，而且非常具有威严。法兰克福是隔离的，因此我们的想法是保护年轻人，这样结构的破坏就不会抑制他们的可能性。直到今天，我仍然保留着一张录音，《黑人历史上的伟大时刻》。所有这些都是防御工事，因此强加给我们的限制永远不会突破成人、社区、教会和亲戚的力场，因此你有梦想，你相信，你想要实现，你感到有责任做出贡献，你做了所有这些事情，而且根本没有任何种族劣等的等式在起作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;在我长大的时候，种族隔离已经结束了，但我们仍然得到提出的图像就好像每个黑人孩子都在充满种族主义的思想中长大。就像，不，实际上，在我长大的社区中，当你在学校表现出色的那一刻，整个社区都会说，“拜托！”每个人都在努力提升你。这种态度在电影中得到了体现——拉斯汀正在利用他年轻时的贵格会精神，他正在利用一种资源。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没错。他的母亲是一位重要的活动家，非常著名的黑人活动家会来和他的家人住在一起。这是一个赋权的世界——在这个世界里，你尽你最大的能力赋予年轻的力量，让他们能够前进，做上一代人做不到的事情。这是社区的责任，有庆祝感，也有责任感。贝亚德就是和那些孩子们在一起的。他说：“我将挑战你变得更聪明、更深入、更快、更好，你会思考这些事情，并且会去做。你将尽你所能地努力工作，没有什么可以阻止你，因为没有什么可以阻止我。”&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;这是对该社区的庆祝，然后尽可能地伸出援手并具有包容性。有一天你醒来，你会制作一张伊丽莎白时代歌曲和黑人灵歌的专辑。&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt; div data-node-id=&quot;f3d8oc&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot; ggq6t&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt; p >;&lt;strong>;无人能实现的组合。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加油！不管怎样，如果你想做，就做吧。就像，我要去肯塔基州，我想学习歌舞伎，所以我就去学习歌舞伎。走进这个世界，充满冒险精神和好奇心，尽可能多地接触和联系不同的人，建立一个联盟，并以战士的身份奉献自己，帮助世界变得更加广阔和包容，时期。这就是你所做的，因为它是在肯塔基州的一个小镇上为你小规模完成的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然后你经营公共剧院并为尽可能多的不同艺术家打开大门，喂养他们，抚养他们，给他们钱，因为这就是为你做的。每当您遇到障碍物时，请弄清楚该障碍物如何不会阻止您。我在贝亚德真正认识到那种责任感、那种社区意识、那种辛勤工作的感觉。我用了“反抗”这个词，但反抗几乎就是对障碍给予了太多的信任。他与亚当·克莱顿·鲍威尔（Adam Clayton Powell）接触，后者想羞辱他，然后他展示了这些孩子的才华和成就。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，还有帕萨迪纳的故事：更多人们知道的事情比电影中透露的要多，但我想把它作为一个羞耻的小秘密角落，这样，随着电影朝着游行的方向发展，这部电影正在向他揭露最后一个羞耻的小角落，因此，就在他去华盛顿之前，他将其从他的系统中驱除。 Going to DC isn&#39;t just for the march—it&#39;s claiming the streets of a segregated town, which is what DC was at the time, and claiming the sunlight and the daylight as your own, so that the first time you&#39;re kissing that boy, it&#39;s not in some dark alley with fire escapes hovering over you. He&#39;s on a journey of liberation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;You mentioned your tenure at the Public Theatre. One of the great struggles and triumphs of your tenure there was making it a place where more people could come. It seems now that the struggle for big nonprofit theatres is just to keep existing. You&#39;re still a participant in the theatre, if not at the same intensity as you once were. What is your view about what&#39;s happening now, and how it relates to some of the challenges you faced?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I think any time you come into contact with a complication—as I was talking earlier about my health—it&#39;s frightening and overwhelming, but it&#39;s also a chance to reinvest, rediscover, and rebuild. I don&#39;t feel equipped to offer forth a solution, but it&#39;s a really interesting time that all these regional theatres, post-&lt;em >;COVID&lt;/em>;, are going through. It&#39;s post-&lt;em >;COVID&lt;/em>; and post-&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/george-floyd&quot;>;George Floyd&lt;/a>;, so people are saying, “Let&#39;s engage people of color in leadership positions,” in a way that has never been done before. I think I was one of two, maybe three, people of color who were leading an arts organization at the time when I was at the Public, so it&#39;s a really interesting time, trying to commit and do the right thing in a landscape that is radically shifting, in a landscape where the subscriber base is virtually vanishing. How do you do that? Do you try to bring some commercial stuff to Broadway so you can get that money? How do you hold on to the passion of the vision in that landscape?&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;8okgo&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;I&#39;m not sure, I&#39;m not going to bring up any solutions, but it really is fascinating, and smart people are involved in trying to solve it.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Thinking about the deep tectonics of the theatre, one could ask a similar thing about the business of movies—your actors can&#39;t even talk about this movie yet, on account of the strike. Have you learned anything about the movie business in this moment? The Directors Guild, obviously, was able to patch things up quickly.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yeah, and I&#39;m in the Writers Guild as well. I&#39;ve been working—literally, it&#39;s, like, I was editing and then added the in-credit songs, and, after that, I just started going around talking to lovely people like you. I&#39;ve just been doing that fucking non-stop, you know what I mean?&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;I&#39;ve got one last question for you, and this one&#39;s for me, because I love Chris Rock, who plays Roy Wilkins. It&#39;s such unexpected casting. How did that come to be?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;It was that two things happened. Chris reached out to me and said, “You&#39;re doing a new movie? I would love to work with you.” And then I was looking at pictures of Roy Wilkins, and I thought, He kind of looks like Chris Rock. It was the same with Audra [McDonald]. I went, Oh, Ella Baker. Audra has this extraordinary purity of focus. But Chris reached out, and then I was looking at pictures of Wilkins, and it was literally that: Wow, OK, that would be interesting. And then you go on the journey. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;xaejll&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 19:06:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Can Seawalls Save Us From Rising Seas and Surging Storms?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/news/annals-of-a-warming-planet/can-seawalls-save-us]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05T11:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542a31405eb91fba6e6b113/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Seawall_Social.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Pacifica, California, just south of San Francisco, is the kind of beachfront community that longtime residents compare to Heaven. One of its streets is called Paradise Drive; local fishermen brag that Pacifica Pier is among the state&#39;s best places to catch salmon, striped bass, and crab. Every few years, a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/photo-booth/the-superbloom-is-a-glimpse-of-californias-past&quot;>;superbloom&lt;/a>; blankets the coast with golden wildflowers. When the sun cuts through the region&#39;s famous fog, the sky sometimes glows, as in a Turner painting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Some of Pacifica&#39;s most dramatic views could be found on Esplanade Drive, where mid-century developers built bungalows on top of a cliff. For almost fifty years, residents gazed out from their back yards to see whales splashing in the Pacific. Then, in 1998, a group of homeowners gathered to say goodbye. “I cannot express how spectacular it has been living here,” one of them, Joe Parker, said at the time. “I&#39;ve seen dolphins out there. I recognize all the seabirds.” Beverly Axelrod, who had spent fourteen years on Esplanade Drive, recalled how her ocean view had “healed everything.” But then a series of vicious storms, fuelled in part by the warm waters of El Niño, had washed away more than thirty feet of the cliff beneath their homes. Workers had to saw Axelrod&#39;s house in half to prevent it from falling into the sea. Ken Lajoie, a local geologist, said that, even after the wind and waves abated, more of the cliff would crumble. The city ultimately condemned seven houses to be bulldozed. One woman was now paying the mortgage on a house that didn&#39;t exist; Axelrod compared the demolition to “being at the bedside of somebody who&#39;s dying.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In the nineteen-eighties, Pacifica had fortified parts of its shore with a twenty-foot-tall concrete seawall. It had also coated some areas with loose rock, known as riprap. After the storms of 1998, the city shored up its defenses again; state and federal agencies gave Pacifica $1.5 million to pile riprap at the base of the cliff. The city thought of its investments as forward-thinking, in light of climate change. But Lajoie warned that riprap seawalls usually fail. “Stop building structures along eroding coastlines,” he told a San Francisco &lt;em>;Chronicle&lt;/em>; reporter, in 2001. “Prevent future construction of seawalls of any type.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Lajoie was right: the seawall beneath Esplanade Drive did not stop the sea. In 2010, part of the cliff fell out from under an apartment building, which had to be abandoned and then torn down. By 2018, only one house remained on a portion of the street that overlooked the cliff. After its patio tumbled off the edge, the city government bought the house and demolished it. Around that time, the mayor of Pacifica, John Keener, started talking about adapting to rising seas, and even about “managed retreat.” Instead of trying to fortify the shore forever, he suggested, residents might consider moving out of harm&#39;s way.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Most people, understandably, don&#39;t want to abandon their homes. In a new book, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/California-Against-Sea-Vanishing-Coastline-ebook/dp/B0BW17YCH5&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/California-Against-Sea-Vanishing-Coastline-ebook/dp/B0BW17YCH5&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/California-Against-Sea-Vanishing-Coastline-ebook/dp/B0BW17YCH5&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;California Against the Sea: Visions for Our Vanishing Coastline&lt;/a>;” (Heyday), Rosanna Xia, an environmental reporter at the Los Angeles &lt;em>;Times&lt;/em>;, visits Pacifica and encounters a sign that reads “&lt;em >;NO MANAGED RETREAT&lt;/em>;.” At a city-council meeting, a father of three stands up and declares, “It&#39;s a war with the sea. We may win, we may lose, but we should never give up the ground unnecessarily.” Keener was voted out of office, in large part by residents calling for stronger coastal protections. “The city fell asleep and should&#39;ve seawalled all this decades earlier,” one man told Xia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Pacifica embodies one of the central disagreements about rising seas. Fight or flight? Stay or go? Flight can seem unimaginable. But, if we try to fight the ocean with rock and concrete, it will cost us—and it may not work. Pacifica currently plans to borrow tens of millions of dollars to reinforce its seawall. Writing for a community blog, Gregg Dieguez, a critic of this plan, objected not just to its price but to the “moral hazard” it would create: by forestalling erosion, the seawall might only encourage more people to live in risky places. “Once sea level rise gets here, it&#39;s never going away, at least not for thousands of years,” Dieguez wrote. Meanwhile, he noted, only one per cent of the homes in Pacifica were at risk. “You will have to decide, as a group, whether paying to hold back the tides is a good use of your precious money,” he concluded. It&#39;s a question many more of us will soon be asking. When do seawalls make sense? And when is it better to give in to the tides?&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The oldest known seawall was built around 5000 BC, after a period of warming that melted glaciers and lifted the Mediterranean by a staggering twenty-six feet. A Stone Age community, living near a beach in present-day Israel, tried to ward off the sea with a wall of three-foot-tall boulders about the length of a football field. But, in the millennia that followed, the Mediterranean rose even more. Archeologists ultimately discovered the stones on the seafloor, under ten feet of water. The site, they wrote, was “ominously relevant” to our time. Other excavations have turned up ancient coastal fortifications in places like Lebanon and Egypt. Ancient Roman ports used a kind of concrete that grew stronger in contact with water.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In the war with the sea, the Dutch have probably spent the longest in the trenches. When Pliny the Elder visited the Low Countries in 47 AD, he compared the people he met to marooned sailors living on artificial mounds of mud; by the early Middle Ages, locals started to build a seawall. A 1948 book by a Dutch engineer, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Dredge-Drain-Reclaim-Art-Nation-dp-9401516693/dp/9401516693&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Dredge-Drain-Reclaim-Art-Nation-dp-9401516693/dp/9401516693&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Dredge-Drain-Reclaim-Art-Nation-dp-9401516693/dp/9401516693&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Dredge, Drain, Reclaim: The Art of a Nation&lt;/a>;,” describes the wall as a major victory in an existential struggle. “Formerly the terrible evils of the sea, the storm floods and the more terrible marine erosion, had to be endured, but now the fight began to throw the sea out of the country; a fight not yet ended and a fight for to be or not to be,” he wrote. But the walls had a side effect. They locked the land into place, trading in a dynamic shoreline for one that could not adapt as easily, and that would need to be defended forever.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;There are many kinds of coastal protection. Some of the most effective are entirely natural. Marshes, mangroves, and even sandy beaches can absorb the destructive power of waves, helping to soak up water and energy that would otherwise wreak havoc. Engineers can fortify a shoreline by replenishing lost sand, or by adding rock, wood, or concrete. It&#39;s also possible to augment the shore. A rock pile that parallels the coast, shielding the beach from waves, is called a breakwater. A pile that juts out to sea, trapping sand on one side, is called a groin. All of these measures are already widely used on coastlines around the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;6bbjqd&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Hard seawalls may be the bluntest instrument in coastal engineering. Typically, they are made from concrete, stone, wood, or metal, and rise vertically from the shore. But a wave that strikes a seawall never breaks and dissipates, as it would on a beach; instead, it bounces off like an echo, its destructive force intact. In the end, the flow of water and sediment is a zero-sum game. For a wave to spare one place, it has to strike another; for sand to accumulate somewhere, it has to wash away from somewhere else.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;According to the sociologist Summer Gray, seawalls are less a practical solution than a product of technocratic ideology—one that colonial powers have exported around the world. For all their potential benefits, seawalls “harm the environment, shift vulnerability downstream, lead to the disappearance of the beach, and create cycles of dependency,” she writes in her new book, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Shadow-Seawall-Coastal-Injustice-Placekeeping/dp/0520392744&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Shadow-Seawall-Coastal-Injustice-Placekeeping/dp/0520392744&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Shadow-Seawall-Coastal-Injustice-Placekeeping/dp/0520392744&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;In the Shadow of the Seawall&lt;/a>;” (University of California Press). In one meticulous chapter, Gray recounts how the Dutch West India Company settled the low-lying coast of Guyana, in South America. Planters enslaved Africans, who were forced to build seawalls and then to cultivate sugarcane. The people of Guyana eventually came to see their aging seawalls as a necessity; there was now significant development on low-lying land. When storms surge over our protections, we tend to wonder why they weren&#39;t higher, rather than questioning the logic of living by the sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In the nineteenth century, Gray writes, engineers started to consider the unintended consequences of fortifications. In 1899, Edward Case, the keeper of the Dymchurch wall, which protects Romney Marsh, in southern England, noted that, when the “Lords of the Marsh” built their manors in the muck, they locked themselves into centuries of dependence on the wall. “But for the value of the land at stake . 。 。 the struggle must have been abandoned,” Case observed. After waves washed away sediment in front of the wall, he made a counterintuitive argument: seawalls can contribute to the erosion they are supposed to prevent. At the base of a seawall, the constant churn of water stirs up sediment; that sediment is then swept back to sea. This phenomenon is now known as scour. Sometimes the water erodes so much sand that it causes walls to collapse.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Over-Seawall-Tsunamis-Cyclones-Controlling/dp/1642832561&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Over-Seawall-Tsunamis-Cyclones-Controlling/dp/1642832561&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Over-Seawall-Tsunamis-Cyclones-Controlling/dp/1642832561&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Over the Seawall: Tsunamis, Cyclones, Drought, and the Delusion of Controlling Nature&lt;/a>;” (Island Press), by the journalist Stephen Robert Miller, tells a story of double-edged engineering in Bangladesh, where the flow of water and sediment creates a rich and ever-changing agricultural zone. The region “is not so much a world pestered by water as one defined by it,” Miller writes. But, when the British colonized Bangladesh, they fractured the waterscape with embankments, farms, and railroads; after they departed, international development workers went a step further, walling off a hundred and three low-lying islands that they called &lt;em>;polders&lt;/em>;, using a Dutch word for land that is reclaimed and then fortified. Although these walls protect lives and property, they also draw Bangladeshis to areas that are vulnerable to storm surges, which devastate coastal communities during tropical cyclones. Miller writes of some floods that, paradoxically, killed more people in the places with stronger walls. “The embankments provide only pseudo security,” Dilip Datta, an environmental scientist at Khulna University, tells him. “They work against our best interest.”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;duz3sh&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;When I ran these critiques of coastal protection by Rachel Gittman, a marine ecologist at East Carolina University, she offered another reason to worry about seawalls. Natural habitats already serve as powerful buffers against flooding, she said. They absorb water and energy; this is why marsh and mangrove restoration is often the best way to protect a coast. By contrast, when coastal communities wall off the shoreline, they tend to trap ecosystems between the water and the wall, causing a process called coastal squeeze. “It can be a slow drowning of those habitats,” she told me. When they disappear, we may be more vulnerable than when we started.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Our present dilemma is worse than it needed to be. In 1981, a group of coastal geologists gathered on Skidaway Island, in Georgia, to write a report called “Saving the American Beach.” They warned that rising seas and migration toward the ocean would expose a growing number of people to erosion, flooding, and storms. Saving the shore, they argued, might “involve drastic and unpopular measures such as assuming that buildings adjacent to the beach are temporary or expendable.” By the time a second group of experts met at Skidaway, in 1985, their fears had escalated. “Sea level is rising and the American shoreline is retreating,” they wrote. “We face economic and environmental realities that leave us two choices: (1) plan for a strategic retreat now, or (2) undertake a vastly expensive program of armoring the coastline and, as required, retreating through a series of unpredictable disasters.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The Skidaway experts were hardly the only ones to foresee our current circumstances. Yet, in the decades since their reports, the number of Americans who live near a coast has almost doubled. In 2018, coastal counties were home to a hundred and twenty-eight million people, or forty per cent of US residents. Today, about fourteen per cent of the coast is fortified with hard barriers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Coastal protection is usually treated as a cost-and-benefit problem. The more people and property in a given place, the greater a seawall&#39;s benefits. Last year, when the Army Corps of Engineers proposed a vast network of seawalls and gates to shield New York and New Jersey Harbor, it argued that the fifty-three-billion-dollar project was a very good deal: although it “will not totally eliminate flood risks” in the area, it would cost much less than repairing the city after every storm. (Hurricane Sandy caused an estimated nineteen billion dollars in damage in New York City alone.) The densest, wealthiest, and most vulnerable coastal cities—Bangkok, Shanghai, Rio de Janeiro, San Francisco, Miami—are likely to make similar calculations. Yes, a seawall may erode the shore and draw even more people toward the water, but lives and livelihoods are already concentrated there; if a seawall could save them, don&#39;t we have to build one? The opposite, presumably, will be true in rural and ecologically fragile places; a seawall might endanger too many species, or wash away too many beaches, or simply protect too little, to justify the costs.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Such calculations, however, leave a lot out. Industrialized societies have never been good at valuing the nonhuman (the coastal ecosystems that seawalls squeeze out) or the intangible (the cultural, historical, or spiritual value of a place). The cost-benefit equation doesn&#39;t account for moral hazard, either. Seawalls are supposed to shield us from risk, but, if they draw people and property to the shore, they might wind up exposing more of us to it. Money also tends to protect money. Do we want to live in a world where only the wealthy can afford seawalls, and everyone else must retreat or risk drowning?&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Gray, the sociologist, is wary of managed retreat, too. “Staying in place on a warming planet is an inherently unequal struggle,” she writes. She notes that those least able to fight the pressure to relocate—for example, residents of the Maldives, where she sets half of her book—may be urged to move. “Resilience planners often ask vulnerable populations to transform themselves in drastic ways that are not asked of &#39;nonvulnerable&#39; populations,” she writes. Coastal communities that can&#39;t afford seawalls could be left with no good options. Gray never fully unties this knot; she ultimately dedicates her book to “the frontline communities who stay and fight.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;If our math is wrong, what could right it? In an era of rising seas, we are primed to think of coastal protections as prudent. Given their unintended consequences, however, we should be wary of their risks and skeptical of their benefits. Instead of building as many walls as we can, we should build as few as we need to—and only when they protect what matters most. This last notion, of what matters most, is a question, not an answer. Seawalls are expensive, and unfairness will be one of their heaviest costs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In “California Against the Sea,” Xia, the environmental reporter, writes about the difficult realities of trying to incorporate fairness into our tally of costs and benefits. In the Southern California city of Laguna Beach, Xia examines a picturesque public shoreline that separates mansions from the sea. Here, in 2015, a wealthy couple bought an aging waterfront home; they remodelled it into a stone-and-glass fortress and shored up a private seawall at its base. In a sense, they were weighing the costs and benefits of climate adaptation—but only for themselves. A neighbor soon complained to the California Coastal Commission that the wall was a threat to the beach. It was now up to the commission to decide if the wall was allowed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Xia tracks down Orrin Pilkey, a co-author of the Skidaway reports who has become known for his single-minded insistence on managed retreat, to ask him for his opinion. He argues that the neighbor was right to worry. A private seawall can deflect waves toward neighboring houses, forcing them to erect walls of their own—a domino effect in reverse. “If one homeowner wins, the whole state loses,” Pilkey tells her. “If you give up the fight on one location, then you&#39;re going to have to give up eventually on all locations.”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;5fcv88&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;The commission seemed to agree: it declared the wall illegal, ordered it torn down, and fined the couple a million dollars for remodelling a coastal house without its permission. It also resolved to oppose new seawalls up and down the coast, with few exceptions. “Seawalls damage beaches by preventing sand from reaching the beach, which eventually causes beaches to shrink until they disappear,” the commission said in a release. “In an era of sea level rise, the long-term effect of sea walls is to temporarily protect the property behind them, at the permanent expense of public sandy beach space.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In theory, a moratorium on residential seawalls is itself a kind of coastal squeeze, meant to encourage relocation. This is a complicated position to take, but it reflects a complicated reality. The Coastal Commission seemed to be saying that coastal Californians were free to stay until the sea came for their homes—as long as they did not try to stop it from doing so. If you can&#39;t retreat behind a wall, you might retreat to a landlocked town that doesn&#39;t need one. In practice, however, many homeowners would rather dig in for a fight. The Laguna Beach family took the commission to court, and, when Xia finished her book, the rogue seawall was still standing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;On a windy evening in August, I biked to a park in lower Manhattan to meet Yuki Miura, a soft-spoken researcher who has modelled the flooding that a hurricane would inflict on Manhattan. Miura, who grew up in Tokyo, told me that a mega-storm will come eventually. In fact, “it already happened,” she said. The storm surge from Hurricane Sandy, in 2012, peaked at nearly fourteen feet, inundating hundreds of city blocks. “Whenever I run the model, there are certain areas that pretty much always get flooded,” Miura told me. We were standing in one of them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;We walked together toward the East River until we came to a hulking concrete wall, which had been built so recently that it was still wrapped in plastic. Miura told me that, when she visited this area a couple of years ago, as a doctoral student in civil engineering at Columbia University, the lower-Manhattan seawall, known as the &lt;em >;BIG&lt;/em>; U, was only a proposal. “It didn&#39;t exist at all,” she said. She was happy that, at least in this one place, the city had started to fortify the shore.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;To gain access to the waterfront, we walked through a truck-size gap in the wall, passing a wheeled floodgate that looked like a narrow train car. Then we forded a stream of after-work joggers and came to a little cliff of concrete by the river. On the other side of a metal railing, the wake from passing ferries lapped at New York&#39;s fortified shoreline.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;When the next storm comes, Miura told me, the river will start to climb—slowly, more like a rising tide than a tsunami. If a strong hurricane strikes when the tide is already high, “this area would be underwater,” she said. The seawall behind us, which rose sixteen feet above sea level, was tall enough to limit—though not eliminate—coastal flooding from the biggest possible hurricanes. But Miura warned that, if a storm strikes while the wall is under construction, before it protects the entirety of lower Manhattan, then water will find the unprotected areas, flow behind the wall, and fester there. So far, only a small portion of the &lt;em >;BIG&lt;/em>; U has been built.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I asked Miura whether, instead of building walls that could anchor people along the coast, New Yorkers should think about moving away from the shore. “Managed retreat might be a good option in different regions,” she told me. “It&#39;s very hard to imagine here.” Manhattan is home to 1.6 million people and trillions of dollars of coastal infrastructure. Once you&#39;ve built skyscrapers and hospitals and highways along the water, just a few feet above sea level, it&#39;s hard to imagine any path into the future that leaves so much of value behind.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Talking to Miura, I thought about all of the choices that had led to this moment. We are fortifying the shore in part because we burned fossil fuels; we burned fossil fuels because we believed that some other place, or some later generation, would bear the consequences. In this sense, the story of seawalls and their downsides mirrors the larger story of the climate crisis. “We need to solve the problem from the bottom,” Miura told me. Until we do the hard, collective work of slashing emissions, the planet will keep getting hotter, the water will keep rising, and the storms will keep getting worse.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;As the sun set, Miura and I looked out across the water. The clouds were turning purple and orange; a few boats drifted by. It was easy to understand why someone would want to live here. Then my eyes came to rest on the apartment blocks and factories that dotted the Queens waterfront—an area that is as densely populated as parts of Manhattan, but where no comparable seawalls have been built. I asked Miura what would happen there. Could the water that would have flooded Manhattan instead end up somewhere else, like Queens?&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“It will be shifted, yeah,” Miura told me. “Water has to go somewhere.” ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>; &lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 19:06:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[The Cryptic Crossword: Sunday, November 5, 2023]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/puzzles-and-games-dept/cryptic-crossword/2023/11/05]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-05T11:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/625f1f928604b34946f0a298/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/NewYorkerCrossword-Cryptic-PromoSocial-2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;CrosswordEmbedWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;CrosswordEmbedInfoWrapper&quot; >;&lt;iframe id=&quot;crossword&quot; title=&quot;Blank iframe&quot; src=&quot;about:blank&quot; data-src=&quot;https://cdn3.amuselabs.com/tny/crossword?id=72826809&amp;set=tny-new-cryptic&amp;embed=1&amp;compact=1&amp;maxCols=2&amp;src=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.newyorker.com%2Fpuzzles-and-games-dept%2Fcryptic-crossword%2F2023%2F11%2F05&quot;>;&lt;/iframe>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;CrosswordEmbedInvisibleDivWrapper&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;iframe data-testid=&quot;CrosswordEmbedContentIframe&quot; title=&quot;Embedded Crossword&quot; >;&lt;/iframe>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 05 Nov 2023 19:06:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Clarence Thomas’s R.V. Loan and Supreme Court Scrutiny]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/podcast/political-scene/clarence-thomass-rv-loan-and-supreme-court-scrutiny]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04T14:29:42.984Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/63755311573147b2b8a3132b/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/The%20Political%20Scene%20B%20Glasser%20Mayer%20Osnos%20From%20Washington.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;figure data-testid=&quot;IframeEmbed&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;IframeEmbedContainer&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;iframe height=&quot;120&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-scripts&quot; title=&quot;Embedded Frame&quot; src=&quot;https://player.simplecast.com/58725f39-6213-448f-8384-87fd25453744?dark=false&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay *;加密媒体*；剪贴板写入；自动播放;全屏; picture-in-picture&quot;>;&lt;/iframe>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;Listen and subscribe:&lt;/em>; &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.apple?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.apple?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.apple?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Apple&lt;/a>; | &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.spotify?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.spotify?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.spotify?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Spotify&lt;/a>; | &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.google?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.google?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.google?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Google&lt;/a>; | &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Wherever You Listen&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/newsletter/news-politics&quot;>;&lt;em>;Sign up&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>; &lt;em>;to receive our twice-weekly News &amp;amp; Politics newsletter.&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;p >;Justice Clarence Thomas is once again under the spotlight—this time, for a forgiven RV loan. In the nineteen-nineties, a wealthy friend loaned Thomas more than a quarter of a million dollars to purchase a forty-foot motor coach. A Senate inquiry has now found that Thomas&#39;s loan was later forgiven; this discovery raises questions about the ethics of the deal. Over the years, the conduct of Justices appointed by both Democratic and Republican Presidents has been in question, the staff writer &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/jane-mayer&quot;>;Jane Mayer&lt;/a>; explains, “but there is nothing that comes near the magnitude of goodies that have been taken by Clarence Thomas”: if Thomas “were in any other branch of government, he&#39;d never be able to stay in that job.” Senate Democrats on the Judiciary Committee are looking to subpoena three conservative donors and activists tied to gifts and trips involving Supreme Court Justices. Why has the judicial branch been allowed to regulate itself for so long, and who has the responsibility to clean it up? The &lt;em>;New Yorker&lt;/em>; staff writers &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/susan-b-glasser&quot;>;Susan B. Glasser&lt;/a>; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/evan-osnos&quot;>;Evan Osnos&lt;/a>; join &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/jane-mayer&quot;>;Mayer&lt;/a>; to weigh in on how the Supreme Court&#39;s unchecked power has affected American politics.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;lzwzo&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;6oc2sh&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 23:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[My Favorite Restaurants in New York City]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/annals-of-gastronomy/my-favorite-restaurants-in-new-york-city]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651ddc6a9197ccfcbcc4e616/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Forklift_Hanna_final.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;You could write dozens of obituaries a year for beloved New York restaurants that have shuttered their doors. One of the things I love most about this city is how regenerative it is, against all odds. We&#39;re living at a moment when it&#39;s harder than ever to keep a restaurant running, let alone open a new one, yet there are always, improbably, new places to eat—global pandemics and floodwaters be damned. In the past few years, as I ate my way through the boroughs, chronicling meals for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/tables-for-two&quot;>;Tables for Two&lt;/a>;, the delights seemed inexhaustible. I recently transitioned to a new role, which means I&#39;m no longer writing the column every week (though I will still be writing regularly about food for the magazine). As a parting gift to readers, I decided to make a list of my favorite places that I&#39;ve reviewed. It&#39;s s hard to pick, but I&#39;ve found a few thrills to be especially electric. An ancient Jewish lunch counter in the Flatiron district, brought lovingly back to life by new owners and made somehow more essentially itself. A palace of traditional Turkish food in a former pancake house on Staten Island, worth a trip across the Verrazzano Bridge in standstill traffic. A tiny noodle stall buried deep inside a food hall in Koreatown, run by a devoted daughter and her mother, who has a hand in making every plate of food. The best cocktails I&#39;ve ever had—laced with orange-blossom water and dried lime—at a Persian restaurant in Bushwick. Here are twenty New York restaurants, among thousands, that I recommend without reservation.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;My Favorite Restaurants in New York City&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2e573040966bd31a32/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/1200_01_Manhattan.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2e573040966bd31a32/master/w_120,c_limit/1200_01_Manhattan.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2e573040966bd31a32/master/w_240,c_limit/1200_01_Manhattan.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2e573040966bd31a32/master/w_320,c_limit/1200_01_Manhattan.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2e573040966bd31a32/master/w_640,c_limit/1200_01_Manhattan.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2e573040966bd31a32/master/w_960,c_limit/1200_01_Manhattan.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2e573040966bd31a32/master/w_1280,c_limit/1200_01_Manhattan.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2e573040966bd31a32/master/w_1600,c_limit/1200_01_Manhattan.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Two people eat at a table at Superiority Burger.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634bf6fb6ae1a2e91795/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/1_apisukh_superiorityburger_HIRES_WEB.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634bf6fb6ae1a2e91795/master/w_120,c_limit/1_apisukh_superiorityburger_HIRES_WEB.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634bf6fb6ae1a2e91795/master/w_240,c_limit/1_apisukh_superiorityburger_HIRES_WEB.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634bf6fb6ae1a2e91795/master/w_320,c_limit/1_apisukh_superiorityburger_HIRES_WEB.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634bf6fb6ae1a2e91795/master/w_640,c_limit/1_apisukh_superiorityburger_HIRES_WEB.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634bf6fb6ae1a2e91795/master/w_960,c_limit/1_apisukh_superiorityburger_HIRES_WEB.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634bf6fb6ae1a2e91795/master/w_1280,c_limit/1_apisukh_superiorityburger_HIRES_WEB.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634bf6fb6ae1a2e91795/master/w_1600,c_limit/1_apisukh_superiorityburger_HIRES_WEB.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Photograph by Lanna Apisukh for The New Yorker&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;3&quot; >;Superiority Burger&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;em >;Vegetarian&lt;/em>; | &lt;em >;East Village&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Earlier this year, the chef Brooks Headley relocated his previously tiny veggie-burger joint to the relatively sprawling space in the East Village that, for decades, had housed the Odessa Restaurant. The original &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.superiorityburger.com/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.superiorityburger.com/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.superiorityburger.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Superiority Burger&lt;/a>; offered just six dishes, plus specials and desserts. All of it, including the eponymous burger, was vegetarian; a lot was “accidentally vegan.” Everything popped. On recent visits, I was delighted to find that Headley is keeping the focus as tight as ever. New additions are few but powerful. In a nod to Odessa&#39;s Ukrainian heritage, there&#39;s a texturally thrilling stuffed cabbage, filled with sticky rice and oyster and button mushrooms, draped in a sweet-and-sour tomato sauce, and finished with crunchy focaccia bread crumbs. Holdovers from the old menu include the burger, made from quinoa, chickpeas, and walnuts; the Sloppy Dave (tofu chili, frizzled onions); the burnt-broccoli salad (eggplant purée, candied cashews); and the beets with cream cheese and pretzels—all still wonderful. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/06/05/superiority-burger-brooks-headley-restaurant-review&quot;>;&lt;em>;Read the full review »&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A table abundant with food at the Williamsburg restaurant Laser Wolf.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634cd2bfaa5cda472f73/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/2_E9A1914_Final.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634cd2bfaa5cda472f73/master/w_120,c_limit/2_E9A1914_Final.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634cd2bfaa5cda472f73/master/w_240,c_limit/2_E9A1914_Final.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634cd2bfaa5cda472f73/master/w_320,c_limit/2_E9A1914_Final.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634cd2bfaa5cda472f73/master/w_640,c_limit/2_E9A1914_Final.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634cd2bfaa5cda472f73/master/w_960,c_limit/2_E9A1914_Final.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634cd2bfaa5cda472f73/master/w_1280,c_limit/2_E9A1914_Final.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634cd2bfaa5cda472f73/master/w_1600,c_limit/2_E9A1914_Final.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Photograph by Jeremy Liebman for The New Yorker&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;3&quot; >;Laser Wolf&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;em >;Israeli&lt;/em>; | &lt;em >;Williamsburg&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;On a summer evening at &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.laserwolfbrooklyn.com/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.laserwolfbrooklyn.com/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.laserwolfbrooklyn.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Laser Wolf&lt;/a>;, a restaurant on the rooftop of the Hoxton hotel, in Williamsburg, a friendly but authoritative woman zipped dutifully from table to table, pausing at each. “We clap for the sunset,” she announced. “Don&#39;t panic.” For a moment, service seemed to halt. Bodies shifted westward as the collective gaze settled on an unimpeded view of the Manhattan skyline. Phones were drawn. As the gleaming orb sank behind the Con Ed clock tower, blue sky melting into gold, dramatic rays backlighting cotton-ball clouds, applause went up, accompanied by cheers. With a vista like this, food and drink could easily be secondary, not to mention a total ripoff. At Laser Wolf—an outpost of the beloved Philadelphia restaurant of the same name, from the Israeli American chef Michael Solomonov and the restaurateur Steve Cook—it&#39;s the setting that feels negligible. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2022/07/25/at-laser-wolf-dinner-is-even-better-than-the-sunset&quot;>;&lt;em>;Read the full review »&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Dishes of prepared food on a table.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416352f6fb6ae1a2e91797/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/4_Noodletown_Tonje%2520Thilesen_DSC04871.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416352f6fb6ae1a2e91797/master/w_120,c_limit/4_Noodletown_Tonje%20Thilesen_DSC04871.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416352f6fb6ae1a2e91797/master/w_240,c_limit/4_Noodletown_Tonje%20Thilesen_DSC04871.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416352f6fb6ae1a2e91797/master/w_320,c_limit/4_Noodletown_Tonje%20Thilesen_DSC04871.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416352f6fb6ae1a2e91797/master/w_640,c_limit/4_Noodletown_Tonje%20Thilesen_DSC04871.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416352f6fb6ae1a2e91797/master/w_960,c_limit/4_Noodletown_Tonje%20Thilesen_DSC04871.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416352f6fb6ae1a2e91797/master/w_1280,c_limit/4_Noodletown_Tonje%20Thilesen_DSC04871.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416352f6fb6ae1a2e91797/master/w_1600,c_limit/4_Noodletown_Tonje%20Thilesen_DSC04871.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Photograph by Tonje Thilesen for The New Yorker&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;3&quot; >;Great NY Noodletown&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;em >;Cantonese&lt;/em>; | &lt;em >;Chinatown&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;The intensely beloved &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.greatnewyorknoodletown.com/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.greatnewyorknoodletown.com/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.greatnewyorknoodletown.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Cantonese restaurant&lt;/a>; closed for several months in 2022; when the metal gates were finally raised again, last September: rejoicement. The food was as good as—if not better than—anyone remembered. I&#39;d last been there in 2017, when the lo mein with ginger and scallion, a slippery mass of thin, curly noodles, activated taste buds on the back of my tongue that I wouldn&#39;t otherwise know were there. What a pleasure it was to be reunited with that sensation, and to be served a bowl of clear, fragrant broth dense with wontons bobbing like jellyfish, their ruffled bellies stuffed tightly with shrimp, their slippery wrappers trailing like tentacles. Among old favorites I found new ones: thick &lt;em>;e-fu&lt;/em>; noodles strewn over a lobster chopped in its shell; a ceramic crock overflowing with clams, steamed in rice wine with great hunks of ginger and scallion, piled atop glass noodles. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2022/10/17/rejoicing-in-the-return-of-great-ny-noodletown&quot;>;&lt;em>;Read the full review »&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A dish of almond tofu pudding in the shape of a peach.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634c563969e2b7c78a65/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/3_Ju%2520Qi_Ina%2520Jang.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634c563969e2b7c78a65/master/w_120,c_limit/3_Ju%20Qi_Ina%20Jang.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634c563969e2b7c78a65/master/w_240,c_limit/3_Ju%20Qi_Ina%20Jang.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634c563969e2b7c78a65/master/w_320,c_limit/3_Ju%20Qi_Ina%20Jang.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634c563969e2b7c78a65/master/w_640,c_limit/3_Ju%20Qi_Ina%20Jang.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634c563969e2b7c78a65/master/w_960,c_limit/3_Ju%20Qi_Ina%20Jang.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634c563969e2b7c78a65/master/w_1280,c_limit/3_Ju%20Qi_Ina%20Jang.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541634c563969e2b7c78a65/master/w_1600,c_limit/3_Ju%20Qi_Ina%20Jang.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Photograph by Ina Jang for The New Yorker&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;3&quot; >;Ju Qi&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;em >;Beijing Chinese&lt;/em>; | &lt;em >;Flushing&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The most obvious thing to eat at &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.juqiusa.com/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.juqiusa.com/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.juqiusa.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Ju Qi&lt;/a>;, a restaurant in Tangram, a luxury mall in Flushing, is a bird—a whole Peking duck, carved tableside. First, a chef with the precision of a surgeon removes a long strip of lacquered, golden skin, which gets razored into segments the size of postage stamps; each is placed atop a square of steamed bread and finished with a delicate pile of sturgeon caviar. From what looks like a royal jewel chest, a server pulls tiny drawers housing accoutrements—hoisin, scallions, matchsticks of cucumber, pickles, honeydew melon—then demonstrates the optimal technique for wrapping slices of meat and garnishes into bing pancakes, plucked from a bamboo steamer. It&#39;s a thrillingly theatrical experience, with a grand finale: Do you want the carcass hacked into bite-size pieces and crisp-fried, or submerged in a fragrant and savory cloudy soup, with silken tofu and tender greens? I preferred the latter, but both preparations do justice to the precious bits of meat and fat which cling to the bones. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2022/11/14/ju-qi-captures-the-culture-of-beijing&quot;>;&lt;em>;Read the full review »&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Assorted meze from Zara Forest Grill.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541635a4615171c212602f2/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/5_YaelMalka_NewYorker_TableForTwo_ZaraForestGrill_10708%2520copy.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541635a4615171c212602f2/master/w_120,c_limit/5_YaelMalka_NewYorker_TableForTwo_ZaraForestGrill_10708%20copy.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541635a4615171c212602f2/master/w_240,c_limit/5_YaelMalka_NewYorker_TableForTwo_ZaraForestGrill_10708%20copy.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541635a4615171c212602f2/master/w_320,c_limit/5_YaelMalka_NewYorker_TableForTwo_ZaraForestGrill_10708%20copy.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541635a4615171c212602f2/master/w_640,c_limit/5_YaelMalka_NewYorker_TableForTwo_ZaraForestGrill_10708%20copy.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541635a4615171c212602f2/master/w_960,c_limit/5_YaelMalka_NewYorker_TableForTwo_ZaraForestGrill_10708%20copy.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541635a4615171c212602f2/master/w_1280,c_limit/5_YaelMalka_NewYorker_TableForTwo_ZaraForestGrill_10708%20copy.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541635a4615171c212602f2/master/w_1600,c_limit/5_YaelMalka_NewYorker_TableForTwo_ZaraForestGrill_10708%20copy.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Photograph by Yael Malka for The New Yorker&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;3&quot; >;Zara Forest Grill&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;em >;Turkish&lt;/em>; | &lt;em >;Staten Island&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Even in the best circumstances, a trip to Staten Island from any other borough is a commitment, a decent journey by bridge or boat. For &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.zaraforest.com/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.zaraforest.com/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.zaraforest.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Zara Forest Grill&lt;/a>;, in Graniteville, which is closer to New Jersey than Manhattan, it&#39;s a commitment I&#39;m willing to make. For breakfast, there is &lt;em>;gozleme&lt;/em>;, a flaky flatbread folded around potato, spinach and cheese, or ground meat, and &lt;em>;menemen&lt;/em>;, a curdy scramble of eggs, tomatoes, and peppers. Lunch and dinner are best begun with the &lt;em>;balon&lt;/em>; bread, a shiny blimp speckled in sesame seeds which exhales a gust of hot air when you tear off an end, to swipe through meze, such as a luscious labneh hiding crunchy walnuts in its depths, or &lt;em>;aci ezme&lt;/em>;, a coarse and spicy mix of bell peppers, tomatoes, cucumbers, walnuts, parsley, and chili flakes. Standouts among the entrées include the Iskender kebab: glistening shavings of perfectly seasoned lamb gyro are dressed in tomato sauce, piled atop silky yet crispy nubs of “butter-roasted bread,” and served with tangy yogurt. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/06/12/zara-forest-grill-restaurant-review&quot;>;&lt;em>;Read the full review »&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;My Favorite Restaurants in New York City&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2eb41e206869b90d96/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/1200_02_Brooklyn.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2eb41e206869b90d96/master/w_120,c_limit/1200_02_Brooklyn.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2eb41e206869b90d96/master/w_240,c_limit/1200_02_Brooklyn.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2eb41e206869b90d96/master/w_320,c_limit/1200_02_Brooklyn.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2eb41e206869b90d96/master/w_640,c_limit/1200_02_Brooklyn.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2eb41e206869b90d96/master/w_960,c_limit/1200_02_Brooklyn.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2eb41e206869b90d96/master/w_1280,c_limit/1200_02_Brooklyn.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2eb41e206869b90d96/master/w_1600,c_limit/1200_02_Brooklyn.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;monster cake at Thai Diner&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416354b773c4082cdf6206/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/6_Thai%2520Diner_Jutharat%2520Pinyodoonyachet_001.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416354b773c4082cdf6206/master/w_120,c_limit/6_Thai%20Diner_Jutharat%20Pinyodoonyachet_001.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416354b773c4082cdf6206/master/w_240,c_limit/6_Thai%20Diner_Jutharat%20Pinyodoonyachet_001.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416354b773c4082cdf6206/master/w_320,c_limit/6_Thai%20Diner_Jutharat%20Pinyodoonyachet_001.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416354b773c4082cdf6206/master/w_640,c_limit/6_Thai%20Diner_Jutharat%20Pinyodoonyachet_001.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416354b773c4082cdf6206/master/w_960,c_limit/6_Thai%20Diner_Jutharat%20Pinyodoonyachet_001.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416354b773c4082cdf6206/master/w_1280,c_limit/6_Thai%20Diner_Jutharat%20Pinyodoonyachet_001.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416354b773c4082cdf6206/master/w_1600,c_limit/6_Thai%20Diner_Jutharat%20Pinyodoonyachet_001.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Photograph by Jutharat Pinyodoonyachet for The New Yorker&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;3&quot; >;Thai Diner&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;em >;Thai&lt;/em>; | &lt;em >;Nolita&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;jw4ldr&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;The menu at this &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.thaidiner.com/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.thaidiner.com/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.thaidiner.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Nolita restaurant&lt;/a>;, owned by Ann Redding and her husband, Matt Danzer, is partly inspired by the way that Redding&#39;s mother, who emigrated from Thailand, adapted her cooking to the US The Thai disco fries come smothered in massaman curry, red onions, peanuts, and coconut cream; breakfast offerings include spectacular egg sandwiches made with roti snugly folded around a soft scramble, American cheese, Thai basil, and either &lt;em>;sai oua&lt;/em>;—a Northern Thai-style curry-seasoned pork sausage—or avocado and bok choy. Some of the dishes here have been, happily, transplanted from Uncle Boons, the couple&#39;s first, more strictly Thai restaurant, which they were forced to close in 2020. I was especially glad to be reunited with the superlative phat Thai (aka pad Thai), and with a cut-crystal coupe of finely minced peanuts, dried shrimp, raw onion, and ginger, to be wrapped with toasted-coconut sauce in peppery betel leaves. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2021/05/10/the-transportive-thai-diner&quot;>;&lt;em>;Read the full review »&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A person eats an overflowing plate of chicken and fries while another eats a salad.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541637085a119a1d75e5aa0/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/7_Gertrude_Rana%2520Duzyol_0991.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541637085a119a1d75e5aa0/master/w_120,c_limit/7_Gertrude_Rana%20Duzyol_0991.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541637085a119a1d75e5aa0/master/w_240,c_limit/7_Gertrude_Rana%20Duzyol_0991.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541637085a119a1d75e5aa0/master/w_320,c_limit/7_Gertrude_Rana%20Duzyol_0991.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541637085a119a1d75e5aa0/master/w_640,c_limit/7_Gertrude_Rana%20Duzyol_0991.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541637085a119a1d75e5aa0/master/w_960,c_limit/7_Gertrude_Rana%20Duzyol_0991.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541637085a119a1d75e5aa0/master/w_1280,c_limit/7_Gertrude_Rana%20Duzyol_0991.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541637085a119a1d75e5aa0/master/w_1600,c_limit/7_Gertrude_Rana%20Duzyol_0991.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Photograph by Rana Duzyol for The New Yorker&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;3&quot; >;gertrude&#39;s&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;em >;Jewish American&lt;/em>; | &lt;em >;Prospect Heights&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;The restaurateurs behind &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.gertrudes.nyc/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.gertrudes.nyc/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.gertrudes.nyc/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;gertrude&#39;s&lt;/a>;, a bistro in Prospect Heights, pulled inspiration from New York institutions such as Prune, Diner, and Minetta Tavern, as well as from their own backgrounds. “We talked about a menu that, if you had grown up eating specific dishes at your grandparents&#39; house on specific Jewish holidays, would seem really nostalgic and familiar to you,” Eli Sussman, one of the owners, said. “And, conversely, would be appealing even if you had no interest in Jewish cuisine.” The result transcends expectations you might have for a neighborhood restaurant while also resisting gimmickry. The half chicken is brined, cleverly, in dill-pickle juice before it&#39;s roasted. The excellent hamburger is sandwiched on a tall, shiny braided challah roll, which can also be ordered on its own, with a schmear of duck butter. All entrées, including a beautiful whole trout—stuffed with lemon rounds and showered with chopped green olives and herbs—come with a choice of fries, greens, or latkes. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/09/11/burgers-with-latkes-and-a-seder-plate-margarita-at-gertrudes&quot;>;&lt;em>;Read the full review »&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Two people hold bowls of Noona Noodles ramen.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416363f6fb6ae1a2e9179b/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/8_Noona%2520Noodles_Heami%2520Lee_003.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416363f6fb6ae1a2e9179b/master/w_120,c_limit/8_Noona%20Noodles_Heami%20Lee_003.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416363f6fb6ae1a2e9179b/master/w_240,c_limit/8_Noona%20Noodles_Heami%20Lee_003.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416363f6fb6ae1a2e9179b/master/w_320,c_limit/8_Noona%20Noodles_Heami%20Lee_003.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416363f6fb6ae1a2e9179b/master/w_640,c_limit/8_Noona%20Noodles_Heami%20Lee_003.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416363f6fb6ae1a2e9179b/master/w_960,c_limit/8_Noona%20Noodles_Heami%20Lee_003.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416363f6fb6ae1a2e9179b/master/w_1280,c_limit/8_Noona%20Noodles_Heami%20Lee_003.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416363f6fb6ae1a2e9179b/master/w_1600,c_limit/8_Noona%20Noodles_Heami%20Lee_003.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Photograph by Jutharat Pinyodoonyachet for The New Yorker&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;3&quot; >;Noona Noodles&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;em >;Korean&lt;/em>; | &lt;em >;Koreatown&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;p8g61&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;I can think of no better summer meal than a bowl of &lt;em>;naengmyeon&lt;/em>;, a cold Korean noodle soup traditionally eaten after a meal of barbecue. &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.noonanoodles.com/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.noonanoodles.com/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.noonanoodles.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Noona Noodles&lt;/a>;, a stall run by a mother-daughter duo in a food court in Manhattan&#39;s Koreatown, offers two varieties: &lt;em>;mul&lt;/em>; and &lt;em>;bibim&lt;/em>;, rebranded as Icy and Icy Spicy. Both feature an intensely flavorful broth, made by boiling brisket with fresh pineapple, Asian pear, apple, lemon, daikon, and assorted alliums, and are finished with big hunks of slushy ice, which soak up the sweet, sour, savory liquid like snow cones. In the center of each bowl is a pile of skinny, chewy, glassy noodles, plus lightly pickled daikon, cucumber, and a couple slices of brisket. The Icy Spicy also includes a thick layer of gochujang, to be stirred in; the Icy, which contains more broth, comes with pink vinegar (left over from pickling radishes) and hot mustard, for adding a subtler kick. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/05/29/noona-noodles-restaurant-review&quot;>;&lt;em>;Read the full review »&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Man eating a sandwich in a booth at a restaurant.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416365b773c4082cdf6208/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/9_S&amp;amp;P_Cole%2520Wilson_223.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416365b773c4082cdf6208/master/w_120,c_limit/9_S&amp;amp;P_Cole%20Wilson_223.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416365b773c4082cdf6208/master/w_240,c_limit/9_S&amp;amp;P_Cole%20Wilson_223.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416365b773c4082cdf6208/master/w_320,c_limit/9_S&amp;amp;P_Cole%20Wilson_223.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416365b773c4082cdf6208/master/w_640,c_limit/9_S&amp;amp;P_Cole%20Wilson_223.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416365b773c4082cdf6208/master/w_960,c_limit/9_S&amp;amp;P_Cole%20Wilson_223.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416365b773c4082cdf6208/master/w_1280,c_limit/9_S&amp;amp;P_Cole%20Wilson_223.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416365b773c4082cdf6208/master/w_1600,c_limit/9_S&amp;amp;P_Cole%20Wilson_223.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Photograph by Cole Wilson for The New Yorker&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;3&quot; >;S&amp;amp;P Lunch&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;em >;Diner&lt;/em>; | &lt;em >;Flatiron&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Eric Finkelstein and Matt Ross, the sandwich experts and playful nostalgists behind Court Street Grocers and the HiHi Room, have taken over &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.sandwich.place/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.sandwich.place/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.sandwich.place/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;the restaurant&lt;/a>; formerly known as Eisenberg&#39;s, a Jewish-style lunch counter near the Flatiron Building, and proved themselves to be gifted preservationists as well as savvy restaurateurs. The menu has been pared down, but it still feels encyclopedic in the tradition of a short-order diner, featuring roughly three dozen sandwiches, including hamburgers. The classics have not been updated so much as painstakingly honed. “It&#39;s like, in your brain, when you eat something, what you want it to taste like,” Ross told me. “That&#39;s our goal.” Some of my happiest moments of late have been spent marvelling at the glory of dishes I&#39;d taken for granted: a ripe half cantaloupe filled with cottage cheese, a bowl of iceberg lettuce topped with egg salad, cream cheese and chopped green olives (a surprisingly thrilling combination) on squishy white bread. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2022/11/21/playful-nostalgia-and-honed-classics-at-sp-lunch&quot;>;&lt;em>;Read the full review »&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Pintxo matrimonio plated at Ernesto&amp;#x27;s.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541635c082d4e92078a8c5f/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/10_Ernesto&amp;#x27;s_Tonje%2520Thilesen_DSC01372.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541635c082d4e92078a8c5f/master/w_120,c_limit/10_Ernesto&amp;#x27;s_Tonje%20Thilesen_DSC01372.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541635c082d4e92078a8c5f/master/w_240,c_limit/10_Ernesto&amp;#x27;s_Tonje%20Thilesen_DSC01372.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541635c082d4e92078a8c5f/master/w_320,c_limit/10_Ernesto&amp;#x27;s_Tonje%20Thilesen_DSC01372.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541635c082d4e92078a8c5f/master/w_640,c_limit/10_Ernesto&amp;#x27;s_Tonje%20Thilesen_DSC01372.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541635c082d4e92078a8c5f/master/w_960,c_limit/10_Ernesto&amp;#x27;s_Tonje%20Thilesen_DSC01372.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541635c082d4e92078a8c5f/master/w_1280,c_limit/10_Ernesto&amp;#x27;s_Tonje%20Thilesen_DSC01372.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541635c082d4e92078a8c5f/master/w_1600,c_limit/10_Ernesto&amp;#x27;s_Tonje%20Thilesen_DSC01372.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Photograph by Tonje Thilesen for The New Yorker&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;3&quot; >;Ernesto&#39;s&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;em >;Basque&lt;/em>; | &lt;em >;Lower East Side&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;vpi3e&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;If anyone objects to the union of two types of anchovies in the &lt;em>;pintxo matrimonio al ajillo&lt;/em>; at &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.ernestosnyc.com/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.ernestosnyc.com/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ernestosnyc.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Ernesto&#39;s&lt;/a>;, a Basque-leaning restaurant on the Lower East Side, speak now and I will eat yours for you. The matrimony of a &lt;em>;boqueron&lt;/em>; (plump, meaty, and white, pickled in wine vinegar and olive oil) and an &lt;em>;anchoa&lt;/em>; (a dark, skinny, salt-cured umami bomb) is holy indeed, made holier by the kitchen&#39;s decision to mount the pair, like prostrate wedding-cake toppers, on a rectangle of delicately crisp, buttery pastry. Though the fillets are separated by a neat line of &lt;em>;ajillo&lt;/em>;, a zingy condiment of parsley and garlic, each bite brings them together in perfect harmony. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2022/04/11/the-romantic-basque-leaning-food-of-ernestos&quot;>;&lt;em>;Read the full review »&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;My Favorite Restaurants in New York City&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2e573040966bd31a31/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/1200_03_Bronx.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2e573040966bd31a31/master/w_120,c_limit/1200_03_Bronx.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2e573040966bd31a31/master/w_240,c_limit/1200_03_Bronx.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2e573040966bd31a31/master/w_320,c_limit/1200_03_Bronx.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2e573040966bd31a31/master/w_640,c_limit/1200_03_Bronx.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2e573040966bd31a31/master/w_960,c_limit/1200_03_Bronx.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2e573040966bd31a31/master/w_1280,c_limit/1200_03_Bronx.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2e573040966bd31a31/master/w_1600,c_limit/1200_03_Bronx.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Several small Indian food dishes displayed along a wood counter.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361d2bfaa5cda472f77/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/11_Dhamaka_Heami%2520Lee_092.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361d2bfaa5cda472f77/master/w_120,c_limit/11_Dhamaka_Heami%20Lee_092.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361d2bfaa5cda472f77/master/w_240,c_limit/11_Dhamaka_Heami%20Lee_092.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361d2bfaa5cda472f77/master/w_320,c_limit/11_Dhamaka_Heami%20Lee_092.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361d2bfaa5cda472f77/master/w_640,c_limit/11_Dhamaka_Heami%20Lee_092.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361d2bfaa5cda472f77/master/w_960,c_limit/11_Dhamaka_Heami%20Lee_092.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361d2bfaa5cda472f77/master/w_1280,c_limit/11_Dhamaka_Heami%20Lee_092.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361d2bfaa5cda472f77/master/w_1600,c_limit/11_Dhamaka_Heami%20Lee_092.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Photograph by Heami Lee for The New Yorker&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;3&quot; >;Dhamaka&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;em >;Indian&lt;/em>; | &lt;em >;Lower East Side&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;At &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.dhamaka.nyc/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.dhamaka.nyc/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.dhamaka.nyc/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Dhamaka&lt;/a>;, an Indian restaurant in Essex Market, on the Lower East Side, my dining companions and I took turns dragging our spoons through a hot metal pot of &lt;em>;gurda kapoora&lt;/em>;, searching for offal. Which morsels, we wondered, were the goat kidneys and which were the goat testicles? The one male in our group joked that, as the only person among us in possession of both organs, he was uniquely qualified to tell. He had eaten a lot of kidney as a child in Russia, and recognized it to be the firmer of the two organs—it was almost bouncy in texture, with a pronounced flavor that bloomed slowly and grew funkier. I preferred the testicle, meaty but mild, as supple as sweetbread, nearly spreadable. The vehicle for both was an outstanding gravy—built from a base of gelatinous lamb-trotter stock, fragrant and fiery with whole cardamom pods and green chilies, thick with melted tomato—to be spooned atop buttery, griddled halves of &lt;em>;pao&lt;/em>;, a fluffy slider-size roll introduced to India during the Portuguese occupation of Goa. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2021/07/05/learning-to-love-goat-kidneys-and-testicles-at-dhamaka&quot;>;&lt;em>;Read the full review »&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A person holds at plate of food at Mitica.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361f6fb6ae1a2e91799/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/12_Mitica_Jeremy%2520Liebman_G8A6745.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361f6fb6ae1a2e91799/master/w_120,c_limit/12_Mitica_Jeremy%20Liebman_G8A6745.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361f6fb6ae1a2e91799/master/w_240,c_limit/12_Mitica_Jeremy%20Liebman_G8A6745.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361f6fb6ae1a2e91799/master/w_320,c_limit/12_Mitica_Jeremy%20Liebman_G8A6745.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361f6fb6ae1a2e91799/master/w_640,c_limit/12_Mitica_Jeremy%20Liebman_G8A6745.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361f6fb6ae1a2e91799/master/w_960,c_limit/12_Mitica_Jeremy%20Liebman_G8A6745.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361f6fb6ae1a2e91799/master/w_1280,c_limit/12_Mitica_Jeremy%20Liebman_G8A6745.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361f6fb6ae1a2e91799/master/w_1600,c_limit/12_Mitica_Jeremy%20Liebman_G8A6745.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Photograph by Jeremy Liebman for The New Yorker&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;3&quot; >;Mitica&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;em >;Mexican&lt;/em>; | &lt;em >;Greenpoint&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;gy0np8&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;The menu at Mitica, an unassuming Mexican restaurant in Greenpoint, is small enough that I ate through it in just two visits, and found nary a misstep. The guacamole is as unexpectedly, beguilingly luscious as the version at Atla, the upscale NoHo cantina, where one of Mitica&#39;s chefs, Edgar Gonzalez, once worked. Meanwhile, fresh tortillas, still steaming, make for an embarrassment of riches when served with a perfectly cooked fillet of steelhead trout (topped with aioli, smoked and fresh fennel, crispy potatoes, and serrano chili) and with a beautiful rib eye, charred, carved into rosy slices, and finished with a sweet-and-sour pasilla-chili demi-glace, melty whole spring onions, and greens that have wilted in the heat of the meat. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/07/03/the-unassuming-exceptional-food-of-mitica&quot;>;&lt;em>;Read the full review »&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A coffee and a pastry on two tables.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361d2bfaa5cda472f76/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/13_Golden%2520Diner_Heami%2520Lee_r35197.jpeg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361d2bfaa5cda472f76/master/w_120,c_limit/13_Golden%20Diner_Heami%20Lee_r35197.jpeg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361d2bfaa5cda472f76/master/w_240,c_limit/13_Golden%20Diner_Heami%20Lee_r35197.jpeg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361d2bfaa5cda472f76/master/w_320,c_limit/13_Golden%20Diner_Heami%20Lee_r35197.jpeg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361d2bfaa5cda472f76/master/w_640,c_limit/13_Golden%20Diner_Heami%20Lee_r35197.jpeg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361d2bfaa5cda472f76/master/w_960,c_limit/13_Golden%20Diner_Heami%20Lee_r35197.jpeg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361d2bfaa5cda472f76/master/w_1280,c_limit/13_Golden%20Diner_Heami%20Lee_r35197.jpeg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416361d2bfaa5cda472f76/master/w_1600,c_limit/13_Golden%20Diner_Heami%20Lee_r35197.jpeg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Photograph by Heami Lee for The New Yorker&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;3&quot; >;Golden Diner&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;em >;Diner&lt;/em>; | &lt;em >;Lower East Side&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.goldendinerny.com/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.goldendinerny.com/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.goldendinerny.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Golden Diner&lt;/a>;, a Lower East Side greasy spoon that opened in 2019, is not a trendy restaurant posturing as a diner for the sake of nostalgia. It&#39;s a genuine catchall, in the mode of its forebears, but better. The matzo-ball soup is plainly excellent, no bells or whistles. Two eggs are indeed served, as the menu promises, “How you want &#39;em,” scrambled, fried, or folded into an omelette, and plated with a superlative crackly edged hash-brown patty rough-chopped into bite-size pieces. Just like at your local Athenian, you can order half a grapefruit; a side of bacon; a Diet Coke. Coffee refills are free. Unlike your local Athenian, Golden Diner tops its enormous, fluffy pancakes with salted honey-maple butter instead of syrup, in homage to a popular South Korean potato-chip flavor. Its chef, the Momofuku Ko alum Samuel Yoo, is Korean American and grew up in Bayside, Queens. Like a formal poet, he finds creativity within constraints, telling an enchantingly personal story without ever quite coloring outside the lines. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2019/10/28/golden-diner-updates-the-greasy-spoon-tradition&quot;>;&lt;em>;Read the full review »&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;The Cha Siu McRib called McBonnies&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654163674a5ba2f5ff919802/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/14_Bonnie_Kyoko%2520Hamada_086.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654163674a5ba2f5ff919802/master/w_120,c_limit/14_Bonnie_Kyoko%20Hamada_086.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654163674a5ba2f5ff919802/master/w_240,c_limit/14_Bonnie_Kyoko%20Hamada_086.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654163674a5ba2f5ff919802/master/w_320,c_limit/14_Bonnie_Kyoko%20Hamada_086.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654163674a5ba2f5ff919802/master/w_640,c_limit/14_Bonnie_Kyoko%20Hamada_086.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654163674a5ba2f5ff919802/master/w_960,c_limit/14_Bonnie_Kyoko%20Hamada_086.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654163674a5ba2f5ff919802/master/w_1280,c_limit/14_Bonnie_Kyoko%20Hamada_086.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654163674a5ba2f5ff919802/master/w_1600,c_limit/14_Bonnie_Kyoko%20Hamada_086.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Photograph by Kyoko Hamada for The New Yorker&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;3&quot; >;Bonnie&#39;s&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;em >;Cantonese&lt;/em>; | &lt;em >;Williamsburg&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;b3inek&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;At &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.bonniesbrooklyn.com/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.bonniesbrooklyn.com/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.bonniesbrooklyn.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Bonnie&#39;s&lt;/a>;, a Cantonese restaurant in Williamsburg, the poached half chicken, Bak Cheet Gai, comes with teacups of Gai Tong, or chicken broth, redolent of ginger and white pepper. “Sip it as you eat or dunk it to take away the chill,” my server suggested. “I love this liquid!” my dining companion announced as she sipped. I loved this liquid, too; on another evening I ordered a whole teapot of it. I used it as a palate cleanser between bites of long beans—delightfully sweet and shrivelled, positively clanging with garlic, and topped with croutons made from a kind of savory cruller often served with congee—and bites of scorching-hot Cheung Fun, seared rolled rice noodles that were sticky on the outside and custardy within, the concentrated fishiness of XO sauce (from dried scallops and shrimp) punctuated by notes of fennel seed. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2022/06/27/at-bonnies-msg-is-wielded-with-nuanced-artistry&quot;>;&lt;em>;Read the full review »&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Takeout containers and vegetables on table.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636895e3758c86ae286d/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/15_Jalsa_Kyoko%2520Hamada_r36237.jpeg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636895e3758c86ae286d/master/w_120,c_limit/15_Jalsa_Kyoko%20Hamada_r36237.jpeg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636895e3758c86ae286d/master/w_240,c_limit/15_Jalsa_Kyoko%20Hamada_r36237.jpeg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636895e3758c86ae286d/master/w_320,c_limit/15_Jalsa_Kyoko%20Hamada_r36237.jpeg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636895e3758c86ae286d/master/w_640,c_limit/15_Jalsa_Kyoko%20Hamada_r36237.jpeg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636895e3758c86ae286d/master/w_960,c_limit/15_Jalsa_Kyoko%20Hamada_r36237.jpeg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636895e3758c86ae286d/master/w_1280,c_limit/15_Jalsa_Kyoko%20Hamada_r36237.jpeg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636895e3758c86ae286d/master/w_1600,c_limit/15_Jalsa_Kyoko%20Hamada_r36237.jpeg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Photograph by Kyoko Hamada for The New Yorker&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;3&quot; >;Jalsa&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;em >;Indian&lt;/em>; | &lt;em >;Flatbush&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;“I&#39;m a chaat person,” Nowshin Ali explained, when we talked over FaceTime at the beginning of the pandemic. We were discussing the menu at &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.jalsagrill.com/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.jalsagrill.com/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.jalsagrill.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Jalsa Grill &amp;amp; Gravy&lt;/a>;, the restaurant she co-owns with her business partner, Anurag Shrivastava, in Brooklyn&#39;s Little Pakistan, south of Prospect Park. Chaats, a signature dish of Lucknow, Ali&#39;s home town, are defined on Jalsa&#39;s menu as well as I&#39;ve ever seen: “crispy-crunchy-spicy-tangy Indian snacks.” In India, they&#39;re often sold on the street; in the US, they&#39;re treated like appetizers. Was I a chaat person before I tried Jalsa&#39;s iterations? I&#39;d always enjoyed them, but I don&#39;t remember ever crowing in pleasure the way I did after taking a bite of Shrivastava&#39;s palak chaat: a pile of spinach—lightly battered in chickpea flour, warm yet nearly raw, bright green and refreshing—tossed with glossy tamarind sauce, house-made chaat masala, crispy shards of lentil noodle, onion, tomato, and cilantro. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2020/04/20/an-indian-restaurant-in-little-pakistan-feeds-its-neighbors&quot;>;&lt;em>;Read the full review »&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;My Favorite Restaurants in New York City&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2fc0cfacaf9a88b4d0/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/1200_04_Queens.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2fc0cfacaf9a88b4d0/master/w_120,c_limit/1200_04_Queens.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2fc0cfacaf9a88b4d0/master/w_240,c_limit/1200_04_Queens.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2fc0cfacaf9a88b4d0/master/w_320,c_limit/1200_04_Queens.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2fc0cfacaf9a88b4d0/master/w_640,c_limit/1200_04_Queens.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2fc0cfacaf9a88b4d0/master/w_960,c_limit/1200_04_Queens.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2fc0cfacaf9a88b4d0/master/w_1280,c_limit/1200_04_Queens.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2fc0cfacaf9a88b4d0/master/w_1600,c_limit/1200_04_Queens.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Chef Kwame Onwuachi at Tatiana&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636a4b957cead1177913/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/16_Tatiana_Zachary%2520Zavislak.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636a4b957cead1177913/master/w_120,c_limit/16_Tatiana_Zachary%20Zavislak.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636a4b957cead1177913/master/w_240,c_limit/16_Tatiana_Zachary%20Zavislak.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636a4b957cead1177913/master/w_320,c_limit/16_Tatiana_Zachary%20Zavislak.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636a4b957cead1177913/master/w_640,c_limit/16_Tatiana_Zachary%20Zavislak.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636a4b957cead1177913/master/w_960,c_limit/16_Tatiana_Zachary%20Zavislak.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636a4b957cead1177913/master/w_1280,c_limit/16_Tatiana_Zachary%20Zavislak.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636a4b957cead1177913/master/w_1600,c_limit/16_Tatiana_Zachary%20Zavislak.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Photograph by Zachary Zavislak for The New Yorker&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;3&quot; >;Tatiana&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;em >;Afro-Caribbean&lt;/em>; | &lt;em >;Lincoln Square&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;b76rh4&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;In recent years, the fairly staid and hallowed institution of Lincoln Center has done its best to evolve. &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.tatiananyc.com/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.tatiananyc.com/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.tatiananyc.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Tatiana&lt;/a>;, Kwame Onwuachi&#39;s restaurant in the reopened David Geffen Hall, is a triumph in staying relevant while fitting into the broad category of performing arts: all restaurants are theatrical, of course, but eating here is like watching &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/10/09/kwame-onwuachis-cuisine-of-the-self&quot;>;Onwuachi&lt;/a>; deliver a controlled and electric autobiographical monologue. The menu traces a childhood spent in the Bronx and in Nigeria and a career that began in the galley of an oil-spill-response vessel off the coast of Louisiana (his mother&#39;s home state) before leading him to the Culinary Institute of America and then to Per Se, Eleven Madison Park, and the TV show “Top Chef.” The most obvious showpiece is the short-rib pastrami &lt;em>;suya&lt;/em>;, a single, hefty blackened rib, seasoned at the intersection of Jewish deli and northern-Nigerian barbecue, accompanied by caraway-coconut Parker House rolls. I preferred an abundant bowl of braised oxtails, as large and beefy as I&#39;ve ever seen, served with Thumbelina carrots, chayote squash, and rice and peas. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/01/16/kwame-onwuachis-electric-tatiana-at-lincoln-center&quot;>;&lt;em>;Read the full review »&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;The vibe at Place des Fêtes&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636c4a5ba2f5ff919804/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/17_PlaceDesFetes_MengwenCao_001.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636c4a5ba2f5ff919804/master/w_120,c_limit/17_PlaceDesFetes_MengwenCao_001.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636c4a5ba2f5ff919804/master/w_240,c_limit/17_PlaceDesFetes_MengwenCao_001.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636c4a5ba2f5ff919804/master/w_320,c_limit/17_PlaceDesFetes_MengwenCao_001.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636c4a5ba2f5ff919804/master/w_640,c_limit/17_PlaceDesFetes_MengwenCao_001.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636c4a5ba2f5ff919804/master/w_960,c_limit/17_PlaceDesFetes_MengwenCao_001.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636c4a5ba2f5ff919804/master/w_1280,c_limit/17_PlaceDesFetes_MengwenCao_001.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636c4a5ba2f5ff919804/master/w_1600,c_limit/17_PlaceDesFetes_MengwenCao_001.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Photograph by Mengwen Cao for The New Yorker&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;3&quot; >;Place des Fêtes&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;em >;Wine Bar&lt;/em>; | &lt;em >;Clinton Hill&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.pdfnyc.com/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.pdfnyc.com/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.pdfnyc.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Place des Fêtes&lt;/a>;, the name of a plaza in the Nineteenth Arrondissement of Paris, translates to “party square.” Place des Fêtes, a wine bar and restaurant in Clinton Hill, with its buttery leather stools and whitewashed brick walls, would be perfect for a first date. The kitchen—overseen by the chef and co-owner Nico Russell, known previously for Oxalis, in Crown Heights—can make magic with whatever the season, or the pantry, presents. Fingerling potatoes, grilled low and slow until their skins turned thick and crisp and separated from their velvety flesh, smacked of a campfire, except for a luscious green gloss of savory sabayon. A plate of four skinny Don Bocarte anchovy fillets in olive oil, imported from Spain, seemed austere, but proved beguilingly unctuous. My favorite of the cocktails was also the lowest ABV, the Vermut and Soda, which the bartender accurately described as “almost like a Dr. Pepper,” though it&#39;s not nearly as sweet, and imparts the barest impression of smoke. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2022/07/04/making-magic-at-place-des-fetes&quot;>;&lt;em>;Read the full review »&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A plate of oysters at Chez Ma Tante&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636a4615171c212602f4/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/18_Chez%2520Ma%2520Tante_David%2520Williams_180312_r31629.jpeg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636a4615171c212602f4/master/w_120,c_limit/18_Chez%20Ma%20Tante_David%20Williams_180312_r31629.jpeg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636a4615171c212602f4/master/w_240,c_limit/18_Chez%20Ma%20Tante_David%20Williams_180312_r31629.jpeg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636a4615171c212602f4/master/w_320,c_limit/18_Chez%20Ma%20Tante_David%20Williams_180312_r31629.jpeg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636a4615171c212602f4/master/w_640,c_limit/18_Chez%20Ma%20Tante_David%20Williams_180312_r31629.jpeg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636a4615171c212602f4/master/w_960,c_limit/18_Chez%20Ma%20Tante_David%20Williams_180312_r31629.jpeg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636a4615171c212602f4/master/w_1280,c_limit/18_Chez%20Ma%20Tante_David%20Williams_180312_r31629.jpeg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636a4615171c212602f4/master/w_1600,c_limit/18_Chez%20Ma%20Tante_David%20Williams_180312_r31629.jpeg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Photograph by David Williams for The New Yorker&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;3&quot; >;Chez Ma Tante&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;em >;European&lt;/em>; | &lt;em >;Greenpoint&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;ihiue8&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://chezmatantebk.com/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://chezmatantebk.com/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://chezmatantebk.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Chez Ma Tante&lt;/a>;, in Greenpoint, doesn&#39;t bill itself as Québécois or even Canadian, but it strikes me as a restaurant made in the image of Montreal&#39;s dining scene. Its name, which translates to “At My Aunt&#39;s House,” comes from a beloved hot-dog stand in Montreal, and one of the two owners, the chef Aidan O&#39;Neal, spent time cooking there and at M. Wells, a Québécois bistro in Long Island City. The short menu shifts from season to season. When I visited, the chicken-liver pâté, whipped to the consistency of butter, was as nutty and pungent as an aged cheddar. Also excellent was the kedgeree, an Anglo-Indian classic, here featuring slippery flakes of poached cod and chopped egg nestled in delicately curried rice, all topped with a tousled salad of parsley, celery, and thinly sliced sweet onion. And a French fry is a French fry until you&#39;ve had the ones at Chez Ma Tante: enormous, creamy wedges of russet potatoes wearing crispy bronze armor that cracks easily between the teeth but holds up beautifully to thick, glassy, intensely garlicky aioli. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2018/03/12/an-unmistakable-taste-of-montreal-at-chez-ma-tante&quot;>;&lt;em>;Read the full review »&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;One person passes a dish to another person over a table of plates.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416372082d4e92078a8c61/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/19_Torrisi_Caroline%2520Tompkins_0089.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416372082d4e92078a8c61/master/w_120,c_limit/19_Torrisi_Caroline%20Tompkins_0089.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416372082d4e92078a8c61/master/w_240,c_limit/19_Torrisi_Caroline%20Tompkins_0089.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416372082d4e92078a8c61/master/w_320,c_limit/19_Torrisi_Caroline%20Tompkins_0089.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416372082d4e92078a8c61/master/w_640,c_limit/19_Torrisi_Caroline%20Tompkins_0089.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416372082d4e92078a8c61/master/w_960,c_limit/19_Torrisi_Caroline%20Tompkins_0089.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416372082d4e92078a8c61/master/w_1280,c_limit/19_Torrisi_Caroline%20Tompkins_0089.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65416372082d4e92078a8c61/master/w_1600,c_limit/19_Torrisi_Caroline%20Tompkins_0089.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Photograph by Caroline Tompkins for The New Yorker&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;3&quot; >;Torrisi&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;em >;Italian American&lt;/em>; | &lt;em >;Nolita&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Are we living in a Roaring Twenties redux, as was predicted when the pandemic began to wane? At the recently revived &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.torrisinyc.com/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.torrisinyc.com/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.torrisinyc.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Torrisi&lt;/a>;, in Nolita&#39;s historic Puck Building, a woman wearing a flapper headband was a bit too on the nose for my taste, but the restaurant does suggest a return to a brand of extraordinary lavishness that dissipated as the virus spread. Salt-cured ham, sliced in translucent sheets from enormous haunches displayed near the host stand, was served with a pyramid of crisp golden zeppole and pineapple mostarda. A special called Capellini Cantonese, featuring glossy angel hair tangled with garlic and jalapeño, was crowned with half of the most perfectly cooked lobster I&#39;ve ever had. My favorite course was the most inherently excessive: dessert. The staff pushes, rightly, the affogato, a coupe layered sexily with espresso granita, vanilla ice cream, mascarpone mousse, and hot fudge. But nothing beat the “frozen yogurt”: half a grapefruit hollowed out and filled with absurdly creamy, tart soft-serve, swirled with grapefruit-Campari jam and a grassy, green olive oil, accompanied by a tiny tureen of extra jam—a marvel of both luxury and restraint. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/05/08/torrisi-bar-and-restaurant-review&quot;>;&lt;em>;Read the full review »&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A photograph of five colorful cocktails in a line against an olivegreen curtain.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636f4a5ba2f5ff919806/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/20_Eyval_Cole%2520Wilson.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636f4a5ba2f5ff919806/master/w_120,c_limit/20_Eyval_Cole%20Wilson.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636f4a5ba2f5ff919806/master/w_240,c_limit/20_Eyval_Cole%20Wilson.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636f4a5ba2f5ff919806/master/w_320,c_limit/20_Eyval_Cole%20Wilson.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636f4a5ba2f5ff919806/master/w_640,c_limit/20_Eyval_Cole%20Wilson.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636f4a5ba2f5ff919806/master/w_960,c_limit/20_Eyval_Cole%20Wilson.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636f4a5ba2f5ff919806/master/w_1280,c_limit/20_Eyval_Cole%20Wilson.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6541636f4a5ba2f5ff919806/master/w_1600,c_limit/20_Eyval_Cole%20Wilson.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Photograph by Cole Wilson for The New Yorker&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;3&quot; >;Eyval&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;em >;Persian&lt;/em>; | &lt;em >;Bushwick&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;At this Persian restaurant in Bushwick, I couldn&#39;t help but steal sips of a friend&#39;s orange-blossom Negroni, a cold and viscous concoction that lingered on my tongue and in my memory (I can taste it now!). I&#39;m happy to report that the dynamite drinks portended dynamite food. &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.eyvalnyc.com/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.eyvalnyc.com/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.eyvalnyc.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Eyval&lt;/a>; was opened by Ali Saboor, a former chef at Sofreh—the other best Persian restaurant in Brooklyn. Saboor&#39;s &lt;em>;ghormeh sabzi&lt;/em>; is a particular showstopper, a braised veal shank (don&#39;t forget to check the bone for marrow) crowned with a crisp disk of herbed-rice &lt;em>;tahdig&lt;/em>; and rising regally from a rich stew of tender kidney beans and melty greens and alliums, including parsley, spinach, and leeks, plus fenugreek and &lt;em>;limoo amani&lt;/em>; (dried lime). Plucking out a puckered leathery lime and eating it whole, sticky and sour, left me feeling as lucky as if I&#39;d found the baby in a king cake. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/03/13/dynamite-persian-food-at-eyval&quot;>;&lt;em>;Read the full review »&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;My Favorite Restaurants in New York City&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2f573040966bd31a34/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/1200_05_Closer.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2f573040966bd31a34/master/w_120,c_limit/1200_05_Closer.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2f573040966bd31a34/master/w_240,c_limit/1200_05_Closer.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2f573040966bd31a34/master/w_320,c_limit/1200_05_Closer.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2f573040966bd31a34/master/w_640,c_limit/1200_05_Closer.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2f573040966bd31a34/master/w_960,c_limit/1200_05_Closer.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2f573040966bd31a34/master/w_1280,c_limit/1200_05_Closer.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651dda2f573040966bd31a34/master/w_1600,c_limit/1200_05_Closer.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 19:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Jezebel and the Question of Women’s Anger]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-weekend-essay/jezebel-and-the-question-of-womens-anger]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65454e08cc8a3bfef6f31041/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Holmes_Internet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Earlier this year, Ben Smith, the former editor-in-chief of BuzzFeed News and a onetime New York &lt;em>;Times&lt;/em>; columnist, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/05/15/traffic-ben-smith-book-review&quot;>;published&lt;/a>; a book, titled “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Traffic-Genius-Rivalry-Delusion-Billion-Dollar/dp/0593299752&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Traffic-Genius-Rivalry-Delusion-Billion-Dollar/dp/0593299752&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Traffic-Genius-Rivalry-Delusion-Billion-Dollar/dp/0593299752&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Traffic: Genius, Rivalry, and Delusion in the Billion-Dollar Race to Go Viral&lt;/a>;.” It explores the creation of, and the competition between, well-funded news-and-culture Web sites—BuzzFeed News and the Huffington Post among them—that began in the early two-thousands, just as the professional blogosphere was getting going. One day after the book&#39;s May 2nd release, the &lt;em>;Times&lt;/em>; published a Smith-authored &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2023/05/03/opinion/jezebel-gawker-buzzfeed-ben-smith.html&quot;>;guest essay&lt;/a>;, titled “We&#39;re Watching the End of a Digital Media Age. It All Started with Jezebel.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Jezebel is an influential feminist Web site that I created in 2007. Smith had devoted an entire chapter of “Traffic” to the story of the site&#39;s creation, stumbles, and successes. He was complimentary, calling it “a new kind of cultural politics,” one that built “a community that rejected the old structures of gender and power, and tried to shape new ones.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;One could be forgiven for discerning a slight difference in tone between “Traffic” and the essay that appeared in the &lt;em>;Times&lt;/em>;. Smith&#39;s book took a deep look at the impact of a number of Web sites, but his &lt;em>;Times&lt;/em>; essay seemed to make the argument that Jezebel in particular reflected a “remarkable new openness” and “uncontrollable anger” on the Internet. As he put it, “What makes Jezebel feel so relevant now is that it was among the first places to crystallize the powerful forces that would define social media over the next decade: politics and identity.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I agreed that Jezebel embodied a “remarkable new openness,” and I was flattered by Smith&#39;s acknowledgment of the site&#39;s continued influence. But some of what he wrote gave me pause. His essay positioned the site as the start of an era that would culminate in the 2016 election of Donald Trump. I wanted nothing to do with it. As for “uncontrollable anger”? The phrase felt sexist and paternalistic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I live in Los Angeles, so I wasn&#39;t immediately aware of the conversation about the essay. People started texting me around 7 &lt;em >;AM&lt;/em>; PST In the darkness of my cozy bedroom, I took a quick glance at the piece on my phone, admired the accompanying photo of me (it was a good photo, and I can be vain), rolled my eyes at a few of the conclusions, and then went back to bed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;About half an hour later, I was awoken again, this time by a phone call from a friend. It appeared that a small backlash to the piece was brewing online—namely, on Twitter. Some readers felt that, by focussing his attention on Jezebel, Smith was blaming women for outrage culture. I read this with interest—after all, women get blamed for a lot of things and aren&#39;t credited enough for other things—but I also didn&#39;t have the energy to respond to it. I placed my phone on my bedside table and pulled the covers back over my head.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;I felt ambivalent. The essay had stirred up something from the past that I hadn&#39;t been able to work out: what part, if any, I might have played in the evolution of derisive online discourse. Smith wasn&#39;t purporting to answer this question—some of his language, perhaps deliberately, was a bit vague. But he did make a connection between Jezebel&#39;s often combative commenters and the eventual users of social-media platforms like Twitter, accusing the site of unleashing “searing online mobs.” Jezebel had been created years before the wide-scale adoption of social media, back when people were still going to blogs and then refreshing them to see what new posts had appeared. According to Smith, “The unmediated passions of social media took up where it left off.”&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Anger can be explosive. It can ignite social movements and chip away at calcified ideas about sex, gender, class, and race. It&#39;s also fair to say that when women express it—or are accused of expressing it—they&#39;re easily, sometimes viciously, mocked and derided. This is perhaps doubly true for women of color, who have to contend not only with sexist tropes but also with racial stereotypes and fearmongering around anger and tone. (Both my deputy editor at Jezebel, Dodai Stewart, and I are Black. The widely held assumption that the site was staffed only by white women possibly did us some sort of favor.)&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;But here&#39;s the thing about tone: in many cases, it &lt;em>;does&lt;/em>; matter. And though I was often politically and personally in agreement with our commenters, their over-the-top rhetoric could be alienating to me. I worried that this sort of rhetoric might offend new readers, and that it would be harmful to the new dialogue around gender politics that we were trying to influence and bring into the mainstream. Was there such a thing as “too much” anger? If so, who was I to determine what “too much” is? I felt torn, so I kept these questions mostly to myself.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;When Jezebel launched, I was thirty-three, about to turn thirty-four. The events that led to the site&#39;s creation have been written about many times before. So here&#39;s the short version: disillusioned by the state of American women&#39;s media, I was given the once-in-a-lifetime opportunity to create and oversee a women&#39;s-media entity—in this case, a Web site. I imagined it as one with a lot of personality, with humor, with edge. I wanted it to combine wit, smarts, and anger, providing women—many of whom had been taught to believe that “feminism” was a bad word or one to be avoided—with a model of critical thinking around gender and race which felt accessible and entertaining. As one of my colleagues, Moe Tkacik, &lt;a href=&quot;https://jezebel.com/the-five-great-lies-of-womens-magazines-262130&quot;>;wrote&lt;/a>;, in an early post, “Jezebel is a blog for women that will attempt to take all the essentially meaningless but sweet stuff directed our way and give it a little more meaning, while taking [the more] serious stuff and making it more fun, or more personal, or at the very least the subject of our highly sophisticated brand of sex joke. Basically, we wanted to make the sort of women&#39;s magazine we&#39;d want to read.”&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Of course, feminist Web sites and blogs were already exploring a new kind of politics among young American women. But, unlike Jezebel, they rarely incorporated robust and sustained pop-culture analysis, and they existed on the periphery of the Internet. (They also didn&#39;t have the funding and other resources that my staff and I enjoyed.) These sites, independently owned, with names like Feministing, Feministe, Racialicious, and AngryBlackBitch, had cultivated devoted readerships, but their audiences were small, and their language was often academic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Our audience, on the other hand, started off big and quickly got bigger, reaching more than ten million page views a month in the first year. (We had the benefit of being part of a larger blog network, anchored by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/gawker-was-a-great-place-to-become-a-journalist&quot;>;Gawker&lt;/a>;, which we would overtake in traffic in less than three years.) I was delighted, if a little taken aback, by our readers&#39; immediate passion and loyalty. Within two months of the site&#39;s launch, some readers were, unprompted, referring to themselves as “Jezebelles” or “Jezzies” in the comments sections of the site. Familiar screen names and avatars began to appear as regular readers populated the threads, talking with one another and, occasionally, with the site&#39;s writers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The majority of our commenters were very good. Smart, observant, well-read, vibrant, and dizzyingly funny, they added context and nuance to the stories we published and pressed us to do better. Within a year of Jezebel&#39;s launch, they even &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2008/05/04/fashion/04jezebel-1.html&quot;>;attracted&lt;/a>; the attention of the New York &lt;em>;Times&lt;/em>;, which described them as meeting for drinks and renting vacation houses together. But sometimes they were bad: sarcastic, mean, intellectually dishonest, and bullying toward one another. And sometimes they were horrible, behaving like a twisted Greek chorus trying to upstage the main performers. (Years later, as comments on Web sites began to migrate to social media, I would come to realize that they &lt;em>;were&lt;/em>; the main performers.) “That&#39;s sort of the nature of having a commenting community,” Erin Ryan, an early commenter who became a writer for the site, told me. “People start feeling like they should have a say in what happens there. And really that&#39;s not how a publication works.” At one point, in 2009, I toyed with the idea of handing the site over to the commenters for a day, just to watch them fail.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;hoqrk9&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;l9yp34&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;At times we were accused of “tone-policing” our readers. And it&#39;s true: we &lt;em>;did&lt;/em>; tone-police, especially those commenters who were nasty or uncivil. We would take to the comments threads to warn readers about crossing some sort of line. When they derailed a thread, we&#39;d ask them to move the discussion into the comments of a daily anything-goes post that I pointedly named “Groupthink.” (Most of the commenters didn&#39;t seem to get the joke.) I could have, maybe should have, been tougher on them. My managing editor at the time counselled me to think of Jezebel as a virtual dinner party my writers and I were throwing. “You wouldn&#39;t allow someone to be that rude to other guests or hosts. You&#39;d kick them out,” he said. “Do the same thing in the comments.” But we rarely banned anyone outright. No one wanted to punish readers for being impassioned.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I like to think that, though the moderation was irritating to many commenters, it was also empowering. Readers knew that we were watching and that we cared about what they had to say. Someone once told me that the Jezebel commenters were so devoted, if often critical, because the community was made up of bright, ambitious young women who were underutilized and underappreciated at their day jobs. I thought that this was a fascinating, if depressing, observation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I wondered, sometimes, whether my concerns about the comments were themselves sexist. Was I holding women to a standard of comportment? Complicating matters further was the fact that I&#39;d started Jezebel and shepherded it to success on the back of my own anger. Though that anger, as I&#39;ve explained, was legitimate and warranted—American women had been sold a bill of goods about who they were and what they wanted, or what they &lt;em>;should&lt;/em>; want—it was starting to define the site, for both readers and casual observers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I remember one blogger, a woman named Susannah Breslin, who, sometime after the site&#39;s launch, accused its writers of “caterwauling about the patriarchy.” This made us laugh. Breslin&#39;s accusation that writers on Jezebel yelled a lot—er, caterwauled—made sense. We were not without mischievousness (our parent company encouraged a certain amount of snark), but we also leaned into our anger—about sexism, about racism, about the erosion of women&#39;s reproductive rights.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Other critics accused us of intentionally stoking readers&#39; outrage. In mid-2009, Slate&#39;s women&#39;s Web site, DoubleX, published, as one of its first posts, an article &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20090823044352/http:/www.doublex.com/section/news-politics/trouble-jezebel&quot;>;which claimed&lt;/a>; that Jezebel “is hurting women.” “It&#39;s staffed by bloggers who are expected to produce around 10 high-traffic posts a day,” the feminist scholar Linda Hirshman (who passed away this week) wrote. “It didn&#39;t take the bloggers long to realize that one way to attract a lot of traffic was to offer up outrageous behavior to the clicking public.” She recalled an evening in 2008 when two Jezebel writers got drunk during an onstage interview for the talk show “Thinking and Drinking” and made glib remarks about sexual assault. (These comments were then &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.huffpost.com/entry/jezebelism_b_110903&quot;>;posted&lt;/a>; on the Huffington Post for all to see.)&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I understood such hesitations—we had a big platform, and we were young and provocative and perhaps not ready for prime time—at the same time that I rejected them. In that instance, the outrageous behavior was not engineered, nor was the traffic welcomed. The entire staff was humiliated, and I was livid about it for months. Less of an embarrassment was &lt;a href=&quot;https://jezebel.com/ten-days-in-the-life-of-a-tampon-388226&quot;>;Tkacik&#39;s post&lt;/a>; titled “Ten Days in the Life of a Tampon.” (The headline about sums it up.) We were well aware that this sort of gross-out story might generate page views, but it was written not to attract outsized attention but to engage in a bit of truthtelling—in this case, about how women&#39;s bodies actually work. I didn&#39;t like it when feminists policed other feminists, though it had been happening for generations. And I wanted to think that we knew a little something about how to politicize a generation of young women—not by enforcement of doctrine but by example.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Still, a story about Jezebel was emerging: that we were deliberately provoking our readers. In July, 2010, the writer Emily Gould &lt;a href=&quot;https://slate.com/human-interest/2010/07/how-feminist-blogs-like-jezebel-gin-up-page-views.html&quot;>;published&lt;/a>; a piece titled “Outrage World,” also at DoubleX, in which she accused Jezebel and other feminist blogs of cynically causing “firestorms” in order to boost page views. Gould went on to attack the site for exploiting “women&#39;s worst tendencies” by pushing readers “to feel what the writers claim is righteously indignant rage but which is actually just petty jealousy, cleverly marketed as feminism.”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;mmb6q&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;When I look back at the piece, one thing is obvious to me: some of the firestorms that began on the site accompanied legitimately infuriating reporting. The main example of a provocative post was a June, 2010, story that Irin Carmon, who would go on to do groundbreaking work on sexual harassment and abortion rights, reported about sexism at “The Daily Show.” Carmon spoke to writers, staffers, and a former executive on the show, who painted a picture of a beloved, seemingly progressive media organization that was, in fact, a boys&#39; club. (In 2017, Jon Stewart admitted, during an interview with Howard Stern, that she was right.)&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The other thing I noticed was that Gould, like many of Jezebel&#39;s critics, saw the writers as &lt;em>;responsible&lt;/em>; for the commenters: if Carmon&#39;s post provoked readers, then that was part of some master plan; if the commenters were enraged or cruel, this, too, was engineered by the site&#39;s staff. During my time editing the site, I found these assumptions intensely frustrating. In reality, every day was a negotiation between trying to be fair to our commenters and insuring group civility. (Gould declined to comment for this piece.)&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;When writing this, I remembered a &lt;a href=&quot;https://jezebel.com/no-offense-1749221642&quot;>;2015 Jezebel piece&lt;/a>; by Jia Tolentino called “No Offense.” In it, Tolentino, who at the time was the deputy editor of the site (and now is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/jia-tolentino&quot;>;a &lt;em>;New Yorker&lt;/em>; staff writer&lt;/a>;), tries to tackle multiple things at once, including how anger works on the feminist Internet and the ways in which digital media blurs the distinctions between readers and writers, creators and consumers. “There&#39;s a large gap between &#39;this is bad&#39; and &#39;you should be offended&#39; that seems to vanish on the internet, and the harder we try to widen it on this website, the more we are constrained by that lingering expectation: that Jezebel exists, as some have always imagined it to, for the infantilizing purpose of telling women when they should get mad,” she wrote. Later, she added, “In theory, people still expect a feminist site to tell people what to be offended at; but what people seek from a feminist site is that the site itself will cause offense.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I&#39;m not sure that what people &lt;em>;seek&lt;/em>; from a feminist site is that it will cause offense. I think they look for community. But communities can be difficult—chaotic, contentious, cacophonous. I recently came across a two-hundred-plus-page &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.ideals.illinois.edu/items/113064&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.ideals.illinois.edu/items/113064&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ideals.illinois.edu/items/113064&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;dissertation&lt;/a>;, published in 2019, called “Architecture and the Record: Negotiating Feminism in the Jezebel Comments.” It was . 。 。 a lot. The author, Melissa Forbes, accused the site (again!) of choosing to “cater to outraged feminists.” I thought that she wasn&#39;t giving the staffers, or our readers, much credit. But I was intrigued by Forbes&#39;s observation that the comments provided a corrective to the feminism of the site&#39;s writers. When the writers themselves were glib or cruel, she wrote, the commenters offered “a different kind of feminism from that practiced on the top half of the page.” I take issue with the idea that there are “different kinds” of feminism, though there are different “waves” of it. But I do believe that the commenters&#39; close reading of everything we did was how they forged community. They learned from one another, developed relationships, and discovered their own voices—and that was true even when they were (rightly or wrongly) angry with the editors and writers. As one commenter quoted by Forbes put it, “I have learned a lot from the kinds of articles you publish on this website, and even more from your regular commenters.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;That leaves the question of what, exactly, the Jezebel commenters had to do with the anger that exploded on social media. A few weeks ago, I spoke to the author and technologist Tobias Rose-Stockwell about his new book, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Outrage-Machine-Amplifying-Discontent-Undermining/dp/0306923327&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Outrage-Machine-Amplifying-Discontent-Undermining/dp/0306923327&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Outrage-Machine-Amplifying-Discontent-Undermining/dp/0306923327&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Outrage Machine: How Tech Amplifies Discontent, Disrupts Democracy—and What We Can Do About It&lt;/a>;,” which looks at the ways that enmity on the Internet is rewarded by social-media platforms, advertisers, and individuals. I told him about Smith&#39;s piece, and my ambivalence toward it. I explained that, though I detested accusations that we had used anger to manipulate readers, I wondered whether the outrage culture on social media had its roots in comments sections.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Rose-Stockwell was not particularly familiar with Jezebel. (In his defense, he was not part of its target audience.) But he echoed Smith&#39;s assertions, calling the early two-thousands comments sections of Web sites “proto-social media.” Sites like Jezebel, he said, were showing that it was “possible to bring people from passive consumers of news to engaged participants in the editorial process—something that was new for a media site.”&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;In 2007, when we launched Jezebel, Rose-Stockwell explained, reader remarks could not be easily boosted or reposted. Outrage or offense still occurred within the confines of communities. By 2009, however, social media—what he called “an opinion-serving machine”—was changing everything. That year, he said, “three key features: &lt;em>;algorithmic feeds&lt;/em>;, &lt;em>;social metrics&lt;/em>;, and &lt;em>;one-click sharing&lt;/em>; fundamentally upgraded the speed at which we spread knowledge, propelling us into the modern viral era.”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;35q9dq&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;u2nd&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;In his book, Rose-Stockwell points out that virality did not emerge by accident. Social-media technologists prioritize posts using emotional language. These posts, in turn, can start “trigger chains”—in which social-media users are encouraged to react to inflammatory comments and “pick sides on topics about which we would otherwise have few opinions”—and cause “emotional contagion,” in which a person expressing an emotion leads to the “reflexive production of the &lt;em>;same&lt;/em>; emotion by others in the same proximity.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;After I read this, I felt some measure of relief. The stories and topics we wrote about on Jezebel weren&#39;t being “served,” in some premeditated performance or attempt at manipulation. They were organic. &lt;em>;They were the point&lt;/em>;. And we were not abstract algorithms or “conflict entrepreneurs” (another useful phrase from Rose-Stockwell&#39;s book, describing people who create or stoke chaos online in order to boost their own profiles). We were young women with agency and points of view. We were also, I should add, pretty funny. “I think that people didn&#39;t give us credit for having a sense of humor,” Dodai Stewart, the former deputy editor, told me. “I don&#39;t want to discount some of the more serious things, but, from my perspective, our meetings weren&#39;t us sitting around with everyone red in the face, full of outrage and upset. We were having fun, mostly.” Erin Ryan, the former writer and commenter, took this a step further. “I don&#39;t want to rag on anger,” she told me. “I think anger can be great. It&#39;s the basis of a lot of great comedians and writers and opinion writers. I&#39;d say Jezebel was a passionate Web site. But the passion wasn&#39;t necessarily just outrage for the sake of outrage.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In our conversation, Rose-Stockwell explained that he&#39;s not trying to condemn outrage so much as look at it from a more systemic perspective. Outrage, online or off, allows us to understand the things that are wrong with society, and to work together to begin to fix them. It can unite people, he said, and help society to cohere around certain norms. In this sense, a lot of the outrage on Jezebel was, indeed, productive, contributing to a larger political and cultural project. I think that one can draw a straight line from the feminist Web sites of the early two-thousands to a growing mainstream discourse around gender politics and race and patriarchy, from Beyoncé performing in front of a sign that read “Feminist” at the 2014 MTV Video Music Awards to the Women&#39;s March in 2017 and the explosion of #MeToo that same year to the recent juggernaut that is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-front-row/barbie-is-brilliant-beautiful-and-fun-as-hell&quot;>;the Barbie movie&lt;/a>;. (Yes, the Barbie movie. One of my former colleagues jokingly described the film as making her feel “like I was trapped in the Jezebel comments.”)&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;A few weeks ago, I reached out to Smith and told him that I&#39;d been trying to sort out the discomfort I&#39;d been feeling in the wake of his piece. I explained that I needed him to clarify what he meant when he said that Jezebel was the start of a particular digital-media age. What age was that?&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;z6oef5&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;“Social media,” he said. “That&#39;s how I think about it.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I pressed him. Was he saying that Jezebel influenced the &lt;em>;tone&lt;/em>; on social media, the conversation, or both? Did the site augur something that was brand new, or reflect something that was already in process?&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;He replied that this was a question he&#39;d struggled with while writing his book. “I feel like when I was writing, the thing that I was always running up against was, Did X cause Y, or are X and Y being carried along in the same stream?” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;I also wanted Smith to respond to my frustrations about that phrase “uncontrollable anger,” and the apparent ease with which he, knowingly or not, placed blame for the current political climate on outraged or opinionated women.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;He conceded that his phrasing might have been problematic or inartful. “I&#39;m not trying to invalidate women&#39;s anger at all, but it does seem like that was part of the mix, and powerful,” he told me.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“I think that anger was part of it, yes, but I don&#39;t think it was uncontrollable,” I replied. “I&#39;d say it was &lt;em>;very&lt;/em>; controlled, actually, because that was the way women learned they should express it.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I see Jezebel not as the beginning of the end of the digital-media era but as a moment—a spark—within an ongoing discussion about gender politics. That conversation has led to new realities around sexual assault and harassment, pay inequity, and cultural depictions of women. It also makes some people uncomfortable—in part because it involves women expressing their anger in public and sustained ways. “Every woman has a well-stocked arsenal of anger,” Audre Lorde wrote in 1981, which can act as a “powerful source of energy serving progress and change.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;If that&#39;s part of Jezebel&#39;s legacy, I&#39;ll take it. It&#39;s about everything I could have hoped for. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;bhh62v&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 19:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why Antisemitism Led a DeSantis Ally to Jump to Trump]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/news/q-and-a/why-antisemitism-led-a-desantis-ally-to-jump-to-trump]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654405d6f9309101ece468bb/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Chotiner-11-05-23-gradient.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Randy Fine is the only Jewish Republican in the Florida legislature, and has for several years been a strong supporter of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/ron-desantis&quot;>;Ron DeSantis&lt;/a>;, the state&#39;s governor. Fine served as DeSantis&#39;s Jewish outreach chair during the 2018 gubernatorial campaign, supported DeSantis&#39;s reëlection bid last year, and backed him for President. Then, two weeks ago, Fine decided to switch his support to former President Donald Trump.原因？ Antisemitism. In Fine&#39;s view, DeSantis has insufficiently addressed numerous neo-Nazi marches that have taken place in Florida in recent years. (The &lt;em>;Times&lt;/em>; reported last month that DeSantis&#39;s unwillingness to condemn the marches has concerned some Republican donors at a time when his campaign is already lagging well behind Trump&#39;s.) The &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/dispatch/waking-to-an-attack-from-hamas&quot;>;Hamas attack on October 7th&lt;/a>; was the final straw.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I recently spoke by phone with Fine to try and understand DeSantis&#39;s behavior, and why Fine was now turning to a man with a long history of using antisemitic tropes, and all-around bigotry. Our conversation, edited for length and clarity, is below.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;A lot of people have come to support Donald Trump for different reasons over the years: the fact that he&#39;s a businessman, the economy, immigration. But you are supporting him in part because of your concerns about antisemitism. Can you talk a little about that?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Well, I was a big supporter of the President during his four years in office. I was at the Abraham Accords when they were signed. I was in the White House at least half a dozen times, so I was always a big fan of the work that he did. The fact that I had endorsed the Governor was not “I&#39;m against Donald Trump,” if that makes sense.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Right, you had to choose, and so you chose, but you weren&#39;t—&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I had been very unhappy with the quietness around the rise of Nazism. And while I wasn&#39;t beating the Governor up publicly over it, I was very vocal privately, asking why we were not using the laws that are in place. Why aren&#39;t we taking this seriously? So were lots of his Jewish supporters.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;And what was his response?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Well, the response is what you hear. I think he&#39;s been very consistent. I don&#39;t know if it&#39;s the truth, but what he says is he doesn&#39;t want to elevate them by talking about it. He questions whether they are real. He&#39;ll call them fake, and he thinks that they&#39;re doing it to make him look bad. And he has said that consistently for eighteen months.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;And you felt like you couldn&#39;t get through to him on that?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I couldn&#39;t, but the Nazis are one level of scary.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;They are a high level for sure.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Look, I don&#39;t worry about these neo-Nazis executing the Holocaust in America. It&#39;s bad and we need to do something about it. Don&#39;t get me wrong. But Hamas is a whole &#39;nother level. And so, while I had been unhappy in private, I changed as a person on October the 7th. And when I saw these protests break out within twenty-four hours in Florida, I knew that I had laid the groundwork by passing laws that could deal with this.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Which protests are you talking about?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;There were pro-Hamas protests in Florida, in Tampa, and Fort Lauderdale. The other thing I came to realize was that, if Donald Trump had been President, October 7th wouldn&#39;t have happened. I would bet every dollar, because it didn&#39;t happen in his four years.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;It&#39;s possible that October 7th didn&#39;t have to do with Trump, no?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The world was afraid of him. The world was afraid of him. No one&#39;s afraid of Joe Biden unless you&#39;re the person cleaning the stairs. No one&#39;s afraid of him.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Wait, what&#39;s the stair joke?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;You know, he falls down the stairs.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Oh, I see. That&#39;s a good one.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yeah. I mean, no, it&#39;s fine. But people were afraid of Donald Trump. Iran would sit there and think, You know what? If we do this, he could nuke us. I&#39;m sure that went through people&#39;s minds because that&#39;s the kind of guy that he is. And so, I said, Look, I&#39;ve got DeSantis saying things but not acting, and I&#39;ve got Trump who acts.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Kind of a Teddy Roosevelt thing. Talk softly, but carry a big stick.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Well, Trump doesn&#39;t talk softly. Trump talks loudly and carries a big stick but—&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Better than Teddy Roosevelt.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I&#39;m not saying better; I&#39;m just saying different. I&#39;ve been the voice of my Jewish community in Florida for seven years. I&#39;m the only Jew in the legislature in the majority party. I am the one who advocates for these things. People look to me, and I also have to deal with them when they&#39;re unhappy, which they have been for two years because of the silence and the antisemitism. The New York &lt;em>;Times&lt;/em>; wrote a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2023/10/28/us/politics/desantis-israel-antisemitism.html&quot;>;piece&lt;/a>; where they interviewed multiple donors of the Governor who said that they&#39;d called him and said, Do something about it. And he wouldn&#39;t do it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;It&#39;s a little confusing why he wouldn&#39;t respond to people like you who are concerned about this. I have noticed that he often doesn&#39;t like to respond to criticism that requires him to criticize the right in turn&lt;/strong>;.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I don&#39;t know the reason. The one that I think is the most noble of all is he is very confident that he is right almost all of the time. And when he thinks he is right, he is very stubborn and maybe he believes what he&#39;s saying. And look, I understand the stubbornness. In many ways, as governor, he was stubborn, and he was right. Look at &lt;em >;COVID&lt;/em>;.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;3gx5x&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;1ga11v&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Let me ask you about Donald Trump&#39;s response to this. His first public comments were to criticize the Prime Minister of Israel and to say that Hezbollah was very smart. How does that fit into what you&#39;re talking about?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I can vote for the governor who says all the right things or I can vote for the President who actually does them. I&#39;m focussed on the actions. I know what the world was like when he was President. He is the first American President to have a Jewish child and Jewish grandchildren, who I know that he cares about. And so, I know that he is not an antisemite.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;You mentioned neo-Nazis earlier. Trump very famously was not all that angry about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/the-battle-of-charlottesville&quot;>;a neo-Nazi march in Charlottesville&lt;/a>; where someone was killed. How does that fit into what you&#39;re talking about?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Well, that whole thing is a fiction.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;I see.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;No, no, no. If you listen to what he said, he didn&#39;t equivocate and say, Nazis are good. He didn&#39;t do that. But people were able to take a very narrow slice of what he did, of what he said, and make him look bad. Again, he did the Abraham Accords, and he moved the Embassy. He let them annex the Golan. So, look, I&#39;m also a little bit like Donald Trump. I&#39;m a retired businessman. I understand the need to be brash and blunt and to get what you want out of life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;In both cases, do you think your ideas may stem from your business experience?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Maybe.我不知道。 But I think there&#39;s value in a little bit of uncertainty. I believe that a lot of these foreign powers were afraid of Donald Trump because they couldn&#39;t read him. China says, Well, man, if we invade Taiwan, he could nuke us and go to war.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Trump has a long history of statements that people have thought played into antisemitic stereotypes. There&#39;s his friendship with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/kanye-wests-parler-games&quot;>;Kanye West&lt;/a>; who has made many antisemitic remarks. There&#39;s his talking about Jews and money all the time. There&#39;s talking about dual loyalty, all these things.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yes, yes.是的。 I understand. Here&#39;s what I&#39;ll say. There&#39;s English, there&#39;s French, there&#39;s Spanish.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Business-ese?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;And then there&#39;s Trump. I think a lot of times you have to say, What does he actually mean? Not, What is he actually saying? So I was there in 2016 or 2015 when he spoke to the Republican Jewish Coalition, and he said, None of you support me because I don&#39;t need your money, or something like that. And I didn&#39;t support him at the time. I remember thinking, That sounds terrible, but I understand what he&#39;s saying. And I also think people take him out of context. So, for example, he said, Hezbollah is smart. Well, smart doesn&#39;t equal good. And, by the way, as a business person, the No. 1 mistake you can make in business is assuming that your enemy is dumb.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;I think your words versus actions distinction is an important one, but, to me—&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;zii7yk&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;That&#39;s what this is all about.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;The reason I brought up Charlottesville is not just that Trump&#39;s words offended people but that to any sentient person watching him, it was very clear that he was annoyed to have to denounce neo-Nazis. Whether that&#39;s because they like him, or whether that&#39;s because he has sympathy with them, I can let you analyze.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;He doesn&#39;t have sympathy for them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Why do you think they like him?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I don&#39;t know that they do. I don&#39;t think they like DeSantis. People will say, Oh, they&#39;re holding up Trump signs and DeSantis signs. They hate DeSantis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;We can stick to Trump.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;But I think it&#39;s the same for him. I don&#39;t think they actually do like either of them.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;They&#39;re sort of pretending to like him?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Look, I think he may not have wanted to say something. I remember what I said when it happened. They&#39;re marching around with their tiki torches saying, Jews won&#39;t replace us. That is their famous line. I was, like, “Guys, you got nothing to worry about: if you were doctors and lawyers and Nobel Prize winners, you might have something to worry about, but we&#39;re not interested in living at home with our parents, when we&#39;re in our forties, playing World of Warcraft all day. You&#39;re safe.” These people, to some degree, they are losers. If they weren&#39;t losers, they wouldn&#39;t do this. I mean, by definition, if you think this is a good idea, you&#39;re an idiot.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Right, and, if there are people at some neo-Nazi rally who like Trump, it&#39;s not necessarily clear that they like him because of issues related to race or Jews. They could like him for the reason any normal person might like him, that he&#39;s a businessman, et cetera.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yeah. But going back to Charlottesville, honestly, it&#39;s been so long—I can&#39;t remember what I ate for breakfast, let alone what happened six years ago. But I do remember that there was controversy. And there were people who weren&#39;t racists who said, Look, that is our history. We should not just discard it and melt these statues down. I think that&#39;s what he was getting at. I don&#39;t know where I fall on that, except I will say this: George Washington owned slaves. I mean, no one&#39;s perfect.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;He didn&#39;t go to war against the United States, which Robert E. Lee did, which is one distinction between those two.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I understand, but I don&#39;t think you can say that someone from Virginia who doesn&#39;t want to take down a Robert E. Lee statue is inherently a racist. They just want to preserve their heritage or what have you. I understand the other side as well. And, by the way, you can just go forward and say, Whoever owned slaves shouldn&#39;t be recognized for anything. They own slaves. It&#39;s beyond terrible.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Do you think one reason Trump got into so much hot water around Charlottesville was because people thought, Well, it&#39;s not just about Charlottesville per se. It&#39;s that he said these things about Mexicans. He called Obama&#39;s birthplace into question. Things like that.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;nojx59&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;f7dzb&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Like I said, there&#39;s English, there&#39;s French, there&#39;s Spanish, and there&#39;s Trump. And look, I also think—I&#39;m not going to say fake news, fake news—but guys in your world were very hard on him. And, by the way, in many cases wrongly.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Last question. When you thought about supporting DeSantis and now moving to Trump, did &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/american-chronicles/the-devastating-new-history-of-the-january-sixth-insurrection&quot;>;January 6th&lt;/a>; ever give you second thoughts, or have we sort of moved past that as a country?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;So I have an interesting view on January 6th.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Uh oh.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I was a page. The most informative year of my life as a kid, I was a page for the US House of Representatives. I worked on the floor of the House for a year, and the desk that I got to use was pushed in front of the main doors to the chamber to keep people from coming up. And I cried that day. It&#39;s a very sad day for me. And the people who did it should be held accountable, but it was an epic clown show and a riot. It wasn&#39;t a coup attempt. What has been described is way more than it actually was. If you&#39;re going to do a coup, you show up with guns.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Well, some of them had guns.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I know, but this was a mob riot gone mad. Well, people did bad things. I&#39;m not saying they didn&#39;t, and I&#39;m not saying they shouldn&#39;t be punished. I think they should, and I said so at the time. What they did was not OK, but it wasn&#39;t the end of the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;But when you said it wasn&#39;t a coup attempt, they did, on the House floor, try to throw out the results of the Presidential election.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;This was a clown show. That&#39;s what it was. I always think of a guy, the shaman-hat guy. [&lt;em>;Jacob Chansley, known as the QAnon Shaman, was sentenced to forty-one months in federal prison for his role in January 6th.&lt;/em>;] I mean, these were wackos.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Is it worrisome that the former President was supportive of these wackos?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I don&#39;t think he was supportive of the wackos. So, no. I remember watching it that day, and he&#39;s like, Let&#39;s go to the Capitol, but be peaceful. And did he really understand? Sometimes people don&#39;t understand what&#39;s going on in real time. Oh, yeah. They&#39;re in the Capitol. There&#39;s the fog of war. In the middle of something, you don&#39;t actually have all the details of what was going on.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Although you could say that business experience is the type of thing that allows people to see things right when they are happening&lt;/strong>;—&lt;strong>;to be ahead of the market?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;That&#39;s not necessarily true.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Oh, OK&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In order to be ahead of the market, you still gather all the facts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;If Trump had gotten all the facts on the day of, things might&#39;ve been different, I think.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I believe if the President had understood truly what was happening, I think he probably would&#39;ve acted differently. Yeah. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;mt4rwl&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 19:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[In the Middle East, Despair Is Not an Option]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/11/13/israel-gaza-hamas-war]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/654595f03dcbffdb74c6fb34/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Remnick-Comment-Against-Despair-Social.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;In an era of darkness and blood, it is nearly impossible to remember that, from Moscow to Jerusalem, there was once a time of promise. Not resolution, not paradise, and certainly not the end of history––but promise. Between 1989 and 1995, the following things happened: the fall of the Berlin Wall and the liberation of Eastern and Central Europe; the collapse of Soviet Communism and the (seeming) end of the Cold War; the brief, but startling, appearance of a pro-democracy movement in Beijing and other Chinese cities; the end of South African apartheid; and the signing of the Oslo Accords by the Israeli leadership and the Palestine Liberation Organization.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In other words, in many nations, political leaders, dissidents, and social movements, having exhausted so many rotten ideas and endured so much oppression and tragedy, began to push the world in a direction of decency, democracy, and compromise. Of course, there is much that is oversimplified in that sentence—euphoria and triumphalism obscured some of the dark currents that persisted in those countries and in human nature itself—but the promise was real, and it ran deep.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Now we live in ominous times, with Vladimir Putin&#39;s Russia laying waste to whole cities and towns in Ukraine, and the death count mounting in the Middle East. Rarely a day passes when there is not a new threat of broader conflagration. Will Putin deploy the worst weapons in his arsenal or extend his forces to other former Soviet republics? Will the Middle East conflict expand to Lebanon, Syria, and Iran? Only the hard of heart do not mourn the loss of life and work to stop it; only a fool does not recognize the possibility of worse days to come. Yet despair, though a temptation, does not constitute a vision. In 2016, when a bigoted authoritarian won election as President in this country, despair was not an option. It is not an option now.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;It is almost a certainty, though, that, at least for some time, the forces of reaction, of furious radicalism, will persist. Two vivid examples among many: recently, a senior Hamas official, Ghazi Hamad, declared that Israel can expect “a second, a third, a fourth” attack, until it is eliminated from the map. “We must annihilate that country,” he said, “because for the Arab and Islamic world it constitutes a disaster.” In Hamad&#39;s view, there is no need to regret the brutalities of October 7th. “We did not want to harm civilians, but there were complications on the ground,” he told Lebanese television. “Everything we do is justified.” At the same time, in the Israeli parliament, Zvi Sukkot, a radical settler with a long record of disgraceful provocations against Palestinians in the West Bank, has been appointed to lead the subcommittee on West Bank issues. Israeli authorities were previously so wary of Sukkot that they deemed him unfit to serve in the Army. Merav Michaeli, the leader of the Labor Party, called him “one of the most dangerous people in Israel, a racist, pyromaniac, terror supporter,” capable of igniting a “second front” on the West Bank. (In the past, Sukkot was repeatedly arrested and expelled from the West Bank, on suspicion of committing arson and perpetrating violent attacks, which he denied.)&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;The forces of hatred extend well beyond the region. The director of the FBI, Christopher Wray, testified in the Senate that levels of antisemitism are at “historic levels” in the US and warned that extremists could “draw inspiration” from Hamas and assault Jews on American soil. Wray also said that Jews, despite representing just 2.4 per cent of the American public, are targets of “something like sixty per cent of all religious-based hate crimes.” The wave of antisemitism is arguably more pronounced in Europe, where the German President, Frank-Walter Steinmeier, was so alarmed that he told a rally at the Brandenburg Gate that it was “intolerable that Jewish people are today once again living in fear in our country, of all places.” And, as Rozina Ali writes in the &lt;em>;Times,&lt;/em>; fears of Islamophobic attacks in the Muslim American community are also on the rise; one of the more appalling examples is the recent stabbing death, in Illinois, of a six-year-old Palestinian American child, Wadea al-Fayoume, by his family&#39;s landlord, who, according to the boy&#39;s mother, shouted before attacking them, “You Muslims must die!”&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Israel was created precisely out of a sense that a tiny and persecuted population, following centuries of violence culminating in the Holocaust, could no longer endure the precarity of exile. More than any event in Israeli history, the massacre of October 7th shattered the country&#39;s sense of protection. At the same time, the Palestinians of Gaza, after years of Israeli siege and blockade, and immiserating misrule by Hamas, live in a state of excruciating loss and fear; the Palestinians of the West Bank continue to live under an unbearable occupation that has lately grown so intimidating and violent that there is frequent talk in the territories of a “second Nakba.” And any attempt to establish a landscape of security and human dignity will wither if the likes of Ghazi Hamad and Zvi Sukkot go on playing leading roles. Any world in which Hamas and an increasingly reactionary Israeli leadership dictate the policy and the temper of the region is doomed to more injustice, confrontation, and death.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;udoju&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;ek6yv&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;President Biden&#39;s challenges are immense. Facing a likely reëlection campaign against an increasingly manic Donald Trump as well as the Russian assault on Ukraine and the constant challenge of China, Biden must also find, day to day, ways to press for peace and security in the Middle East, while encouraging the positive participation of complicated regional powers, including the UAE, Qatar, Egypt, Jordan, and Saudi Arabia. The standard practice of embracing Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu in public and pressuring him in private has long proved to be a mug&#39;s game. He has been in the business of deceiving American Presidents since the nineteen-nineties. “I know what America is,” Netanyahu once said. “America is a thing you can move very easily.” Moreover, the man who advertised himself as “Mr. Security” presided over the biggest security failure in the history of the state.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;It may take years for a new political culture to take hold among the Palestinians and the Israelis. It may be many years before the psychic wounds heal. Right now, to most ears, talk of a “two-state solution” is nostalgic fantasy and a “one-state solution” a recipe for instant civil war. With all eyes blurred by rage and grief, an absence of vision is the reality. But, as the Palestinian academic Sari Nusseibeh put it to me recently, “People have to be shown or given options. We don&#39;t have the option of being pessimistic.” At least one source of inspiration is that era of history, not so distant, when leaders and movements, for all their flaws and failures, agreed to agree, and fought for the rights of ordinary human beings to live in freedom and without fear. That is a process that is never fully achieved anywhere, but it cannot be relinquished to a state of despair. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;0qzhq4&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 19:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[What Will It Take to Win Brooklyn’s First Majority-Asian District?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-local-correspondents/what-will-it-take-to-win-brooklyns-first-majority-asian-district]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34e75635ded66f5083f/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0698.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;On a Saturday in early fall, a sisterly crowd of political volunteers milled about in a community center in Sunset Park, Brooklyn. They were there to help elect a thirty-seven-year-old Democrat named Susan Zhuang as the City Council member for the borough&#39;s first-ever majority-Asian district, the recently redrawn Forty-third. The district, in the usual manner of these things, has a complicated outline, with several sharp turns. It roughly resembles a crowing rooster, with the top of its head touching Kai Feng Fu dumpling house, on Eighth Avenue, and its feet perched right around the Shore Parkway Jewish Center, in Bensonhurst. Voting for the seat concludes on November 7th.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A map of the 43rd District&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34ee609e828dea719b4/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1010.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34ee609e828dea719b4/master/w_120,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1010.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34ee609e828dea719b4/master/w_240,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1010.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34ee609e828dea719b4/master/w_320,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1010.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34ee609e828dea719b4/master/w_640,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1010.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34ee609e828dea719b4/master/w_960,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1010.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34ee609e828dea719b4/master/w_1280,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1010.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34ee609e828dea719b4/master/w_1600,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1010.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;The recently redrawn Forty-third District is Brooklyn&#39;s first-ever majority-Asian district.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;Zhuang, who lives in Bensonhurst, grew up outside Shanghai, and came to the US when she was twenty. She describes her introduction to local politics as almost accidental. A friend asked her to deliver a box of tea to a longtime assemblyman named William Colton; when she got to his office, she was struck by the number of people waiting for his help in dealing with various issues—housing, food stamps, Social Security. Zhuang, who has an MBA, volunteered to help low-income families and small businesses with their taxes. Eventually, she became Colton&#39;s chief of staff.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Zhuang arrived late at the community center, in a pink campaign T-shirt and sneakers; she had to stop on the way to see one of Colton&#39;s constituents, who was concerned about a dying sycamore tree. (“Potholes, street lights, or trees that need to be cut—anything—they come to our office,” she said.) The assembled volunteers were set to canvass the surrounding neighborhood, a challenging part of the district, where the predominantly Chinese residents had not exhibited much interest in local politics. “I want to get Asians to come out to vote, no matter if you vote for me or not,” Zhuang said. “Because the general public thinks Asians don&#39;t vote, that Asian voices don&#39;t matter. We need to make sure our voice matters.”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Susan Zhuang&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34e7f0186339818578b/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1395.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34e7f0186339818578b/master/w_120,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1395.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34e7f0186339818578b/master/w_240,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1395.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34e7f0186339818578b/master/w_320,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1395.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34e7f0186339818578b/master/w_640,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1395.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34e7f0186339818578b/master/w_960,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1395.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34e7f0186339818578b/master/w_1280,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1395.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34e7f0186339818578b/master/w_1600,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1395.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Zhuang, who lives in Bensonhurst, grew up outside Shanghai, and came to the US when she was twenty.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Seated at a table near the front of the room were three volunteers of high-school age. They were briefed by another volunteer, who wore a paisley dress above trench boots and had mala prayer beads on her wrist. “Everyone has to remember, Susan&#39;s No. 1 policy is public safety,” she told the teens. “She supports police officers and also wants to regulate electric scooters.” Zhuang chimed in: “Listen, they&#39;re not going to want to have a conversation with you for a long time. If they do, then you mention more. If they don&#39;t, tell them Susan is for public safety.” In 2014, not long after Zhuang began volunteering for Colton, a Chinese American police officer named Peter Liang shot and killed an unarmed Black man named Akai Gurley who was walking in a stairwell, with his daughter, at a housing project in East New York. Although Liang and the NYPD insisted that the shooting was accidental, Liang was convicted of second-degree manslaughter. (The conviction was later downgraded to criminally negligent homicide.) Many Asian Americans in the city, including Zhuang, believed that Liang had become a scapegoat for the larger problem of police violence. “Yes, he made a mistake,” Zhuang said, “but so many cops don&#39;t get indicted. When it&#39;s an Asian cop, they say he&#39;s a killer.”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;feature-large-callout&quot; >;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Campaign volunteers call registered voters and remind them of the upcoming election for council district 43 in November...&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34d7f01863398185789/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0819.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34d7f01863398185789/master/w_120,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0819.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34d7f01863398185789/master/w_240,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0819.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34d7f01863398185789/master/w_320,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0819.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34d7f01863398185789/master/w_640,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0819.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34d7f01863398185789/master/w_960,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0819.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34d7f01863398185789/master/w_1280,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0819.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34d7f01863398185789/master/w_1600,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0819.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Two young volunteers make calls for Susan Zhuang.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;The volunteer in paisley assembled a canvassing group that included two teen-agers and two adults. The kids were both freshmen at so-called test schools: Joanna, bespectacled, attends Brooklyn Tech, and Anna, who wore a Snoopy sweater, goes to Stuyvesant. (One of the adults in the group was Anna&#39;s mom.) Despite Zhuang&#39;s emphasis on public safety, she may be best known as an advocate for preserving the Specialized High School Admissions Test as the sole criterion for entry into these schools. Asian American New Yorkers have punched above their weight on the test: more than half of the students who received offers to attend the schools this year were Asian. (Only three per cent were Black and around six per cent were Latino.) Joanna said that she needed to announce a major at the end of sophomore year and was considering math. She wanted to get into a good local college, such as Hunter. “I just want to not be in debt,” she said. It seemed like a lot to have contemplated by fourteen. “I feel like it&#39;s a waste of my time to not think about these things, when I still have time to think about it,” she said.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A candidate talks with a constituent on a stoop.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34e05eb91fba6e6b223/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1409.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34e05eb91fba6e6b223/master/w_120,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1409.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34e05eb91fba6e6b223/master/w_240,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1409.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34e05eb91fba6e6b223/master/w_320,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1409.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34e05eb91fba6e6b223/master/w_640,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1409.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34e05eb91fba6e6b223/master/w_960,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1409.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34e05eb91fba6e6b223/master/w_1280,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1409.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34e05eb91fba6e6b223/master/w_1600,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_1409.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“I want to get Asians to come out to vote, no matter if you vote for me or not,” Zhuang said. “We need to make sure our voice matters.”&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Together, the group walked through the streets that thread Eighth Avenue. When the group arrived at their first door, Joanna volunteered to take the lead. But no one answered, so they were off to the next. On the way, Joanna asked Anna where she went to school, and her eyes widened when she heard Stuyvesant, which, along with Bronx Science, is perhaps the most prestigious of the test schools. The group spent three hours canvassing, and spoke to about a dozen people, but it was tough going. “Chinese people are so brutal,” Joanna said. “They just ignore you.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;About a month earlier, near the jutting wing of the district, around a hundred people filled half of the restaurant New Choi Fook, which has the best price for king crab in Bensonhurst, at least according to one reviewer. The crowd was there to raise money for Ying Tan, Zhuang&#39;s Republican opponent. The candidate, in a red dress and white heels, explained that her campaign could be traced to a moment five years earlier, when she began to look into schools for her oldest child, then three years old. “Has anyone noticed that schools lean toward being unfair for us?”她问。 “We can&#39;t let people think that, as Chinese people, we won&#39;t speak up.”&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Ying Tan&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34c05224fc450603344/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0768.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34c05224fc450603344/master/w_120,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0768.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34c05224fc450603344/master/w_240,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0768.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34c05224fc450603344/master/w_320,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0768.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34c05224fc450603344/master/w_640,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0768.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34c05224fc450603344/master/w_960,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0768.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34c05224fc450603344/master/w_1280,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0768.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34c05224fc450603344/master/w_1600,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0768.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Tan, a member of the New York Young Republican Club, previously volunteered on the State Senate campaign of Vito LaBella.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;Tan, who is thirty-two, grew up in Taishan, which has been called the “wellspring of the Chinese diaspora.” She now lives in Rego Park, in Queens, and volunteers at a senior-day-care center owned by her husband. Tan is a member of the New York &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/03/27/roger-stone-shakes-a-nixonian-martini&quot;>;Young Republican Club&lt;/a>;; last year, she volunteered on the State Senate campaign of Vito LaBella, a sixty-one-year-old ex-cop from Bay Ridge. He lost the race, narrowly. Afterward, both LaBella and Tan declared their candidacies for the City Council seat in the new Forty-third. Just eight hundred and thirty-eight people voted in the Republican primary; Tan won by thirty-one votes. But LaBella has stayed in the race, on the Conservative Party line, which may complicate Tan&#39;s path to victory. A political consultant working for Tan, George Sarantopoulos, told me he was frustrated by LaBella&#39;s decision. At a recent Republican gathering, Sarantopoulos pleaded with his fellow Party members to reach out “to the Chinese voters, to the Russian voters, to the religious Jewish voters,” adding, “I&#39;m sorry, if we want to be a party of 2023—our Italian friends are moving to Jersey, to North Carolina, they&#39;ve passed on. We have to get out of our comfort zone and reach out to those new voters.”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Craig Eaton a former Chairman of the Kings County Republican Party centerleft George Sarantopoulos and candidate Ying...&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34b05eb91fba6e6b221/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0649.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34b05eb91fba6e6b221/master/w_120,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0649.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34b05eb91fba6e6b221/master/w_240,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0649.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34b05eb91fba6e6b221/master/w_320,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0649.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34b05eb91fba6e6b221/master/w_640,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0649.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34b05eb91fba6e6b221/master/w_960,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0649.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34b05eb91fba6e6b221/master/w_1280,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0649.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34b05eb91fba6e6b221/master/w_1600,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0649.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Tan at an event in the home of Craig Eaton, a former chairman of the Kings County Republican Party.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;The evening got under way, and a volunteer from Bensonhurst named Rosanne Li went to the front of the room. Like most of the evening&#39;s speakers, she spoke primarily in Cantonese, with English sprinkled in. Praising the diminutive Tan, she said, “You wouldn&#39;t expect someone with such a small”— switching to English—“body figure”—back to Cantonese—“but she has &lt;em>;power&lt;/em>;.” Li tried to explain why it was important to elect Tan. “Just before, as I was walking on Eighty-sixth Street, I was feeling scared,” she said. “I saw, with my mama, a”—switching to English—“homeless.” She said that she took a picture, and listed other places where she&#39;d seen homeless people. She was worried that they would show up on her street, too.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;feature-large-callout&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GroupCalloutWrapper&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;The Sunset Park neighborhood outside of 5014 8th Avenue in the Brooklyn borough of New York City.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34ce609e828dea719b2/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0298.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34ce609e828dea719b2/master/w_120,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0298.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34ce609e828dea719b2/master/w_240,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0298.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34ce609e828dea719b2/master/w_320,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0298.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34ce609e828dea719b2/master/w_640,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0298.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34ce609e828dea719b2/master/w_960,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0298.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34ce609e828dea719b2/master/w_1280,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0298.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34ce609e828dea719b2/master/w_1600,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0298.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Campaign signage for Democratic candidate Susan Zhuang greets residents of the Sunset Park neighborhood outside of 5510...&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34cd65d7ddb9c9bc21f/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0571.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34cd65d7ddb9c9bc21f/master/w_120,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0571.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34cd65d7ddb9c9bc21f/master/w_240,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0571.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34cd65d7ddb9c9bc21f/master/w_320,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0571.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34cd65d7ddb9c9bc21f/master/w_640,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0571.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34cd65d7ddb9c9bc21f/master/w_960,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0571.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34cd65d7ddb9c9bc21f/master/w_1280,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0571.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34cd65d7ddb9c9bc21f/master/w_1600,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0571.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;A member of the New York Young Republican Club&#39;s Asian Caucus, Nick Tan—no relation—sat with a family of constituents around a rotating array of steamed fish, Yangzhou fried rice, and other dishes. Nick, who grew up in New Jersey, lives in Manhattan. “Democrats, especially the Asian ones, don&#39;t represent us,” he said. But, in the past two years, he went on, “the Asian community finally woke up, and made this very rightward shift.” Asian values are conservative at heart, he insisted. What did he think of Tan&#39;s Republican primary challenger, LaBella, staying in the race? “It&#39;s the voters who will control the Party,” he said, adding, “Will the Party bosses ever like us? Probably not.” But it was “the country-club Republicans who hold back the Yings of the world,” he said, and “they&#39;re going to be irrelevant. Asian Americans will be the new electorate of the Republican Party, and it will be a strong one.” What did he think of the night&#39;s speeches? “I forgot my Chinese a long time ago,” he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Across the table sat a constituent in her late thirties named Liz Yang, whose family came to New York from Guangzhou. Her mother-in-law went to Tan&#39;s senior-day-care center. “Growing up, I thought Republicans were for the rich, and Democrats—if it weren&#39;t for those government benefits, my parents would be struggling to raise us,” she said. But now, many of her friends are Republican, and her view of the two parties had changed. “They&#39;re not protecting the rich,” she said, of the GOP, “they&#39;re protecting the wealth for people who actually earn it. It&#39;s the Republican Party that wants to protect the middle class. Democrats want to keep us low-income.” She had friends who were moving from Section 8 housing into their own homes, and she had begun to feel that government assistance “makes people lazy,” she said. Also, it was too complicated. When she&#39;d been laid off, she applied for unemployment, but doing so felt like a full-time job. Plus, she was navigating health care for her father, who&#39;d had a stroke. “I really wish our health-care system was like the Canadian system,” she said. “The taxes are higher and it&#39;s equal opportunity, instead of ours.” Ying Tan, like most Republicans, seems skeptical of nationalized health care: “You always have to watch when the government manages seniors&#39; and retirees&#39; health insurance,” she has said.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;After the fund-raiser, Rosanne Li stood outside the restaurant with her mother. Both were buzzing from the event. Democrats were ruining the city, they agreed. In the schools, for instance, children were being exposed to homosexuality, Li said. Later, she tried to explain what worried her about this. “You know how my mother and I have a good relationship with each other? I don&#39;t want schools to indoctrinate kids to be homosexuals—that would break the relationship between the kid and their parent. The home and the family would be broken,” she said. “When I hear that some people who don&#39;t have a good relationship with their parents, whatever it is that caused them not to have”—she paused to think of the term, then switched to Cantonese—“a stable family, I don&#39;t want indoctrination to rock that stability.”&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;The maître d&#39; of New Choi Fook popped his head out of the door. “If you&#39;re going to be chatting outside, you might as well just come in and have some tea,” he said in Cantonese. The Lis thanked him but explained that they were headed home. They turned and began their walk beneath an elevated subway line as a D train rumbled above. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;feature-large-callout&quot; >;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Residents of the Sunset Park neighborhood navigate the bustling area of 50th Street and 8th Avenue in the Brooklyn...&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34c3414ce5f07fda04e/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0190.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34c3414ce5f07fda04e/master/w_120,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0190.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34c3414ce5f07fda04e/master/w_240,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0190.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34c3414ce5f07fda04e/master/w_320,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0190.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34c3414ce5f07fda04e/master/w_640,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0190.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34c3414ce5f07fda04e/master/w_960,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0190.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34c3414ce5f07fda04e/master/w_1280,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0190.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543f34c3414ce5f07fda04e/master/w_1600,c_limit/Lo-Alvarado_0190.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 19:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Save the Bees]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/humor/daily-shouts/how-to-save-the-bees]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-04T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542bc23550b72623ee9b195/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Bees-2560-1440-01.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Bee flying toward a sunflower with a welcome mat.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6731d907ff8996c2de5/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Bees_72dpi-01.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6731d907ff8996c2de5/master/w_120,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-01.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6731d907ff8996c2de5/master/w_240,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-01.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6731d907ff8996c2de5/master/w_320,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-01.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6731d907ff8996c2de5/master/w_640,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-01.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6731d907ff8996c2de5/master/w_960,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-01.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6731d907ff8996c2de5/master/w_1280,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-01.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6731d907ff8996c2de5/master/w_1600,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-01.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Plant Bee-Friendly Flowers&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Lavender, sunflowers—you name it! Just make sure that whatever you plant generates tons of pollen, has a long blooming season, and provides its own welcome mat.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Bees bathing in a bowl.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b673550b72623ee9b191/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Bees_72dpi-02.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b673550b72623ee9b191/master/w_120,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-02.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b673550b72623ee9b191/master/w_240,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-02.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b673550b72623ee9b191/master/w_320,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-02.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b673550b72623ee9b191/master/w_640,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-02.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b673550b72623ee9b191/master/w_960,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-02.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b673550b72623ee9b191/master/w_1280,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-02.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b673550b72623ee9b191/master/w_1600,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-02.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Create a Bee Bath&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Bees need a place to cool off, hydrate, and hear the latest buzz, like, “Sandra hatched her larva last week!” and “Did you hear the queen is hooking up with two dozen drones?”&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Two worker bees trying to rouse a third bee who died.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b67305eb91fba6e6b118/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Bees_72dpi-03.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b67305eb91fba6e6b118/master/w_120,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-03.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b67305eb91fba6e6b118/master/w_240,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-03.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b67305eb91fba6e6b118/master/w_320,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-03.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b67305eb91fba6e6b118/master/w_640,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-03.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b67305eb91fba6e6b118/master/w_960,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-03.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b67305eb91fba6e6b118/master/w_1280,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-03.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b67305eb91fba6e6b118/master/w_1600,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-03.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Raise the Minimum Wage&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;After all, that honeycomb won&#39;t make itself! A thirty-dollar-an-hour raise may initially shock a few downtrodden worker bees, but as honey consumers the least we can do is meet the bee union&#39;s demands.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Bee flying to his bee mansion.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6742408ffacffe2a45b/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Bees_72dpi-04.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6742408ffacffe2a45b/master/w_120,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-04.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6742408ffacffe2a45b/master/w_240,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-04.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6742408ffacffe2a45b/master/w_320,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-04.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6742408ffacffe2a45b/master/w_640,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-04.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6742408ffacffe2a45b/master/w_960,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-04.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6742408ffacffe2a45b/master/w_1280,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-04.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6742408ffacffe2a45b/master/w_1600,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-04.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Build a Bee Home&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;First, consider the personality of each bee. Most bees live in small wooden boxes filled with various hollow tubes. However, some prefer Craftsman cottages; several like ranch-style structures; and a select few desire a rococo-esque mansion with elaborate gilded interiors.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Three bees watching tv and lounging on the couch.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6732604a96cc492fac7/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Bees_72dpi-05.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6732604a96cc492fac7/master/w_120,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-05.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6732604a96cc492fac7/master/w_240,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-05.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6732604a96cc492fac7/master/w_320,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-05.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6732604a96cc492fac7/master/w_640,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-05.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6732604a96cc492fac7/master/w_960,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-05.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6732604a96cc492fac7/master/w_1280,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-05.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6732604a96cc492fac7/master/w_1600,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-05.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Eliminate Productivity Quotas&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Harvesting a huge amount of nectar per hour can cause mass burnout. Hundreds of exhausted bees are now unable to do anything but lie on the couch and binge-watch “The Masked Stinger” and “The Real Houseflies of Beverly Hills.”&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Bee in therapy session.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b673d2c509c63cc3e625/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Bees_72dpi-06.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b673d2c509c63cc3e625/master/w_120,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-06.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b673d2c509c63cc3e625/master/w_240,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-06.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b673d2c509c63cc3e625/master/w_320,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-06.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b673d2c509c63cc3e625/master/w_640,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-06.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b673d2c509c63cc3e625/master/w_960,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-06.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b673d2c509c63cc3e625/master/w_1280,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-06.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b673d2c509c63cc3e625/master/w_1600,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-06.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Hire a Teeny-Tiny Therapist&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Because bees are very sensitive to vibration, temperature changes, and their emotional needs.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Bees protesting.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b675e609e828dea71720/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Bees_72dpi-07.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b675e609e828dea71720/master/w_120,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-07.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b675e609e828dea71720/master/w_240,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-07.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b675e609e828dea71720/master/w_320,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-07.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b675e609e828dea71720/master/w_640,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-07.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b675e609e828dea71720/master/w_960,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-07.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b675e609e828dea71720/master/w_1280,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-07.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b675e609e828dea71720/master/w_1600,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-07.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Join the Protest&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Who&#39;s got the power? Bees got the power! Join their march against predatory labor practices. Display additional solidarity by boycotting bee predators, like bears and badgers and skunks.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Bees at a beach.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b675d2c509c63cc3e627/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Bees_72dpi-08.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b675d2c509c63cc3e627/master/w_120,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-08.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b675d2c509c63cc3e627/master/w_240,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-08.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b675d2c509c63cc3e627/master/w_320,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-08.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b675d2c509c63cc3e627/master/w_640,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-08.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b675d2c509c63cc3e627/master/w_960,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-08.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b675d2c509c63cc3e627/master/w_1280,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-08.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b675d2c509c63cc3e627/master/w_1600,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-08.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Sponsor a Vacation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;No one can be a busy bee &lt;em>;all&lt;/em>; the time. Where will they go during their PTO? Vegas? Hawaii? None of your beeswax.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Woman kneeling and listening to bees.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6752604a96cc492fac9/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Bees_72dpi-09.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6752604a96cc492fac9/master/w_120,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-09.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6752604a96cc492fac9/master/w_240,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-09.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6752604a96cc492fac9/master/w_320,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-09.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6752604a96cc492fac9/master/w_640,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-09.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6752604a96cc492fac9/master/w_960,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-09.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6752604a96cc492fac9/master/w_1280,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-09.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6542b6752604a96cc492fac9/master/w_1600,c_limit/Bees_72dpi-09.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Listen&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;If you&#39;re not sure how to help, don&#39;t be afraid to ask. Crouch down and get it straight from the bee&#39;s mouth.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 19:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[High Camp and High Tragedy in Two Electrifying Off-Broadway Productions]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-theatre/high-camp-and-high-tragedy-in-two-electrifying-off-broadway-productions]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-03T20:19:04.202Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543c8fb88ffdfa1b02d39cf/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/shaw-snatch%20adams.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Snatch Adams, a six-foot-tall walking vagina working as a red-nose clown, would usually be entertaining folks on the vaudevillian “Borsch” Belt comedy circuit—“borsch” as in (a)bort(ion)—but extremists have been closing Planned Parenthoods. There&#39;s certainly not a lot of other things an unemployed, six-foot-tall vagina-clown can do. Start a podcast? Launch a wellness app? Snatch (Becca Blackwell) and their dear friend Tainty McCracken (Amanda Duarte) experience a flicker of confusion, but then the right idea strikes like a period on a day you&#39;re wearing white pants: air a TV talk show called “It&#39;s That Time of the Month,” which mashes together the best of Conan O&#39;Brien, “Pee-wee&#39;s Playhouse,” and performance artist Carolee Schneemann in her “Interior Scroll” era.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Heretofore, the comic and experimental performer Blackwell&#39;s best-known work was “They, Themself and Schmerm,” an immensely funny standup piece about their transition, which somehow got laughs out of stories about, among other things, childhood molestation. (“Schmerm” is the garbled sound a person might make when trying to say several pronouns at once.) Right before the pandemic shutdown—like, two days before—I saw Blackwell&#39;s chilled-out show “Schmermie&#39;s Choice,” at Joe&#39;s Pub, another autobiographical, standup-flavored set, which explored the giddiness of sex on testosterone, and the ways that various tab A&#39;s fit into various slot B&#39;s. Their latest work, “Snatch Adams &amp;amp; Tainty McCracken Present It&#39;s That Time of the Month,” at SoHo Rep, retains some of Blackwell&#39;s earlier shaggy-dog, low-fi vibe, but here the imagination and the glitz factor have been dialed up to &lt;em>;Versailles&lt;/em>;. This, at last, is Blackwell&#39;s magnum opus, or, to give the collaboratively devised piece its proper due, Blackwell and Duarte&#39;s magnum o-pussy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Every Johnny needs an Ed, every Conan an Andy, so our host, Snatch—wearing a shell-pink yonic body-taco, complete with sequinned mucus membranes—bounces thoughts off Tainty, a crass, gonadal sidekick, who wears a mustache, two large, pendulous balls that dangle around his shoulders, and, on his head, an anus that resembles a ruched sofa cushion. (Amanda Villalobos did the original design for both of our leading genitalia.) The bantering pair sit at matching desks, though Snatch sometimes wanders into the crowd for some affirmative consent-style participation. The show feels loose and seemingly unscripted, though Blackwell and Duarte are credited as writers, and it was directed, thrillingly, by Jess Barbagallo. The trio&#39;s combined strength lies in creating and controlling a gently permissive queer mayhem, with Blackwell&#39;s soft-spoken diffidence giving way to Duarte&#39;s joke-swinging insult comedy. (Their respective affects are reminiscent of Big Bird and Oscar the Grouch.) “Oh, sure, let&#39;s make it about you,” Snatch said kindly, the night I saw it, when Tainty interrupted with comments about his temporarily missing penis. It wasn&#39;t mean, or even passive-aggressive; Snatch just loves to listen.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Snatch and Tainty&#39;s wonderful fake television show doesn&#39;t &lt;em>;air&lt;/em>;, exactly, so much as gestate inside a gorgeously baroque, pink-and-gilt set, designed by Greg Corbino, which features a chapel-size model of a lower body, with a throbbing, door-like vagina dead center, bracketed by huge golden legs. When guests on “It&#39;s That Time of the Month” visit with Snatch, they sit in ovary-shaped chairs that detach from two elaborate fallopian tubes glued to the wall; and when audience members compete in games, as in a race to figure out how to fasten a sanitary belt, or the hit-Snatch-with-a-herpes-sore challenge, they might stand on helpfully provided silicone blood-clot mats. (The Pyramid Club has closed in the East Village, but its sweet, sticky, pharaonic-splendor-made-from-trash spirit lives on.)&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;And hey, why &lt;em>;is&lt;/em>; it so rare to talk about menstruation? That squeamishness in our still-puritan public sphere takes on a specific menace when one considers, for example, that Florida legislators have tried to ban discussion of menarche at school. You can trace a direct line from fear about periods to the desire to regulate bodies and the ways they express themselves. Everyone on set certainly knows about that line. There&#39;s pain in Snatch&#39;s voice during a ripped-from-Jay-Leno-style bit about so-called “funny headlines”; they read several that refer to the increasing number of anti-trans and anti-abortion bills—and are not actually funny at all.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;When Blackwell, their hair pulled back and wearing street clothes, arrives as a guest of Snatch&#39;s show (this requires a quick-change and some magic by the video designer Nicholas Zeig-Owens), the tone pivots from high camp to candor. Blackwell performs a little standup but mostly focusses on telling us what they&#39;ve learned from their transition. “I lived successfully as a woman, now I live successfully as a man,” Blackwell says. “And, you know what, they&#39;re the same. Because &lt;em>;I&#39;m&lt;/em>; the same.” Certainly, a few of the folks in the audience had to be coached through a few basics, like the exact location of the clitoris, but Snatch and Tainty insist that it&#39;s actually quite easy to understand one another&#39;s holes and non-holes, as long as we&#39;re willing to stop attaching so much shame to them. And, gosh, imagine if this is what our late-night shows had been telling us all along. We leave the theatre through a narrow pink tunnel—and it&#39;s enough to make you feel reborn.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Speaking of seeming binaries that shift and melt, a revival of Brian Friel&#39;s “Translations,” the first offering in a season devoted to work by the Irish dramatist at the Irish Repertory Theatre, is all about permeable boundaries—the lines between eras, countries, languages, and constructions of mind and identity. Friel&#39;s beautifully modulated drama, from 1980, takes place in 1833, in an Irish hedge school in Baile Beag (or Ballybeg). Such informal institutions were common, prior to the full nationalization of schools, as a response to the repression of Catholic education. In the tiny community of Baile Beag, lessons bend to the hedge teacher&#39;s whim—and, in this case, the white-bearded schoolmaster Hugh (Seán McGinley) loves the classics. His students work out their sums in chalk, or study maps, but they&#39;re also catechized in Latin and Greek, and his star pupil, the eccentric Jimmy Jack (John Keating) seems to live deep in myth itself, dreaming of a “flashing-eyed Athene,” the goddess who might, he says—half-joking, half-sure—come share his loneliness.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;91ogwm&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;twkqdd&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;But, of course, change is coming. Friel is unsubtle about this: the famine will arrive in just a few years, and characters are already worried about the possibility of blight. British soldiers with red coats and cut-glass accents come stomping into the school, unable to understand the Irish-speaking locals, eager to ascertain certain property lines so that taxes can be more efficiently collected. Hugh&#39;s sons are neatly split by dramaturgical necessity: Manus (Owen Campbell) is a caretaker son, gentle and dedicated to tradition, whereas the prodigal one, Owen (Seth Numrich), has thrown his lot in with the colonizing English-speakers, aiding in their surveying work by giving new, Anglicized names to the local rills and roads.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;feature-large-callout&quot; >;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Seven actors performing in the play “Translations.”&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543c90091280ec09e07c719/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/shaw-translations.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543c90091280ec09e07c719/master/w_120,c_limit/shaw-translations.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543c90091280ec09e07c719/master/w_240,c_limit/shaw-translations.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543c90091280ec09e07c719/master/w_320,c_limit/shaw-translations.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543c90091280ec09e07c719/master/w_640,c_limit/shaw-translations.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543c90091280ec09e07c719/master/w_960,c_limit/shaw-translations.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543c90091280ec09e07c719/master/w_1280,c_limit/shaw-translations.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6543c90091280ec09e07c719/master/w_1600,c_limit/shaw-translations.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;The hedge school of “Translations.”&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Photograph courtesy Carol Rosegg&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;In an effort to maximize the romance and erudition of lost-in-time Baile Beag, Friel has us believe that the soldiers can&#39;t understand the Latin spoken to them, even when Lieutenant Yolland (dashing Raffi Barsoumian) very much wants to hear what the local beauty Maire (Mary Wiseman) has to say. But surely any officer in the King&#39;s army would have been force-fed Virgil at school? Friel&#39;s larger point—one about the way words can make a world but cannot make a welcome—is one he paints in more delicate colors. Just as you&#39;ve been lulled into believing you&#39;re watching a jolly clash-of-cultures romance, tragedy rears up. We should have known from hearing so much of the Aeneid in his characters&#39; mouths: violence and heartbreak happens in that story also.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Doug Hughes directs an exquisite production. Charlie Corcoran&#39;s set, which is mostly a stretch of sky above a low grass hill, shimmers like nacre; Michael Gottlieb&#39;s lighting design, particularly in the play&#39;s final, stunning moment with Hugh, is finely shaded, before plunging into a spotlit darkness reminiscent of Caravaggio. The theatre at the Irish Rep is quite small, and the director keeps his company in severe check, so that even a drunken scene (Owen and Yolland swill poteen together) never rises to the level of a shout. This leashed quality amplifies Friel&#39;s affectionate and sorrowful characterizations, as well as his extraordinary tension, for instance, in the lovely, foolish seduction scene at the end of the first act. Yolland, speaking English, and Maire, whose lines are in English but whom we perceive as speaking Irish, can barely say “sorry” to each other without misunderstanding. Their actual exchange of troth must happen in glances, and then, ruinously, they are understood in a different way, when they&#39;re seen by a girl on the hill. This choreography of looks requires a thick atmosphere, in the same way a light beam needs smoke to be visible. Hughes and his tremendous cast fill the room with that atmosphere, to the point that we can almost see thoughts darting between people—or, as poor, blithe, almost-mad Jimmy Jack might, Athena brandishing her spear in the gray air. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;lxyuj&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 05:06:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>