<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>纽约客</title><description>纽约客全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.newyoker.com <item><title><![CDATA[Biden’s Middle East Burden]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/bidens-middle-east-burden]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17T18:48:30.219Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ec810f45a3e98c312b24a/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/Remnick-10-17-23.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt; div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12. 5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4 H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt; svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/标题>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径 d =&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;今天早些时候，我为一家五口举行了葬礼：Livnat 和 Aviv库茨和他们十几岁的孩子罗特姆、尤纳坦和伊夫塔赫。他们是 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/israels-calamity-and-after&quot;>;10 月 7 日&lt;/a>;哈马斯武装分子横扫屠杀的 1400 名以色列人中的 5 人穿过加沙地带附近的城镇和基布兹。当救援队最终找到他们聚集在床上的尸体时，他们看到阿维夫·库茨用双臂搂住了他的妻子和孩子，这是最后的拥抱。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;库茨一家被紧紧地埋在一起。的坟墓。他们的名字被一一念出，棺材被粗绳慢慢地放入地下。花了很长时间，五个坟墓才被土填满。一名孩子的祖父高喊哀悼者的卡迪什语，数百人悲痛欲绝。最近几天，全国各地都是这样，一个又一个的葬礼，而且还会有更多的葬礼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在葬礼开始之前，我和家人的朋友聊了聊。他们说，这是处于悲伤深处的人们唯一可以处理的事情。他们很伤心。他们麻木了。他们白天都在梦游，整夜不眠。 “这是不可思议的，”当我们走向坟墓上方的白色帐篷时，其中一位告诉我。 “如果可以的话，你要怎么生活？”哀悼者们谈到了库茨一家的善良、慷慨、他们共用的学校、他们一起打的篮球。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;葬礼地点甘亚夫内镇的新公墓已不复存在。距离加沙地带不到半小时车程。在仪式开始前的几个小时，广播电台播放了有关来自加沙的火箭弹的警报。以色列对加沙的空袭已经持续数天。据估计，自大屠杀以来被杀害的巴勒斯坦人人数已超过三千。在加沙，不断有葬礼、破碎的家庭、生活在恐惧中的平民，这很难说是一种修辞上的“对等”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这样的苦难中，转向政治似乎是可恶的。 ，尤其是在政治经常成为贬低的舞台的时代。但政治，或者更确切地说，治国之术正是现在所需要的，以避免更大的灾难——而更大的灾难肯定会伴随着愤怒而产生的鲁莽决定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// www.newyorker.com/tag/joe-biden&quot;>;拜登总统&lt;/a>;将于周三抵达中东。据白宫称，除了与以色列人交谈外，他还将在安曼与埃及、约旦和巴勒斯坦权力机构的领导人举行会议。二十个月来，拜登政府成功巩固了北约对乌克兰这个极其复杂的国家的支持。高风险外交和政治技巧的壮举。然而，在一个普遍存在混乱的世界中，不可能一次只做一件事。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;经过最近几天与以色列人和巴勒斯坦人的多次交谈，在参观了10月7日大屠杀的现场后，我发现很难传达总体情况恐惧和愤怒的感觉，以及复仇需求的强度。这里的气氛在某些方面让人想起9/11之后美国的气氛。在最原始的层面上，人们不仅要哀悼、保护、捍卫和反击，而且要“根除”、“压平”、“结束它们”，这几乎是不可避免的。但它必须受到抵制。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;拜登总统需要抑制这种要求更多流血的呼声。他与以色列的亲情表达感动了许多以色列人。他们不仅注意到美国军舰在东地中海的部署是对真主党和伊朗的警告，而且还发出了信号警告以色列领导人不要“重新占领”加沙。拜登必须大力推动内塔尼亚胡总理采取战略远见和克制的行动。内塔尼亚胡现在越来越不受欢迎，并因令人震惊的军事和情报失误导致以色列南部大屠杀而受到广泛指责。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data -attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;拜登正在步入情感漩涡。打开这里的收音机，或者末日滚动浏览您选择的社交媒体，盯着您的 WhatsApp - 每时每刻都会带来更多残酷的故事。打开电视新闻，又是一次导弹警告，又是一次空袭。警觉的感觉是无情的。 &lt;em>;他们用推土机冲破了加沙的围栏，骑着摩托车和皮卡，带着 AK-47 和火箭弹冲进以色列——接下来会发生什么？&lt;/em>; 有人谈到以色列、巴勒斯坦、以及伊朗及其代理人，其中最重要的是黎巴嫩的真主党。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;似乎没有人愿意指望内塔尼亚胡。他的支持率直线下降，他最终可能面临辞职的前景。他一贯将自己的政治利益置于国家利益之上。当哈马斯领导人上周决定实施他们的可怕阴谋时，时机对其成功至关重要。他们认识到以色列国防及其自吹自擂的“初创国家”技术的弱点；他们还看到了一个&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/israel-turns-seventy- Five-as-a-nation-divided&quot;>;分裂的国家&lt;/a>;和极其反动和无能的领导层。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大规模地面入侵加沙的后果是不可知的，尽管它很容易导致数千人丧生。死亡人数正在迅速增加。据当地卫生部称，周二晚上，有报道称加沙城发生空袭，造成数百人死亡。据美联社报道，如果这些报道得到证实，这将是自 2008 年以来以色列对加沙最致命的空袭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以色列与任何其他国家一样，有权保护其存在及其公民，并且如果说有一些简单的方法可以不付出代价地打击哈马斯，那是愚蠢的。但是，以加速残酷行为来回应残酷行为、轰炸医院和学校、重新占领部分或全部加沙会产生什么结果呢？有一点是肯定的：这将加剧普通巴勒斯坦人的痛苦和怨恨。这会让以色列更加安全吗？大规模地面战争会对以色列与埃及、约旦、摩洛哥和其他相对温和的阿拉伯国家的关系产生什么影响，更不用说对与沙特阿拉伯的潜在正常化产生影响了？巴勒斯坦权力机构的领导层——老化、腐败，而且由于以色列政府的不正当破坏而变得软弱——只会在约旦河西岸和加沙失去更多的地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登无疑将向以色列领导人表达对巴勒斯坦权力机构的支持。哈马斯劫持的以色列人质以及大屠杀的幸存者。但授予复仇议程许可不会有好结果。在这片小小的土地上——饱受历史、仇恨和灾难性错误的折磨——栅栏两边无数的生命都处于危险之中。以色列“缩小”冲突、忽视冲突的想法始终是一种幻想。如果没有某种解决方案，以色列人和巴勒斯坦人的正常生活最终将是不可能的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在从甘亚夫内的葬礼返回特拉维夫的路上，我与年轻的巴勒斯坦诗人莫萨布·阿布·托哈进行了交谈他和家人住在加沙北部。他不太关注最大的地缘政治和军事问题，而是关注周围的危险。我们已经聊了好几天了，昨天他说：“我希望你下次打电话时我还活着。”今天，在得知加沙城医院爆炸事件后，莫萨布给我发了这条信息：“救命，救命，救命。” ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;v2tse9&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; >;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;h5xqc4&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt; div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ side>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live= “礼貌” aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/文章>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 03:06:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How Jane McAlevey Transformed the Labor Movement]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/news/persons-of-interest/how-jane-mcalevey-transformed-the-labor-movement]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17T18:59:48.904Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6526b707be673549da56009f/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/Schirmer-Jane-McAlevey-Lead.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt; div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12. 5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4 H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt; svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/标题>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径 d =&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;今年一月，Jane McAlevey 在康涅狄格州花了一周时间领导一场组织闪电战。用工会的话说，闪电战是一种快速、集中的组织努力，旨在在短时间内吸引尽可能多的工人。该运动的目标雄心勃勃——让大约两万五千名家庭保健工作者不仅与他们的老板作斗争，而且还与他们面临的更广泛的社会和经济问题作斗争，包括缺乏经济适用房、公共服务不足等问题。运输以及债务减免的需要。在 7 天的时间里，麦卡利维和大约 200 个其他组织者挨家挨户与数千人交谈——其中大部分是疗养院、团体之家和家庭医疗保健公司雇用的黑人和棕色人种妇女。麦卡利维和她的团队告诉他们，“这是一项新计划，旨在将你们所有人都拥有但往往没有意识到的权力带到桌面上。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于麦卡利维来说，美国最杰出的劳工之一对组织者和战略家来说，该项目提供了一个重新审视二十多年前她在康涅狄格州斯坦福德提出的战略的机会，即“全员”方法。上世纪九十年代，位于美国最富裕县之一的斯坦福德缺乏经济适用房的问题几乎盖过了工人们心目中的所有其他问题。这不是一个仅靠工会就能解决的问题，但如果从战略上加以利用，工会就有能力应对这个问题。麦卡利维开始组织四个不同部门的工人——看门人、出租车司机、城市职员和疗养院助手——并确定他们可以通过城市的教堂施加影响。 （几年后，麦卡利维在谈到这场运动时写道，“工人们对自己的信仰比对工作更关心，他们敬畏上帝胜过敬畏老板。”）很快，这座城市最有权势的传教士就开始举办讨价还价会议。在教堂的地下室里。活动结束时，四千多名工人建立了第一个工会并签订了新合同。他们的努力还使多个公共住房项目免遭拆除，为这些单元的改进赢得了一千五百万美元，并获得了新的法令，规定了未来的经济适用住房水平。他不仅是一位组织专家，而且还是一位组织方法论的社会科学家。她写了&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/books/under-review/jane-mcaleveys-vision-for-the-future-of-american-labor&quot;>;四本书&lt;/a>;已成为新一代劳工领袖的试金石。麦卡利维并没有指示组织者在他们碰巧面临的任何方向上尽其所能地奔跑，而是强调策略。她建议组织者首先进行她所谓的权力结构分析，该分析询问谁有权改变问题（并不总是最明显的目标）以及工作人员拥有哪些权力来影响这些参与者。然后，她带领员工进行一系列逐步升级的行动，从参加会议到佩戴纽扣上班，再到参加罢工：她称之为“结构测试”。在过去十年中，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/dispatch/how-to-unionize-at-amazon&quot;>;亚马逊仓库工人&lt;/a>;和&lt;a href=&quot;https: //www.newyorker.com/news/dispatch/the-social-justice-imperative-behind-the-la-teachers-strike&quot;>;洛杉矶教师&lt;/a>;借鉴了麦卡利维的方法。 （麦卡利维在《纽约客联盟》第一份合同的谈判期间非正式地为纽约客联盟提供了建议，该合同于 2021 年签署。）如果在过去的任何时候&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/podcast/political-scene/在-historic-battles-of-hot-labor-summer&quot;>;炎热的劳工夏天&lt;/a>;，或者在它之前的十年里，你遇到一群工人在纠察线上昂首阔步，或者兴高采烈地提出远远超出范围的要求很可能他们中的许多人都读过麦卡利维的书。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当麦卡利维去年冬天回到康涅狄格州时，她希望这场运动能够成为一本关于全体工人的书的基础方法。该项目之所以重要有两个原因。首先，这是她迄今为止最雄心勃勃的研究工作，不仅涉及数万名医护人员，还涉及他们的教堂、租户工会和邻里委员会。工会通常将其组织范围限制在工作场所，将更广泛的社会问题留给政治运动。但这种方法放弃了麦卡利维所说的第三条权力阵线：工人与其社区的关系。如果没有这种程度的协调，工人们就不可能实现任何接近他们的目标，其中包括赢得每小时 25 美元的最低工资和负担得起的医疗保险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更根本的是，该项目是很可能是麦卡利维的最后一次。 2021年9月，她被诊断出患有高危型多发性骨髓瘤。自从她确诊以来，她的医疗团队为她提供的每一种治疗方案都以失败告终，速度比预期的要快。今年一月领导闪电战的前几天，麦卡利维住院接受紧急治疗。人们认为她正在度过最后的日子。她说服医生让她出院——她要领导一场闪电战，时间已经不多了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于麦卡利维来说，坚持不懈是一种生活方式。她语速很快，经常骂人，直言不讳到了鲁莽的地步，很容易笑。她不能容忍平庸，尤其是左派。工会领导，她曾经&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://jacobin.com/2023/05/jane-mcalevey-interview-labor-movement-strategy-whole-worker-organizing-supermajority-leadership/ &quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://jacobin.com/2023/05/jane-mcalevey-interview-labor-movement-strategy- Whole-worker-organizing-supermajority-leadership/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://jacobin.com/2023/05/jane-mcalevey-interview-labor-movement-strategy-whole-worker-organizing-supermajority-leadership /&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;备注&lt;/a>;，“每天选择。 。 。失去。”当我准备去纽约看望她时，在四月一个阴天的周末，麦卡利维给我发了一份行程安排：周六，我们和一位组织者一起喝了一杯，七点吃晚饭，然后所有严肃的谈话都在提示音下结束。这是勇士队对阵国王队的季后赛第一场比赛。麦卡利维过去二十年来一直在湾区兼职生活，他是一位顽固的&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/golden-state-warriors&quot;>;金州&lt;/a>; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当我到达麦卡利维位于曼哈顿的租金管制公寓时，她热情地欢迎我，穿着牛仔裤、高跟凉鞋和勇士队球衣。在最近的大部分公共活动中，她都戴假发，以掩盖化疗的影响，但在家里她就不戴假发。当我访问时，一层细软的毛发刚刚开始重新长出来。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >; &lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;我坐在桌边，她忙着做沙拉，解冻一罐自制的香蒜酱做意大利面。当我第一次联系她写这篇文章时，她告诉我，她不希望她的癌症诊断出现在故事​​中。这是可以理解的，但不可能：除其他外，这样做将要求我从麦卡利维的生活中剔除一根线索。当简大约三岁的时候，她的母亲黑泽尔·麦卡利维因乳腺癌病得很重，为了不让简亲眼目睹母亲的衰落，她被带到了别处居住。四十四岁时，黑兹尔去世了。简五岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;一家人住在距纽约市四十英里的斯洛茨堡。在那里，简的父亲约翰·麦卡利成为一名政治家，首先担任市长，然后担任该县的督察。简早年的大部分时间都在肮脏和无人监管的情况下度过，到处都跟着她的哥哥姐姐。她对姐姐凯瑟琳产生了深深的依恋，她在青少年时期就成为了这个家庭的看护人。作为对凯瑟琳做饭、打扫卫生、照料、照看房子和照顾孩子的奖励，凯瑟琳被授予最大的卧室，里面配有立体声音响、电视，而且位置优越，靠近浴室。 “我会不惜一切代价进入那个房间，”简回忆道。尽管弟弟妹妹们羡慕凯瑟琳的财产，但她是这个家庭的核心。 “我们总是说她是最受欢迎的麦卡利维，”简回忆道，“因为她是每个人的妹妹、母亲。她扮演了每一个角色。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;靠一名公务员的工资抚养七个孩子是很困难的。简十岁左右的时候，她的父亲差点破产，后来简才明白这是一种尴尬。大约在这个时候，他再婚了。简十六岁时与继母发生争执，离家出走。正如她继兄所解释的那样，“简在成长过程中总是处于一些可怕的事情的底部。她的母亲被带去等死。我们的父亲不知道如何照顾家庭。而简总是处于最底层。”&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;有一段时间，麦卡利维和她的姐姐布里住在一起，她住在曼哈顿的一个激进的合作公寓里，在进入纽约州立大学布法罗分校入学之前，她在那里做服务员来支付学费。当州长马里奥·科莫提议提高学费时，她热衷于校园组织活动。正如她告诉我的那样，“我实际上负担不起一个学期超过两百美元的费用。”在&lt;em>;纽约州立大学&lt;/em>;的第一个学期，简和其他人挤满了一辆又一辆巴士，满载愤怒的学生到奥尔巴尼表达他们的不满。科莫放弃了他的加息提议。 &lt;em>;纽约州立大学&lt;/em>;学生赢得了胜利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此后不久，麦卡利维成功竞选了&lt;em>;纽约州立大学&lt;/em>;布法罗分校的学生会主席，作为竞选名单的一部分其纲领是不增加学费、不增加租金、校园内不设立军事防御项目、不收取体育费用。麦卡利维开始全职担任纽约州立大学学生会主席。十多年来，从种族隔离的南非撤资一直是纽约州立大学学生组织者的首要任务，但前 SASU 学生组织者、现任罗格斯大学劳动研究教授的珍妮丝·法恩 (Janice Fine) 告诉我，他们的努力的重点不明确。麦卡利维改变了这一点，将目标从纽约州立大学校长小克利夫顿·R·沃顿转移到了州长科莫。正如法恩解释的那样，“我们的目标从被任命的官员变成了当选的人，一个更容易受到国家看法影响的人。” 1985 年，董事会投票决定从在种族隔离的南非开展业务的公司手中剥离 1150 万美元的股票。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;麦卡利维在劳工运动中找到了第一份工作，负责康涅狄格州斯坦福德的竞选活动。随后，她受雇于服务业雇员国际工会（SEIU），负责组织拉斯维加斯的医院工作人员。 McAlevey 在 &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Raising-Expectations-Hell-Fighting-Movement/dp/1781683158&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot; 中写道： “ExternalLink”、“outgoingURL”：“https://www.amazon.com/Raising-Expectations-Hell-Fighting-Movement/dp/1781683158”}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com /Raising-Expectations-Hell-Fighting-Movement/dp/1781683158&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;回忆录&lt;/a>;，“工会在任何领域都没有明显的权力。工人们在任何与组织或动员有关的事情上都非常软弱。我被派去那里总体上清理这个地方，特别是组织新的医院工作人员加入工会。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;受到三十年代工会策略的启发，麦卡利维开始举办公开谈判会议，在其中数百名工人与老板面对面坐着。 “我们的想法是向老板和工人们证明，工人们站在一起，工会负责，”麦卡利维多年后写道。她没有让谈判代表提出要求，而是找到了对每个问题都充满热情的工人，并且可以直接与雇主讨论病人与护士的比例、时间表或工资。当地护士弗雷多·塞拉诺 (Fredo Serrano) 告诉我：“简能认清人。她知道我们需要什么。她知道影响力在哪里。她知道谁是领导者。”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node- id=&quot;1nzin7h&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt; div >;&lt;p >;在一次会议中，工人们发现自己面对的是一位臭名昭著的敌对管理谈判代表，而这位谈判代表也是一个爱嚼口香糖的人。他越生气，咀嚼的声音就越大，轻蔑地吹着泡泡。 “这成为他蔑视工人和简的外在表现，”组织者之一克里斯汀·华纳 (Kristin Warner) 回忆道。休息期间，一名工人想知道如果每个人都开始嚼口香糖，谈判者会如何反应。简和工作人员组织者对这个想法欣喜若狂，跑出去拿物资。下一次谈判陷入僵局时，谈判室里的 200 名医护人员小心翼翼地拆开口香糖并咀嚼——大声敲打墙壁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但麦卡利维的愿景是建立一个以工人为主导的、激进的组织。工会的成立使她与全国工会领导人产生了分歧，后者希望工会与医院企业领导层达成协议。 2006年秋天，当维加斯的医院工作人员处于罢工边缘时，SEIU的全国法律领导人给麦卡利维打电话。 “这是一个非常不寻常的电话，”麦卡利维告诉我。这位法律领袖警告麦卡利维，全国工会刚刚重新谈判了一项全国劳工和平协议；现在罢工已不再可能。如果当地人不服从国家的指示，他们可能会面临被托管的风险，从而消除他们来之不易的民主性格。 （SEIU 拒绝发表评论。）&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;麦卡利维告诉所有工人领袖到她家处理紧急情况会议。当他们到达时，麦卡利维解释了这个选择：他们可以遵循国家命令并取消罢工投票，或者他们可以继续他们的计划，冒着工会大门被国家领导人锁上的风险。该组织同意继续进行罢工投票。 “那些工人根本不在乎。我们正在这样做，”麦卡利维说。当团队第二天早上通知国家法律工作人员时，麦卡利维知道她必须离开 SEIU 只是时间问题&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几周之内，简接到了另一个改变生活的电话：她的妹妹凯瑟琳刚刚被诊断出患有乳腺癌。简搭乘下一趟航班飞往凯瑟琳居住的纽约。 “我们花了四十八个小时拥抱和哭泣，然后制定了一个计划，我承诺定期回家探望，”麦卡利维说。和简一样，凯瑟琳也有一头长长的金发。 “我告诉凯瑟琳的伴侣，当头发第一次脱落的迹象出现时，给我打电话，我会在那里，”麦卡利维回忆道。几周后，麦卡利维和她的妹妹坐在纽约的一家假发店里，握着她的手，而她妹妹的头被剃光了，一簇簇头发掉落在地板上。 “凯瑟琳哭得歇斯底里，他们不得不不停地停止剃须刀，”麦卡利维告诉我。 “我只记得自己心里想，表现得好像你能渡过难关。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她姐姐的诊断证实了一种深深的不祥预感。正如麦卡利维所说，“我一直相信我会在四十出头时死于乳腺癌，就像我的母亲一样。” 2008 年初，即治疗大约一年后，凯瑟琳得知她携带 BRCA1 基因突变，该突变与侵袭性癌症风险增加有关。凯瑟琳的结果促使简接受了检测。她很积极。预防性手术显示她患有早期卵巢癌。正如麦卡利维几年后所写的那样：“导火索在我 40 多岁的时候就被点燃了。就像我的母亲一样。就像我姐姐一样。”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data- testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Jane McAlevey 穿着牛仔裤和粉色上衣站在外面的阳台上&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/照片/6526b7023d1c5b43016c4be9/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Schirmer-Jane-McAlevey-Secondary.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6526b7023d1c5b43016c4be9/master/w_120,c_limit/Schirmer-Jane -麦卡利中学.jpg 120w，https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6526b7023d1c5b43016c4be9/master/w_240,c_limit/Schirmer-Jane-McAlevey-Secondary.jpg 240w，https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6526b7023d1c5b43016c4be9/大师/w_320，c_limit/Schirmer-Jane-McAlevey-Secondary.jpg 320w，https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6526b7023d1c5b43016c4be9/master/w_640，c_limit/Schirmer-Jane-McAlevey-Secondary.jpg 640w，https：/ /media.newyorker.com/photos/6526b7023d1c5b43016c4be9/master/w_960,c_limit/Schirmer-Jane-McAlevey-Secondary.jpg 960w，https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6526b7023d1c5b43016c4be9/master/w_1280,c _限制/席尔默- Jane-McAlevey-Secondary.jpg 1280w，https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6526b7023d1c5b43016c4be9/master/w_1600,c_limit/Schirmer-Jane-McAlevey-Secondary.jpg 1600w&quot;sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/图片>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;麦卡利维解释说，组织不是一门告诉人们该做什么的艺术，而是一门倾听他们无法忍受的事情的艺术。&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;明年麦卡利维从与卵巢癌和 BRCA1 基因相关的多次手术中康复。被困在家里的她开始写作。她的回忆录《提高期望》读起来就像散弹枪一样，是一系列劳工组织战斗故事。简的一些导师，包括社会学家弗朗西斯·福克斯·皮文（Frances Fox Piven），想要一些更有分寸的东西。皮文鼓励她去读研究生，以加深她的见解。因此，距离四十五岁仅剩几周，麦卡利维就读于&lt;em>;纽约市立大学&lt;/em>;研究生中心的社会学博士课程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;麦卡利维在阿迪朗达克山脉度过了研究生院的第二个夏天，在蓝山中心举行写作静修会，完成《提高期望》的修订。八月的一个星期五，凯瑟琳和她的伴侣计划接麦卡利维去萨拉托加温泉度过周末。但是，前一天，简的导师兼蓝山中心主任哈里特·巴洛找到简，让她知道她姐姐的伴侣正在打电话。她告诉简凯瑟琳的癌症又复发了。 “我走出办公室，记得看着哈丽特说，‘我妹妹就要死了，’”麦卡利维回忆道。第二年春天，凯瑟琳去世了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;麦卡利维从研究生院抽出时间来照顾凯瑟琳，回到&lt;em>;纽约市立大学&lt;/em>;完成她的学位。 Shortly after she graduated, her dissertation was published as a book, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/No-Shortcuts-Organizing-Power-Gilded/dp/019062471X&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/No-Shortcuts-Organizing-Power-Gilded/dp/019062471X&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/No-Shortcuts-Organizing-Power-Gilded/dp/019062471X&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;No Shortcuts&lt;/a>;,” dedicated to Catherine. “No Shortcuts” describes three common pathways to create change: advocating, mobilizing, and organizing. Advocacy relies on lawyers, consultants, and lobbyists to secure one-time wins, often via backroom deals. Mobilizing draws in activists to participate in rallies or protests. McAlevey distinguishes both of these activities from organizing, which she defines as something stronger and more abiding. For McAlevey, organizing means that “ordinary people help make the power analysis, design the strategy, and achieve the outcome.” The book outlines the key elements of McAlevey&#39;s method, from conducting a power-structure analysis and stress tests to identifying leaders in the rank and file. But it also offers a radical theory of power. Organizing is not an art of telling people what to do, McAlevey explains, but of listening for what they cannot abide. “Anger is there before you are,” the opening page of “No Shortcuts” declares. “Channel it, don&#39;t defuse it.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Almost instantly, “No Shortcuts” became an underground bible of organizing. In the summer of 2017, a West Virginia history teacher named Jay O&#39;Neal started a labor-themed reading group with some colleagues. “We were, like, the teaching conditions suck in West Virginia,” he told me. “How can we get our unions moving and doing something?” McAlevey&#39;s distinctions between advocacy, mobilizing, and organizing gave the group language for their frustration, and her emphasis on power structures helped them decide to target the state legislature. “It&#39;s like when you&#39;re growing up and you hear, like, a love song, and you&#39;re, like, Oh, that&#39;s exactly how I&#39;ve been feeling,” O&#39;Neal explained. Within months, O&#39;Neal and his colleagues led a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/the-new-old-politics-of-the-west-virginia-teachers-strike&quot;>;statewide walkout&lt;/a>; that set off the #RedForEd teachers&#39; strikes. In 2017, the leaders of Los Angeles&#39;s teachers&#39; union had a chapter-by-chapter discussion of “No Shortcuts” that guided the buildup to the union&#39;s successful strike in 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;McAlevey&#39;s influence spread to other progressive struggles. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-new-yorker-interview/naomi-klein-sees-uncanny-doubles-in-our-politics&quot;>;Naomi Klein&lt;/a>;, the leading climate activist and writer, told me that McAlevey&#39;s focus on winning helped the movement to reframe &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/climate-change&quot;>;the climate crisis&lt;/a>; as a power struggle. “We&#39;re not losing because people don&#39;t know there&#39;s a problem,” Klein told me. “We&#39;re losing because there are vested interests who may not be large in number, but they are mighty in their political and economic power.” McAlevey&#39;s work, she went on, asked, “Where&#39;s your war room? Where&#39;s your power map? Have you stress-tested?” I recently found myself talking to a McGill professor from Nigeria who studies African diasporic social movements. “Oh, Jane!” she exclaimed, when I told her about this piece. “My Nigerian comrades have trained with her.”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;a2huv&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Some union organizers similarly concerned with building worker power have wondered if McAlevey&#39;s path from union complacency to union militancy breezes over a critical component: union democracy. Mike Parker—a veteran labor organizer, educator, and author, who died last year—once observed that workers often must win the fight for the union presidency before they can win the fight with the boss. But such struggles get little airtime in McAlevey&#39;s work. “It&#39;s as if she hopes that current leaders will see the light and &#39;empower&#39; their members from above,” Parker wrote. Others have taken this argument further, charging McAlevey with an overreliance on professional staff at the expense of a radically empowered rank-and-file. McAlevey throws up her hands at this critique. “The idea that you&#39;re just gonna beat Amazon when you&#39;ve never run a campaign in your life is, like, seriously? Gimme a fucking break,” she told me.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;After Amazon workers in Alabama failed to unionize, in the spring of 2021, McAlevey published a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thenation.com/article/activism/bessemer-alabama-amazon-union/&quot;>;column&lt;/a>; in &lt;em>;The Nation&lt;/em>; about the campaign&#39;s weak points. “When there are more outside supporters and staff being quoted and featured in a campaign than there are workers from the facility, that&#39;s a clear sign that defeat is looming,” she wrote. The piece drew heated criticism. Some saw it as punching down. Union leadership blamed high employee turnover for their failures. McAlevey, however, stood by her assessment. “When you do something that&#39;s stupid, I&#39;m gonna call it out,” she told me. “I will not take a word of that article back.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;What some may perceive as arrogance is perhaps better understood as impatience. McAlevey has no time to waste. In fact, none of us do. She just perceives this scarcity more acutely than most. In recent months, she said, she has been working harder than ever: “I feel great and I feel horrible. I feel frenetic.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In March of 2022, after five months of intensive chemotherapy, McAlevey received a stem-cell transplant. For three months, she sealed herself in her apartment, recovering, but also revising a new book, which had just received peer reviews. Published this spring, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Rules-Win-Power-Participation-Negotiations/dp/0197690467&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Rules-Win-Power-Participation-Negotiations/dp/0197690467&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Rules-Win-Power-Participation-Negotiations/dp/0197690467&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Rules to Win By&lt;/a>;,” which she co-authored with Abby Lawlor, is part theory and part nuts and bolts; its focus is McAlevey&#39;s strategy of using big, open bargaining sessions to secure winning contracts.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;When autumn arrived, McAlevey, who is a senior policy fellow at the Labor Center at the University of California, Berkeley, joined thousands of her UC co-workers on strike. One day, on the picket line, she collapsed—probably the result of a long bike ride the day before, she thought. She went to the hospital, where a panel of blood work revealed that the stem-cell transplant had failed; a treatment that typically results in five to seven years of remission had lasted her less than a year. McAlevey was put on high-dose chemotherapy and underwent radiation treatments on her hip and jaw.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;By Christmas, it became clear that the treatment plan wasn&#39;t working. The most promising treatment for multiple myeloma was a course of cellular immunotherapy, but McAlevey&#39;s doctors believed that her condition wasn&#39;t stable enough to make her a promising candidate. “It wasn&#39;t worth it to any doctors to get me in their clinical trials,” McAlevey told me. Uncharacteristically, she paused. “That was pretty intense.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Shortly after the New Year, a group of McAlevey&#39;s closest friends met at her home in California to help arrange her affairs. Together, they packed up nearly fifty boxes of McAlevey&#39;s favorite belongings—clothing, pottery, art work, jewelry, books—which would be sent to close friends and family upon her death. The next week, she flew to New York to begin an intensive treatment regimen at Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center. If this treatment did not take, she would be heading to hospice. Friends and family from around the world lined up next to her hospital bed, crying, telling her they loved her. “I called it death tourism,” McAlevey told me. She was grateful for it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;When the treatment ended, with no hitches, McAlevey began negotiating her release. The blitz in Connecticut was to start at the end of the month. “I mean, I hadn&#39;t reacted badly to any of their tests or treatments,” she told me. “I just wanted them to let me the hell out of here. And my doctor was, like, We&#39;re not getting you out of here to go do some crazy thing with a bunch of people, and I said, &#39;Yeah, actually, you are.&#39; ” McAlevey, the expert negotiator, won.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;By this past spring, Jane had defied doctors&#39; predictions: she was not dead. This piece of good news coincided with another—“Rules to Win By” was about to launch. On March 25th, McAlevey&#39;s friends held a party to toast her accomplishments, including still being alive and completing a book.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The party was at the People&#39;s Forum, a political-education and event space in midtown Manhattan. In the morning, fifty or so guests joined a live discussion of McAlevey&#39;s legacy for the podcast “The Dig.” McAlevey, who was wearing jeans, puffy purple shoes, and a sleeveless, peach blouse, took the stage, along with her interviewer, the &lt;em>;Jacobin&lt;/em>; editor Micah Uetricht. Uetricht lobbed slow, arching questions at McAlevey that allowed her to reflect on her life&#39;s work. Organizing is a craft. Everyone can do it, but it depends on concrete methods and skills. “Every day, for organizers, there&#39;s a strategic choice, the possibility of choosing a way to win. I write books to call people out and say, &#39;Let&#39;s try to win today,&#39; ” McAlevey explained.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;When the session ended, I looked around the room. A few rows from me, an older, mustached man wearing a flannel shirt caught my eye. I recognized him as Marshall Ganz, a famed labor organizer with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2014/04/14/hunger-artist&quot;>;Cesar Chavez&lt;/a>;&#39;s United Farm Workers campaign, who is widely credited with developing the grassroots model for Barack Obama&#39;s 2008 Presidential run. Speaking softly, almost musically, he told me, “Jane and I, we belong to the same church. We fundamentally believe that people have power—not as props, not as resources, but as people with agency.” We were among the last guests still in the room when he pulled out his phone and began reading me a Mary Oliver poem that, he said, reminds him of McAlevey. “I look upon time as no more than an idea,” Ganz read. “Each body a lion of courage, and something / precious to the earth.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;By evening, the rows of folding chairs had been cleared out to make a dance floor, bottles of wine and champagne had replaced the coffee carafes, and hot trays of catered Lebanese food lined the back walls. McAlevey had changed out of her jeans and wore a sweeping red dress and heels, with her head bare. The crowd milled around, sipping champagne, until the party&#39;s mcs, two comedians, announced the first activity: Icebreaker Jane Bingo. Everyone received a bingo grid with squares containing phrases like “Too intimidated by Jane to hit on her”; “Have a selfie with Bernie Sanders”; “Are also dying.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In a toast, Janice Fine, Jane&#39;s longtime friend and comrade, reported that McAlevey had fired her from the party-planning committee. “I was making things too emotional,” she chuckled. Bronwyn Dobchuk-Land, a friend of Jane&#39;s from graduate school at &lt;em >;CUNY&lt;/em>; and a criminal-justice professor at the University of Winnipeg, teased, “Well, Jane, if you had known your life was going to be cut short, do you think you would have come to Winnipeg three times? Joke&#39;s on you.” Dobchuk-Land told of a time when Jane took a very pregnant Bronwyn on a vigorous walk to the top of Winnipeg&#39;s “Garbage Hill,” precipitating Bronwyn&#39;s labor. While Bronwyn was in the hospital, Jane cleaned her house, stocked her fridge, and did her laundry. She was the first friend to hold Bronwyn&#39;s daughter. “And I believe she planned it that way,” Dobchuk-Land said. “To know Jane is to be organized by her.” ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 03:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Daily Cartoon: Tuesday, October 17th]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/cartoons/daily-cartoon/tuesday-october-17th-out-for-the-season]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17T15:36:27.738Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652ea729f45a3e98c312b23e/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/A28348.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Buy &lt;em>;New Yorker&lt;/em>; Cartoons »&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;tfquzg&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;cr5fx8&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:06:01 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Martin Scorsese on Making “Killers of the Flower Moon”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-front-row/martin-scorsese-on-making-killers-of-the-flower-moon]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6529d837a6c0cad6e89e9c99/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/brody-martin%20scorsese.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Martin Scorsese has the best curveball in the business. His 2013 film, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/richard-brody/the-lasting-power-of-the-wolf-of-wall-street&quot;>;The Wolf of Wall Street&lt;/a>;,” based on the true story of a large-scale financial fraudster, is also his wildest and wackiest comedy, closer in inspiration to Jerry Lewis than to Oliver Stone. His modern-gothic horror-thriller “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/richard-brody/out-of-the-past&quot;>;Shutter Island&lt;/a>;,” from 2010, is primarily a refracted personal essay about his childhood spent watching paranoid film-noir classics in the shadow of nuclear war. And now his forthcoming film, “Killers of the Flower Moon,” his first attempt—as an octogenarian—at a Western, is essentially a marital drama akin to Stanley Kubrick&#39;s final film, “Eyes Wide Shut.” It borrows more from such intimate psychological dramas as “Phantom Thread,” “Suspicion,” and, yes, “Gaslight” than from any of the Western classics of John Ford. In other words, the first of the mysteries that Scorsese&#39;s new film poses isn&#39;t in the plot—it&#39;s the mystery of its own genesis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;When I met Scorsese several weeks ago, I told him, before we got started, that I do very few interviews, because, well, I have a director&#39;s films, and, if watching them doesn&#39;t give me enough to think about and to write about, then I&#39;m in the wrong profession. That said, there was much that I wanted to know about Scorsese, not least because of the paradox of his artistic position: he directs extraordinary movies on hundred-million-dollar budgets yet makes them deeply personal and packs them with artistic flourishes—spectacular camera moves, intimate observations, dramatic shocks, and moments of performance—that are as daring as they are distinctive. I wanted to ask about his methods because I&#39;ve long felt that a huge part of the art of directing is &lt;em>;producing&lt;/em>;—that the originality of a finished film usually has its roots in the distinctiveness of its director&#39;s approach to the systems and methods that get it made.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I&#39;d seen something of Scorsese&#39;s behind-the-scenes originality in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-front-row/review-jonas-mekass-illuminating-documentary-of-martin-scorsese-on-the-set-of-the-departed&quot;>;Jonas Mekas&#39;s documentary&lt;/a>; about the making of Scorsese&#39;s 2006 gangland drama “The Departed”—the movie for which Scorsese finally won the Oscar for Best Director, after five previous nominations ended in disappointment—and which heralded his great outburst of work in the past decade and a half. I&#39;d also seen it in “The Wolf of Wall Street,” in the way that Scorsese took the increasingly commonplace technology of CGI and proceeded to use it like a painter. But the part of his process on “Killers of the Flower Moon” that I was most curious about involved the subject matter. Set in Oklahoma in the nineteen-twenties, “Killers of the Flower Moon” is based on the &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Killers-Flower-Moon-Osage-Murders-ebook/dp/B01CWZFBZ4&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Killers-Flower-Moon-Osage-Murders-ebook/dp/B01CWZFBZ4&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Killers-Flower-Moon-Osage-Murders-ebook/dp/B01CWZFBZ4&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;nonfiction book&lt;/a>; of the same name by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/david-grann&quot;>;David Grann&lt;/a>;, a colleague of mine at &lt;em>;The New Yorker&lt;/em>;. In the movie, Leonardo DiCaprio plays Ernest Burkhart, a white man who marries an Osage woman named Mollie (Lily Gladstone), under the direction of his gangster-like uncle (Robert De Niro), as part of a wide-ranging and murderous scheme to pry away the wealth of the Osage Nation, on whose territory oil has been discovered.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;One of the common frustrations of watching movies adapted from books is the inevitable abridgment of the source material. Reading a book several hundred pages long takes many more hours than watching even a longish feature, and, often, one can sense an adaptation&#39;s compression and gaps without having read the book. Scorsese&#39;s new film is colossal—three hours and twenty-six minutes—but even that duration could never encompass the plethora of incident that Grann delivers in his fascinating, horrifying book. Scorsese escapes this dilemma with a move of almost Houdini-like ingenuity, zeroing in on something that even Grann&#39;s voluminous research couldn&#39;t shed much light on: what was that couple&#39;s relationship like? Thanks to this change in emphasis, the task of writing the script became not one of condensation but one of expansion—of filling a historical gap by means of imagination. And the way in which the couple&#39;s relationship is reimagined, as Scorsese made clear to me, embodies his own grappling with the underlying morality of Grann&#39;s tale—a responsibility to place the Osage people at the center of the story that turned out to shift the very aesthetic of the movie.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Almost all directors are also actors; they just happen to reserve their performances for their cast and crew. Some also perform in movies, their own or those of other directors; Scorsese has done both, albeit in incidental roles. In “Killers of the Flower Moon” he appears in a small but crucial dramatic role, a performance that is far more powerful than a Hitchcockian wink or a cameo to please connoisseurs. Scorsese won his Oscar at a time when the studios had already become inhospitable to his kind of large-scale yet artistically ambitious filmmaking, and the ensuing rise of superhero movies and other primarily youth-centered IP franchises made matters worse. Scorsese has leveraged his eminence to take a leading role in advocating for studios to both invest in the preservation and distribution of classic movies and release new and substantial movies by ambitious directors. In effect, he has become the face and the voice of the cause of cinematic art—past, present, and future. No spoilers, but, when he acts in “Killers,” he nonetheless speaks for himself and speaks, too, for the cinema at large.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;In person, Scorsese has a lot to say, and the fascination of what he says is heightened by his way of saying it. Just as a scene in a movie may be made of dozens of shots of diverse durations, assembled in various ways, and often ranging far in time and space and tone, so Scorsese speaks in a free-associative, quick-cut, montage-like manner that is entirely his own, building drama as the details accrete and connect with verbal counterparts to cuts, dissolves, superimpositions, and other kinds of cinematic punctuation. His conversation is the image of a mind in motion, ranging freely between memory and perception, between practical specifics and ideas, between firsthand experience and notions gleaned from watching movies—all infused, like his films, with purpose and passion. Just as “Killers of the Flower Moon” was the fastest three and a half hours of my moviegoing life, my conversation with Scorsese about it was the fastest hour of conversation I&#39;d ever experienced. Our discussion has been edited for length and clarity.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;There&#39;s something special about “Killers of the Flower Moon.” You always tell good, moving, passionate stories, but here I felt like you were doing something more than telling a story. I felt like you were bearing witness. Did you have that feeling when you were making the film? Was that part of what went into the project?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Definitely. And I think it goes back to a time in &#39;74, when I had this opportunity to spend some time, only a day or two, maybe two days, with the Oglala Lakota (Sioux) tribe, in South Dakota, and I was involved with a project that didn&#39;t work out. It was a traumatic experience, and I was so young I didn&#39;t understand. I didn&#39;t understand the damage and the poverty. I grew up with poverty in another way, which was working-class men and women on Elizabeth Street and Mott Street and Mulberry, but we also had the Bowery. So I grew up with &lt;em>;that&lt;/em>; poverty. But I never saw anything like &lt;em>;this&lt;/em>;, and I can&#39;t describe why—it was hopeless. I met some Native Americans again in LA at the time, and we talked about another project, and I saw too that this incredible fantasy that we had growing up as children was something that—even despite the wonderful attempts at righting the wrongs of the Hollywood films with “Broken Arrow,” “Drumbeat,” “Apache,” “Devil&#39;s Doorway”—all the films that were pro-Native American, there were still American white actors playing the Native Americans. But the stories were balanced toward not only who had right on their side, but also a respect for the culture, particularly in “Broken Arrow,” I thought.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;But, in any event, no, I was always aware of poverty, and I always felt I was witness to it there only for a couple of days. But culminating in the end of the Western with Sam Peckinpah, there was a new territory then: how are we to think, what are we to make of all this in terms of the Native American experience? Are they really gone? In a way, as children, we thought, Well, they&#39;re with us, but they&#39;re like us now. We were children and, I think, meant to think that way of the forced assimilation, to a certain extent, of the Native populations. But I didn&amp;#x27;t know. When I got out there and I saw what it was, it was different.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;hbfp1k&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;k6n2u&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;But from 1974 to now—it&#39;s forty-nine years. Had you been thinking of a project involving Native Americans for the entire time?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;I stayed away from it. I stayed away from it because the shock was so strong. Somehow it had to be the right story, and that&#39;s taken a long time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;How did you find David Grann&#39;s book? How did it come to you?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Oh, Rick Yorn gave it to me. Rick is my manager, and also Leo DiCaprio&#39;s manager. And, yeah, the idea of the flower moon—the flower moon is feminine and we had just worked on “Silence,” and the moon images and the sense of Jesus as the feminine side of Jesus rather than the masculine side is really important. And so, for me, the flower moon, the feminine, but the “killers of the flower moon,” the clash of that, and this landscape, which I only had in my imagination—I&#39;d never been out to the prairie. When I got out there, we were driving for so long on one road, and I wondered why we were going so slowly, and I looked at the—it was, like, forty-five minutes—I looked at this speedometer, we&#39;re doing seventy-five, and I realized this place never ends. And on either side there were no trees. You really couldn&#39;t tell how fast you were going.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;What you did with the book, I mean, not that I would ever want to teach, but if I were teaching a class on adaptation, I would show people your film and I&#39;d have them read David&#39;s book, because your transformation of the book is, to me, one of your many great achievements, because you have everything that&#39;s in the book, almost everything that&#39;s in the book, almost all the salient details of the horrors, in the film. But you reverse the perspective.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Yeah. Leo and I wanted to make a film together about this whole idea of the West and all that sort of thing. And he was going to play Tom White, the FBI agent. And so I said, I&#39;m thinking, how are we going to do this? Because I&#39;m just, not to be glib, but Tom White, in reality, was a very strong-willed man. Very, very, very disciplined, moral, straightforward. And laconic. Hardly said anything. Didn&#39;t need to say much. Now, Leo likes—I told him many times, I said, Your face is a cinema face. I said, You can do silent films. You don&#39;t need to say that or this, just your eyes do it, move, whatever you do, he just has it—but I do know he likes to speak in films.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Then I&#39;m realizing, too, who are these people? I said, These guys come in from Washington, and the moment they get off that train, the moment they enter that town, you look around and you see Bob De Niro, you see so-and-so—“I know who did it.” The audience is way ahead of us. I said, It&#39;s, like, we&#39;re going to watch two and a half hours of these guys trying to find things. That&#39;s a police procedural. In the book, it works; in the book, it works. But a police procedural, for me, I&#39;ll watch it, but I can&#39;t do it. I don&#39;t know how to do it. I don&#39;t know how to do the plot. I don&#39;t know where to put the pen. And so I said, What the hell are we going to do here? So we tried and tried and tried. Our script was over two hundred pages, and one night we had a big reading: myself and Leo and [the co-writer] Eric [Roth] and my daughter, a number of people. The first two hours, we were moving along. The second two hours, boy, is this getting a little long in the tooth, as they say. It was just getting to be—we really ran out of energy in the story, and I wanted to tell more and more of the story, and I wanted to do more digressions, to go off in tangents, so to speak, what seem like tangents, but are not.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;But at the same time, luckily I had gone out to Oklahoma a few times and the first thing I did was, I was very concerned about meeting the Osage Nation to see how we could coöperate together. I found that yes, they were concerned about trust. I got them to understand that I wanted to do the best I could with them and the story, and that they could trust me, I hoped. And they began to, but I also understood why they don&#39;t. I totally get it. And that&#39;s the story. Now here, what really is the story is that you have trust in a marriage, right? OK, there are different levels of it and there are aspects and mistakes and things, but there&#39;s trust. Well, what I was learning from the Osage was that all the families are still there. The Burkharts and the Roans, Henry Roan. What we were told by their descendants was, Don&#39;t forget this, that Ernest and Mollie were in love. Why the hell did she stay? Not &lt;em>;why&lt;/em>; did she stay with him? &lt;em>;How&lt;/em>; did she stay with him? Why one person stays with another, we don&#39;t know. “How” is another issue, another way into the story. The “how” is deception, self-deception; the “how” is love stronger than what she dares think he is doing. So this was a coverup, and yet she trusted. And so this love story, this love story. And we had met with Lily [Gladstone] through a Zoom because [the casting director] Ellen Lewis showed me Kelly Reichardt&#39;s “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/goings-on-about-town/movies/certain-women&quot;>;Certain Women&lt;/a>;.” Lily was extraordinary in it. And then Leo and her met on the Zoom because he was very concerned about who are we going to get to play this part? Obviously, she has to be Native American, and we wanted the Osage approval. They approved her, and, before they approved her, Leo had this conversation with her on Zoom, and as soon as the Zoom call was over he said, “She&#39;s amazing.” I said, ”Yeah, for many different reasons.” I think a lot of it you can see in the film; she has integrity, a sense of humor.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;ci4o99&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;There&#39;s a profundity to her and there&#39;s a sweetness, at times, of face. We felt confident that she knew more than us. She just knew it, meaning she knows the people, she understands the situation, she understands the delicacy of the confusions and, I think, the trespasses, so to speak. But in any event, after doing the reading, a week later, Leo came to me and—we still had this in our head, that they&#39;re in love. And the reality was that she didn&#39;t leave until after the trial. We had scenes in there, the FBI guys—or the Bureau guys—were saying, “How is she still with him?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;They actually said that. We have the court transcript. She&#39;s still there in the court. She&#39;s in the court. Doesn&#39;t she get it? But there was something about him and her together, and then she left him after that. And we said, Well, what was that about? And I said, What if that&#39;s the story? And Leo came to me and said—so we tried to build it in within the context of somebody else playing Ernest, and Tom White dealing with, again, the police procedural, but it overwhelmed it. The procedural overwhelmed the personal story. And Leo came to me again, he came to my house one night, a week later, and he said, “Where&#39;s the heart of the film?” I said, “Well, the heart is with her and Ernest.” He said, “Because no matter what, if I&#39;m playing Tom White, we deal with the iconic nature of the Texas Ranger.” We have seen that; it&#39;s good. Does he need to do it? How would I do it any differently? I tried. I couldn&#39;t find a way. So he looked at me and sat down and said, “Now, don&#39;t get upset.” He said, “But what if I play Ernest?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;So it was his idea to do it. Wow.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I said, “If you play Ernest and we deal with the love story, then we&#39;re at the very heart of it. We&#39;re in the the day-to-day.” I said, “You realize, of course, that means we go in the center of script, rip it open and change everything and tell the studio you want to play the other guy, and we&#39;re going to go this way, and Lily&#39;s great, and we&#39;ll rewrite the whole thing,” which is what we did.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;But “rewrite” is the wrong word. We constructed it all. Eric [Roth], me, a couple of friends helped. That&#39;s what we had done with “Casino,” too, Nick Pileggi and I, we worked from transcripts. And so I would say, “That&#39;s great over here.” And then another guy would say, “Hey, why don&#39;t we put &lt;em>;this&lt;/em>; in?” And so, cobbling and pushing and shoving, I mean, until we went into rehearsal, and then, even in rehearsal, we just kept working on it and working on it, and we had a lot with the Osage themselves, they would say things, and one guy, Wilson Pipestem, who was a lawyer, a really terrific guy, Osage, he was very concerned at first. He looked at me and said, “You don&#39;t understand, we have a certain way of life.” And he&#39;s a very strong lawyer, an activist, and he pointed out and said, “We grew up this way, we grew up that way”—he was giving me examples of things in the midst of, not a lesson, not an argument against me, but an argument for himself and for his people, saying, “This is what we are, you don&#39;t understand this. For example, when I was young, my grandmother would be in the house and all of a sudden this storm would come up and I&#39;d be running around and she&#39;d say, &#39;Nope, sit down, sit down, let the storm flow over us, the power of the storm. It&#39;s a gift from God. It&#39;s a gift from Wah&#39;Kon-Tah. Let the storm—don&#39;t move, just absorb the storm.&#39; ” And he said, “That&#39;s the way we live.” So I wrote it down. Grab from here, grab from there. And there was the end of the scene, the dinner scene with Mollie and Leo, which we had written where she said, “Would you like some whiskey?” and they drink and she drinks more than him, but she doesn&#39;t get drunk and he does. And I said, “We could do a great scene.” I said, “But there&#39;s something—what if the rain hits? What if the storm happens, without making it too ominous, the storm, but it&#39;s the power of the storm, the beauty of Wah&#39;Kon-Tah, the gift of the storm. And, in order to do that, you have to be quiet. You can&#39;t be your little coyote self.” And she controlled him that way, and he just waits.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;So that&#39;s the way it was constructed. We had fun with that because we were always finding new things, because somebody would go by and say something, or [the producer] Marianne Bower would find out a great deal. She was our connection with all the people. She&#39;d work with the different departments, different Osage technical advisers for different departments, and, well, “So-and-so said this and so-and-so said that.” “That&#39;s interesting. What is that?” “Well, you know what they normally do: the youngest member of the family walks over the coffin of the eldest who died.” Well, that&#39;s got to be, it&#39;s got to be. We have to do it.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;05b5&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;84sohh&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;So then the funeral scenes got bigger. So, in a way, what I mean by “got bigger” was that I—we even had more, but we had to narrow it down, narrow it down. Then I had the—coming from Sicilians, one of the key things, I grew up with a lot of the old people dying off. So I grew up in a lot of funeral parlors, and the old Italian ladies, the old Sicilians in black, it&#39;s like “Salvatore Giuliano,” remember? “Turiddu!” and she screams on her son—that&#39;s who we grew up with. And the son&#39;s holding the mother back and she&#39;s throwing herself in the coffin. I said, “They were talking about the wailers and the mourners.” I said, “They have mourners.” They have people who cry. So we got to do that. And when we did it, I found that—they said, “We do it in front of the house.” I said, “Great.” And I said, “Well, let&#39;s get a wide shot of it from way above.” And there was the house, there was nothing behind it, and there were these three figures, and they&#39;re wailing, and the way it sounded, well, that&#39;s great. “Don&#39;t you want a tighter shot”? I said no. He said, “I got a tighter shot, it&#39;s maybe from—” I said, “No, the shot is up here. I think it&#39;s up here because they&#39;re wailing out to Wah&#39;Kon-Tah. We see it all. And there&#39;s this little house, pathetic human beings. We&#39;re all as we are, and we&#39;re just wailing and you barely hear it.” So this is the way it was.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Your description of your discovery of the overhead shot reminds me of one of the things that&#39;s miraculous in masterworks of large-scale filmmaking, which is that it&#39;s like you&#39;re painting a painting with a paintbrush at the end of a crane, but you&#39;re not driving.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;No, I&#39;m not driving it. I would like to, I&#39;d like to drive the crane, but then I&#39;d get into all kinds of trouble. But no, I don&#39;t want the technology to limit me, meaning to get too hung up on the technology. I&#39;ve always been fighting that for years. That&#39;s why I had good relationships with a number of different directors of photography, Mike Chapman and certainly Michael Ballhaus, others I&#39;ve worked with that were terrific, but we only did one or two films together. But often I would find that many DPs love the equipment and the equipment gets in the way.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;I had a shock of a lifetime when I saw something that was put up online soon after the release of “The Wolf of Wall Street,” which is a &lt;a href=&quot;https://vimeo.com/83523133&quot;>;video made by Brainstorm Digital,&lt;/a>; a company that did some post-production work on the film. And what they showed was the footage as it appears in the film, and then the raw footage from the camera and how, by means of digital technology, by CGI, things were—a wedding scene was lifted physically off of one site and placed on another completely different background.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Oh, yeah, we did something. Yes, yes, yes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Did you find yourself needing to use a lot of CGI in the making of “Killers of the Flower Moon”?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;No, not really. Except for straightening out some landscape. For example, certain trees that weren&#39;t quite right, supposedly.We were told those trees don&#39;t necessarily belong in this part of the ground, whatever. No, we found that what [the production designer] Jack Fisk did with Pawhuska, where we shot, to make it look like Fairfax— Fairfax was about forty-five minutes away—it was like a studio. It was like we were literally going to these places. We had the storefronts reconstructed. It was like going back in time, really. We were spending a lot of time in 1921 and &#39;22.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;One of the things about this film, and, for me, your recent run of films, including “The Irishman,” is that they are ferociously political. I really get a sense of “The Irishman” as, Let me show you what&#39;s lying underneath this respectable society, and, with “Killers of the Flower Moon,” it&#39;s like lifting up the lid and saying, This is your American history. This is what you didn&#39;t learn in school. This is what our society now is built on and doesn&#39;t dare look in the face.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Exactly. Exactly. Maybe because where I came from, I saw it on street level, I think. A lot of it has to do with believing that you&#39;re right, believing you deserve it. And that&#39;s what I&#39;ve been becoming aware of in the past twenty-five, thirty years of the country based on people who formulated the country, white Protestant—English, French, Dutch, and German. And so that country was formed that way with that kind of thinking. It&#39;s European, but not Catholic, not Jewish, but the work ethic of the Protestant, which is good. It&#39;s just that that was the formation. And then the political and power structure came out of that and stays with that. It just stays with it. I also saw and experienced people close to me who were basically pretty decent, but did some bad things and were taken advantage of by law officers. So I grew up thinking there&#39;s no lawman you could trust. There was some good police, there were some good cops on the beat, nice guys. Some were not. But, from my father&#39;s world, from his generation, it was a very different experience. But this issue of—I really admire the idea of people who really get into politics for public service and are really public servants. That&#39;s really interesting. If they really serve the public.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;oys79g&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Could you make a film about one?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I don&#39;t know. One who could try, one who could try to be a good public servant. It reminds me of the line in “Black Narcissus.” The Mother Superior tells Deborah Kerr before she goes to India: Remember, the leader of them all is the servant of them all.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;I have the feeling that something changed in your work after “The Departed,” after you won the Oscar. Not that awards really matter, but that, at that point, it was like you had nothing else, whether consciously or unconsciously, nothing more to prove. And you then made a film that I consider one of your best and one of your, in the most positive sense, craziest films, “Shutter Island.”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yeah, the people are split on that one. But I like it, in the sense that every line of dialogue could mean an infinite number of things. It was really quite interesting for me, I really wanted to do it. Winning the award was—don&#39;t forget, it was thirty-seven years before an Oscar for Best Director, let alone Best Picture, which was a total surprise to me. But it&#39;s a different Academy from when I was starting. But, for me, that award was, it was inadvertent. I had made “The Departed” as a sign-off. I was leaving and just going to make some small films, I don&#39;t know. And it just happened that “The Departed” clicked. And it was a very difficult one to make, for many different reasons. That&#39;s a whole other story. But we fought our way out of it—through it, I should say. Through it, out of it. And, when I finally threw it up on the screen, people liked it. I don&#39;t mean I didn&#39;t think that it was good or bad. I just felt we had accomplished something. I didn&#39;t know it was going to be that way. I had no idea. And my next film was going to be “Silence.” That was the idea. But what came in between was “Shutter Island.” There were issues there. I did feel something—let&#39;s make, OK, now I can—let&#39;s try and make another &lt;em>;movie&lt;/em>;. And I got the script and I just fell in love with the script. Then I didn&#39;t realize, until we started working with the actors, the different levels, and I knew the levels were there, but how to perceive—how to shoot it, how to perceive the images, and also how to direct the actors.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;But the thing about it was that in a way, after “Departed,” it was like I knew I could not make films for the studios anymore, because at that time—there&#39;s no ill will between us and the people who were at the studio at the time—but, even to this day, they wanted a franchise film, and I killed off the two guys. They wanted one to live. I didn&#39;t want to make films that way. And I realized there was no way I could continue making films. And so everything since then has been independent to a certain extent since “Shutter.” The guy who took care of me was [the Paramount Pictures CEO] Brad Grey. He came in, Brad gave me “Departed,” and he agreed on “Shutter.” And so then he passed away. And, since then, it&#39;s really been independent. There&#39;s no room for me to make films through the studios that way anymore.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Well, that&#39;s been my hypothesis: that an entire generation of younger filmmakers found their second wind with independent producers, whether it&#39;s Wes Anderson or Sofia Coppola or Spike Lee.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Yeah.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;But, from your generation, you are the person who—the studio was holding you back in a certain sense. Not that you made bad films, you made wonderful films. But I kind of always felt there&#39;s more. There&#39;s a—not compromise—but there&#39;s a wall that a filmmaker hits, any filmmaker hits when they&#39;re working for the big studios.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;There&#39;s no doubt. And my thing was to explore that. And in some cases—in the case of “Last Temptation of Christ,” I had a deal at Universal. I owed them some movies; that became “Cape Fear” and “Casino,” and that was it. But by the time we did “Kundun” and “Bringing Out the Dead,” it was over.一切都结束了。 We were declared gone, “Bringing Out the Dead” only played for a few weeks. And it was a Paramount film. And that was the end. And again, [my agent, Michael] Ovitz came and kind of helped me and put together “Gangs of New York” with Leo, with [Harvey] Weinstein, and all of them. That became a whole other period of my life. I was glad when it was over, but I was obsessed with “Gangs.” I never really even finished it in my head. And I just said, OK, this obsession is over with. I still haven&#39;t, at that point, hadn&#39;t cracked the script for “Silence.” So I was ready to do a &lt;em>;movie&lt;/em>;. I wanted to work and make a film, and they had this thing called “The Aviator.” They didn&#39;t tell me what it was about. And so I started reading it, don&#39;t tell me it&#39;s Howard Hughes, because Spielberg, Warren Beatty want to do—but then I kept reading it. It&#39;s the different Howard Hughes, it&#39;s the early Howard Hughes. He flies and he&#39;s—but right here, in the meantime, he can&#39;t touch a doorknob.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;8q76ti&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;llltjm&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;That&#39;s interesting. So we did that. And, even that, that was fine. That was a terrific shoot. The editing was good, but the elements involved in the distribution caused some serious problems toward the end. I had some very, very ugly—and I decided at that point, you can&#39;t make films anymore. If this is the way I&#39;m going to have to make them, it&#39;s over. And so I said, I wanted to make this. I found the script of “The Departed” and I liked the idea and I said, “Let&#39;s just make this in the streets and let&#39;s do something.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;But that became—it turns out it was Warner Bros., which was one of the distributors of “Aviator” that we had some arguments with. And they said, “Don&#39;t worry, we&#39;ll take care of you.” But, in the meantime, it was difficult. And so, after that I said, “No more.” And so we went into “Shutter Island,” but I was able to make “Departed” pretty much the way I wanted to. But it was a knockdown, drag-out fight all the way from Day One to the end. So by that point I realized, if that&#39;s the way you&#39;re going to make a film, there&#39;s no sense anymore. So it was going to be independent films and it was going to be going into “Silence” and that sort of thing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;So did you think you were going to scale back and work on very low budgets with seven people in the street?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yes. Yes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Are you still tempted?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;I think, let me put it this way, it&#39;s into my head. Seven people could be seventy, but it&#39;s got to &lt;em>;feel&lt;/em>; like seven, because, quite honestly, I&#39;m short. I&#39;m old now. Try to get in the room with the lighting and all the cable. I have to have an assistant in front of me, taking me. I would love to be able to have the freedom of the smaller crews again, a sense of freedom. But in the case of “The Irishman,” for example, out of the question, because of the trucks, because of the CGI, and Bob [De Niro] and me, I was seventy-five. Bob was seventy-five, Al [Pacino] was seventy-seven, Joe [Pesci], I don&#39;t know what age he is. I mean, at a certain point, by the time we all get on set, they&#39;re good for a certain amount of hours.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;And if you want to say, “Hey, we&#39;re going to go down the block and shoot another scene, we&#39;re going to move all the trucks,” they need sleep. So we were kind of locked in there. But with “Killers of the Flower Moon,” by having Pawhuska to ourselves, that was quite something. Adam Sumner&#39;s a brilliant assistant director. He works with Steven Spielberg and Ridley Scott. His staging is wonderful, and the background stuff—I would say, “OK, they&#39;re going to be coming down the block here, we&#39;re going to track this way,” and, of course, it&#39;s 1921. So the background, costumes, horses, you need people doing things. It&#39;s not like shooting in New York, but we had the control. It was like a studio. We had the control. And that, in a funny way, made it feel like we were making a smaller picture.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;And we had such devotion from the Osage, from all the people working behind the camera to get the costumes right. I chose them. You could see it with [the costume designer] Jackie West. I sent black-and-white pictures everywhere, and drawings. I would circle a tie or a collar or a shoe. They would bring me stuff from the Osage and I&#39;d circle certain things. They&#39;d tell me what&#39;s right and what&#39;s wrong for certain. But, primarily, I mean buttons. I would go on—every place in the film, all the men&#39;s and women&#39;s costumes had gone through me, through to Jackie, from historical photographs and from films like “The Winning of Barbara Worth,” which I saw one night. My wife was in the hospital, it was on TV on TCM. And I think Gary Cooper&#39;s wearing the goggles in the car. It&#39;s a silent film. And so we had the goggles. Or “Blood on the Moon,” which I looked at again last night because I want to do something on TCM with it. “Blood on the Moon,” the costuming there and the brooding nature of the way they move. And Robert Mitchum, Charles McGraw, Robert Preston. Very, very important influence for this picture. So it felt free, and maybe in a way, too, because we weren&#39;t in LA, we weren&#39;t in New York. There wasn&#39;t anywhere to go. You&#39;re in a big house that I had rented and you go and make the movie, you&#39;re not going to Tulsa; you have night life in Tulsa. I was in Bartlesville, where Terry Malick grew up.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;So you&#39;re all focussed together and there&#39;s essentially nothing to think about but the movie.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The picture. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;58t3h&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 18:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[A Journalist Exposes the Philippines’ Extralegal Killings]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/news/q-and-a/a-journalist-exposes-the-philippines-extralegal-killings]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65297bbd0a152c346bc003ab/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/remnick-patricia%20evangelista.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Over the years, I&#39;ve had the honor of reading and publishing reporters who are as resilient as they are intelligent: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/katherine-boo&quot;>;Katherine Boo&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/jon-lee-anderson&quot;>;Jon Lee Anderson&lt;/a>;—I won&#39;t go on because the list is as long as it is distinguished. It is a cliché to compare such writers to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2009/04/13/a-fine-rage&quot;>;George Orwell&lt;/a>; or, more lately, with justice, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/letter-from-the-uk/a-memorial-for-the-remarkable-martha-gellhorn&quot;>;Martha Gellhorn&lt;/a>;. But, if the shoe fits . 。 。 Recently, a Filipina reporter named Patricia Evangelista came by the office, for an interview for &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://link.chtbl.com/qOucM248&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://link.chtbl.com/qOucM248&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://link.chtbl.com/qOucM248&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;The New Yorker Radio Hour&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Our topic was her new book, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Some-People-Need-Killing-Country/dp/0593133137/ref=sr_1_1?crid=1BEU0AZ5JNE3C&amp;amp;keywords=some+people+need+killing+patricia+evangelista&amp;amp;qid=1697206966&amp;amp;sprefix=some+people+need+k%2Caps%2C122&amp;amp;sr=8-1&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Some-People-Need-Killing-Country/dp/0593133137/ref=sr_1_1?crid=1BEU0AZ5JNE3C&amp;amp;keywords=some+people+need+killing+patricia+evangelista&amp;amp;qid=1697206966&amp;amp;sprefix=some+people+need+k%2Caps%2C122&amp;amp;sr=8-1&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Some-People-Need-Killing-Country/dp/0593133137/ref=sr_1_1?crid=1BEU0AZ5JNE3C&amp;amp;keywords=some+people+need+killing+patricia+evangelista&amp;amp;qid=1697206966&amp;amp;sprefix=some+people+need+k%2Caps%2C122&amp;amp;sr=8-1&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Some People Need Killing&lt;/a>;,” about the reign of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2016/11/21/when-a-populist-demagogue-takes-power&quot;>;Rodrigo Duterte&lt;/a>;. It is hardly written with Orwellian cool, but it stands next to “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Homage-Catalonia-George-Orwell/dp/0156421178&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Homage-Catalonia-George-Orwell/dp/0156421178&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Homage-Catalonia-George-Orwell/dp/0156421178&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Homage to Catalonia&lt;/a>;.” Evangelista&#39;s title comes from a vigilante, whose offhand comment to her exemplified the bloodiness of the Duterte Presidency and its extralegal drug wars. Evangelista covered the killings, which left thousands dead, for the independent news platform &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/dispatch/the-triumph-of-marcos-dynasty-disinformation-is-a-warning-to-the-us&quot;>;Rappler&lt;/a>;. The site was co-founded by the journalist &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/podcast/the-new-yorker-radio-hour/the-nobel-prize-winner-maria-ressa-on-the-turmoil-at-facebook&quot;>;Maria Ressa&lt;/a>;, who, along with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/q-and-a/how-russias-nobel-winning-newspaper-is-covering-ukraine&quot;>;Dmitry Muratov&lt;/a>;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/the-nobel-peace-prize-acknowledges-a-dangerous-era-for-journalists&quot;>;won the Nobel Peace Prize&lt;/a>; two years ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Ressa would surely be the first to say that there would have been no Nobel, and very little truth in the Duterte era, were it not for the meticulous reporting of Evangelista and others like her. Evangelista was on the street every night, surveying the horror, examining the corpses, talking to the grieving families, and prodding the police. She wrote news pieces, and she wrote longer investigations. Now, in “Some People Need Killing,” she has written a journalistic masterpiece. She is a very rare talent; our conversation below was blunt—“Can I curse?”—and open. It has been edited for length and clarity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Your book is one of the most remarkable pieces of narrative nonfiction I have read in a long, long time. But let&#39;s start with you: you were a staff writer at a newspaper in the Philippines that has a reputation for intense independence, and rare independence. Tell me how your career started.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Well, I&#39;ve been a trauma journalist for more than a decade. That means I go to places where people die. I pack my bags, I interview the survivors, I file my stories. And then I go home, to wait for the next catastrophe. I don&#39;t wait very long.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;For most of the time I spent as an investigative reporter for Rappler, I covered disasters, I covered massacres. I covered the aftermath of internal conflict. And, in 2016, a man named Rodrigo Duterte ran for the Presidency of the Philippines.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;He ran on a platform of death, and that&#39;s not an exaggeration. He promised that the fish would feed fat on the corpses of criminals. He said morticians would grow rich with a deluge of dead. He said that if your neighbor&#39;s child is an addict, to kill them yourselves. It would be a kindness to their parents.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Duterte won.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;There&#39;s not a country I can think of without a drug-addiction problem, without a drug-trafficking problem. What was Duterte running against, and why?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Well, when he ran, things were generally stable, so to speak. So it was necessary to create a spectre that he could run against. The Philippines has a drug problem, as most countries do, but comparative studies will demonstrate that we have less than half the global average when it comes to drug use.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;But that wasn&#39;t the picture Duterte painted. He painted a picture of drug dealers leaving the country in shambles. He said that every drug addict was schizophrenic, hallucinatory. That he will rape your mother and butcher your father, and, if he can&#39;t find a child to rape, he&#39;ll rape a goat. And he said, if you don&#39;t believe it, if you don&#39;t believe how terrible they are, that he would give you drugs himself. Feed them to your children, and watch them become monsters.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;He was elected in 2016.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Not a good year for democracy.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Not quite.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;How would you compare Duterte to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/donald-trump&quot;>;Donald Trump&lt;/a>;? Or would you?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Well, certainly they make &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/trumps-bloody-campaign-promises&quot;>;promises&lt;/a>;. But there are charismatic men all over the world who will make promises, who will say outrageous things, and people will laugh, and they will draw crowds. And sometimes it&#39;s funny.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Then they say more terrible things. Kill the drug addicts. And people will find that maybe a little acceptable, because they make life terrible. And then later they&#39;ll say, Kill the activists, and then kill the journalists, and then kill whoever it is. So are they similar men? Certainly in that they like the outrageous, and they like the applause, and they know how to entertain a crowd.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Perhaps one of the differences is that Duterte keeps his promises. Not all of them—he didn&#39;t end drugs in the Philippines, or criminality, or corruption; but he said, “Kill them all,” and people died.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;This is a quote, “Kill them all,” and it resounds through your book like a ghostly chorus. You used the phrase “drug pusher” in the book, but this phrase includes a number of people, including drug users.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yes. In Filipino, Duterte calls them “&lt;em>;durugistas&lt;/em>;,” meaning drug dealers, drug users, junkies. Sometimes, he even refers to people who want to protect individuals who are castigated for using drugs that way. So, it can be any sort of association.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Now tell me about Rappler, the publication you were writing for. Maria Ressa is the famous editor of it, co-winner of the Nobel Prize. Tell me about how you started working on the Duterte regime&#39;s brutality, what your daily life was like, and what kind of danger you were in day to day.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;What was good about working for Rappler was that there was no editor who said, “Step back, it&#39;s dangerous.” Maria was something like a lightning rod. When the government was angry, they directed the anger at her. Those of us in the field had the freedom to cover what we needed to cover. We were small-staffed. We had very few resources. We had two cars.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Two cars.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Two cars.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;How many people on the staff?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Reporters? Fewer than twenty.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Tiny.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Tiny. And, to answer your question, about why I started covering the drug war: we saw it coming. Early on, I was doing analysis for Rappler, looking at the narratives that the Presidential candidates were using to sell themselves. The final story I wrote before the election was called “The Rapture of Rodrigo Duterte.”And I thought I went terribly purple on that piece. The final line was: “The streets will run red if Rodrigo Duterte is elected.” And I regretted that line, because I thought it was too dramatic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;And then I was standing by the side of a road, and there was a body on the ground, and I stepped over the gutter, and the blood ran red over my boots. And then I understood. And the only way I could survive that on a daily basis was that, at the height of the drug war, when there were corpses every night, was to—&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;rnno1&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;e4om6h&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;On the streets of Manila.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;On the streets of Manila. The night shift, a group of very talented photographers and writers from everywhere, would go body to body, crime scene to crime scene. And, at the height of the killings, when there were so many, I would ask the same questions every night: Was it a body dump? Was it a salvaging? Was it by a bus? Was it a drive-by? Was the killer—&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Police reporting.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Police reporting, essentially. Was the killer a cop, or a vigilante? Were the hands bound? Was the head wrapped in tape? Was the body stuffed in a bag? Was there a gun on the ground? That sort of thing. And then you learn to develop a better checklist, so you don&#39;t miss anything.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;And then—and this is the new thing—and then you learn to stand still and listen for the screaming. That&#39;s how you find out who the family is. And then you go up to them, you apologize, you console, you keep your voice low. You ask simple questions. What was his name? When did you last see him? How did you know he was gone?&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Mostly what I asked was, Tell me a story. Tell me your story. And then tell me what happened next. And the methodology was important to me, because it kept me on the scene in my mind, and I would test it every time. If I could close my eyes and see the room or the highway, or the alley, in three hundred and sixty degrees—know where the bullet came in, how the light pitched through the window if there was a window, know that the bikini briefs were red-and-white polka dots—then it meant I could go home, and it could live in my head, and I could tell the story again.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;What&#39;s the effect on you, to do this night after night after night?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;[&lt;em>;Long pause.&lt;/em>;] I knew this question was coming; I still don&#39;t have an answer. Usually the question people ask is, How do you survive it? And I have a pretty good answer for that. It&#39;s caffeine, nicotine, and alcohol. But that&#39;s the throwaway line.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Yeah, that&#39;s the glib version.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;That&#39;s the glib version. The not-so-glib version is that it is very hard to keep my universe in place, in that I appear to be a functioning member of society. When I was filing stories, I was delivering the word count. But you pay for it. You pay for what you do.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;And I think the best explanation was something some war correspondent said before: you&#39;re not a camera, in that you take all of this in. I take all of this in, and I live with it every day; every story, every interview I never publish, lives in my head. They play back at three in the morning. And then every phone call from an unknown number, I think, Someone&#39;s going to tell me someone&#39;s dead, and it&#39;s because of something I wrote. And you can&#39;t explain why the nightmares play out the way they do. And you can&#39;t explain why sometimes you just sit there, and then your brain goes in a loop, and the loop doesn&#39;t stop. So to get that book out—I&#39;m hoping the loop may stop for a little bit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;You think the writing of it may in some way end your nightmares, and purge them.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;No. I made a mistake. I thought if I took a break from the night reporting and wrote a book, that maybe that was a safer place for my head.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Or it may have just clarified the stories.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;It clarifies the stories. And maybe it was good, because I didn&#39;t intend to write this book in the first person. This was meant to be a reportorial book, third person—here are the dead, here is what happened, here is who&#39;s responsible. But I came to understand, through the writing process, that I had to take accountability. This whole dramatic “I am an objective reporter, I write in the third person”—that&#39;s not a moral high ground. That&#39;s a failure of nerve.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Because I can tell you the worst of all of this: It&#39;s that I go to cover a story, and there&#39;s your blood on the ground, and there&#39;s all of that. And I&#39;m used to that. It&#39;s the aftermath, of going to Starbucks and getting a cappuccino. It&#39;s that I can &lt;em>;go&lt;/em>; to Starbucks and get a cappuccino. And I know, two blocks down, some family can&#39;t even afford the coffin to bury the kid in. But you have to divide your brain, because if you help one family it means you bought the story. And I feel like I&#39;m making moral judgments every step of the way. And, if I stray out of the way just one bit, I won&#39;t have control.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;And this is why I&#39;m terribly inarticulate about all of this. I try not to think about it, and I hang on by my fingertips.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;You wrote these stories again, and again, and again, as did your colleagues. And yet the drug war, to use Duterte&#39;s phrase for it—this kind of murderous, extralegal, ongoing assault—was popular.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Describe the popularity of it and why.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;What Rodrigo Duterte did was he told a story. And he started with language—and I know that I promised not to deploy profanity during your interview. But I find it very odd to sit in a polite setting, expected to be polite—&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;w2s977&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Don&#39;t be.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Speaking about the man who decided to break language. A large part of the fact-checking of the book was about discovering the nuances—of when he said “&lt;em>;putang ina&lt;/em>;,” in Filipino, did he mean “motherfucker” or “son of a bitch”? So he liked—&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;This was on national broadcast?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;This is a national broadcast. And, generally, regardless of which culture you&#39;re from, a public figure, a politician, a head of state, is not expected to deploy profanity in public speeches. And he said, Fuck that. He said Barack Obama was a son of a bitch. He said the Pope was a son of a bitch. Many people, many institutions, were sons of bitches. The European Union, the United States, journalists, the United Nations, activists, drug dealers, everyone.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;And he, like Donald Trump, discovered that that had enormous connective appeal.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Precisely. And he said many things that other Presidents never said before. He said he would kill a hundred thousand criminals when he was elected. He said he wanted to rape an Australian missionary, except he couldn&#39;t, because she was dead by the time he showed up.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;He said—I believe he wanted to be the first one there.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yes. He said journalists are legitimate targets of assassination. He said he killed cops. He killed kidnappers. He killed—&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;He himself, he personally—?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;He himself. He used that language. And then he would say, Sometimes, I only killed three. Or three hundred. Or a thousand. It doesn&#39;t matter. Because listen to the language: I killed, I shot, I saved, I ordered. I. I, Rodrigo Duterte. So it&#39;s that sort of mythology that exploded. Rodrigo Duterte, the one who will save us all.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;What did you learn about your fellow Philippine citizens? What did you learn in reporting about your country?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I learned that, inasmuch as Duterte made himself the everyman, it meant every man could be Duterte if they wanted. Duterte may have provided the language. He provided the vernacular, he provided the narrative—but we wanted it, too. We decided that some people didn&#39;t deserve to live.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;You write these stories. What effect did this have on the populace, on the country as a whole?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I hesitate to use the word “trauma,” because I&#39;m told that this is a word that is overused in general. But we&#39;re a traumatized nation, and the trouble is, in the aftermath, after six years of Duterte, we elected the son of another dictator. And we elected Duterte&#39;s daughter. So it&#39;s the dictator&#39;s son with the punisher&#39;s daughter.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Bongbong.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Bongbong Marcos. And there&#39;s no accountability there. There&#39;s no reckoning. If you don&#39;t know there are wounds, you can&#39;t fix things. So there are many children and many generations of people who will continue to believe that some people—because of some failure of virtue or some sickness or some whatever any politician says—some people do not deserve to live.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;How many people were killed? What do we know about the numbers?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I can&#39;t give you any numbers because we don&#39;t know for sure. The highest estimate is up to maybe thirty thousand. What I can tell you is that the police admit to having killed at least six thousand. And it&#39;s not like the police wandered around executing people and saying, OK, you&#39;re next on the kill list. There is a narrative, a performance of regularity behind it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;What do you mean?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In that, when Duterte said, I will kill you all, I will destroy you, he never said murder them. He said, you can kill legally because they might fight back. They will fight back. And that was the loop of the narrative. They are drug addicts; therefore, they are armed. Because they are drug addicts, they will fight back. And, if they fight back, they must die.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Now, how long has it been since you left the Philippines?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;A few months, give or take. It was recommended that it was in my best interests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;What does that mean?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;It means we don&#39;t know the risk of my having released this book. There was a security assessment, and the assessment was, Get the fuck out.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;And do you think you&#39;ll go back?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yes, absolutely. When I&#39;ll go back is not certain, but I have to go back. It&#39;s not moral patriotism or anything—that&#39;s my home. And the story is ongoing. It&#39;s not over. People are still dying on the streets. Journalists have been shot in Manila. And there are many other stories that have to be told about my country. I am a field reporter; that&#39;s where I belong. And I&#39;m also formerly Catholic—I own the guilt. How can I sit in New York when the people whose stories I told—who took the risk to tell me their stories—are sitting in shanties across the country, and might be at risk because of things they told me?&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;In the book, you describe yourself as “a citizen of a nation I cannot recognize as my own.” Do you still feel that way?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yes, but in a more nuanced fashion. I am Filipino; I take accountability for the choices we made. We voted for Duterte. I may not have, but that&#39;s under my watch as well. But I refuse to believe that this is the only possibility for my country. I don&#39;t think this is the only future possible for us.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Do I believe that journalism is the way forward?我不知道。 Because I have learned after many years to negotiate my expectations as a journalist. If I believed my stories saved lives, or changed things, I would&#39;ve stopped working. I wouldn&#39;t have been able to get up in the morning. Now all I believe is that my job is to keep a record, and that&#39;s it. And if someday that record is necessary, then it&#39;s out there.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;You don&#39;t think your stories change anything?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;No. No. Maybe—I don&#39;t know. But I can&#39;t believe they do, because, if I expect that, I will be like the rest of my country: expecting, and hopeful, and not getting anything, and breaking down in the aftermath.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;If journalism doesn&#39;t save the world—and it doesn&#39;t; we both know that—I would like to have honored the people who risked their lives to tell their stories. They didn&#39;t have to talk to me, and they did. They are living examples of what happens when autocrats and dictators rise, and we let them. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;ouhee2&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 18:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Monthly Baby-Milestone Pics That Aren’t Total B.S.]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/humor/daily-shouts/monthly-baby-milestone-pics-that-arent-total-bs]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330049a7417af1a2d87/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/baby2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Two parents looking hesitantly at their crying newborn.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f222deef1049b9cb8/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby1.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f222deef1049b9cb8/master/w_120,c_limit/baby1.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f222deef1049b9cb8/master/w_240,c_limit/baby1.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f222deef1049b9cb8/master/w_320,c_limit/baby1.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f222deef1049b9cb8/master/w_640,c_limit/baby1.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f222deef1049b9cb8/master/w_960,c_limit/baby1.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f222deef1049b9cb8/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby1.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f222deef1049b9cb8/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby1.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Birth/Zero Months&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;Hello, world! Your first breath took ours away . 。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Toddler crying and baby swaddled and sleeping.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330049a7417af1a2d87/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby2.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330049a7417af1a2d87/master/w_120,c_limit/baby2.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330049a7417af1a2d87/master/w_240,c_limit/baby2.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330049a7417af1a2d87/master/w_320,c_limit/baby2.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330049a7417af1a2d87/master/w_640,c_limit/baby2.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330049a7417af1a2d87/master/w_960,c_limit/baby2.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330049a7417af1a2d87/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby2.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330049a7417af1a2d87/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby2.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;One Month&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;We&#39;re all in love!&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Mother lying on couch with baby after breastfeeding.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330a2dd76a04bfbc90a/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby3.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330a2dd76a04bfbc90a/master/w_120,c_limit/baby3.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330a2dd76a04bfbc90a/master/w_240,c_limit/baby3.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330a2dd76a04bfbc90a/master/w_320,c_limit/baby3.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330a2dd76a04bfbc90a/master/w_640,c_limit/baby3.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330a2dd76a04bfbc90a/master/w_960,c_limit/baby3.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330a2dd76a04bfbc90a/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby3.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330a2dd76a04bfbc90a/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby3.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Two Months&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;Breast-feeding is bliss—plus, it&#39;s free!&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Mother sleeping on floor and baby in seat watching Sex and the City on TV.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330c3a50683a2af350a/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby4.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330c3a50683a2af350a/master/w_120,c_limit/baby4.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330c3a50683a2af350a/master/w_240,c_limit/baby4.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330c3a50683a2af350a/master/w_320,c_limit/baby4.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330c3a50683a2af350a/master/w_640,c_limit/baby4.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330c3a50683a2af350a/master/w_960,c_limit/baby4.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330c3a50683a2af350a/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby4.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da330c3a50683a2af350a/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby4.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Three Months&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;Cute AND curious?!?&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Toddler sister holding baby by her head.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f7fe886897d6c15dd/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby5.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f7fe886897d6c15dd/master/w_120,c_limit/baby5.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f7fe886897d6c15dd/master/w_240,c_limit/baby5.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f7fe886897d6c15dd/master/w_320,c_limit/baby5.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f7fe886897d6c15dd/master/w_640,c_limit/baby5.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f7fe886897d6c15dd/master/w_960,c_limit/baby5.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f7fe886897d6c15dd/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby5.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f7fe886897d6c15dd/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby5.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Four Months&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;Proud big sis.&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Baby sitting in soiled diaper.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f049a7417af1a2d86/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby6.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f049a7417af1a2d86/master/w_120,c_limit/baby6.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f049a7417af1a2d86/master/w_240,c_limit/baby6.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f049a7417af1a2d86/master/w_320,c_limit/baby6.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f049a7417af1a2d86/master/w_640,c_limit/baby6.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f049a7417af1a2d86/master/w_960,c_limit/baby6.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f049a7417af1a2d86/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby6.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da32f049a7417af1a2d86/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby6.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Five Months&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;Such a huge miracle in such a small person!&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Mother breastfeeding and on a Zoom call.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da331e396915a860c1834/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby7.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da331e396915a860c1834/master/w_120,c_limit/baby7.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da331e396915a860c1834/master/w_240,c_limit/baby7.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da331e396915a860c1834/master/w_320,c_limit/baby7.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da331e396915a860c1834/master/w_640,c_limit/baby7.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da331e396915a860c1834/master/w_960,c_limit/baby7.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da331e396915a860c1834/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby7.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da331e396915a860c1834/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby7.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Six Months&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;#momboss #leanin #haveitall&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Baby opening up Christmas presents.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33158a4e8bc4ae074a9/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby8.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33158a4e8bc4ae074a9/master/w_120,c_limit/baby8.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33158a4e8bc4ae074a9/master/w_240,c_limit/baby8.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33158a4e8bc4ae074a9/master/w_320,c_limit/baby8.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33158a4e8bc4ae074a9/master/w_640,c_limit/baby8.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33158a4e8bc4ae074a9/master/w_960,c_limit/baby8.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33158a4e8bc4ae074a9/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby8.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33158a4e8bc4ae074a9/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby8.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Seven Months&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;A child&#39;s smile is worth more than all the money in the world.&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Woman dressed up as Cruella de Vil and baby dressed as a dalmatian.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33258a4e8bc4ae074ab/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby9.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33258a4e8bc4ae074ab/master/w_120,c_limit/baby9.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33258a4e8bc4ae074ab/master/w_240,c_limit/baby9.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33258a4e8bc4ae074ab/master/w_320,c_limit/baby9.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33258a4e8bc4ae074ab/master/w_640,c_limit/baby9.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33258a4e8bc4ae074ab/master/w_960,c_limit/baby9.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33258a4e8bc4ae074ab/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby9.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33258a4e8bc4ae074ab/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby9.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Eight Months&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Happiness is the laughter of children.&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Baby crying in carseat.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33350dc7809a525eb42/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby10.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33350dc7809a525eb42/master/w_120,c_limit/baby10.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33350dc7809a525eb42/master/w_240,c_limit/baby10.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33350dc7809a525eb42/master/w_320,c_limit/baby10.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33350dc7809a525eb42/master/w_640,c_limit/baby10.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33350dc7809a525eb42/master/w_960,c_limit/baby10.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33350dc7809a525eb42/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby10.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da33350dc7809a525eb42/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby10.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Nine Months&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;Twinkle, twinkle, little star, do you know how loved you are?&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Baby crying in stroller.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da3326e2c178a7300bf98/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby11.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da3326e2c178a7300bf98/master/w_120,c_limit/baby11.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da3326e2c178a7300bf98/master/w_240,c_limit/baby11.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da3326e2c178a7300bf98/master/w_320,c_limit/baby11.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da3326e2c178a7300bf98/master/w_640,c_limit/baby11.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da3326e2c178a7300bf98/master/w_960,c_limit/baby11.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da3326e2c178a7300bf98/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby11.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da3326e2c178a7300bf98/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby11.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Ten Months&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;If you&#39;re happy and you know it, clap your hands!&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Closeup of baby&amp;#x27;s dirty face.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da332d1519e9981cf6bc5/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby12.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da332d1519e9981cf6bc5/master/w_120,c_limit/baby12.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da332d1519e9981cf6bc5/master/w_240,c_limit/baby12.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da332d1519e9981cf6bc5/master/w_320,c_limit/baby12.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da332d1519e9981cf6bc5/master/w_640,c_limit/baby12.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da332d1519e9981cf6bc5/master/w_960,c_limit/baby12.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da332d1519e9981cf6bc5/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby12.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da332d1519e9981cf6bc5/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby12.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Eleven Months&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;All of God&#39;s grace in one tiny face.&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A party hat birthday card teddy bear and ball.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da333d1519e9981cf6bc7/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/baby13.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da333d1519e9981cf6bc7/master/w_120,c_limit/baby13.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da333d1519e9981cf6bc7/master/w_240,c_limit/baby13.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da333d1519e9981cf6bc7/master/w_320,c_limit/baby13.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da333d1519e9981cf6bc7/master/w_640,c_limit/baby13.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da333d1519e9981cf6bc7/master/w_960,c_limit/baby13.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da333d1519e9981cf6bc7/master/w_1280,c_limit/baby13.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652da333d1519e9981cf6bc7/master/w_1600,c_limit/baby13.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;ONE YEAR!&lt;/strong>;&lt;br/>;Mommy went on a work trip and Daddy forgot about the picture thing.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 18:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Louise Glück, Remembered by Writers]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/books/page-turner/louise-gluck-remembered-by-writers]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-17T00:45:15.242Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652d944836878a543204e2e3/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/Glu%CC%88ck-Final-Photo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot; 24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508 L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H1 6V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>; &lt;span >;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d =“M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z”>;&lt; /path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot; ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;&lt;em>;Louise Glück，他为《纽约客》贡献了诗歌半个世纪，星期五去世。我们收集了认识格吕克、阅读过格吕克并与她一起研究过的作家和诗人对她的生活和作品的反思。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2005 年秋天，我报名参加了路易丝·格吕克的写作研讨会。在我们的小型文理学院，格吕克教授的形象令人生畏。我和我的同学都知道能和她在一起是一种荣幸。距离诺贝尔奖还有十多年，但我们隐约意识到她已经赢得了奖项，而且是大奖项。更重要的是，她是一位实践诗人。她在我们公司是不是很乏味？这门课的名字叫《诗歌概论》，没有任何入学条件。我们大多数人不知道什么是诗歌，并误以为花饰、华丽和杂技隐喻是诗歌形式的顶峰。也就是说，我们还是孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;然而，格吕克教授拒绝像对待孩子一样对待我们。这一事实在上课的第一周就显现出来了，当时她说我认为很时尚的诗句中有几行是“惰性的”。我原以为我知道这个词的意思，但我从未听过它被如此强烈地厌恶地使用。直到多年后，当我读到她的文章《诗人的教育》时，她在文中将“作家的基本体验”描述为“无助”，我才意识到她对页面惰性的反应源于她自己无能为力，无法做出其他回应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;写任何你想要的东西，她告诉我们。只要确保它没有死就可以了。每节课，格吕克都会从我们提交的作品中选择一首诗来大声朗读和分析。几周后，我的一首诗被选中。我不太记得这首诗的内容，只记得那是关于一对母女以及她们之间无法表达的膨胀感情。这首诗的一些特点让格吕克印象深刻。第一，“剥落的门廊秋千，嘎吱作响的微弱”这句话是一个错误；它太过分了，而且因太多的绝望而嘎吱作响，“听起来像诗”。不过，撇开这句话不谈，她发现这首诗语言的“稀疏”品质很有吸引力。这是她读过的第一本书。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;格吕克每周都会给我们布置作业。我总是让我的诗保持简单，因为我的“诗歌形式”的简单似乎让它们对格吕克有利。其中一首诗她甚至称之为“成就”，似乎没有意识到它的稀疏并不是一种风格选择，而是缺乏经验的结果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在我们上次的师生会议上，格吕克教授称我走进她的办公室。我上交的最后一首诗没有成功，她坦白地告诉我。对于这最后的作业，我决心证明我可以写出一些非常不稀疏的东西。因此，我花了相当多的时间模仿一位二十世纪著名诗人的风格，我不懂他的巴洛克诗句，因此觉得值得模仿。在格吕克教授面前，我现在看着我提交的页面。她甚至没有费心去标记它，因为正如她所说，“那里没什么东西。”当她说出这些话时，一种液体般的羞耻感涌上了我的心头。一切都结束了。我被发现了，不仅是因为我的平庸，还因为我的不正当欺骗。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;她一定还说了其他的话，但我没有听到他们的声音。我的耳朵只有听到我认为是安慰的声音才会竖起。 “我早期的一些诗不错，”她说。他们“虽然还没有完全达到目标，但已经非常接近了”。接近什么？我不敢问。然后我短暂的写作生涯中最令人困惑的事情发生了。 “当你写得更多时，你可以在假期把它们寄给我，”她说。她在记事本上写下了她的地址，然后撕下来给我。我的第一个想法是，在她交出了所有成绩后，她不可能获得报酬来阅读学生诗歌。让我震惊的第二件事是她确信我会写更多的诗，尽管最近的一首诗付出了灾难性的努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >; &lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;我从来没有给她寄过任何诗。但是，很长一段时间，她写下地址的那张纸片是我拥有的最珍贵的东西。几年过去了，渐渐地，我开始写，不是诗歌，而是一些小小的反思，这些反思变成了关于我的母亲、童年和感情的长篇文章，事实证明，这些感情无法以任何形式轻易表达。&lt;/p>;&lt;我在格吕克课堂上的时间并不标志着我作为作家的生活的开始。这几乎不标志着我对成为一个人意味着什么的概念的开始。但它让我相信，成为一个人的愿望是一场斗争，我可以在其中获得代理权。是否继续写作将是我的选择，拥抱这个选择以及写作本身的质量就是成为一名作家的原因。当我在页面上读回自己的话时，我仍然有“不完全在那里”的感觉。每次都是一场斗争，开始时的言语缓慢而沉重，如果我勤奋和耐心，就会获得一些接近生活的东西。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;创造的野心与恐惧没有区别，有时接近信念，你永远不能这样做。格吕克作为诗人的天才体现在她敏锐的理解上，即这门手艺让我们所有人回到了童年，无助且渴望掌握。作为一名教师，她同样表现出非凡的慷慨，这意味着她永远不能不诚实地告诉学生这一过程的现实。她相信，作家的生活“因渴望而变得有尊严，而不是因成就感而变得平静”。她告诉我们，你想写什么就写什么，只要确保它没有死，她知道我们肯定会写已经死的东西，但这取决于我们从那里走向何方。 —&lt;em>;范嘉阳&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然我不太确定我第一次读到路易丝·格吕克的诗，但我相信那是她的诗《Mock Orange》，在“&lt;a data-offer”中-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Morrow-Anthology-Younger-American-Poets/dp/0688034500&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot; ：“https://www.amazon.com/Morrow-Anthology-Younger-American-Poets/dp/0688034500”}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Morrow-Anthology-Younger-American- Poets/dp/0688034500&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;莫罗美国年轻诗人选集&lt;/a>;”，其中她戴着头带，目中无人，我很确定我第一次来到哪里喜欢她的工作，就在我发现她的首本书的副本时，“&lt;a data-offer-url =“https://www.amazon.com/Firstborn-American-Poetry-Louise-Gluck/dp/0912946938” data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Firstborn-American-Poetry-Louise-Gluck/dp/0912946938&quot;} “ href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Firstborn-American-Poetry-Louise-Gluck/dp/0912946938&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Firstborn&lt;/a>;。”尽管她最终不再那么欣赏这些早期的诗歌，但对我来说，这是一扇窗户，让我了解她后来的作品中只会加深的东西——即家庭、失落和神话。再后来，我的艺术界而非诗人的朋友们对格吕克书中的鲜明语言大加赞扬“&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Ararat-American-Poetry-Louise -Gluck/dp/088001248X&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Ararat-American-Poetry-Louise- Gluck/dp/088001248X&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Ararat-American-Poetry-Louise-Gluck/dp/088001248X&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;阿拉拉特山&lt;/ a>;”和“&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Wild-Iris-Louise-Gluck/dp/0880013346&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot ;ExternalLink”,“outgoingURL”:“https://www.amazon.com/Wild-Iris-Louise-Gluck/dp/0880013346”}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Wild- Iris-Louise-Gluck/dp/0880013346&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;野生鸢尾&lt;/a>;”；我刚开始接触这部作品时，就听到了他们在其华丽朴素中所听到的丰富情感。那时我还有我的父亲，但时间不够长，十九年前我失去他后，格吕克的书就在等着我——我特别认为她的诗《晚祷》是一本有用的悲伤实地指南。 “你允许我/使用泥土，”格吕克写道，最后，“我对这些藤蔓负责。”我会将其包含在“&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Art-Losing-Poems-Grief-Healing/dp/1608194663&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot ;:“ExternalLink”、“outgoingURL”:“https://www.amazon.com/Art-Losing-Poems-Grief-Healing/dp/1608194663”}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon .com/Art-Losing-Poems-Grief-Healing/dp/1608194663&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;失去的艺术&lt;/a>;，我编辑的一本挽歌。&lt;/p >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;当时我不知道“&lt;a href=&quot;https://archives.newyorker.com/newyorker/1991-11-04/flipbook/068/&quot;>;晚祷&lt; /a>;”首次出现在&lt;em>;《纽约客》&lt;/em>;上，我也没有想到我会有机会编辑，也就是说，将她的诗收录在杂志中。她寄来的诗是打印出来的，并通过普通邮件送达的。她不喜欢电子邮件，也不喜欢任何现代事物，但这只是魅力的一部分。她的诗确实是来自另一个世界的信件，我们总是渴望将它们掌握在手中。她获得诺贝尔奖的那天，对这一荣誉感到困惑——“我毫无准备，”她说——我们最近拿走了她的诗“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2020/10/ 19/song&quot;>;歌曲&lt;/a>;”，几天后在杂志上刊登。这是《纽约客》版面五十多年来出现的巅峰之作。当我们哀悼她的去世时，她的去世似乎如此突然，但她的作品就像《晚祷》中的藤蔓一样，不断更新。正如她在《歌》中所说：“然后我说我很高兴我做了梦/火还活着。” —&lt;em>;Kevin Young&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大一的时候，Louise 教我复习。这也许是一年来课堂内外的艰苦课程中最难学的一课。在我第一次提交后，当我读到她独特的半印刷、半草书的潦草字迹时，我哭了，她对我的诗“传统得无可救药”。我想，我终于达到了作为作家的极限。我很平庸，必须学会承受。后来，路易丝和我对这种青少年情感的漩涡笑了起来。我们都有一种情节剧的倾向，并且意识到这种倾向，因此对它产生怀疑，当再次面对无法消除它时，我们感到厌倦的娱乐。 （也是从她那里，我学会了如何嘲笑习惯性的错误而不容忍它们。）&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有时她会圈出一行，并将其命名为整首诗中唯一“活着”的东西。有时她会说：“这里有一些东西，但还没有出现在页面上。”我认为她对一首在各个细节上都充满活力的诗的可能性的兴奋帮助我继续尝试。我记得那种尝试，这是痛苦而缓慢的，因为写作和修改通常是痛苦而缓慢的，就像炼金术的转变一样。我记得坐在宿舍里的超长单人床上打字，然后——这就是我的记忆——突然明白了如何重新想象，而不是简单地重写。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在她对我的工作的态度中以及她自己的——在一本又一本的书中，她努力在必须抵制的界限内进行重塑，即使这些界限是不可避免地由自我所布置的——她向我展示了写作所需要的那种奉献精神：对事物的忠诚做出一个人能做出的最好的事情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当我写这篇文章时，我意识到，在教我复习的过程中，路易丝也教会了我遭受语言丧失的痛苦。虽然这很可怕，因为语言来之不易（来自世界，来自自我），但要真正创造，必须丢弃很多东西。写作需要无情的爱。因为她，我不再那么害怕重写，但我不知道如何承受失去她，即使她留下了所有的语言。 —&lt;em>;Elisa Gonzalez&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当然，她会在 10 月 13 日星期五去世。它可以与 X-Acto 刀的创造者之一的女儿相媲美。我们害怕亵渎她留下的缺席，所以我们都愚蠢地引用她的话，直觉上只有她的诗才能引起她的死亡。事实上，任何类型的写作都是困难的——有东西很少比没有好。格吕克教授没有假装忘记这一点，而是将其提炼出来，阅读她的作品不仅无法抵御写作的困难，而且无法抵御值得书写的知识。她诗中的文字就像在冰冷的溪流上摆动的占卜棒。你只能持有它们这么长时间。当我在学校时，她曾短暂担任我的教授，她的办公室位于英语大楼的最顶层。你得爬四层楼梯，然后她的门就在长长的走廊尽头，没有任何标记。尽管她总是很友善，但我们大多数人都害怕见到她。我记得的是一张小圆桌；你坐在她对面，她会拿着一支粗短的铅笔仔细阅读你扇形的书页。我的诗很少能让她继续下去，但现在，有一首诗仍然让人感觉充满了她注意力的黑暗品质。当我读到它的时候，我能感觉到她的眼睛正盯着我。 ——&lt;em>;凯蒂·沃尔德曼&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路易丝·格吕克曾经对我说，她认为美国诗人在社交场合对彼此的看法极其谨慎，但在私下却很混杂。她认为这是一个应该颠倒过来的公式。我们在电话里讨论她的文章《美国自恋》，这篇文章最近发表在《三便士评论》上。路易丝在中断两年半后刚刚重新开始写作，所以她很高兴是可以理解的。这意味着，在佛蒙特州生活多年后，她将能够在马萨诸塞州剑桥为自己构建的新生活中创作诗歌。我已经知道，长时间的沉默是她写作生活中痛苦且难以解释的一部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几周后，当我开车驶入路易丝居住的死胡同时，她正在街脚下等待。她穿着一身黑衣服，肩上挎着一个小钱包。她的头发刚洗过。我们要出去吃饭，但她想先带我看看她的公寓和花园，我从未见过，我认为这是友谊的种子正在种下的标志。路易丝住在三层楼的二楼，她那摆满书籍的小书房位于前面树顶的一个壁龛里。公寓刚刷成白色，几乎没有家具。地幔上展示着一系列日本悬付。她的卧室位于后面，俯瞰着花园，床上的床单是白色的，就像公寓的大部分一样。床脚有两只毛绒动物，食蚁兽或犰狳，路易丝告诉我特别喜欢它们，因为它们可以用微波炉加热并用作加热垫。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline- recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;在后院，她种了一个马蹄形的大花园，里面的很多东西都来自她在佛蒙特州的老花园。那里有淡粉色的茶玫瑰、深栗色的牡丹，还有一小片网状覆盖的生菜地。她告诉我卡萨布兰卡百合很快就会盛开，记得我写过一首关于它们的诗。然后我们驱车前往英曼广场，路易丝在附近一家餐馆预订了她常去的餐桌。首先，我们每人喝了一杯加州霞多丽，路易丝间歇性地往她的酒里洒了苏打水。晚餐时，她点了一碗贻贝，加额外的肉汤、大蒜和欧芹，然后是芝麻菜沙拉，不加梨、核桃或蓝纹奶酪；我点了一份沙朗牛排和蒲公英沙拉，当我们的饭菜到达时，我们分享了第二杯霞多丽。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;路易斯告诉我，写她最近的一本书，“&lt;a data-offer-url= &quot;https://www.amazon.com/Seven-Ages-Louise-Gluck/dp/0060933496&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https: //www.amazon.com/Seven-Ages-Louise-Gluck/dp/0060933496&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Seven-Ages-Louise-Gluck/dp/0060933496&quot; rel=&quot; nofollow noopener“ target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;七个时代&lt;/a>;”就像“飞翔”一样，她讲述了一位来自威廉斯敦的古典主义者朋友的故事，他做了一个梦，梦中路易丝出现了。路易丝、她的朋友和她朋友的丈夫在一栋高楼的屋顶上，路易丝告诉他们必须全部跳下去，因为如果他们这样做就不会受伤。于是，他们跳了起来，全都涅槃了。路易丝书中的最后一首诗《寓言》将这个梦重新配置为路易丝和情人：&lt;/p>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;然后我低下头，看到了&lt;br/>;我正在进入的世界，那将是我的家。&lt;br/>;我转向我的同伴，我说&lt;em>;我们在哪里？&lt;/em>;&lt;br/>;他回答&lt;em>;涅槃。&lt;/em>;&lt;br/ >;我又说了一遍&lt;em>;但是光不会给我们带来平静。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;p>;我们谈论了孤独，路易丝承认三天独处太久了很多。随着我们的谈话变得亲密起来，她侧身坐在椅子上，像小鸟或青少年一样将细长的腿折叠起来。作为一个感性主义者，她用食指擦掉盘子里的沙拉酱和果汁，然后不自觉地舔了舔。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我告诉路易丝，我认为她的新长诗《十月》最近出现在&lt; 《纽约客》非常精彩，她很高兴。这是一个由六个部分组成的抒情序列，她解释了如何首先写前两部分，而我喜欢的第三部分是最后写的：&lt;/p>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;&lt;em>;来吧对我来说，世界说。我穿着羊毛外套&lt;br/>;站在一个明亮的入口处——&lt;br/>;我终于可以说&lt;br/>;&lt;em>;很久以前：&lt;/em>;它给了我相当大的快乐。美丽&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;疗愈者、老师——&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;死亡不能伤害我&lt;br/>;比你伤害我更严重，&lt;br/>;我心爱的生命。&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;p>;“剩下的部分就像被子上的碎片一样缝在一起，”她告诉我，并补充说，这在一定程度上是为了回应她从颈部扭伤中恢复过来的反应。我说我相信身体有治愈的冲动，而且我是在一次骑自行车事故中看到自己的身体恢复过来时了解到这一点的，那次事故中我被抛到了很远的地方，在医院的床上昏迷了好几个小时。但路易丝反驳说，身体的冲动是走向崩溃和腐烂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们讨论了在工作中超越爱欲的必要性，并讨论了这种情况在职业生涯中何时发生。我们讨论了美国诗歌的当代品味，并一致认为时代精神正在发生变化，但未来如何是未知的。当我向她展示我的新系列的两种不同夹克设计时“&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Middle-Earth-Poems-Henri-Cole/dp/0374529280&quot; data-event- click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Middle-Earth-Poems-Henri-Cole/dp/0374529280&quot;}&quot; href=&quot; https://www.amazon.com/Middle-Earth-Poems-Henri-Cole/dp/0374529280&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;中土&lt;/a>;，”在将每个人靠近她之后在昏暗的灯光下，她说她更喜欢更朴素的版本。然后她告辞去洗手了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;等待她回来的时候，我想起了路易丝公寓那洁白的环境。在她的浴室里，白色的浴缸、白色的马桶、白色的底座水槽、白色的瓷砖、白色的地板、白色的橱柜和白色的垃圾桶都灯火通明，并被一面带有闪亮镀铬支架的大斜边椭圆形镜子所抵消。我想象路易丝躺在那个白色的浴缸里，就像博纳尔画中的人物一样，审视着自己的身体，漂浮在梦境或思想中，或者两者兼而有之。在那里，任何真相都逃不过她的眼睛。她的家让我想起了我在京都周边山麓参观过的日本茶馆，那里非常注重简朴和质朴。她的诗可以说受到了这种美学的影响，在这种美学中，美总是不完美的、无常的或不完整的，并且只承认三个简单的现实：没有什么是永恒的，没有什么是完成的，没有什么是完美的。这种日本美学给我们带来一种宁静的忧郁或精神上的渴望，就像路易丝的诗有时为我带来的那样——简单的词汇、戏剧性的并置、微妙的节奏和苍凉的情感。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当路易丝回到餐桌上，她问起我的感情生活，我如实回答。路易丝总是仔细听着，沉思片刻才回答。她说她认为作家必须坚强才能生存。她说她试图教导她的学生要有雄心壮志。她说她总是在倾听孤独的哀歌。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Louise 每天都会打电话给她的母亲“查看情况” ”。她的母亲九十五岁了，那天早上，当路易丝报告她去看了正牙医生时，她母亲回答说：“太棒了，亲爱的。”电视的背景声音很大，她妈妈显然误会了。她以为路易丝说过她去过“兰花食者”。路易丝很高兴并想告诉我，因为我来自“郁郁葱葱的南方，那里可能真的有吃兰花的人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有一次，在一次公开朗读会上，我听到路易丝在她的普利策奖获奖作品集《野鸢尾》是上帝的形象，当他说话时，听起来非常像她的母亲，尽管她从未告诉过她的母亲这一点。当我告诉路易丝我母亲如何使用我小时候她经常使用的法语表达方式时，例如“&lt;em>;mon&lt;/em>; &lt;em>;derrière&lt;/em>;”（“我的屁股”）和“&lt;em>;分钟” ，papillon&lt;/em>;”（“慢点，牵住你的马”）——路易丝说她的父母在日语和法语中也有一些小短语，他们过去常常叫家人吃饭等等。她讨厌它们。&lt; /p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt; div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;89kke&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;41b2r&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot; BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;晚餐后，在回家的车上，路易丝和我谈论了在幸福和爱情时期写作——她相信这是可能的。路易丝描述了很久以前的一段时光，当时她住在佛蒙特州，在婚姻中感到无比幸福，而且还能写作。我告诉她我相信爱是我们最高的使命，我希望我不会在没有经历过它的情况下死去。在她的前门，我们拥抱了。第二天早上，她飞往华盛顿，那里将有一群年轻诗人聚会，路易丝将向他们介绍他们。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们会像年轻的小鹰互相注视，”她说着，猛地关上了汽车。门关上了。 —&lt;em>;亨利·科尔&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几年前，我正在与一位女演员朋友（实际上是熟人）聊天，在谈话即将结束时，我问了一个常见的问题：她在工作吗？有什么值得她花时间的剧本吗？事实上，这位女士说，她被选去参加一部小型合奏剧，在其中她要与传说中的 K 一起演奏和对抗；这是一部由 Z 创作的电视电影，Z 是一位我们都很欣赏他作品的作家。但是，我反驳道，她这个直觉的、内在的表演者真的能和K一起表演吗？我说，虽然 K 在许多项目中都很着迷，但我一直无法找到她的伤口——我的女演员朋友立刻明白了这种感觉。作为一名完美的艺术家，她知道伤口对于创造性的内心生活至关重要，她所经历的伤害有助于她理解其他人如何生活、受苦和生存。我说，虽然 K 的相对健康可能对她的生活有好处，但这对于艺术来说并不是最好的事情，或者至少对于我感兴趣的那种艺术来说，它传达了一些站立的感觉。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当我第一次听说路易丝·格吕克去世的消息时，我想起了那段对话，在记忆中，它听起来就像一首只有路易丝·格吕克才能写的诗——她知道如何写出这种创造性的炼金术，如何体验它。炼金术是她最伟大的科目之一，就像通过受伤的自我了解性格和灵魂的真相一样。格吕克在她 2009 年的诗《蝙蝠》中写道，“有两种视觉：/看到事物，属于光学科学，与/看到超越事物的事物，/源于剥夺。”作者建议，如果我们对生活感到厌倦，我们如何才能超越我们的满足呢？在她充满电感和斯巴达风格的作品中，格吕克也专注于一首诗周围的白色空间，这种白色的光如何使她的文字变得炽热，即使我们试图阅读它们、梦想它们、歌唱它们，也超出了我们的能力范围。一首格吕克的诗听起来像是你与一个比你聪明的朋友进行过的最亲密、最有建设性的对话，她的智慧是一种礼物，她的话语是一种慈善形式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我是来找格吕克的在她职业生涯的后期，当我这样做时，我并不“喜欢”她的写作。对我来说，它感觉不像“诗”——浪漫、“狂野”——而是像视觉艺术家伊莱恩·赖切克（Elaine Reichek）缝在“世界末日壁纸”中的线条。事实上，我认为有些诗作为视觉对象会更能引起共鸣——至少对我来说是这样。可以挂在墙上并从远处研究的东西——我在格吕克的诗句中感受到的距离。但当我读到她的最后一卷时，“&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Winter-Recipes-Collective-Louise-Gl%C3%BCck/dp/037460410X” data-event- click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Winter-Recipes-Collective-Louise-Gl%C3%BCck/dp/037460410X&quot;} &quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Winter-Recipes-Collective-Louise-Gl%C3%BCck/dp/037460410X&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;来自集体的冬季食谱&lt; /a>;”（2021），我开始理解为什么格吕克使用相对简单的语言来抓住事物的核心：赢得她的诗歌的结局。她似乎并没有兴趣完成一首诗来放手；她只是想把它写完。相反，她想要朝着结论的&lt;em>;声音&lt;/em>;前进，乡村教堂的钟声宣布一天的结束和另一天的开始。例如，格吕克在《冬季食谱》中的诗《夜间思考》带领我们踏上了一段关于自我的探究之旅：&lt;/p>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;很久以前我出生了。&lt;br/>;已经没有人&lt;br/>;记得我小时候的事了。&lt;br/>;我是个好孩子吗？ &lt;br/>;坏？除了在我的脑海里&lt;br/>;争论现在&lt;br/>;永远沉默了。&lt;br/>;什么构成&lt;br/>;坏孩子，我想知道。绞痛&lt;br/>;我妈妈说，这意味着&lt;br/>;它哭了很多次。&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;p>;当然，“它”是格吕克，也不是格吕克：她可能患有肠绞痛，但还有许多其他患有肠绞痛的婴儿，这是一个婴儿的世界。然而，在这首诗的结尾，格吕克变成了一个“我”，一个自己的婴儿：&lt;/p>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;多么遗憾我变得&lt;br/>;言语，没有联系&lt;br />;那个记忆。我母亲的爱！&lt;br/>;我很快就显现出&lt;br/>;真正的自我，&lt;br/>;坚强但酸涩，&lt;br/>;就像闹钟一样。&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>; &lt;p>;坚固但酸涩，就像闹钟一样，会发出烦躁的噪音。而且，当我第一次读到这首诗时，我不仅听到了钟声，还听到了钟声。我在格吕克的描述中感受到了幽默，他对身体和心灵的成长和成长超越了“母养”。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;我当我开始认真阅读格吕克的作品时，我对她的生活知之甚少。无论如何，一开始我从来不会被诗人的传记所吸引：他们是谁的声音和韵律——构成他们灵魂的东西——都存在于作品中，连同他们的伤口。碰巧，受益于精神分析的格吕克并没有回避直接的自传，尤其是在她的哲学散文中。尽管她被认为是一位忏悔诗人，就像罗伯特·洛厄尔和西尔维娅·普拉斯一样，在她职业生涯的早期，我不得不说，我越来越喜欢她的写作，部分原因是她在内心深处隐藏着多少东西。它。很难找到与生活相符的隐喻，但格吕克却一次又一次地做到了这一点。在格吕克出生之前，有一个姐姐，但她去世了，让格吕克在她还不知道这意味着什么之前就失去了亲人。她一生都与一个她诗人无法摆脱的幽灵生活在一起。我们在格吕克 1975 年的非凡作品《黑暗中的格蕾特》中看到和感受到的正是这种令人难以忘怀的感觉，其中部分内容是：&lt;/p>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;这就是我们想要的世界。&lt;br/ >;所有愿意看到我们死的人都死了。 I hear the witch&#39;s cry&lt;br/>;break in the moonlight through a sheet&lt;br/>;of sugar: God rewards.&lt;br/>;Her tongue shrivels into gas. 。 。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;No one remembers. Even you, my brother,&lt;br/>;summer afternoons you look at me though&lt;br/>;you meant to leave,&lt;br/>;as though it never happened.&lt;br/>;But I killed for you. I see armed firs,&lt;br/>;the spires of that gleaming kiln come back, come back&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;Nights I turn to you to hold me&lt;br/>;but you are not there.&lt;br/>;Am I alone? Spies&lt;br/>;hiss in the stillness, Hansel,&lt;br/>;we are there still and it is real, real,&lt;br/>;that black forest and the fire in earnest.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;p >;To turn to someone who is not there is to know something about both deprivation and hope. When Glück wishes for something that is not there, how can she will it to be present? Through words and their failures. From her 1989 lecture “The Education of the Poet”:&lt;/p>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;The fundamental experience of the writer is helplessness. This does not mean to distinguish writing from being alive: it means to correct the fantasy that creative work is an ongoing record of the triumph of volition, that the writer is someone who has the good luck to be able to do what he or she wishes to do: to confidently and regularly imprint his being on a sheet of paper. But writing is not decanting of personality. And most writers spend much of their time in various kinds of torment: wanting to write, being unable to write; wanting to write differently, being unable to write differently. 。 。 。 [The writer&#39;s life] is dignified, I think by yearning, not made serene by sensations of achievement.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;ik095q&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;In other words, writing heals nothing: it only reopens a wound as you try—in vain—to dress it. Writers are not nature; we do not regenerate and grow again. But we can rise, crooked and beautiful, as we try to describe what nature does to us, which is one of the themes of Glück&#39;s 1992 collection “The Wild Iris.” In that book, Glück gives the wounded and wounding earth—and all that grows in it—a voice. From “Daisies”:&lt;/p>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;. 。 。 It is&lt;br/>;not modern enough, the sound the wind makes&lt;br/>;stirring a meadow of daisies: the mind&lt;br/>;cannot shine following it. And the mind&lt;br/>;wants to shine, plainly, as&lt;br/>;machines shine, and not&lt;br/>;grow deep, as, for example, roots. It is very touching,&lt;br/>;all the same, to see you cautiously&lt;br/>;approaching the meadow&#39;s border in early morning&lt;br/>;when no one could possibly&lt;br/>;be watching you.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;p >;Sometimes, while reading Glück, I am reminded of this comment by Diane Arbus, to whose photographs of the real and imagined self Glück&#39;s poems—or, more precisely, her ethos as an artist—can sometimes bear an uncanny resemblance. Describing the experience of taking photographs at a nudist camp in New Jersey, Arbus recalled:&lt;/p>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;I mean there&#39;d be an empty pop bottle or a rust bobby pin—the lake bottom oozes mud in a particularly nasty way and the outhouse smells, the woods look mangy. It gets to seem as if way back in the Garden of Eden after the Fall, Adam and Eve had begged the Lord to forgive them and He, in His boundless exasperation, had said, “All right, then. Stay. Stay in the Garden. Get civilized. Procreate. Muck it up.” And they did.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;p >;In her poems, Glück describes how the landscape we&#39;ve mucked up is just another manifestation of our loneliness, and how we try to fill that loneliness with some spiritual value beyond ourselves. Can that spirit hear us? Or is it too late? The earth in “The Wild Iris” also helps the poet reckon with death, with how the life we&#39;re given is the life that must be taken away, in order for the world to blossom (if it can). In “Heaven and Earth,” Glück writes:&lt;/p>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;Where one finishes, the other begins. 。 。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;The extremes are easy. Only&lt;br/>;the middle is a puzzle. Midsummer—&lt;br/>;everything is possible.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;Meaning: never again will life end.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;p >;Never will imagery like Glück&#39;s end. It will last as long as death still grows in the moist and not holy earth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;—&lt;em>;Hilton Als&lt;/em>; ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;dm652f&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 09:06:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[New High-Stakes Dating Shows You Won’t Want to Miss]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/humor/daily-shouts/new-high-stakes-dating-shows-you-wont-want-to-miss]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16T21:11:54.376Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6529cd6fea7c98fc2f5ea20f/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Shouts-Dating-Shows-1016-23.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;If you never skip an episode of “Love Island” but feel like the contestants don&#39;t have enough to lose, or if you wish the cash prize on “Too Hot to Handle” required a little more risk-taking to win, then you&#39;ll love our new lineup of high-stakes dating shows! Coming soon to a streaming service near you.&lt;/p>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;4&quot; >;“Heart to Heart”&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Hot young singles looking for love and a heart transplant arrive on an island, ready to party. But there&#39;s a catch! The winner gets a new heart only if they find their soulmate. Everyone else goes home empty-handed. Good luck, young paramours!&lt;/p>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;4&quot; >;“Billionaire Beach”&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Ten bachelors and ten bachelorettes live on a beach together.收获是什么？ One of the bachelors is a billionaire, and &lt;em>;everyone&#39;s&lt;/em>; trying to end up with him. The other catch? The billionaire decides to retreat to his own separate, private beach. They never see him again. Also, they all have to pay for this “vacation.” The billionaire does not.&lt;/p>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;4&quot; >;“Love Is BlA.I.nd”&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Single men and women go on virtual dates and look for love online with the goal of getting engaged before ever meeting in person. The twist: all but one of them is an artificial-intelligence chatbot. Get ready for one lonely human to meet their soulmate . 。 。 and then grapple with the fact that they&#39;re not even real.&lt;/p>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;4&quot; >;“Pension Peninsula”&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Two dozen auto workers spend a month living together at a beautiful resort. The only rule? No touching! If one of them even pecks another one on the cheek, they all lose their pensions. (They are not told about the one rule.)&lt;/p>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;4&quot; >;“Tropical Treason”&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Fit, fun hotties from all over the world get dropped off in the tropics. Each of them is given a sealed envelope they can open and read aloud only once—to the person they believe to be their one true love! Unfortunately, each card contains one of their nation&#39;s most highly guarded secrets. In the finale, they are all tried for treason.&lt;/p>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;4&quot; >;“Archenemy Archipelago”&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;People who have hated one another for their entire lives are stranded on a group of unclaimed islands. There are no laws. Whoever makes it to the end of the season can leave the show and try to find a love that&#39;s as powerful as the connection they felt with the one person they despise most in this world.&lt;/p>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;4&quot; >;“A Date with Debt-stiny”&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;A group of thirtysomethings are paired with people they believe to be their scientifically proven soulmates. But they&#39;re in for a surprise—those soulmates are also their debt collectors.&lt;/p>;&lt;div role=&quot;heading&quot; aria-level=&quot;4&quot; >;“You and Who?”&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;You&#39;re on this show now. Yes, you. The one reading this. You&#39;re being filmed and your life is being broadcast all around the world. You have two weeks to fall in love. We won&#39;t stop watching you until you&#39;ve done so. Have fun! ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;This is drawn from“&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/This-Wont-Help-Proposals-Apocalypse/dp/1615199993&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/This-Wont-Help-Proposals-Apocalypse/dp/1615199993&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/This-Wont-Help-Proposals-Apocalypse/dp/1615199993&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;This Won&#39;t Help: Modest Proposals for a More Enjoyable Apocalypse&lt;/a>;.”&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;1pq3m5&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;phvgbr&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 07:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Nanci Griffith’s Lone Star State of Mind]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/listening-booth/nanci-griffiths-lone-star-state-of-mind]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16T20:47:58.509Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652996db55cb8e4a802ed65e/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/syme-nanci%20griffith.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >; &lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox= &quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312 L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4 H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存这个故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width =&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>; &lt;路径 d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M 23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt; /svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt; div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;出生于德克萨斯州的歌手兼作曲家 Nanci Griffith 的声音是一种“后天的品味”，因为一位评论家在格里菲斯两年前去世（享年六十八岁）后如此评价。对我来说，格里菲斯独特的声音——妖艳的少女气息，咄咄逼人的甜美，高亢而颤抖的音调几乎像羔羊一样——就像一顿家常饭菜一样令人安慰，但这很可能是因为我在意识到格里菲斯的歌声之前就已经喜欢上了它。一种小众的乐趣。从我出生起，我母亲就给我播放南奇·格里菲斯 (Nanci Griffith) 的唱片；格里菲斯过去是、现在仍然是她最喜欢的歌手，因此通过继承，她成为了我的歌手之一。我最早的听觉记忆是在公路旅行中听格里菲斯的唱片——后来我发现这种经历在南方或西方长大的千禧一代中很常见。格里菲斯的歌曲大多是关于汽车电影院和廉价商店小说的温柔、浪漫的小调，具有广泛的吸引力，但似乎对十九世纪八九十年代的某种郊区婴儿潮一代妈妈有特殊的吸引力，她们在格里菲斯的高潮中得到安慰。 - 女人咕咕地谈论孤独、长途驾驶和失去的爱情。最近，当我与 32 岁的创作型歌手萨拉·雅罗斯 (Sarah Jarosz) 交谈时，她出现在一张新的致敬唱片《不止是耳语：庆祝南奇·格里菲斯的音乐》中，该唱片由 Rounder Records 发行了黑胶唱片， 10 月 13 日，她告诉我，她和父母一起开车旅行时也听过格里菲斯的音乐。 “当时我还没有真正理解歌词的含义，”雅罗斯说。 “但音乐仍然萦绕在我的心头。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这张致敬专辑最初是由前 Rounder Records 总裁 John P. Strohm 在格里菲斯去世前构思的。它现在作为一种音乐纪念馆。 Jarosz 演唱了《More Than a Whisper》中的第一首歌：一首温柔的民谣歌曲，翻唱自 Griffith 1982 年第二张专辑《Poet in My Window》中的民谣《You Can&#39;t Go Home Again》。 Jarosz 在德克萨斯州温伯利长大，距离格里菲斯的家乡奥斯汀不远，她告诉我，当她从格里菲斯的二十多张唱片的深厚目录中选择要翻唱的歌曲时，她选择了这首歌，因为她父母对这首歌的喜爱。格里菲斯以她最喜欢的作家之一托马斯·沃尔夫 (Thomas Wolfe) 于 1940 年出版的一本遗作小说命名了这首歌，她经常在专辑内注中感谢他。知道这一点后，雅罗斯的父母有一次带着一本小说去参加南奇·格里菲斯在奥斯汀仙人掌咖啡馆举行的音乐会，并恳求这位歌手在这本书上签名。格里菲斯在上面写道：“南奇，再次回家。”这本书成为了一种传家宝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这段铭文的一个讽刺之处在于，格里菲斯很少有宾至如归的感觉，无论是在德克萨斯州还是在音乐中，格里菲斯的唱片所捕捉到的怀旧的地方感也是如此。行业。她的长期制作人兼合作者吉姆·鲁尼在最近的一次电话中告诉我，“我认为她长期感到不受重视。”格里菲斯于 2021 年 8 月 13 日去世时，她正在田纳西州纳什维尔过着隐居的生活。她已经九年多没有录制专辑了，也有七年多没有演出了。她的管理层仅解释说，她死于“自然原因”，格里菲斯本人要求在她去世一周后才发表正式声明。一周过去了，没有任何进一步的声明出现。粉丝们纷纷猜测。她曾两次与癌症作斗争，据她自己承认，多年来她一直在与严重的抑郁症作斗争，正如她曾经告诉记者的那样，这种抑郁症有时会导致“酗酒、服用各种药片、做任何会让我情绪低落的事情”。离开那堵墙。”她在晚年的生活中一直在培养一种严格保护自己的隐私并培养一种疏离感。 “她身上有一种非常孤独的性格，”鲁尼说。 “这并不是因为其他人不喜欢她的工作。”他补充道，“这对我来说是她晚年最难处理的事情——这个信息似乎没有传达给她。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鲁尼制作了出现在“”中的三首歌曲。不仅仅是耳语”，但在她去世后不久，他也发现自己承担了一个规模更大的格里菲斯项目。令他惊讶的是，格里菲斯给他留下了她前三张唱片的母版，以及一本未出版的小说《两个善良的心》的手稿，该小说讲述了一个来自德克萨斯州的女孩离开该州去寻找冒险的故事。八月，他自行出版了这本书，并通过 Craft Records 发行了格里菲斯前四张专辑的精美新盒装重新发行版：“There&#39;s a Light BeyondThese Woods”（1978）、“Poet in My Window”（1982） 、《千载难逢》(1985)和《最后的忠实信徒》(1986)。除了监督音频的忠实重制外，最初制作“蓝月亮”和“真正信徒”的鲁尼还整理了格里菲斯早年的广泛口述历史，以配合该收藏。通过一系列的采访，一个年轻、乐观、雄心勃勃、善于合作、善于交际的格里菲斯出现了——尽管她顽强的孤独从一开始就很明显。十九世纪七十年代末，格里菲斯从奥斯汀搬到休斯敦后不久，乔伊·勒沃伦 (Joy Lewallen) 与她当时的丈夫、歌手兼作曲家埃里克·泰勒 (Eric Taylor) 成了朋友。安德森博览会 (Anderson Fair) 的一张桌子，这家餐厅后来成为休斯顿民谣音乐的中心，汤斯·范·赞特 (Townes Van Zandt) 和露辛达·威廉姆斯 (Lucinda Williams) 等人经常光顾。 “南奇会在一个角落里，吃一盘意大利面，喝着 Shiner 或 Lone Star，创作一首歌，”勒瓦伦回忆道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鲁尼将重新发行的套装称为“在角落里工作，这也是格里菲斯二十八岁时发行的第二张专辑中的一首歌曲的标题。他告诉我，他的意思是这个标题充满希望，是对一位新兴艺术家的职业道德的认可。但他也表示，就像格里菲斯的同名曲子一样，它带有一丝忧郁的色彩。这首歌也许是她录制过的我最喜欢的歌曲，是一首优美的、精简的原声哀歌——只有格里菲斯和她的吉他，以及在空灵的甜美和喉音之间摇摆的声音。格里菲斯唱的是一位职业音乐家独自旅行，带着一杯威士忌和陌生人作为她唯一的同伴。这是音乐家在夜幕降临时，当离开酒吧的掉队者呼喊着再唱一首歌时，演奏的那种泪流满面的曲子。对我来说，它几乎总是能引起大哭。我最喜欢的诗句是最后一首，格里菲斯唱道：“早上五点的这些城市街道/我会停下来给你打电话/但我快到家了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在纸面上，当格里菲斯十二岁时第一次在奥斯汀咖啡馆唱歌时，她所取得的成就似乎是不可救药的牵强附会。她二十四岁时在独立厂牌 BF Deal 录制了她的第一张专辑，并在不到十年后与纳什维尔主要厂牌 MCA 签约。 1994 年，她凭借翻唱唱片《Other Voices, Other Rooms》荣获格莱美最佳当代民谣专辑奖。她与 Emmylou Harris、&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/postscript/john-prines-perfect-songs&quot;>;John Prine&lt;/a>;、Don McLean、&lt;a href =&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2022/03/28/retirement-the-margaritaville-way&quot;>;吉米·巴菲特&lt;/a>;、阿洛·格思里，甚至是她儿时的偶像之一，民谣歌手&lt; a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/culture-desk/how-odetta-revolutionized-folk-music&quot;>;奥德塔&lt;/a>;。尽管如此，格里菲斯常常对自己在音乐界的地位感到不安。她对一名记者说，一位马华高管告诉她，“我永远不会上电台，因为我的声音会伤害人们的耳朵。”尽管她是爱尔兰真正的明星，她 1987 年版本的朱莉·戈尔德 (Julie Gold) 的歌曲《From a Distance》在爱尔兰名列前十，但她有时也表示感觉自己被美国音乐界的其他艺术家所掩盖。贝蒂·米德勒最终使《From a Distance》在美国红极一时，格里菲斯允许崭露头角的乡村明星凯西·马蒂亚翻唱她的歌曲《Love at the Five and Dime》。两个版本于同一年发布；格里菲斯的原作没有上榜，而马蒂亚的则排名第三。格里菲斯可能对记者很敏感。 1998年，她给德克萨斯州的几家报纸写了一封愤怒的公开信，痛斥这些报纸的批评者，因为她认为德克萨斯州媒体普遍蔑视她的工作。她在信中写道：“我始终感到自豪，也知道伟大的事物来自我的祖国——很少有人能回到那里。”这封信刊登在《休斯敦纪事报》和《休斯敦纪事报》上。奥斯汀&lt;em>;纪事&lt;/em>;。 “毕竟，德克萨斯州是地球上唯一真正吃掉幼崽的地方。”格里菲斯在信中将自己与作家凯瑟琳·安妮·波特进行了比较，后者出生于德克萨斯州印第安河，但一生的大部分时间都在格林威治村、墨西哥和欧洲等地的波西米亚飞地中度过。格里菲斯在谈到波特时写道：“她也有摆脱困境的智慧。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;格里菲斯经历的部分原因是时机问题。她另类的、自我意识的艺术审美——更像是史蒂夫·尼克斯而不是塔米·怀内特——也许能让格里菲斯成为一名可行的流行歌星，但她搬到纳什维尔的时期正值音乐家史蒂夫·厄尔称之为“巨大的可信度恐慌”的时期。让威利·尼尔森和梅尔·哈格德成名的“都市牛仔”时代已经结束，许多乡村音乐巨星——肯尼·罗杰斯、琳达·朗斯塔特和阿拉巴马——正在跨入主流。纳什维尔的高管们不愿意因为流行电台而失去更多的艺术家，因此急于签下一批更坚韧、更锋芒毕露的艺术家，如厄尔、莱尔·洛维特、kd lang 和瑞奇·斯卡格斯。格里菲斯是乡村音乐界中一位善于交际的人，造就了许多这样的艺术家——在年轻的莱尔·洛维特为他的大学报纸采访了她之后，她邀请他在安德森博览会的舞台上表演——但她温柔的歌曲让她显得格格不入。与她的强硬的同龄人。她经常穿着碎花麻袋连衣裙和短袜，抱着或坐在她最喜欢的书之一（拉里·麦克默特里（Larry McMurtry）的《孤独的鸽子》、尤多拉·韦尔蒂（Eudora Welty）的《三角洲婚礼》）旁边，为专辑封面摆出姿势。她以大学新生的热情将自己的专辑献给作家和艺术家，并在专辑附注中感谢卡森·麦卡勒斯和杜鲁门·卡波特。在她的不止一张专辑中，她把巨大的母鹿眼睛向上倾斜，好像她在努力不哭。在 MCA，她开始在乡村部门录音，但最终转入流行部门，五年后退出。她的唱片公司和评论界似乎都不确定该把她的音乐放在哪里。在《德克萨斯月刊》的一篇长文中，迈克尔·霍尔写道，一些乡村音乐守门人认为她是“贺卡民谣”和“假天真”。&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;格里菲斯的疏离感被证明是她艺术的一个生成主题。 1982年她和泰勒离婚后，她再也没有结婚，没有孩子，在晚年的大部分时间里，她选择独自生活。在她 1991 年同名专辑中最著名的歌曲之一“Late Night Grande Hotel”中，格里菲斯用一种近乎令人陶醉的依恋感唱出了她有目的的孤独感：&lt;/p>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;也许你在想&lt;br/>;你以为你很了解我&lt;br/>;但没有人知道别人的心&lt;br/>;在这家深夜的豪华酒店里我感觉自己像嘉宝&lt;br/ >;因为独自生活是我做得最好的事情。&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;p>;尽管格里菲斯表现出可爱的天真，但她写的歌词表明了深刻的自我意识。在一首歌中，她唱道：“你永远不会拥抱我/我不喜欢被拥抱。”另一个人写道：“半夜电话铃声响起/我把床单拉高/如果我开灯它会停止叫声吗？ /我害怕这里的这些阴影/因为我的过去真的很可怕。”她轻松活泼的风格可以给她歌词的悲伤带来一种偷偷摸摸的力量。她最朗朗上口的歌曲《听广播》讲述的是一个女人头也不回地开车离开家庭生活的故事，配上欢快的小酒馆低音线。 “当你找不到朋友时，”她以欢快的副歌唱道，“你仍然有收音机。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;迈克尔·霍尔 (Michael Hall) 在他 1999 年的文章中指出，她的批评者引用了她的日记写作风格，“在依赖真实性的体裁中看到虚假的东西。”我看到的是一位艺术家试图记录富有想象力的女孩的内心生活。事实上，她唱的歌曲讲述了迅速发展的友谊、蓝月亮的魔力以及迷失在廉价商店的小说中，这一事实并不让我觉得虚伪，而是让我感到振奋，超前于时代。格里菲斯的歌词可以被理解为泰勒·斯威夫特日记歌曲创作的先驱。斯威夫特 2009 年首张专辑中的《I&#39;m Only Me When I&#39;m With You》中唱到了她与密友躺在星空下的情景，这首歌曲的前身是《There&#39;s a Light BeyondThese Woods》（玛丽·玛格丽特） ”，这是格里菲斯首张唱片中一首令人难以忘怀的自传体歌曲。在歌曲中，格里菲斯唱到了她儿时最好的朋友，她和他一起在奥斯汀长大，幻想着成为音乐家并离开小镇。 “我们去纽约吧，玛格丽特！”她在唱歌。 “我们会躲在地铁里/喝诗人的酒。”然后玛格丽特与丈夫和家庭安定下来，格里菲斯必须把她抛在身后：&lt;/p>;&lt;blockquote >;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;那么我们十岁时，在我们的树林之外发出的光芒又如何呢？&lt; br/>;那时你是个漫步者。&lt;br/>;我们计划的幻想，好吧，玛吉，&lt;br/>;我现在正在实现它们。&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/blockquote>;&lt;p>;Sarah Jarosz告诉我她几乎考虑选择“There&#39;s a Light BeyondThese Woods (Mary Margaret)”作为她对致敬专辑的贡献。 “这首歌让我心碎，”她说。除了她珍贵的书铭文之外，促使她选择《你不能再回家》的原因还在于它的副歌——“这个老镇从来没有真正关心过我/我不知道为什么我总是来这里在我的梦中”——这呼应了雅罗斯自己对于从德克萨斯州搬到纳什维尔，以及作为一名试图在这个行业规划自己的道路的女性的矛盾感受。 “南奇是一位艺术家的典范，她无法被描述，也无法被归类，并且可以同时成为多种事物，”她说。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;在重新发行的套装和致敬专辑之间——其中包括格里菲斯的同龄人，例如莱尔·洛维特 (Lyle Lovett)，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/culture-desk/iris-dements-new-album-is-a-sutain-political-statement&quot;>;Iris DeMent&lt;/a>; 、艾米卢·哈里斯 (Emmylou Harris) 以及民间领域的年轻艺术家，包括亚伦·李·塔斯詹 (Aaron Lee Tasjan) 和莫莉·塔特尔 (Molly Tuttle)——我们正处于格里菲斯的复兴之中。她没能活着看到这一切，但她在死前确实听到了一首致敬歌曲。 2019 年 12 月，吉姆·鲁尼 (Jim Rooney) 到她家为她播放翻唱的《Love at the Five and Dime》，这首歌曲是他制作的约翰·普林 (John Prine) 与肯塔基州冉冉升起的歌手凯尔西·沃尔登 (Kelsey Waldon) 的二重唱。当天他拜访了普莱恩，给他播放了录音。这是鲁尼最后一次见到这两位艺术家。但令他感到鼓舞的是，格里菲斯可能是个难听的听众，但她似乎很喜欢她的老歌的新演绎。他告诉我，当普莱恩和沃尔登低吟着副歌时，“跳舞离我近一点，现在跳舞近一点/今晚跳舞近一点，”格里菲斯的脸上露出了微笑。 “在我看来，凯尔西让她想起了自己，”鲁尼说，“当她年轻的时候。” ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;n4rihe&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; >;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;xqckdb&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt; div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ side>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live= “礼貌” aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/文章>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 05:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[A Russian Journalist’s Pained Love for Her Country]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/news/persons-of-interest/a-russian-journalists-pained-love-for-her-country]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16T20:01:27.238Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652983c110114da26d9e58ae/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/Yaffa_Elena.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt; div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2. 95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/s vg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存这个故事&lt;/ span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span>;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d= “M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d =“M23 3” H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Elena Kostyuchenko 五岁时，在距离莫斯科一百七十英里的省级城市雅罗斯拉夫尔，她和母亲共用的房间的一角被一台屏幕凸出、图像模糊的电视机占据。科斯秋琴科被迷住了。她用手指掸去照片上的灰尘。 “感觉就像轻柔地触摸飞蛾的翅膀，”她在“&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Love-Russia-Reporting-Lost-Country/dp /0593655265&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Love-Russia-Reporting-Lost-Country/dp/ 0593655265&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Love-Russia-Reporting-Lost-Country/dp/0593655265&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;我爱俄罗斯&lt;/a>; ”，贝拉·沙耶维奇 (Bela Shayevich) 和伊洛娜·亚日宾·查瓦斯 (Ilona Yazhbin Chavasse) 翻译并于本月出版的回忆录和报告文学集。后来，十几岁的时候，科斯尤琴科在学校图书馆发现了报纸。 “我对它们着迷——这些图片没有改变，你可以一边阅读一边思考，”她写道。 “我决定去一份工作。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kostyuchenko 最梦想工作的报纸是 &lt;em>;Novaya Gazeta&lt;/em>;，其中 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker .com/magazine/2009/03/23/the-accused&quot;>;安娜·波利特科夫斯卡娅&lt;/a>;，一位无所畏惧、受人尊敬的记者，提交的快件讲述了俄罗斯车臣战争的残酷真相。科斯尤琴科描述了看到波利特科夫斯卡娅文章的感受。 “我感觉自己发烧了，”她写道。 “结果我对我的国家一无所知。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2005 年，科斯尤琴科开始在《新报》实习，蹑手蹑脚地走进波利特科夫斯卡娅的办公室，把苹果放在她身上桌子。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/vladimir-putin&quot;>;弗拉基米尔·普京&lt;/a>;是新任总统，高油价推动了消费繁荣。但科斯秋琴科对冲锋陷阵的俄罗斯更感兴趣，而不是被抛在后面的俄罗斯，一个被创伤和迷失方向所定义的地方，或者更确切地说，一个民族，但也有坚韧和决心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于早期的一篇作品，科斯秋琴科在路边的一家妓院“市场”闲逛了一晚，观察性工作者和她们的顾客如何争吵、纵容、讨好、对待——以及虐待——彼此。另一方面，她在莫斯科北郊一家未完工的医院废墟中徘徊，该医院已成为不合群的青少年和其他迷失或被抛弃的人的圣地。她描述了一位这样的流浪者，他来到这里寻找神秘的邂逅，结果却在空荡荡的电梯井里被头撞了。他气呼呼地离开，宣称：“灵魂拒绝了我。”对于科斯尤琴科来说，这是一个熟悉的俄罗斯，不复杂，不富有，也不强大，但正如她的书名所暗示的那样，她热爱——而且仍然如此。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你知道你拥有什么样的爱为了你的手，或者你的腿，”科斯图琴科最近在柏林告诉我，她去年搬到了那里。 “或者为了你的家，或者你的家人。最重要的是，这种爱与依恋感和归属感有关。”她说，人们应该对这一事实既清醒又成熟。 “你要对属于你的东西负责。”她接着说：“我和生活在这片土地上的人们有着共同的命运。是的，这种命运并不总是幸福的，但它是我们的，我们所有人的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在普京的俄罗斯，揭露黑幕的新闻业已成为一项困难、报酬低、吃力不讨好的职业，而且常常是彻底危险的职业。 2006 年，科斯楚琴科在《新报》任职一年多后，波利特科夫斯卡娅在莫斯科公寓楼的电梯里被枪杀。她是过去二十年来被杀害的七名《新报》记者之一。科斯秋琴科描述了她的纪念照片挂在该报的会议室，旁边还有她被谋杀的同事的照片。 “每当一幅新的肖像出现时，我们都会尝试把它挂起来，这样墙上就没有更多的空间了，”她写道。 “当你无法保护自己或你的人民时，你就会变得迷信。”但是，她知道，“总有空间再容纳一个人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科斯尤琴科现在三十六岁，是俄罗斯最优秀的记者之一；她带着一种柔和的、近乎空灵的气质，掩盖着一种顽固、甚至激烈的报道能量。她可以感到愤怒、羞耻、厌恶，但她并不觉得自己和她笔下的俄罗斯有什么不同。 “我是俄国人。我出生在俄罗斯，”她写道。 “我的母亲是俄罗斯人，我的亲生父亲也是俄罗斯人。 。 。 。我的姓氏是乌克兰人，是我母亲第一次婚姻时的姓氏。我们的姓氏是马利舍夫。我有蓝眼睛和白皮肤，斯拉夫特征。我把长发编成辫子。我的母语是俄语，我说俄语时没有任何口音。在我的国家我从来没有觉得自己像个外国人。我属于这里。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科斯尤琴科告诉我，这本书是个人的清算，试图弄清楚她是如何错过——或者更确切地说，未能对俄罗斯陷入法西斯主义做出充分反应的。这一轨迹导致了对乌克兰的入侵和一场持续了近两年的战争，但实际上开始得更早。对于科斯尤琴科来说，时钟从她达到公民意识时开始：也就是说，在普京巩固权力并构建独裁制度并最终对其邻国发动战争的那些年里。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport -monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Kostyuchenko 是一名同性恋，她在二十多岁的时候就开始参与 LGBT 活动。她写道，当时，她认为，如果她和当时的女友参加莫斯科的骄傲游行（该游行被官方禁止），随着时间的推移，他们将能够冷静而令人信服地捍卫自己的权利。相反，她的太阳穴被打了一拳，她的女朋友也被捕了。 2013年，当俄罗斯杜马通过一项法律，禁止传播所谓的“非传统性关系宣传材料”时，她站在杜马前，亲吻了女友，以示抗议。东正教活动分子向他们投掷鸡蛋和粪便。 “法律很明确，”科斯图琴科告诉我。 “我们在社会上并不平等。这显然是法西斯主义的表述。”但是，她说，“这是一个令人不快的想法，我不想完全朝那个方向看。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021 年，科斯尤琴科在一所国营居民住宅内住了两周。患有精神和神经系统疾病。从这段经历中得出的文章是《我爱俄罗斯》的核心杰作，这是一篇令人心碎、发自肺腑的文本，几乎像是从页面上飘过：工业清洁用品；不新鲜的稀汤；脏床单。护士们在病房里走来走去，准备用装满镇静剂的注射器给任何造成问题的人注射。到外面散步，即使只是到有围墙围起来的庭院，也会被允许或拒绝，也有类似的反复无常。科斯尤琴科与两名妇女阿丽娜和维拉的遭遇令人心痛，她们的怀孕被强行终止，然后在未经同意的情况下被绝育。 “我要怎样才能脱离这个地狱呢？”维拉问道。&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;在 3-A 病房的一扇金属门后面，这里关押着最棘手的病例，科斯尤琴科遇到了蒂玛，一个瘦弱的赤身裸体的男人，嘴唇上挂着口水，臀部因反复注射而瘀青。当科斯尤琴科和一位名叫卡蒂亚的志愿者建议带他在院子里短暂散步时，负责泰玛病例的医生表现出了困惑的怀疑态度。但是，几天后，3-A 病房的护士们惊讶地发现，Tyoma 已经不再撕扯和咀嚼窗台碎片了。 “事实证明，在俄罗斯，我们有国家出资维持的集中营，”她告诉我。 “我们的税收让人们像动物一样被关起来，被剥夺权利。”&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >; &lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;科斯尤琴科还意识到，疗养院是其墙外更大的俄罗斯的特别残忍的表现。 “你独自一人，与国家面对面，”她说，“这就是它的样子，这就是国家的真实本质。”一个家长式国家自以为知道什么对它的指控是最好的，但它真正关心的是它自己的权威和便利。如果这意味着要向屁股注射一针镇定剂，那就这样吧。你最好的机会只是避免更糟糕的命运。 “如果你想保持安全，你必须脸上挂着微笑，或者至少保持中立，”科斯图琴科写道。 “对他们对你和你周围的人所做的事情漠不关心，温顺。”事后看来，科斯尤琴科告诉我，“我知道我的国家存在法西斯主义，同时相信如果我这样做我的工作，如果我描述这种法西斯主义，那就足够了。但这永远还不够。”尽管俄罗斯独立记者的生活并不轻松或光鲜亮丽，但它也有自己的舒适感、仪式感和满足感。有人报道了旅行和在剧院的夜晚，甚至深夜与同事在某人的厨房里喝酒。 “我喜欢我的生活，不想改变它，”她说。对于科斯尤琴科和她圈子里的其他人——非营利组织创始人、实验剧院导演、书店或咖啡馆老板——来说，用她的话说，这些“水晶小世界”似乎会不断扩大。有一天，这些小世界将合二为一，普京就没有立足之地了；这个俄罗斯不会属于他。但是，她告诉我，“2 月 24 日”——俄罗斯入侵的那一天——“这些世界破碎了，它们消失了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第二天深夜，科斯秋琴科越境进入乌克兰，成为一个极小的国家之一。成功从战区进行报道的俄罗斯记者人数。 （也就是说，从那些受到攻击的人的角度来看，大量官方媒体的记者参与了进行攻击的俄罗斯部队。）她从当时在俄罗斯占领下的敖德萨和赫尔松进行报道。她在前线偷偷进出；在赫尔松市内，她找到了俄罗斯军队对当地居民施以酷刑的大楼。她的文章由《Novaya Gazeta》发表，其编辑德米特里·穆拉托夫 (Dmitry Muratov) 荣获&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/the-nobel-peace -prize-acknowledges-a-dangerous-era-for-journalists&quot;>;代表论文获得 2021 年诺贝尔奖&lt;/a>;；但是，鉴于俄罗斯的战时审查制度，她和她的编辑们删除了某些单词和段落，并用括号或斜体注明文本已被删除。 “我们不想隐藏这种强制审查行为，而是想把它说清楚，”她告诉我。 “另外，用俄语，你可以清楚地分辨出缺少的内容。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她从南部城市尼古拉耶夫发来的电报以其原始形式出现，俄罗斯军队在战争初期对这座城市进行了无情的炮击。作为本书的最后一章。本书的写作令人振奋，在临床记录中充满痛苦，夹杂着一种内疚感，而这种内疚感是完全徒劳的。科斯秋琴科参观尼古拉耶夫太平间。 “冷藏室里的尸体层层叠叠，”她写道。 “两个女孩一个压在另一个身上。她们是姐妹。年长的已经十七岁了。在一堆尸体中我只能看到她的手，她修长的手指上涂着整齐的粉红色指甲油。小女孩三岁，躺在她姐姐身上。她是金发碧眼的。她的下巴被纱布绑住，双手被绑在一起放在肚子上。弹片留下的红色小伤口布满了她的全身。这个女孩看起来还活着。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三月下旬，科斯尤琴科在前往马里乌波尔的途中，当时这里是战争中最持久、最残酷的围困之地，这时她接到了来自 &lt;a href=&quot; 的电话。 https://www.newyorker.com/news/q-and-a/how-Russias-nobel-writing-newspaper-is-covering-ukraine&quot;>;穆拉托夫&lt;/a>;，&lt;em>;新报报&lt;/em>;莫斯科的编辑。他得到的消息称，亲克里姆林宫的车臣武装分子奉命在检查站拦截科斯秋琴科并杀死她。穆拉托夫说她必须立即离开乌克兰；起初，科斯图琴科拒绝了。 “整个城市连同数万名居民都被摧毁了，”科斯图琴科谈到马里乌波尔时说道。 “这是规模令人难以置信的战争罪行，必须记录下来。”但她态度软化，并计划逃离乌克兰。突然无法完成这项任务给她带来的压力比生命受到的威胁更严重。 “我无法接受自己的无助，”她在为位于里加的独立俄罗斯新闻网站 Meduza 撰写的一篇文章中写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科斯尤琴科再也没有回到过莫斯科。她开始了令人沮丧的&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/03/13/how- Russian-journalists-in-exile-are-covering-the-war-in-ukraine&quot;>;流亡&lt;/a>;——威尼斯、布拉格、瑞士的一个村庄，以及在美国的一段时间——与她的女友伊安娜（Iana）一起，伊安娜是一名记者和残疾人权利活动家。 （科斯尤琴科发表有关疗养院的文章后，伊安娜出现在《新报》的办公室，他们就认识了。）到那时，《新报》实际上已被关闭。在收到州监管机构的多次警告并担心受到刑事起诉后，其员工投票决定无限期暂停运营。科斯秋琴科不同意这一决定，但选择不投票——她在国外，面临着自己的困难，但不是那些仍在俄罗斯的同事所面临的困难。 “我没有承担做出不同决定的风险，”她告诉我。 “他们做到了。因此，我不确定我的意见是否重要。”&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Kostyuchenko 和 Iana 最终在柏林租了一套公寓。科斯图琴科想要回去工作；她尤其希望返回乌克兰，但这并不是一件容易的事，因为在入侵之后，俄罗斯公民需要获得批准（很少获得批准）才能进入该国。她前往乌克兰驻慕尼黑领事馆申请签证。在返回柏林的途中，她病倒了。症状接连而来：胃痛、恶心、脸部、手指和脚趾肿胀。两个月来，医生几乎不知道她可能出了什么问题。最后，其中一人提出她可能是中毒了。 “这个想法似乎太疯狂了，”她告诉一名警探。 “我当时在欧洲。我觉得我很安全。”侦探严厉地回答。 “你来到这里，以为自己是在度假，”他说。 “我们这里有政治谋杀案。俄罗斯的特工部门在这个国家很活跃。”他批评科斯尤琴科对自己的安全采取了鲁莽和懒散的态度。&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto; height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;eb4rhl&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-隐藏=“true”>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;1at8de&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;她被送往柏林 Charité 医院，在那里 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker .com/tag/alexey-navalny&quot;>;阿列克谢·纳瓦尔尼&lt;/a>;在 2020 年中毒后接受了治疗。检察官办公室结束了调查，然后重新展开调查，但她没有听到任何进一步的消息。当经常报道安全部门的俄罗斯独立网站《内部人士》向一些医生和化学家介绍科斯尤琴科的情况时，所有人都表示，她的症状“除了外源中毒之外无法解释”。他们将一种有机氯化合物列为可能的毒物，并建议它是通过皮肤摄入或吸收的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德国警方告诉科斯图琴科要保持不可预测的时间表，定期移动，并避免重复路线或目的地。她和伊安娜搬出了柏林的公寓，前往斯堪的纳维亚半岛北部偏远的田园地区参加居住项目。从那里，他们开始穿梭于欧洲朋友的家和公寓之间。今年秋天，他们计划前往美国参加科斯图琴科的新书发布会。她回忆起她早期在《新报》上看到的一次恐惧，当时她正在调查一个由莫斯科黑帮和腐败警察组成的团伙，这些团伙杀人目的是偷窃然后出售昂贵的汽车。科斯图琴科被跟踪，有人试图闯入她的公寓；一些官员出现在该报的办公室并发出威胁。她告诉我一位富有同情心的警察调查员向她转述的话：“如果他们想杀了你，他们就会杀了你。你可以让这个过程变得更长，对他们来说成本更高。但这不可能保证你的安全。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;所谓的中毒对科斯尤琴科来说是一个尴尬的话题。她尽量不去想她的工作固有的危险。 “有多种职业会给你的生命带来潜在风险，”她告诉我。 “警察、救援部门，对不起，举个例子，军队。”她说，这就是工作的性质。 “事实证明，在俄罗斯，新闻业就是其中之一。它并没有使它变得更重要或更不重要。当然，在这种条件下工作很不幸，但我已经这样做了很长时间。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科斯尤琴科告诉我，更困难的事情是与俄罗斯分离。随着战争的拖延，俄罗斯继续给乌克兰人民带来苦难并镇压本国公民，她发现更难维持或表达对祖国的热爱。科斯秋琴科并不认同她的国家在某种程度上被普京单独困住的幻想。 “他是一种症状，可以说是我们所有狗屎的化身，”她告诉我。 “但他并不是所有麻烦的根源。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不久前，在他们的一次例行电话中，仍然驻扎在莫斯科的穆拉托夫提出了一个让科斯秋琴科觉得很有说服力的比喻。他告诉她，普京和克里姆林宫的其他高级官员把自己表现得像牧师，声称要调解信徒与上帝的关系。也就是说，他们充当俄罗斯人如何感受对他们的国家的爱或任何东西的中间人。 “国家站在我们和我们对国家的热爱之间，”她告诉我，解释这个想法，“并告诉我们什么是正确的，我们应该如何感受，我们有义务做什么。”科斯图琴科在她的作品中试图挑战这一想法，但也许是徒劳的。 “爱不需要沉默，”她告诉我。 “这不需要撒谎。这不需要谋杀。”相反，她说，爱是一种“积极的感觉”。她解释说：“你会看到俄罗斯的许多缺点并指出它们。你试图阻止它所犯下的邪恶，纠正你能纠正的，哀悼你不能纠正的，并在这种悲伤中找到一些目的。” ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;dvgxfc&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-隐藏=“true”>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 04:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“Taylor Swift: The Eras Tour” is Intimate, Colossal, and Slightly Disappointing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-front-row/taylor-swift-the-eras-tour-is-intimate-colossal-and-slightly-disappointing]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-16T20:02:30.418Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/652d4cfca2dd76a04bfbc885/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/Brody-Eras-Tour.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >; &lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox= &quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312 L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4 H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存这个故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width =&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>; &lt;路径 d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M 23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt; /svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt; div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;像大多数人一样，我知道一些 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www .newyorker.com/tag/taylor-swift&quot;>;泰勒·斯威夫特&lt;/a>;的歌曲仅仅因为活着，但听到音乐是一回事，聆听音乐又是另一回事。她的演唱会电影《泰勒·斯威夫特：时代之旅》（Taylor Swift: The Eras Tour）于去年八月在加利福尼亚州英格尔伍德的 SoFi 体育场举行的三场演出期间拍摄，其主要优点就是将人们的注意力集中在她的音乐上，持续两又三刻钟，就像在聆听室一样。它所揭示的她的艺术才华只会让我更加欣赏这位流行巨星的创作实质和想象力——实际上是她的存在。音乐会是一场盛大的演出，既亲密又宏大。在大型舞台表演中，斯威夫特掌控着整个体育场。她经常独自一人，有时有几个舞者加入，有时还有一大群舞者支持，巨大的视频屏幕和舞台布景作为精心设计的背景，配有灯光秀和烟雾效果。 （至于乐队，它被保持在很远的地方，在自己的围场中。）这个节目的电影将她的歌曲创作放在前台，就好像她的音乐是一个电影剧本，通过她的表演赋予了戏剧性的生命。 p>;&lt;p>;有些电影导演设法将大预算的制片厂电影变成个人作品，而且，当我观看时，我觉得斯威夫特以类似的方式霸占了名人的强大机制。这场音乐会的概念是自传式的：斯威夫特一张一张专辑地回顾她的职业生涯，她将每一张专辑都归因于她生命中的不同“时代”，并且每一张专辑都构成了演出的一个片段。她以第一人称的方式写作，细节丰富、坦率，但也以一种为她的自画像增添叙事丰富性的方式锁定了现代美国年轻女性的神话：年轻的浪漫和男朋友、朋友和亦敌亦友、学校和邻居以及家庭。这些歌曲反映了一种轻率的愿望，即充分而深入地体验当下的激情，意识到日常生活中的惯例所构成的障碍，以及通过纯粹的情感力量超越这些障碍，走向来之不易的自我的感觉。知识。斯威夫特是一位最好意义上的情节剧作家，她在平凡的生活和环境中寻找英雄般的伟大，将她的经历视为一种自然主义传奇的形式，在她的观众中，女孩和年轻女性发现自己的经历受到认真对待，因为她们应得的。尽管有“时代”的概念，斯威夫特的歌曲却奇怪地脱离了他们的时代：在将她生活的细节扩展到准普遍性的过程中，她过滤掉了文化细节，仿佛邀请听众用他们个人的参考资料来填补空白.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我发现自己想到了道格拉斯·瑟克的浪漫情节剧，例如“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/richard-brody/movie-of-the- week-writing-on-the-wind&quot;>;Written on the Wind&lt;/a>;”，斯威夫特对她专辑“&lt;a href=&quot;https”中的一首歌曲“最后一个伟大的美国王朝”的表演强化了这一概念。 ://www.newyorker.com/culture/culture-desk/taylor-swifts-new-album-folklore&quot;>;民俗&lt;/a>;”，其中她讲述了已故社交名流和艺术赞助人丽贝卡·哈克尼斯（Rebekah Harkness）的故事（她的斯威夫特于 2013 年购买的罗德岛豪宅）。当她唱这首歌时——讲述的是一位“中产阶级离婚者”与工业财富继承人结婚并成为丑闻焦点的故事——陪伴她的不仅有舞者，还有一位扮演哈克尼斯的女演员，她穿着迷人的五十年代风格的衣服长袍和长及肘部的手套。这个数字是对经典时代好莱坞浪漫爱情故事的印象派折射，是电影舞台的高潮，尽管不是最有创意的序列。 （早期的一些歌曲在一座巨大的、抽象几何剖面立体模型般的房子前上演，具有更直接引人注目的吸引力，让人想起杰里·刘易斯的“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker. com/culture/richard-brody/dvd-of-the-week-the-ladies-man&quot;>;The Ladies Man&lt;/a>;”——以及&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://images. app.goo.gl/xcLCZNqR4a8Lq5zr8&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://images.app.goo.gl/xcLCZNqR4a8Lq5zr8&quot;}&quot; href =&quot;https://images.app.goo.gl/xcLCZNqR4a8Lq5zr8&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;好莱坞广场&lt;/a>;。）&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次旅行的概念——“时代” ” 斯威夫特的职业生涯——很容易显得自我夸大，但它不会这样，因为它提供了真实体验的核心。斯威夫特在公共场合长大，她的粉丝对她作品的每一个新方面的热烈反应，与她的艺术发展所伴随的重大生活变化（内在和外在）相对应。 （不要让那些考虑过约翰·科尔特兰或弗朗茨·舒伯特逐年音乐自我转变的人投下第一块石头。）这部电影展示了斯威夫特的表演既巧妙又谦虚；她展现了惊人的才华，但并没有令人生畏的精湛技艺。尽管她的舞蹈很娴熟，但她通过大步、手势和眼神的戏剧表演传达了更多的信息。她的歌声强劲但不歌剧，富有表现力但不浮夸，处于对话或忏悔语气的边缘。实际上，这是一种与歌词相契合的声音——既不压倒性也不平淡，而是对日常生活中非凡事物的强化和升华。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;简而言之，斯威夫特表演的魅力是个人的。这就是为什么这部电影最终达不到她的审美。音乐会电影&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2023/10/13/movies/taylor-swift-eras-tour-concert-film.html&quot;>;很少有简单的纪录片&lt;/a>;；相反，他们通常会制作一个图像轨道来配合音乐轨道，有点像音乐视频，突出庆祝和促销方面。但这部电影（由萨姆·扳手执导）几乎没有为表演增加另一个层次的体验，因为它的视觉构图时时刻刻都受到惯例和自满的负担。这并没有妨碍音乐，但它忽视了斯威夫特存在的真实性，以及她表演的身体方面。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;电影中缺少的是接近感和时间感。 《时代之旅》几乎没有提供斯威夫特的满屏特写镜头，而且都是一闪而过。事实上，这部电影几乎完全由非常短的镜头组成，无论是斯威夫特在舞台上大步流星地唱歌，还是用吉他或钢琴为自己伴奏，通过口头评论介绍歌曲。以这种方式拍摄和剪辑电影的决定不仅仅是对注意力短暂和对停滞不耐烦的让步。扳手、谢尔盖·艾森斯坦或 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/ridley-scott&quot;>;雷德利·斯科特&lt;/a>; 等短镜头都有一个目的：确保每张图像都准确表达一个意思事物，将复杂性降低为可立即掌握的统一体。要将这些图像变成一个复杂的整体，需要精湛的剪辑，但《时代之旅》的剪辑并没有应对挑战，在图像与图像之间提供很少的变化或对比。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拍摄与斯威夫特的艺术才华截然相反。这部电影的视觉单调——毫无创意的角度、千篇一律的节奏、顽固地脱离动作——使电影体验变得令人厌倦，尽管人们可以看到现场表演令人振奋。斯威夫特舞台表演的魅力之一是它明显缺乏自发性——乐队被边缘化，除了在一些戏剧化的时刻，吉他手短暂地和她一起即兴演奏。但我说“明显”是因为我不相信这一点：尽管经过了所有仔细的排练，这些数字都像发条一样准确无误，但斯威夫特却非常专注于当下。然而，这部电影只在闪烁和闪烁中捕捉到了这种热情，就好像在静止的画面中，从未在运动中一样。一种更自由、更有创意的导演方法——比如更长、更紧急的特写镜头，或者更耐心、更好奇的广角镜头——将揭示斯威夫特表演的自发性、直接性和人性。这样的电影将反映她的专注与放弃、思想与情感的结合，融合在景观中心的艺术家的内心生活中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相反，这部电影的拍摄和剪辑就像商业广告一样——这显然是一个有效的方法，因为它为包括我在内的一群中年电影评论家提供了一个机会，以一种可能造成不公正的风险的方式来奉承她的作品。像许多父母、祖父母、阿姨和叔叔一样，电影作家可能会咕咕地说，“她真是个好女孩”，仿佛含蓄地将她与更前卫的摇滚乐手和说唱歌手，或者更鲁莽的名人区分开来。她很可能是一个好人，但她的艺术涉及的远不止这些，她为她的艺术付出的也远不止这些。要展现泰勒·斯威夫特的激情和力量，需要一部更好的电影；她应得的不仅会展示她如何摆脱它，而且会展示她如何振作起来。 ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;ud33zh&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;mrdq87&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 17 Oct 2023 04:06:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>