<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>纽约客</title><description>纽约客全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.newyoker.com <item><title><![CDATA[“Thank You for Speaking While I’m Interrupting”: The Crosstalk Chaos of the Second Republican Debate]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/thank-you-for-speaking-while-im-interrupting-the-crosstalk-chaos-of-the-second-republican-debate]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-28T04:40:02.051Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6514e5eb18d4f5c40bb13efe/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/BWW-republican-debate-09-27-23.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article- body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height =&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot; M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H 20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/ span>;&lt;span >;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >; &lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存这个故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot; >;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid =&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;共和党总统辩论花了大约半个小时周三晚上，从单纯的无聊变成了无法挽回的混乱。来自南卡罗来纳州的美国参议员蒂姆·斯科特（Tim Scott）询问一家生物技术公司创始人维韦克·拉马斯瓦米（Vivek Ramaswamy），当他自己“只是与中国共产党和美国做生意”时，他怎么能指责他的竞争对手“被收买”？资助亨特·拜登的人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拉马斯瓦米，无论是在政治上还是在最基本的人类方式上，似乎没有其他共和党总统候选人能够真正支持他，他戏剧性地张开了双臂，向其他人表示敬意。在舞台上。 “这些人都是好人，但被破碎的制度所玷污。 。 .”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“并非所有人都被污染了！”北达科他州州长 Doug Burgum，他是 &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.realclearpolitics.com/epolls/2024/president/us/2024_republican_presidential_nomination-7548.html&quot; data-event-click=&quot; {“element”：“ExternalLink”，“outgoingURL”：“https://www.realclearpolitics.com/epolls/2024/president/us/2024_republican_presidential_nomination-7548.html”}&quot; href=&quot;https:// /www.realclearpolitics.com/epolls/2024/president/us/2024_republican_presidential_nomination-7548.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;民意调查&lt;/a>;大约百分之一，大声喊道，然后斯科特，拉马斯瓦米和佛罗里达州州长罗恩·德桑蒂斯同时开始讲话。过了将近两分钟，他们的声音才完全分开。当拉马斯瓦米试图因从中国撤资而获得功劳时，唐纳德·特朗普的前联合国大使尼基·哈利插话道：“是的，就在你竞选总统之前”，这也许是相声灾难中唯一的好台词。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拉马斯瓦米看上去并不慌张——他的笑容灿烂，头发扎成蓬巴杜发型，声音充满宣言——但他显然也不知道自己想说什么。有一次，他试图打破喧嚣，讽刺地对他的对手说：“谢谢你们在我打断时讲话。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这就是“谢谢你们在我打断时讲话”这场辩论中，共和党人挑战特朗普总统提名的混乱和漫无目的是众所周知的。特朗普在每项民意调查中都遥遥领先，他选择不参加在加利福尼亚州西米谷的罗纳德·里根总统图书馆举行的活动，他有时在这个场所发挥领导作用&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.politico.com /news/magazine/2023/09/22/ronald-reagan-library-donald-trump-feud-00116983&quot;>;发生争执&lt;/a>;。在他缺席的情况下，这场辩论被宣传为投票中的其他共和党人改变命运的机会：黑莉将自己确立为唐纳德·特朗普的主流替代者，斯科特明确了他的竞选目标，德桑蒂斯则找到一种方法来扭转他在民意调查中的下滑，这种情况现在已经持续了几个月，并且仍然定义了竞选活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这一点上，德桑蒂斯从一开始就失败了，当时花了整整十五分钟的时间主持人呼吁他。当他有机会说话时，他通常看起来有点闷闷不乐，他倾向于滔滔不绝地说出一些听起来可疑的排练台词。在谈到扩大国内石油钻探的计划时，德桑蒂斯表示，“我们将选择米德兰而不是莫斯科。我们将选择马塞勒斯而不是毛拉。我们将选择巴肯而不是北京。”在这个人再次押韵之前阻止他。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;但是，实际上，这对他的竞争对手来说也好不了多少。几个月来，媒体一直在猜测，如果前新泽西州州长克里斯·克里斯蒂能够登上辩论舞台，会对唐纳德·特朗普造成多么严重的伤害。成功之后，克里斯蒂现在有机会直接与特朗普交谈：“你今晚不在这里，因为你害怕上台捍卫你的记录。你正在回避这些事情。让我告诉你将会发生什么。你继续这样做，这里就没有人会再叫你唐纳德·特朗普了。我们要叫你唐老鸭。”看到这里，克里斯蒂显得莫名其妙地得意起来。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;&lt;p>;这就是水平。有一次，拉马斯瓦米在回答有关父母权利的问题时表示，变性是一种精神疾病。 “我和老师睡了三十八年了，”迈克·彭斯说，他指的是他的妻子凯伦，她曾在弗吉尼亚州一所私立基督教学校教艺术。 “全面披露。”如果被迫选出一个获胜者，我可能会选择妮基·哈利，主要是因为她看起来对周围发生的一切感到厌恶。在辩论前夕，哥伦比亚广播公司新闻发布了一项民意调查，似乎表明竞选尚未结束：爱荷华州和新罕布什尔州的大多数共和党初选选民仍在考虑不止一个选择，民意调查发现，“只支持特朗普的选民数量超过了根本不考虑他的选民的三分之一。”如果说这在晚上一开始就带来了一丝希望，那么一旦辩论开始，它很快就消失了。这些候选人看起来都无法击败唐纳德·特朗普。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;为什么共和党阵营如此糟糕？一种解释可能是，自特朗普首次竞选总统以来的八年里，周期性的忠诚之战在很大程度上消耗了共和党的精力，而新想法的供应却在减少。该广播由福克斯商业频道和Univision 主办，以一张向罗纳德·里根致敬的帅气照片开始：扔一个足球，骑上一匹马，告诉辩论观众英语中最可怕的九个单词是“我来自政府”我是来帮忙的。”但除此之外，关于边境危机、国债、家庭价值观重要性的无休止的重复也显得有些陈旧。特朗普并没有摧毁党内的建制派，而是将其保存在琥珀中——就好像在他走下特朗普大厦自动扶梯的那一刻，共和党的时间已经停止了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;辩论进行到一半时，主持人达纳·佩里诺（Dana Perino）向前副总统彭斯提出了一个很好的问题（不是她唯一的问题）。 “你上个月说过，如果当选，你将废除所有奥巴马医改授权，”佩里诺说。 “然而，你在 2016 年也做出了同样的承诺。”佩里诺问道，为什么这次有什么不同？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;彭斯在 1 月 6 日对特朗普的蔑视为他赢得了该领域荣誉人物的声誉，他说：“好吧，首先让我发言大规模枪击问题。”因此，彭斯没有解释为什么奥巴马医改在他有权力废除的情况下仍然是国家法律，而是解释说，解决大规模枪击事件的办法是加快死刑，这样任何被判犯有大规模枪击罪的人都会被判死刑。佩里诺等待着这种野蛮行径结束。然后她精明地说：“这是否意味着奥巴马医改会继续存在？”人群又笑又鼓掌，因为她是对的。可能是这样。 ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;1ru8qi&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; >;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;jrch7k&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt; div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ side>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live= “礼貌” aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/文章>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 13:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How the AR-15 Became an American Brand]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/books/under-review/how-the-ar-15-became-an-american-brand]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27T21:07:38.495Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651326a7a2955540489130d3/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/Witt-AR-15.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >; &lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox= &quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312 L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4 H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存这个故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width =&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>; &lt;路径 d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M 23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt; /svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt; div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;去年夏天，当“在小镇尝试一下”的视频发布时，乡村音乐明星杰森·阿尔丁 (Jason Aldean) 的一首单曲引起了一场小小的争议，人们经常在旁白中提及阿尔丁曾于 2017 年 10 月 1 日在拉斯维加斯举行的 91 号公路丰收节上登台演出。那天晚上，当阿尔丁表演一首名为“当她说宝贝时”的歌曲时，一个名叫 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/i-sell-tools-a-las- vegas-firearms-dealer-who-sold-guns-to-stephen-paddock&quot;>;斯蒂芬·帕多克&lt;/a>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/i-realized-我可能会死在拉斯维加斯枪击事件中幸存下来>;开始从曼德勒湾（附近的度假村和赌场）的三十二楼向人群开枪&lt;/a>;以下。在大约十分钟的时间里，帕多克发射了一千多颗子弹，造成五十八人死亡，四百多人受伤，然后自杀。在第一声枪声响起时录制的视频中，阿尔丁告诉观众逃跑，然后自己逃离了舞台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在那个特定的夜晚，阿尔丁出现在拉斯维加斯，这是一个巧合，但发布了“尝试一下”六年后，人们选择了一首颂扬私刑正义的歌曲“in a Small Town”。音乐录影带将反警察抗议和便利店抢劫的镜头拼接在一起，形成了国家混乱的印象；它的歌词包括这样的台词“我爷爷给了我一把枪/他们说有一天他们会围捕”。阿尔丁将&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/another-worst-mass-shooting-in-the-united-states&quot;>;拉斯维加斯大屠杀&lt;/a>;排除在外他对美国混乱的热议，反而投射出一种控制的幻想。去年夏天观看这段视频时，我不禁想起，考虑到阿尔丁与大规模枪击事件的联系，美国近代史上在一个小镇上尝试过的一件事就是导致十九名儿童死亡的大屠杀&lt;a href=&quot;https:// /www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/seeing-america-again-in-the-texas-elementary-school-shooting&quot;>;去年在德克萨斯州尤瓦尔迪&lt;/a>;；那个小镇的执法人员在大厅里等了一个小时，没有与枪手对峙；小镇上唯一的儿科医生后来向国会作证，称通过衣服上的漫画来识别死者，因为他们的尸体受损太严重。从这个角度考虑，“在小镇尝试一下”成为一个寓言，讲述了对国家完整性的威胁的姿态，同时忽视了&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/dispatch/two-mothers-confront -the-unimaginable-in-uvalde&quot;>;生活现实&lt;/a>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/letter-from-the-southwest/the-staff-of-uvaldes- local-paper-cover-the-worst-day-of-they-lives&quot;>;恐怖事件令人不安，无法调解。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关于该视频的大部分争议都集中在一个镜头上1927 年，阿尔丁在田纳西州的一家法院前与乐队一起唱歌，一名黑人被白人暴徒私刑处死。同样值得注意的是，该视频表现了某种美国枪支的心理分裂，尽管讨论较少。狂热者：他的傲慢与怯懦、虚张声势与虚无主义的独特结合；他的孔雀行为；他的种族主义；他相信法律和秩序的神话，而不是腐败的经验证据。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拉斯维加斯 91 号公路音乐会上的枪击事件是美国历史上由一人实施的最致命的大规模枪击事件。作为 Cameron McWhirter 和 Zusha Elinson，“&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/American-Gun-True-Story-AR-15/dp/0374103852” data-event- 的作者click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/American-Gun-True-Story-AR-15/dp/0374103852&quot;}&quot; href =&quot;https://www.amazon.com/American-Gun-True-Story-AR-15/dp/0374103852&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;美国枪：AR的真实故事- 15&lt;/a>;”，步枪的新历史，观察到，当晚被杀的美国人比阿富汗二十年战争中任何一场战斗中的美国人都要多。拉斯维加斯和尤瓦尔迪的大规模枪击事件； &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/american-racism-and-the-buffalo-massacre&quot;>;纽约州布法罗一家杂货店发生大规模枪击事件&lt;/a >;，尤瓦尔迪前十天；不到两个月后，在国庆节游行中发生大规模枪击事件&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/highland-park-and-an-illegitimate-supreme-在伊利诺伊州海兰帕克市的法庭上，犯罪者使用了同一种枪，即 AR-15 半自动步枪。 （更准确地说，在维加斯，帕多克有 14 辆 AR-15，他在酒店房间里装好子弹并排成一排，他用撞火枪托改装了枪支，使它们模仿自动射击。）以及 AR-15 的型号，在 McWhirter 和 Elinson 的使用中，该术语指的是一种步枪样式，而不是其名称的原始 ArmaLite 品牌。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/the-weekend-essay/the-last-gun-i-shot&quot;>;AR-15&lt;/a>; 极其致命且易于获得，已成为对于那些认为此类武器不应参与平民生活的人和那些认为拥有此类武器是一项宪法权利的人来说，这是一个政治象征。它在美国的销售受到最低限度的限制。斯蒂芬·帕多克一年内购买了其中三十一把。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;麦克沃特和艾林森是商业记者，《美国枪支》在某种程度上是一本关于一个行业如何制定向特定类型推销枪支的策略的书一个人——通常是一个男人——它可以让他相信 AR-15 是他身份的一个组成部分。为此，主流枪支制造商开始吸引非常特殊的人群。 AR-15看起来很坚固，但它很轻并且易于射击。营销人员利用了一位高管所称的周末战士的“想要的因素”，前几代人嘲笑他们为“沙发突击队”。 2010 年对 AR-15 车主的一项调查发现，其中 99% 是男性，73% 已婚，56% 没有军事或执法背景。作者写道：“从很多方面来说，AR-15 都是现代美国男人的理想枪支：它看起来很有男子气概，但他在射击时不需要付出太多努力。” 《美国枪》以一个普通的商业故事的方式审视了使用半自动步枪进行大规模枪击事件的现象，以及我们仍然无法产生防止此类枪击事件发生的政治意愿：AR-15 是一种消费品，广告商成功地附加了一种身份，这种身份已转化为一种如此棘手的政治，以至于在某些圈子里，它似乎比对死亡的恐惧更有力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;AR-15 的历史并非始于沙发突击队，但具有另一种男性原型：战后车库修补匠，他相信《大众机械》杂志的承诺，即业余发明家“可以凭借他们的聪明才智推动国家前进，并通过技术致富”正如作者所写，“这个过程”。 AR-15 的发明者尤金·斯通纳 (Eugene Stoner) 后来因对其发明的道德含义完全不感兴趣而被召回。他更喜欢讨论枪支的技术方面，而不是其杀人的目的。 “这是一种失控的爱好，”斯通纳后来谈到他发明枪械的职业生涯时说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;斯通纳 1922 年出生于印第安纳州的一个小镇，但在科切拉山谷长大南加州。对“发射各种射弹”的迷恋在童年时期就表现出来了。他六岁时引爆了第一枚管状炸弹，七岁时建造了自己的大炮，十岁时向父母的房子发射了一枚火箭。 1944 年，他加入了海军陆战队，从事航空军械工作，但斯通纳的兴趣不是飞机，而是枪支。他很喜欢它们，并且有兴趣改进 M1 加兰德步枪，这是他作为海军陆战队员配发的步枪。 （他从未亲眼目睹过战斗。）随着朝鲜战争的爆发，M1 由木头和钢制成，重达近 10 磅，事实证明它对于现代战争来说是不够的，笨重且后坐力惊人。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;在在更轻的军用步枪的军备竞赛中，美国已经落后了。 “突击步枪”一词是纳粹 Sturmgewehr 的翻译，是由枪械制造商雨果·施迈瑟 (Hugo Schmeisser) 在第二次世界大战末期开发的“风暴步枪”，这是一种更轻、快速射击的步枪，更适合近距离使用，而不是近距离使用。长距离。俄罗斯枪支设计师米哈伊尔·卡拉什尼科夫 (Mikhail Kalashnikov) 在开发 AK-47 时研究了纳粹枪支。到 20 世纪 50 年代中期，苏联及其共产主义盟友已经制造了数百万支 AK-47，这些步枪可靠、耐用且易于携带。随着这十年的发展，美国对 AK-47 对应产品的需求变得越来越明显。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;战争结束后，斯通纳离开了海军陆战队，并最终成为一家设计飞机零件的工程公司的合伙人。作者写道：“尽管他缺乏正规教育，但他通过自学工程、物理和材料科学原理取得了成功。”在空闲时间，斯通纳研究新型铝合金，并在外出吃饭时强迫性地用笔在桌布上涂鸦设计。他的妻子和孩子们会记得他总是带着画板或便笺簿，以防灵感来袭。他在工作中使用机器来制造枪支零件，然后晚上在车库里组装和测试。他的实验带来了一项创新（他获得了专利），通过使用枪支重新装弹来更好地引导枪支开火时释放的能量。他通过将瞄准具提高到步枪上方、添加突击步枪的手枪式握把以及消除 M1 步枪枪托的角度来补偿系统对瞄准和后坐力的影响。他于 1954 年完善的原型如今存放在佛罗里达州的一家博物馆中，后来被视为天才之作。 “枪支设计历史学家将斯通纳的创新比作沃尔夫冈·阿玛多伊斯·莫扎特的交响曲，”作者写道。 “斯通纳既是合成者，又是创造者。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;斯通纳的发明恰逢向私人承包商开放武器采购，以及艾森豪威尔政府领导下的所谓军工联合体的诞生。斯通纳很快就被仙童发动机和飞机公司旗下的枪械子公司 ArmaLite 聘用，该公司正在寻求进入这一行业。使用新材料制造轻型枪械的意图从 ArmaLite 的名字中就可见一斑。麦克沃特和埃林森将实验室的任务与当今硅谷的登月研究公司进行了比较。其办事处位于好莱坞。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;AR-15 是 ArmaLite 开发的第十五种武器。 （与一些误解相反，AR-15 型号的 AR 指的是公司名称的前两个字母或 ArmaLite Research，而不是“突击步枪”。）斯托纳的新步枪由铝、玻璃纤维和塑料制成。它们的重量不到七磅，不需要特殊的射击专业知识或体力来携带。它们也比之前的步枪更致命，后者使用相对较大的子弹，在撞击时会直接穿过身体。斯通纳的发明使用高速发射的小口径子弹。作者写道：“AR-15 发射的一颗子弹先从鼻子飞过空中。” “但是当它击中身体时，它就变得不稳定了。一旦不稳定，子弹就会像龙卷风一样撕裂身体，盘旋倾斜，摧毁器官、血管和骨骼。”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style =&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;vm3h3g&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;ojf3w3&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;ArmaLite 开始尝试向美国销售其最新设计陆军，这一进程因“游说者、企业高管、军事官僚和国会议员”的泥沼而受阻，他们在武器采购问题上争论不休。 1959年，ArmaLite放弃了该枪的设计，并将该枪的设计卖给了柯尔特公司，但在1960年，在二战末期负责对东京进行燃烧弹轰炸的美国空军将军柯蒂斯·勒梅（Curtis LeMay）之后，在国庆节派对上的一个西瓜，最终被推荐用于军事测试和购买。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这把枪于 1962 年首次在南越士兵中进行试听。早期的枪支在战斗中使用有限，”作者写道。很快，M16，即步枪的全自动军用版本，成为美国军方的标准步枪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;早期的 M16 因干扰而闻名，这是急于大规模生产的结果。越南战争的头几年给军队带来了可怕的后果。 “我们感觉自己像小白鼠，”一位越战老兵告诉作者。到 1970 年，这个问题得到了解决，在随后几年的战争神话中，M16 成为一种标志性武器，成为《现代启示录》、《猎鹿人》和《第一滴血》电影中的枪。 McWhirter 和 Elinson 引用了“&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Dispatches-Michael-Herr/dp/0679735259&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;中的描述： “ExternalLink”、“outgoingURL”：“https://www.amazon.com/Dispatches-Michael-Herr/dp/0679735259”}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Dispatches-Michael -Herr/dp/0679735259&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;快讯&lt;/a>;，”迈克尔·赫尔 (Michael Herr) 对这场战争的新闻报道：“每一轮都像高速风的微小集中，使然而，AR-15 的民用版本却迟迟没有流行起来。从 1964 年到 1973 年，柯尔特公司每年生产的 AR-15 从未超过 5000 支（在一个 1968 年人口拥有约 9000 万支枪支的国家）。当时，步枪主要由猎人使用，而猎人并不想要速射枪。 1977 年 AR-15 专利到期后，其他公司看到了柯尔特没有看到的机会。这把枪开始在那些认为自己需要军用级武器的人们中越来越受欢迎——一把“如果社会崩溃了可以在战斗中使用的枪”。在那些年里，这是一个相对小众的市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;直到两千支之后，AR-15 才成为该国销量最高的步枪。该枪已被纳入国会于 1994 年通过的为期十年的“攻击性武器”禁令，这是政府和执法部门为防止半自动步枪落入他们认为的坏人之手而做出的努力的一部分。 1989 年，一名手持 AK-47 的枪手袭击了加利福尼亚州斯托克顿的一所小学，之后就开始推动此类禁令。其最著名的倡导者之一是达里尔·盖茨 (Daryl Gates)，他是 20 世纪 80 年代和 90 年代初洛杉矶臭名昭著的种族主义警察局长。盖茨厌倦了看到警察在与配备 AR-15、Uzi 和 AK-47 的街头帮派的冲突中被枪杀，他认为这些武器在他所谓的“复杂的城市社会”中没有立足之地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;事实证明，该法律在政治上不受欢迎，在下一个选举周期中伤害了它的一些支持者。这也是无效的。它的法律语言没有将半自动步枪作为一个类别取缔，而是根据武器的“军事特征”对其进行定义，这意味着它们可以很容易地进行修改以符合新规则。其结果是创建了一个符合禁令的半自动步枪市场，而买家渴望拥有政府告诉他们被禁止的枪支，这推动了这一市场的发展。禁令颁布后，某类枪械制造商开始与 AR-15 联系在一起。还有 DPMS Panther Arms，其标志是咆哮的黑豹；还有大毒蛇，它有一条露出獠牙的蛇。这些枪械制造商最初在枪展上与体育人群发生冲突，吸引了被污蔑为局外人的战术观众。他们向末日准备者推销符合禁令的 AR-15，受益于对千年计算机故障等潜在灾难的恐惧。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt; 2001 年 9 月 11 日，世界贸易中心发生恐怖袭击，将原本的利基市场转变为大众市场。从 2001 年到 2003 年，AR-15 的产量增长了 97%，在犯罪率下降抑制了手枪销售、狩猎受欢迎程度下降的时代之后，支撑了对枪支的需求。这些年来，AR-15 逐渐被视为行业的财务救星。 2004年，攻击性武器禁令到期，随后又通过了一项新法律，使枪支制造商免于承担责任，整个行业都全力投资步枪，甚至像史密斯和史密斯这样的传统枪支制造商也开始涉足步枪领域。 Wesson 是一家上市公司，开始将财富寄托在销售上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;AR-15 在新千年越来越受欢迎的主角之一是史蒂芬·范伯格 (Stephen Feinberg)，他是一名“军事爱好者”（沙发的更友好术语）枪支行业采用的突击队）和华尔街一家名为 Cerberus Capital 的对冲基金的亿万富翁负责人。范伯格是一名枪支收藏家和战利品猎人，他假装是一个爱国的普通人，包括开皮卡车、喝百威啤酒、雇佣一名前海军陆战队狙击手教他远程射击。 2000 世纪中期，Cerberus 开始收购枪支公司，整合原本分散的行业的生产，并通过规模降低成本。他对枪支公司的疯狂收购如此引人注目，以至于阴谋论者开始怀疑乔治·索罗斯是幕后黑手。 （全国步枪协会出面澄清谣言。）&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次收购恰逢所谓的枪支销售繁荣。在 2008 年总统竞选中，巴拉克·奥巴马 (Barack Obama) 在枪支管制问题上采取了温和立场，但这对业界来说并不重要，业界利用他来引发禁枪威胁并提高销量。范伯格的枪支集团名为自由集团 (Freedom Group)，它收购了 DPMS Panther Arms、Bushmaster 和一些老品牌，包括雷明顿 (Remington)。他们将 AR-15 放到了沃尔玛的货架上（沃尔玛一度在 2015 年停止销售 AR-15，声称其决定不是为了应对大规模枪击事件中反复使用 AR-15，而是因为销量下降）。营销人员利用这把枪来应对男性气概危机，在《Maxim》杂志上刊登广告，展示大毒蛇的 AR-15 模型，并附上“考虑重新发行你的男人卡”的字样。视频游戏是接触这一有抱负的人群的有用渠道。 Freedom Group 的一份内部营销备忘录中写道：“随着城市化程度的提高以及进入射击/狩猎区域的机会减少，潜在的年轻射击者接触枪支和弹药的主要方式是通过虚拟游戏场景。”业界开始避免使用“突击步枪”一词，而是使用“现代运动步枪”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美国枪”提出的最意想不到的问题之一是：如果边缘领主的身份被许多凶杀案的大规模枪击案并不是疏远或精神疾病的结果，而是说明一家贪婪的私募股权公司照常开展营销活动的成功？ Correlation is not cause, but the rise of the AR-15 as the weapon of the post-millennial mass-shooting phenomenon happened in tandem with this sales pitch.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The book suggests mass shootings stoked fears of weapons bans that led to greater gun sales. In 2013, the authors write, the year after twenty schoolchildren were killed with an AR-15 at Sandy Hook Elementary School, in Newtown, Connecticut, AR-15s generated at least seven hundred and eighty million dollars in revenue for gunmakers, compared with only ninety-three million dollars in 2004. McWhirter and Elinson recount a Freedom Group earnings call a week after the Sandy Hook shooting where an executive discussed an acquisition that would increase its margins on the gun. “We were in the business of legally making guns to legally sell to legal gun owners,” an executive would later state in a court deposition. “So there is no other thing to do than wake up and make guns on Monday morning.”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;xgu45j&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;McWhirter and Elinson are agnostic on a ban on semi-automatic rifles. They suggest that, even if such a ban were politically viable and supported by the courts, it would not be the only option. In a chapter called “Beyond the Talking Points,” they offer other ways to prevent mass shootings with AR-15s. They cite the example of a sheriff in Florida who used the state&#39;s red-flag laws, which were passed in the aftermath of the school shooting in Parkland, in 2018, more than eight hundred times to remove guns from individuals in Polk County. Another effective policy is requiring a license to buy a gun, as is necessary in Massachusetts, New York, and other states. “Mass shootings had sixty percent lower odds of occurring in states that require permits to purchase guns than in those that didn&#39;t,” they observe. They report research that finds that restricting large-capacity magazines does not reduce the number of mass shootings but does reduce the number of people who are killed in them. They suggest that the country&#39;s background-check system, which scans for things like criminal records and restraining orders, is antiquated, missing open threats made in Internet chat rooms or the impressions of family members or classmates.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“American Gun” has an epigraph from J. Robert Oppenheimer: “When you see something that is technically sweet, you go ahead and do it and you argue about what to do about it only after you have had your technical success.” The authors find that Eugene Stoner, the inventor of the AR-15, had little of Oppenheimer&#39;s moral angst. He did not live to see what happened in Newtown, or in Parkland, or in Las Vegas. Before he died in 1997, of cancer that his family believed he&#39;d developed from working with toxic solvents, he wrote a letter to the US Marines, asking to be buried at Quantico with full military honors in consideration of his contribution to the nation. Instead of the usual twenty-one-shot salute, he requested that the Marines salute him with the M16 on its fully automatic setting. “Each burst could be considered a salvo,” he wrote. “I would like three salvos, thus maintaining the Roman Legion&#39;s tradition of striking their shields three times to honor fallen comrades.” That was how he wished to be memorialized: with an outburst of automatic rifle fire. His wishes were honored. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;rc3zu&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 06:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Inside a Trump 2024 Rally in Iowa]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/podcast/political-scene/inside-a-trump-2024-rally-in-iowa]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27T20:45:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/637541f2b19ab8521b9fe1c2/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/The%20Political%20Scene%20In%20Conversation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;figure data-testid=&quot;IframeEmbed&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;IframeEmbedContainer&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;iframe height=&quot;120&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-scripts allow-same-origin&quot; title=&quot;Embedded Frame&quot; data-src=&quot;https://www.wnyc.org/widgets/ondemand_player/thenewyorker/?share=1#file=/audio/json/1367817&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay *; encrypted-media *; clipboard-write; autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&quot;>;&lt;/iframe>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;Listen and subscribe:&lt;/em>; &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.apple?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.apple?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.apple?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Apple&lt;/a>; | &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.spotify?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.spotify?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.spotify?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Spotify&lt;/a>; | &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.google?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.google?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.google?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Google&lt;/a>; | &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Wherever You Listen&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/newsletter/news-politics&quot;>;Sign up&lt;/a>; to receive our twice-weekly News &amp;amp; Politics newsletter.&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;p >;Last week, Benjamin Wallace-Wells, who writes about politics for &lt;em>;The New Yorker&lt;/em>;, went to Dubuque, Iowa, to attend a Trump rally. Wallace-Wells is now covering his third Trump campaign for President. This time, what stood out to him most was how much the rhetoric of the GOP has shifted in the course of those three cycles. The former President, once an insurgent and inflammatory voice, now just sounds like an ordinary Republican. Wallace-Wells joins Tyler Foggatt to discuss what he heard from voters in Iowa, what he has observed in the broader Republican field, and why Donald Trump&#39;s 2024 lead has been so significant.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;z89xb&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;f4gf6&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 05:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Why Kim Kardashian in “American Horror Story: Delicate” Makes Sense]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/cultural-comment/kim-kardashian-in-american-horror-story-makes-sense]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27T17:58:17.866Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131953a12b3bdc35742f8f/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/Fry-Kim-K-AHS.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt; div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12. 5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4 H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt; svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/标题>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径 d =&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;《美国恐怖故事：精致》第十二部首映后的第二天&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2018/05/14/how-ryan-murphy-became-the-most-powerful-man-in-tv&quot;>;瑞恩·墨菲的赛季&lt;/ a>; 和 Brad Falchuk 的 FX 选集系列，我的动态中连续出现了两篇 Instagram 帖子。 TMZ 宣布：“金·卡戴珊 (Kim Kardashian) 在《美国恐怖故事》首映后，其演技受到好评如潮。”手指轻轻滚动几下，《纽约邮报》就发文：“金·卡戴珊 (Kim Kardashian) 猛烈抨击了《美国恐怖故事》的表演：‘糟糕的女演员。’ ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然我短暂地想知道 Instagram 的算法是否试图以我为代价来开一个批评毫无意义的玩笑，但我所遇到的并置实际上并不那么令人惊讶。卡戴珊——电视真人秀巨星、塑身衣和护肤大亨、实习律师、坎耶·维斯特的前妻和孩子的母亲，以及二十一世纪美丽标准的首席仲裁者——如果不是一个分裂的人物，那就什么也不是。她经常因为体现了“因出名而出名”的信条而受到严厉批评，她最后一次担任演员是在十年前（在泰勒·佩里的《诱惑：婚姻顾问的自白》中，扮演主角的同事），所以她在《美国恐怖故事：精致》中的表演将转变为一种事件，受到人们的热切和惊愕，这是有道理的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;墨菲以其精心设计、风格化的作品而闻名，在这些作品中，他经常给年长的女演员表演像杰西卡·兰格、苏珊·萨兰登和凯西·贝茨这样迷人、具有传奇色彩的角色。 （在《美国恐怖故事》中，这些角色因该剧普遍的哥特和血腥气氛而显得尤为突出。）他也喜欢偶尔的特技女主角选角。 2015 年，在《美国恐怖故事》第 5 季中，三年前她在《&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2018/10/08/lady-gaga-tips-墨菲给了 Lady Gaga 作为女演员的第一个主要角色。卡戴珊的选角似乎也属于同样令人兴奋的一类。在剧中，卡戴珊扮演的是安娜（艾玛·罗伯茨饰）的公关人员西沃恩（Siobhan），安娜（艾玛·罗伯茨饰）是一位年轻女演员，多年来一直在 CW 的青少年肥皂剧中苦苦挣扎，但在出演一部出人意料的恐怖独立电影后终于获得了重大突破。这两名女性最初是在试管婴儿支持小组中认识的，但据我们所知，西沃恩的怀孕尝试并未成功，而安娜和她的艺术品经销商丈夫德克斯正处于胚胎移植的边缘，即将进行胚胎移植由“世界知名的生育医生”编写。&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;“AHS：精致”，由 Halley Feiffer 撰写，根据 Danielle Valentine 的小说“&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot; https://www.amazon.com/Delicate-Condition-Danielle-Valentine/dp/1728276888&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https:// /www.amazon.com/Delicate-Condition-Danielle-Valentine/dp/1728276888&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Delicate-Condition-Danielle-Valentine/dp/1728276888&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener” target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;精致状况&lt;/a>;，”充满了身体恐惧和偏执——一个有趣的“迷迭香的婴儿”——和&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/persons -of-interest/david-cronenbergs-dreams-and-nightmares&quot;>;大卫·柯南伯格&lt;/a>;-邻近的景观，带有一些当代的曲折。安娜的妇科手术是在一间像牢房一样的备用手术室里进行的，既痛苦又不祥。她感觉自己被各种披着斗篷的人物跟踪和监视（名人跟踪者？死神？）；她的日历应用程序被神秘黑客入侵；可疑的阿谀奉承的德克斯正在他的画廊展示一位新艺术家，她不仅用自己的经血进行绘画，而且还是他死去的第一任妻子的随地吐痰的形象（“比安娜漂亮多了”，她的网上仇恨乌鸦之一）；蜘蛛、鸟儿和戴着乌黑假发的女人不断地在意想不到的地方出现。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;在这一切之中，卡戴珊其实还不错。正如一些用户在 Twitter 上指出的那样，她扮演的 Siobhan 似乎是在引导像她的母亲兼经理 Kris Jenner 那样的人，Kris Jenner 是一位宣传和宣传大师，通常被视为她女儿们成功背后的力量。作为一个熟悉工资单上的红颜知己从个人到职业的轻松转变的人，卡戴珊让这个角色感觉很生动。 “你的快乐就是我的快乐。你是我最好的朋友，”西沃恩向浑身颤抖、疲惫不堪的安娜保证，就在她为了“奥斯卡竞选”而向安娜施压，要求她参加安迪·科恩的脱口秀节目后不久。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是，如果选卡戴珊扮演克里斯风格的角色至少在一定程度上是一种公关噱头，我还发现它以更深入、更有趣的方式与《美国恐怖故事：精致》的逻辑相一致。在节目的片头中，随着不祥的音乐响起，我们看到了一幅色彩缤纷、闪烁的图像拼贴画：手术器械、针、刀、珍珠、盛开和燃烧的花朵、口红管、饰有饰钉的细高跟鞋。这里似乎提出的观点在这一集本身中得到了扩展：作为一个女人是一件痛苦而暴力的事情。该节目明确评论了医疗机构的沙文主义做法。 “感觉这么痛正常吗？”当安娜从卵子提取手术中出来时，她皱着眉头问道。当医生轻蔑地告诉她“有些疼痛是意料之中的”时，当医生更愿意与德克斯沟通而不是与她沟通时，她感到很恼火。 （该剧还引用了《创世记》中的一句话：“他对那个女人说，‘我会增加你的痛苦和你的怀孕。’”）然后就是名誉问题。 “他们认为，如果一个女人出现在公众视野中，她就会受到骚扰，”西沃恩用她舒缓的南加州慢吞吞的声音告诉安娜。把这句话放在卡戴珊嘴里显然是一个眨眼的动作，仿佛在说：如果有人知道如何成为公众眼中的女性，那就是她了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但卡戴珊也是一个典型的例子。承受痛苦并将其转化为世俗力量的女人。自从近二十年前成为公众人物以来，她塑造了自己极端且极具影响力的女性气质，似乎在努力锻炼和饥饿，以达到新的美丽理想。 （为了穿上玛丽莲·梦露曾经穿过的礼服，她在 2022 年 Met Gala 上闪电般地、广为人知地减掉了 16 磅，这只是最近的一个例子；她神秘的体重增加，随后失去了丰满的臀部是另一个。）看着她扮演西沃恩（Siobhan）的角色，我再次被她的半机械人特征所震撼，就像一尊华丽的雕像一样几乎一动不动。我一直认为，柯南伯格式的有机与合成相结合的愿景，在《苍蝇》或《撞车》等恐怖惊悚片中显而易见，在卡戴珊身上已经达到了逻辑终点，而《美国恐怖故事：精致》则将这一点推向了现实。 。 “我觉得我侵犯了自己，”安娜告诉西沃恩，同时她在一个按照她的形象为粉丝制作的娃娃身上签名。 “这就是所谓的演员，”西沃恩回答道。是的，我想。但也许，这就是卡戴珊时代的女性。 ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;ngn3fb&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; >;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;59iv2p&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt; div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ side>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live= “礼貌” aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/文章>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 03:06:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Daily Cartoon: Wednesday, September 27th]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/cartoons/daily-cartoon/wednesday-september-27th-donald-trump-overvaluation]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27T16:59:37.771Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6514582b061fe3903150306a/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/A28264.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt; div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;标题>;保存&lt;/标题>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22。 1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>; &lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot; 0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2 .95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/ svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存&lt;/span >;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-内容&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content =daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-银行?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp; ;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;购买《纽约客》漫画 »&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >; &lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;4rhand&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div 数据-node-id=&quot;t3brd5&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; >;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 02:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Julia Fox Didn’t Want to Be Famous, but She Knew She Would Be]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-new-yorker-interview/julia-fox-didnt-want-to-be-famous-but-she-knew-she-would-be]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27T17:06:24.581Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650e186ed266277376e6655e/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/Tolentino-Julia-Fox-TNY-Interview.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot; 24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508 L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H1 6V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>; &lt;span >;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d =“M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z”>; &lt; /path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot; ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;朱莉娅·福克斯 (Julia Fox) 是一个非常缺乏传统观念的一代人，她是最因她最不有趣的事情而闻名——她短暂的、极度公开的关系（&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/culture-comment/kim-and-kanye-and-pete -and-julia&quot;>;某种&lt;/a>;）与 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/kanye-west&quot;>;Kanye West&lt;/a>;，2022 年。她也是一名演员（她在《&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-front-row/the-mesmerizing-chaos-of-uncut-gems&quot;>;未切割的宝石&lt;/a>;她的灵感来自于她）和市中心的多才多艺的 It-Girl：她设计了一个时装系列，自行出版了摄影书籍，并曾经举办过一场艺术展，画布上用她自己的血绘制。她现在是一名播客主持人、一个孩子的单亲母亲、纽约狗仔队饮食的主食，经常穿着听起来像是由变态人工智能生成的服装出现（“朱莉娅·福克斯穿着一套完全由人工智能制成的透明服装”）。避孕套”—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instyle.com/julia-fox-see-through-condom-outfit-7497577&quot;>;&lt;em>;InStyle&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;。）回忆录，“&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Down-Drain-Julia-Fox/dp/1668011506/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;外部链接”、“outgoingURL”：“https://www.amazon.com/Down-Drain-Julia-Fox/dp/1668011506/”}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Down -Drain-Julia-Fox/dp/1668011506/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Down the Drain&lt;/a>;，”福克斯已经成为一名作家，以一种游离的、面无表情的甜蜜讲述她的故事三十三岁时，她经历了几辈子的冒险和灾难。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;福克斯主要在美丽和暴力的记录中记住她的生活。她出生于意大利，童年时期与祖父一起度过，祖父用鸡蛋和糖制作扎巴廖内 (zabaglione)。她喜欢急诊室，也喜欢“知道自己会得到照顾的温暖、平静的感觉。”当她访问纽约时，她睡在她的父亲（一名承包商）正在装修的房子里，但当她六岁时搬到那里时，她有了自己的房间，天花板上画着云彩。身体虐待并不引人注目；她养成了打开吹风机的习惯，以掩盖公寓里和头脑中的噪音。她在无人监管的情况下到处乱跑，偷现金、衣服、糖果。她爱上了她遇到的每一个女朋友。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中学时，福克斯的舌头被刺穿了，在华盛顿静坐抗议伊拉克战争，并发现她喜欢男孩们谈论的关注她在学校的屁股。她躲在家里的上铺，躲避一个二十六岁的男孩，这个男孩刚刚吻了她，并告诉她她看起来至少十六岁。 （福克斯记得担心是否会继续下去，部分原因是她没有刮胡子。）她对自己与财富和奢侈的接近和距离有了敏锐的认识。她认为，私立学校的女孩“看起来很干净”。 “他们永远不会像我一样剪自己的头发。”很快，她发现男人们会给她买她喜欢的东西——金耳环、伊夫·圣洛朗香水。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;毒品到来，它们的风险与作为极限运动的青少年浪漫交织在一起。一天晚上，福克斯第一次陷入狂喜，第一次达到插入性高潮，镜子里她皮肤下的每一根静脉都让她感到害怕，她告诉经销商她要嫁给他，并将他的名字纹在手腕上。整个高中和二十几岁时，她被卷入了一个破坏性的、半迷人的市中心混战：潜水酒吧、余兴派对、酒店房间、毒品、更多的毒品、一次吸毒过量、另一次吸毒过量、因重大事件被捕她在俱乐部偷了一个女孩的钱包后犯了盗窃罪。身无分文，又不敢偷更多东西，以免违反缓刑，她找到了一份工作&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2021/07/12/a-retired-dominatrix-goes-to -church&quot;>;曼哈顿地牢里的施虐狂&lt;/a>;。当对手将她的红色漆皮 Jimmy Choos 用作烟灰缸时，福克斯将自己的尿液和粪便装满灌肠袋，然后将其喷入另一个女孩的储物柜中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;福克斯显然很有趣。她有宗教信仰；她祈祷有一个糖爹，结果得到了一个亿万富翁，他容忍她吸食海洛因，支持她的时尚抱负，并为她支付公寓费用。当她意识到自己的浴缸里装满了鱼后，她寻求精神科的帮助。她走的是 Cookie Mueller 式的道路她去了路易斯安那州河口，在那里钓鱼、吸食药丸，并在海湾租了一间简陋的高跷房子。她结婚了，然后在离婚诉讼中，她意外怀孕了；她决定怀孕到足月，很大程度上是因为她的预产期恰逢她已故最好朋友的生日。相比之下，她书中关于坎耶的章节就显得微不足道了。说唱歌手的天才逐渐衰退，看起来像一个隐居的独裁者，极度悲伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这构成了一个女人的故事，她受伤而温柔，有保护欲但不可预测，她是一个自我认定的怪胎。福克斯曾一度将自己描述为“一位一生难忘的艺术家，扮演&lt;em>;我&lt;/em>;”。我最近在她的新家遇见了她，她两岁的儿子在门口绅士地挥手迎接我，然后用一个毛绒恐龙木偶攻击我，他还把它转向一小群恐龙。朋友-斜线-助手。福克斯领我下楼来到后院，那里的野餐桌已经被幼儿占领了——粉笔、卡车、火车。此时已是黄昏。当我们说话的时候，福克斯抽了一口烟，把一根棍子折成小块，她把它们按大小顺序整齐地排列起来，后院慢慢地变成了阴影。我们的对话已经过精简和编辑。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;您分娩的那一刻是什么样的？&lt; /strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;哦，天哪，这比任何毒品都好，比我吃过的任何东西都要好——如果我能活在他出来、我抱着他的那十秒钟里，我会的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;您谈到了产后抑郁症以及&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/science/annals-of-medicine/what-we-still-dont-understand-about-postpartum -精神病“产后经历令人震惊，部分原因是母亲被如此浪漫化，也因为女孩从小就被社会化，认为生孩子是最终目标。我对此很好奇，因为正如你的回忆录所明确的那样，你的生活很早就戳破了你的许多浪漫理想。你是如何在完好无损的情况下成为母亲的？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;嗯，我有很多与男人相处的经历，但我真的没有任何与母亲有关的经历。对于男人来说，泡沫很快就破灭了——当我六七岁的时候，我父亲和我最好朋友的母亲有染，这种关系持续了很多年，这真的让我彻底崩溃了。但是，作为母亲，我仍然相信这个谎言。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;你从来没有为你的孩子请过保姆，而且他也不在日托中心 -&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;直到他两岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;头两年的工作量巨大，尤其是作为单亲家长。这是您在怀孕时做出的选择吗？您想主要由您自己来照顾早期的孩子吗？是流行病吗？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;肯定是流行病一点，而且只是在经济上，我真的没有办法。我想我也来自一个我认为自己没有得到适当照顾的地方。我想让我的儿子知道妈妈就在那里，而且她一直都在那里。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;当我怀孕时，我我想，比如，我会雇一个夜间护士，雇一些帮手。但后来他出生了，我想，我不想错过任何一个时刻。我很幸运——我的家人在纽约，我有很多可以拜访的人。我的好朋友艾玛过去常常在周一和周五去日托中心接他，然后带他去公园玩几个小时。而且一开始我没有向任何人求助，因为我真的很难寻求帮助；我真的为自己能够自给自足而感到自豪。但对于一个孩子来说这是不可能的。这就是为什么现在当我看到妈妈们吓坏了，对孩子发脾气时，我可能会说，哇，真是个糟糕的妈妈。现在我就像那个可怜的妈妈。没有人一开始就想成为一名糟糕的父母。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;抚养你的儿子是否会让你对父母抚养你的方式有不同的看法？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我看起来现在更加侧向地看着他们，在某种程度上，就像——他们怎么能这样对我们？但我也对他们有更多的同情和同理心，因为我知道这有多难，我知道他们没有钱，他们处于有毒的关系中，但他们已经尽力了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;实际上，我认为他们没有尽力而为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但我只是在处理痛苦和愤怒的方式上更加激进。我就像塔斯马尼亚恶魔一样——我会摧毁一切，这会是一种宣泄。我的兄弟将这一切内化了，他现在被诊断出患有严重的创伤后应激障碍，现在我的父亲站出来了。他是我儿子最好的爷爷，我的儿子总是很高兴见到他，我要庆祝这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style =&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;3468c&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;kp6n6d&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;母亲改变了我对寻求刺激的关系，到快乐。你也是这样吗？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哦，完全是这样。曾经的我是那么的鲁莽。要么我以为自己是无敌的，要么我就是想死。但现在我永远不会——我永远不会吸毒、酗酒、发疯。我永远不会去跳伞。我什至更加意识到，我必须保持好心情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;重温回忆录中那些渴望死亡的岁月有趣吗？&lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;当我写这篇文章时，肯定有一些时刻，我想，我想兴奋起来。我是用现在时写的，所以我真的很激动，我肯定，我现在就可以兴奋起来，对吧？我觉得还可以吧？但我没有。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;显然，我觉得我的儿子是我的锚，这可能是一件好事，但有时也可能很奇怪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;你描述很早就被性化了——回忆录中有一个时刻，当你十一岁或十二岁的时候，一个成年男人给你提供了你的第一杯混合饮料。同样的事情也发生在我身上，同样的年龄，当时感觉很正常，也很兴奋，但是…… 。 .&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那时，你以为自己已经长大了。你感到受宠若惊。直到二十岁出头，我才真正意识到我周围实际上有多少恋童癖，而我根本没有考虑到这一点。我讨厌感觉自己是受害者——我他妈的&lt;em>;讨厌&lt;/em>;人们为我感到难过或可怜我。但在我二十多岁的时候，我必须真正善待自己，并接受这些糟糕的事情确实发生过。当我还是个十几岁的孩子的时候，男人们会多次向我挥出他们的鸡鸡，然后跟着我，或者用他们的鸡巴在火车上撞到我，这感觉像是正常现象，但现在很可怕.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;你在播客上说，某些记忆是如此令人难堪，以至于你甚至不想回到那里，但你决定无论如何都将它们全部放入你的书中。有什么几乎没有成功的例子吗？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;比如 . 。 。老实说，其中大部分。也许最尴尬的事情就是回到一个明显讨厌你并且对你很不好的人身边，然后一次又一次地回到他身边。这真是丢脸。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;你有代笔吗？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没有。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline- recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;你考虑过吗？或者人们是否试图让您雇用一个？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哦，是的。一开始，我什至不知道从哪里开始，如何构建它。我当时想，为什么我同意这个？我什至给我的一位老写作教授发了消息，因为她提到她使用了代笔作家，我得到了一些联系方式。我什至联系了其中一位，但日程安排有冲突——她，就像，他妈的无法接电话——而我，就像，这已经持续太久了。我需要开始。我想，如果有的话，我可以雇一个代笔人在最后编辑它，然后把我所有的材料寄过来——而且可能也会更便宜。然后我就写了整本该死的书。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;编辑它实际上就像拔牙一样。我派我的编辑到 Simon &amp;amp;舒斯特尔完成了初稿，他说，太棒了！我当时想，等一下。就像，&lt;em>;不&lt;/em>;。所以我重新阅读并编辑了它。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;这很有趣 - 所以你的草稿比你的编辑更努力？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;是的。我真的希望其他人能让它变得更好。但到那时我已经进入最佳状态，我想，我可以做到这一点。人们一直问我写这本书最困难的部分是什么，我告诉他们，就是每天坐在电脑前的椅子上打字第一行。有些日子我花了三个小时。我会在这里踱来踱去，打扫卫生，上TikTok，除了任务之外什么都做。然后，最终，我开始写作，这很好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;你是如何重建你的生活的？记忆不可靠，而且你吸了很多毒。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;书中有些东西，尤其是我年轻的时候，我把时间线打乱了一点，以便让这个故事更有意义。有些角色是复合角色，因为我和很多他妈的人陷入了同样的模式，他们基本上看起来就像一个人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;你写日记吗？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;过去十年我在 Google 文档上写了很多文章。我并不是用笔写日记，但我已经写下了一些东西——感谢上帝，因为，你知道，妈妈的大脑。而且这些文档中的内容更加生动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但我确实记得很多奇怪的事情。我只写了我的核心记忆。基本上，那段时间发生的其他事情，我根本不记得了。但我确实记得的事情我记得很清楚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;有一些细节——当你在预订室时，一个女孩因为拉面粘在她的编织里而被烤——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;强>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就像，我&lt;em>;永远&lt;/em>;不会忘记这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt; /div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div>;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;aculfd&quot;>; &lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;&lt; strong>;你和朋友检查过你的记忆吗？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;是的。然后他们都会有完全不同的记忆，我最终会想，好吧，我可以重建发生的事情。这很有帮助，但最终感觉就像是我必须独自继续这段孤独的旅程。我觉得我需要这样做，不是因为我签了合同或者是在最后期限前，而是因为我只是需要卸载所有这些东西。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我觉得当你谈论一个问题或一个问题时你遇到的问题，它就失去了对你的力量。它成为我们共同承担的负担，或以某种方式解决或代谢，所以你不会留下所有的负担。完成后我感觉轻松了很多。即使我知道我不必再保留这些记忆了，因为我已经把它们写下来了——即使我后来忘记了它们，它们仍然在那里。他们很安全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我有一种不活在当下的倾向。我正处于这场战斗或逃跑之中，但我并没有百分百在这里 - 我正在沉思已发生的事情或担心可能发生的事情。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor =&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;您吸食大麻。我认为大麻确实可以让你活在当下。这是吸引力的一部分吗？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我觉得它不再起作用了。我实际上在五月份就戒掉了大麻。真正发生的事情是我不断丢失我的笔。但我也正在经历一种转变，放弃那些不再对我有用的东西。 And weed had really helped when my son was way more dependent on me, but once he started going to his day care, and once I was in a good schedule with his dad and I was starting to get myself back a little bit, I started to feel like this thing was causing me to check out—to be a bystander to my life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;So are you entirely sober now?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I&#39;ll drink, but at this point it&#39;s probably once a month, and it&#39;s wine. And, when I&#39;m drinking, I&#39;m very conscious that I cannot be hungover tomorrow—I have to wake up early, all of that. So I can never just let loose. I do crave that, but it&#39;s just what it is.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;I want to talk about New York and money. As you remember your childhood, you were really conscious of how rich people were treated differently—rich children in particular. What did this make you aspire to?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I grew up in Yorkville, which is much nicer now, but at the time it was very working-class—it was still affordable, and wasn&#39;t desirable unless you were looking for a cheap place to raise kids. But it&#39;s right near the Upper East Side, like, the Park Avenue Upper East Side. And it felt like there was a line drawn across the neighborhood, and there was us and them. I was friends with kids that grew up in the projects, the sons and daughters of superintendents, cab drivers. And even though we went to the same school as those other girls—this good public school—it felt like they wouldn&#39;t be friends with us and we wouldn&#39;t be friends with them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;And they were always very clean-looking. Nothing ever had a hole, nothing had a tear. Their shoes fit them, their hair was always perfect, their skin was really good. And me and my friends were, like: acne, dirty sneakers that are broken, ripped clothing. And you could see it, it was obvious. I wanted to be like that.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Also, anytime my parents had ever communicated, it was to fight over money or the lack of it. So, at a young age, I was, like, OK, money equals happiness. Or at least it equals a good life and no fighting. Because there were times that my dad didn&#39;t even have twenty dollars—it was that crazy, and I just knew I did not want to end up like that.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;You gain a kind of knowledge when you grow up around rich people as someone who&#39;s not—you see things that rich people themselves don&#39;t. I sometimes think about how my kids are going to grow up—upper-middle-class children in creative-class Brooklyn. I&#39;m glad that they&#39;ll have a different relationship to money than I did growing up, but I feel a pang sometimes, knowing they&#39;ll lack a certain kind of instinct or sight.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;There&#39;s part of me that wants Valentino to grow up the way I did, because, yeah—you know all this shit. And also just because it&#39;s familiar.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;But I think that&#39;s also why I make sure that he knows how to do things for himself, even though he&#39;s still just a baby. I don&#39;t want him to become super dependent on women. When I found out I was having a boy, I was a little disappointed—I&#39;d wanted a girl. But I was also relieved, like, OK, I don&#39;t have to warn her about all these things.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Then I realized that was the mistake parents make with boys, because there are a lot of things you do have to do. I can&#39;t have him becoming an abuser in any type of way. I can&#39;t have him becoming incompetent and eventually making a female counterpart pay for that. I have to make sure that he knows how to do things for himself, knows the value of things, and ultimately just keeps it in his pants. I want my son to really step up and be a protector of women, someone who allows women the space and agency to feel safe and taken care of.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;0dws4&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;ftcat&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;You dated a billionaire for a while, starting in high school. The way you describe it, you kind of Robin Hooded him—you got an apartment where your friends could live, you had him fund these creative projects.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Everyone got put on.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;What did that experience tell you about money?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In the beginning, I was so stoked. I was just, like, &lt;em>;Wow&lt;/em>;. And then pretty early on I thought: Why am I still not happy? Why am I still miserable? And then when he left and I lost everything, that was probably the bigger learning lesson. I had all these things, but suddenly I had to sell all of them to survive, and I was back to square one, hitting up my old dominatrix clients I hadn&#39;t seen in six years, like, Come massage my feet for two hundred dollars.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;It was very humbling, and afterward I had less attachments to items. Back then, the things I was attached to were my Chanel bags, absolutely. Now the only things I&#39;d grab in a fire are things with no monetary value.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;You&#39;ve lost a lot of people you were close to, mostly from drugs. You write about loss very starkly in the memoir. How do you think about those losses in a day-to-day way?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;It just feels really unfair. I think, for a long time, I stopped believing that everything was going to get better, that God was real, all those things. Over anything else that&#39;s ever happened to me, this is what shook me to my core, where I feel like I haven&#39;t been the same ever since.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;It changed your relationship with drugs—&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;It changed my relationship with everything. I feel just a profound sense of emptiness, a void in my soul. And I think I always had a void, but this made it way more jarring. And it&#39;s just so unfair—that&#39;s the only way to describe it, because I see all these fucking shitty people who are still living their lives and not contributing anything to the world, and then my beautiful best friends, the funniest people, people who brought so much laughter into the world . 。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;That&#39;s another thing: I have a lot less laughter in my life. Before, I&#39;d be laughing all day long. Everything was a joke. Everything was crouched-down, pee-in-your-pants hilarious, and now I probably laugh like that once a year.我不是在开玩笑。我不知道。 It makes me really angry. I get super angry about it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;It feels like a much bigger part of your life than people realize. I think of the way you present the Kanye interlude in the book: it seems like your mind, at that time, was on other stuff that was happening simultaneously—child-care arrangements, friends who had died.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;And I was just getting pummelled with questions about my relationship, and this and that. In reality, I wasn&#39;t even thinking about it. That was so nothing in comparison to what I&#39;d just gone through, what I was going through.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Do you think about fame differently after getting much more famous?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;When I&#39;d picture my ideal scenario, I&#39;d always prefer a more niche kind of fame. An indie vibe, not a Page Six vibe. That&#39;s where my comfort zone is. And then being thrust into that whole other division, it was, like, Oh, my God, I hate this.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Well, you&#39;re not getting less famous, or walking it back.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;What I&#39;m hoping for is that one day I can disappear and let the work speak for itself. I have a movie I wrote in the works, other scripts I&#39;d love to develop. I have good TV-show ideas, and none of them have to do with me. Like, I might use some of my experiences, but it&#39;s not the Julia Fox story. I&#39;m just so over Julia Fox, to be honest.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I want to make my art, have some more art shows, and let the art speak for myself. But I know that probably won&#39;t happen for a while. So I&#39;m just going to go with the flow and show up where I can. Because I never &lt;em>;wanted&lt;/em>; to be famous. I just knew that I would be. In my middle-school yearbook, someone wrote that I was most likely to be dead or to be really famous. That always stuck with me, because I overdosed so many times. I only wrote about two overdoses in the book—two or three. But, in reality, like, I&#39;ve lost count. It&#39;s maybe, like, ten.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;In your book, there&#39;s this pattern where you have these deep, mostly platonic, but fundamentally romantic relationships—love affairs, really—with women. And then you&#39;re regularly sucked into these vortexes with a certain kind of man.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Narcissists, yeah.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Men who are proud to possess you, who want control. What do you make of this?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;I think it comes from an unhealed father wound or something. I could really only trace it back to that. And my friendships with women—the relationships with men just pale in comparison. The most profound relationships, the ones that make up the fibres of my being, those have all been with women. I don&#39;t know—maybe I&#39;m a lesbian and I haven&#39;t come to terms with it. But, yeah, I just go after these guys that I know will be bad for me, but I&#39;m just bored, or something. I want to go on a wild ride, to burn it all down. I&#39;m not seeking an emotional connection with them.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;4rxl4e&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;And that&#39;s why I&#39;ve just sworn off men for the past two years. I know my pattern, and until I feel like this wound or whatever it is is no longer there, I just can&#39;t go down that road again.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;You&#39;ve been talking about this—your post-men era. What prompted the beginning of it? Because men had been toxic to you for basically your whole life.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I think it was partly the state of the world that we&#39;re in, where there&#39;s so much violence to women happening right under our noses. It feels like, how could I possibly give myself to a man now when men aren&#39;t really standing up for us, right? It feels like they&#39;re ops, you know? It feels like we need to stand our ground and not even look at them until they fix it, because ultimately they&#39;re the fucking people who have the agency and the power. In any type of movement, it&#39;s always been when the white people and the men jump on board that we actually see change, which is so fucked up. I feel like, until they&#39;re really on our side, they&#39;re enemies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;I wonder how all of this intersects with the way that your body has changed. You got suddenly very skinny in recent years, which you&#39;ve talked about as an involuntary thing—is that right?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yeah.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;And you lost these curves that you were known for, and men reacted in a certain way.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yeah. The losing of the weight, the eyebrows, the clothes, all the things I did—I think I was going for grotesque. I wanted to look a certain way where the girls would appreciate it and the men would despise it.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;But which came first?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;It happened simultaneously, to be honest. I had already been feeling not OK with the state of the world and our political situation, and I was really stressed out, and my friend Harmony died, and I wasn&#39;t eating properly. I would eat maybe one time a day and it would be a sheet cake, and I was on my feet from 7 &lt;em >;AM&lt;/em>; till whatever, I was just burning everything off and losing weight so rapidly. And men started reacting like, Wait, what happened to her? She used to be so hot. And I leaned into it. I was, like, Oh, great, they &lt;em>;hate&lt;/em>; me—and I &lt;em>;love&lt;/em>; it. The more they hated me, the more fun it was to keep doing it. It was amazing to see how they reacted when I just wasn&#39;t giving them their visual stimulus, or whatever. I mean, they lashed out. They, like, took it personally.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;But, anyway, I&#39;m actually gaining weight right now.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Is this also involuntary?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yeah, it just happened. Anytime I try to go on a diet, or lose weight, or gain weight, I&#39;ve never been able to.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Do you now feel any pressure to keep your body as it has been recently? If these two versions of you are so tied to straight-male interest or straight-male aversion—do you worry that you&#39;ll get your curves back and those men will start it all up over again?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I would hate that. I really, truly hope that doesn&#39;t happen. But, also, I have no self-control. I keep three bottles of whipped cream in the fridge at a time.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;You&#39;ve talked about being raised religious, and you still pray. Where in your life do you locate that sense of the divine now?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;There&#39;s just some synchronicity of it all. And I feel like I&#39;ve gotten everything I&#39;ve ever wished for—which is why I tell people to be careful what they wish for, because they&#39;re going to get it, and then there&#39;s going to be a whole lot of other shit they didn&#39;t calculate into the equation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;What did you wish for?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Literally everything. One really crazy God moment I had was—my best friend used to live in Harlem, and one night we were hanging out and I was, like, I want to go home, I haven&#39;t been home in a few days. I was fourteen, and I walked across the park, and I realized I was being followed. So I went into the tunnel, where the cars go, because I thought maybe that would be better, but I was still being followed, and it was two or three in the morning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;So I said a prayer. I literally prayed, God, please get me to the other side of this tunnel. And I looked down and saw five dollars, and then a yellow cab came by, and I hailed it and I took it just to the other side of the park. There are just things like that—where I think I&#39;d be stupid to deny that there&#39;s some greater force. That&#39;s why everything I do, I try to take karma into account, I try not to be a hater, I try to control my negative thoughts. If a negative thought comes into my head, I&#39;m immediately just, like, No, I&#39;m that bitch. I&#39;m amazing. And I do just have an immense amount of faith that, with even the really bad things, there&#39;s some sort of lesson there that I have to learn. That I have to do something positive with, to make it more than just a really shitty thing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;A lot of your choices were driven by being a person in New York without a safety net. Do you feel like you&#39;ve made one for yourself now?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yes. I do. It&#39;s with my chosen family—I know that no matter what, they&#39;re going to take care of me, and they know I&#39;m going to take care of them. It&#39;s this unspoken thing where we have each other, and that&#39;s all we need, and we have a lifetime to prove it. I&#39;ve been with my friends Richie and Brianna for the past twenty years, and we&#39;ve had nothing, we&#39;ve had everything, we&#39;ve had nothing again. And we&#39;ve always been able to bring everything back up again. I feel like that in itself is the goal, you know? That&#39;s the blessing. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;66odm5&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 02:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Trump University Graduates Outraged They Were Never Taught to Defraud Banks]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/humor/borowitz-report/trump-university-graduates-outraged-they-were-never-taught-to-defraud-banks]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27T14:48:39.779Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65143ccc1f9c02ae6f655fcf/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Boro-Trump-University-Social.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;NEW YORK (&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newyorker.com/humor/borowitz-report&quot;>;The Borowitz Report&lt;/a>;)—Graduates of Trump University are incensed that they were never taught that defrauding banks was a crucial strategy to building a real-estate empire, the grads have confirmed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In interviews with Trump U. alumni, the former students expressed shock and dismay that such an important entrepreneurial skill was somehow omitted from the school&#39;s curriculum.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“If I had learned to defraud banks, my post-Trump University career would have played out very differently,” Tracy Klugian, class of 2006, said. “As it is, I&#39;ve gone bankrupt four times.”&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;“Every time a bank asked me how much my properties were worth, I put down the correct figure,” Harland Dorrinson, class of 2007, said. “Trump University really should have taught me how important it is to just pick a big number out of thin air.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Carol Foyler, &#39;08, said that, given the school&#39;s failure to teach the fundamentals of asset overvaluation and bank swindling, her Trump University diploma “isn&#39;t worth the Staples printer paper it was printed on.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“Trump University claimed it would teach me all of Donald Trump&#39;s real-estate secrets,” she said. “Now it seems like he kept his most important secrets secret.”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;59am6f&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;pjn2nd&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 23:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Just Making Sure You Saw My Thing]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/humor/daily-shouts/just-making-sure-you-saw-my-thing]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650e0e52cdb439d21fcbb962/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/shouts-just%20making%20sure%20you%20saw%20my%20thing.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Hey, there, just dropping you a note to make sure you saw my thing. It went up last week, my thing did. You may have seen it on my Web site, or in my e-mail blast, or maybe on one of the various content feeds I update regularly with my things and also short, enticing snippets of my things.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Real quick: please understand that these thing-snippets don&#39;t do justice to the thing-wholes, but I&#39;m hoping they draw enough viewers and entrant-tier subscribers to justify the time I spend maintaining eleven separate social-media platforms, which each has its own formatting guidelines and vibe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;But we were talking about my thing. Did you see it? As an unbiased observer, I find my thing to be unique and stirring and shareable, but not in a cheap way. I&#39;d be happy to discuss it on your podcast.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I spent a lot of time putting together my latest thing, which is usually the case when it comes to these things. Though lately I&#39;ve noticed that I spend just as much time promoting my things as I do making them. Part of the problem is that, many years ago, when I first started working on things, the goal was that I&#39;d be able to place them in any number of legacy publications that, at the time, connected thing-enthusiasts and thing-creators. But, sadly, in the years that it took to become proficient at my thing-making, the majority of these outlets either went out of business or were devoured by one of the private-equity concerns running rampant in a largely unregulated market economy. Whoops!&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;So now I&#39;m forced not just to make the thing but also to design, edit, package, code, distribute, and market it—all without any guaranteed payment or acknowledgment from an easily distractible public. If you&#39;re keeping count, that totals seven jobs and 0.65 salaries. Just me and my thing and the open plain. I&#39;m sort of like a cowboy, in that sense.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Anyway, if you&#39;ve already seen my thing—and you&#39;ve absorbed it to the extent that you can when it&#39;s been flung at you alongside millions of other things that you read, or hear about, or see flashing on the lower third of a touch screen while pumping gas—there are ways you can help me maximize the reach of my thing. Specifically, if you could post it on all eleven of &lt;em>;your&lt;/em>; social-media feeds, or just send it to a few dozen close friends, along with a personal note about how my thing is especially important in these troubled times, that would be sick.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;The goal here—if you need reminding—is to manipulate the algorithm, an opaque puzzle that when cleverly prodded and massaged will yield untold riches from within its silicon vascularity. The algorithm warps and realigns daily, but I got some savvy tips from a colleague who works six part-time gigs on top of making things—I believe his things have something to do with dolls, or maybe wood?—and I&#39;m pretty sure we&#39;ve got it beat.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I&#39;m starting to worry that I might be confusing you for someone who has a similar name. If that&#39;s the case, I&#39;m sorry, and just go ahead and let a few dozen of your friends know about my thing, too.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I don&#39;t know why I do any of this. I feel naked right now. Cold and naked, with the eyes of the world on me, or perhaps looking through me. Sometimes I worry that I&#39;m not there at all, not in any real sense. Make sure to also click that little bumblebee icon next to my thing, by the way. That&#39;s an important part of the process.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;My target audience: I know you&#39;re out there, you must be. Even now, waiting for me. Even now—Oh! There&#39;s a knock at the door! No. Just the wind. But someday, yes. So, as you read this, remember that I am out here, hustling and grinding toward your threshold. And when my day finally comes, you, me, my thing—and all things—we will be forever joined.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I exist.谢谢。 ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;w1t9r7&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;zy9dgq&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 19:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“La Isla” Shows the Absences Left by El Salvador’s Mass Arrests]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-new-yorker-documentary/la-isla-shows-the-absences-left-by-el-salvadors-mass-arrests]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650da7b64577485979424cb2/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/LA%20ISLA_THUMB_3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;feature-large-callout&quot; >;&lt;figure >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;script-container&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;When the government of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/el-salvador&quot;>;El Salvador&lt;/a>; declared a “state of exception” in March of last year, after a sudden spike in gang killings, it was supposed to be temporary. Soldiers and police officers could arrest anyone they considered suspicious. No one was entitled to a legal defense. Each month, the country&#39;s Assembly would have to vote to extend this state of affairs. But the party in power, called Nuevas Ideas, held a super-majority. Their fealty to the President, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2022/09/12/the-rise-of-nayib-bukele-el-salvadors-authoritarian-president&quot;>;Nayib Bukele&lt;/a>;, was total, as was his commitment to an indefinite campaign of law and order based on mass arrests.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The state of exception has now been renewed eighteen times. As one journalist put it to me, &lt;em>;el régimen de excepción&lt;/em>; has become &lt;em>;la normalidad excepcional,&lt;/em>; the exceptional norm. In the past year and a half, the government has jailed nearly seventy-three thousand people. At least a hundred and eighty-five prisoners have died in custody, according to the human-rights organization &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://cristosal.org/EN/2023/08/17/report-one-year-under-the-state-of-exception/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://cristosal.org/EN/2023/08/17/report-one-year-under-the-state-of-exception/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://cristosal.org/EN/2023/08/17/report-one-year-under-the-state-of-exception/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Cristosal&lt;/a>;. It&#39;s impossible to say how many innocent Salvadorans have been arrested and detained, but there&#39;s little question that ordinary citizens have been swept up despite having done nothing wrong. I spent a week in El Salvador at the very start of the state of exception, and immediately encountered two families who&#39;d lost a father and a son, respectively, to arbitrary detention. When we spoke six months later, they still hadn&#39;t returned. Thousands of Salvadorans are languishing in prison, in many cases without knowing the supposed evidence against them.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;external-link-embed--inline&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;a aria-label=&quot;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;The New Yorker Documentary&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-new-yorker-documentary/watch-the-new-yorker-documentary&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-new-yorker-documentary/watch-the-new-yorker-documentary&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;span >;&lt;strong>;The New Yorker Documentary&lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/a>;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;View the latest or submit your own film.&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;a aria-label=&quot;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;The New Yorker Documentary&amp;lt;/strong&amp;gt;&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-new-yorker-documentary/watch-the-new-yorker-documentary&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-new-yorker-documentary/watch-the-new-yorker-documentary&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/5daf63ccaae3dd0008e7fd38/1:1/w_200%2Cc_limit/undefined&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/5daf63ccaae3dd0008e7fd38/1:1/w_120,c_limit/undefined 120w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;No place in El Salvador has been spared from the crackdown, even communities that, historically, have never had gang problems. One such town is the subject of “La Isla,” by the Salvadoran filmmaker Amada Torruella. Tucked away in the Jiquilisco Bay, along El Salvador&#39;s southern coast, it&#39;s called &lt;em>;la isla&lt;/em>; El Espíritu Santo, or the Holy Ghost island.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;If you&#39;re not one of the thirteen hundred residents of the island, you need permission to get there. On arrival, you must present your ID, and the person you&#39;re visiting has to vouch for you. This practice dates to the nineteen-eighties, when the country was in the midst of a civil war. Money from one of the island&#39;s coconut coöperatives went toward collective security. Decades later, gang crime overtook towns nearby but never made it onto the island itself. “There aren&#39;t walls, there isn&#39;t barbed wire, and there&#39;s no gang graffiti,” the reporter Carlos Martínez &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://elfaro.net/es/202208/el_salvador/26319/Las-22-capturas-en-El-Esp%C3%ADritu-Santo-la-isla-sin-pandillas.htm&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://elfaro.net/es/202208/el_salvador/26319/Las-22-capturas-en-El-Esp%C3%ADritu-Santo-la-isla-sin-pandillas.htm&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://elfaro.net/es/202208/el_salvador/26319/Las-22-capturas-en-El-Esp%C3%ADritu-Santo-la-isla-sin-pandillas.htm&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;wrote&lt;/a>; in the news outlet El Faro. “No one can remember the last time someone was assassinated on the island.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;On May 13, 2022, to the shock of the local population, government authorities arrested five &lt;em>;lancheros&lt;/em>;, or boatmen, on the island, later claiming that they were collaborating with the gangs. The boatmen of La Isla perform a vital social service: they are responsible for transporting residents to the mainland and connecting the self-contained world of the island to a wider economy of goods and social services. Over the next several months, the police and Army arrested twenty others from La Isla, bringing the total to twenty-five.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Within days of the first arrests, Torruella arrived on the island. Originally from San Salvador, she travels extensively in the rural parts of the country, making films and teaching media-education classes. The historical legacy of La Isla, as well as its people, drew her there. She wanted to make a film that captured “the absences” that families were experiencing as they lost loved ones to mass arrests. “This film is a portrait of the island,” she told me. Amid the starkness of the national situation, it was the kind of place where “everything is not how it seems.” She said, “If this is what this island is living, if this is what these twenty-five people from the island are living, what is it that thousands of others are experiencing in the country?”&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;The subjects of Torruella&#39;s film are all female—the wives, mothers, and sisters of the men who have been arrested and sent to prison. “We had just come back from doing some shopping,” one of them says, “when suddenly an officer from the Armed Forces approached him.” She sits on a tidy bed in a small house, sifting through legal papers; her partner has been gone eighteen days. “It&#39;s a lie,” she says, of the government&#39;s accusation. Five months later, she&#39;s still not heard anything from him. “Innocent people are being taken away,” another wife says. “Why not investigate before taking them away?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;What&#39;s most remarkable about Torruella&#39;s film is its counterpoise between the sense of raging injustice and the island&#39;s mystic stillness. La Isla is a lush, beautiful place, with towering coconut trees and quiet lagoons. But it all feels haunted, as though the natural world of the island stands in silent rebuke to the political incursion. The absence of the detained men is practically palpable in the physical landscape. The quiet ripples of water suggest that someone has been swallowed up. The rows of leaves on a fern seem to resemble prison bars. Boats rock in the current, empty and unmanned.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The fallout is literal, too. Overnight, families have lost not only fathers, husbands, brothers, and sons but also entire livelihoods. The electricity has been turned off at one household because of a failure to pay. The outer walls of another home are starting to crumble. In one stunning scene, the women gather around a table and reminisce about their men. The camera is positioned on eye level with the women but focusses on their hands as they flit anxiously on a white tablecloth. Only seven of the twenty-five arrested residents have since been released.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Bukele has managed to do what his predecessors couldn&#39;t: virtually dismantle El Salvador&#39;s rapacious street gangs. Gangsters have gone into hiding or fled the country; for now, crime is down. Bukele&#39;s approval rating, at ninety per cent, is the highest in Latin America and perhaps the world. Leaders across the region—from Argentina and Ecuador to Honduras—have vowed to emulate him. In the US, he has earned the praise of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/tucker-carlson&quot;>;Tucker Carlson&lt;/a>; and Marco Rubio, the Republican senator. This film helps to expose the collateral damage. If innocents are locked up, who can rightly enjoy the peace?&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 19:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[A Cartoonist Appreciates the Art at the Metropolitan Museum]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/culture-desk/a-cartoonist-appreciates-the-art-at-the-metropolitan-museum]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-27T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138f32f613508748c4e9/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/0_Si_Met.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Artist drawing a marble statue in their sketchbook.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ec62494e1a7c35707/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/1_Si_Met.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ec62494e1a7c35707/master/w_120,c_limit/1_Si_Met.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ec62494e1a7c35707/master/w_240,c_limit/1_Si_Met.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ec62494e1a7c35707/master/w_320,c_limit/1_Si_Met.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ec62494e1a7c35707/master/w_640,c_limit/1_Si_Met.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ec62494e1a7c35707/master/w_960,c_limit/1_Si_Met.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ec62494e1a7c35707/master/w_1280,c_limit/1_Si_Met.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ec62494e1a7c35707/master/w_1600,c_limit/1_Si_Met.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A marble column.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138e62e026a283cb2ccc/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/2_Si_Met.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138e62e026a283cb2ccc/master/w_120,c_limit/2_Si_Met.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138e62e026a283cb2ccc/master/w_240,c_limit/2_Si_Met.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138e62e026a283cb2ccc/master/w_320,c_limit/2_Si_Met.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138e62e026a283cb2ccc/master/w_640,c_limit/2_Si_Met.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138e62e026a283cb2ccc/master/w_960,c_limit/2_Si_Met.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138e62e026a283cb2ccc/master/w_1280,c_limit/2_Si_Met.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138e62e026a283cb2ccc/master/w_1600,c_limit/2_Si_Met.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I am immediately confronted by things much larger and older than I will ever be able to fully comprehend.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Two people taking photos of art with their phones.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ffb546031cae02e3b/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/3_Si_Met.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ffb546031cae02e3b/master/w_120,c_limit/3_Si_Met.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ffb546031cae02e3b/master/w_240,c_limit/3_Si_Met.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ffb546031cae02e3b/master/w_320,c_limit/3_Si_Met.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ffb546031cae02e3b/master/w_640,c_limit/3_Si_Met.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ffb546031cae02e3b/master/w_960,c_limit/3_Si_Met.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ffb546031cae02e3b/master/w_1280,c_limit/3_Si_Met.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ffb546031cae02e3b/master/w_1600,c_limit/3_Si_Met.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I imagine that having a variety of perspectives might help.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Gustave Courbet “Woman with a Parrot.”&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ed48137d9fb6f7104/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/4_Si_Met.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ed48137d9fb6f7104/master/w_120,c_limit/4_Si_Met.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ed48137d9fb6f7104/master/w_240,c_limit/4_Si_Met.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ed48137d9fb6f7104/master/w_320,c_limit/4_Si_Met.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ed48137d9fb6f7104/master/w_640,c_limit/4_Si_Met.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ed48137d9fb6f7104/master/w_960,c_limit/4_Si_Met.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ed48137d9fb6f7104/master/w_1280,c_limit/4_Si_Met.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138ed48137d9fb6f7104/master/w_1600,c_limit/4_Si_Met.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;Gustave Courbet, “Woman with a Parrot”&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;This painting is from HO Havemeyer&#39;s extensive collection of Courbet&#39;s work. The Havemeyers were initially opposed to acquiring nudes, but, lucky for the rest of us, they were so taken by Courbet&#39;s paintings that they changed course and ended up amassing an enormous collection of his private work, including many nudes.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;(I learned this from the little placard.)&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Woman reading placard next to a painting.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138f62e026a283cb2ccd/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/5_Si_Met.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138f62e026a283cb2ccd/master/w_120,c_limit/5_Si_Met.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138f62e026a283cb2ccd/master/w_240,c_limit/5_Si_Met.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138f62e026a283cb2ccd/master/w_320,c_limit/5_Si_Met.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138f62e026a283cb2ccd/master/w_640,c_limit/5_Si_Met.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138f62e026a283cb2ccd/master/w_960,c_limit/5_Si_Met.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138f62e026a283cb2ccd/master/w_1280,c_limit/5_Si_Met.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513138f62e026a283cb2ccd/master/w_1600,c_limit/5_Si_Met.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Alexandre Cabanel “The Birth of Venus.”&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131390e8f9c7ce111a540e/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/6_Si_Met.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131390e8f9c7ce111a540e/master/w_120,c_limit/6_Si_Met.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131390e8f9c7ce111a540e/master/w_240,c_limit/6_Si_Met.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131390e8f9c7ce111a540e/master/w_320,c_limit/6_Si_Met.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131390e8f9c7ce111a540e/master/w_640,c_limit/6_Si_Met.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131390e8f9c7ce111a540e/master/w_960,c_limit/6_Si_Met.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131390e8f9c7ce111a540e/master/w_1280,c_limit/6_Si_Met.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131390e8f9c7ce111a540e/master/w_1600,c_limit/6_Si_Met.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;Alexandre Cabanel, “The Birth of Venus”&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Cabanel&#39;s nude differs from Courbet&#39;s nudes for its more idyllic depiction of the female form. Mostly, I just like the cherubs, because look at them.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Edgar Degas “The Little FourteenYearOld Dancer.”&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131390beba73981475b61c/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/7_Si_Met.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131390beba73981475b61c/master/w_120,c_limit/7_Si_Met.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131390beba73981475b61c/master/w_240,c_limit/7_Si_Met.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131390beba73981475b61c/master/w_320,c_limit/7_Si_Met.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131390beba73981475b61c/master/w_640,c_limit/7_Si_Met.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131390beba73981475b61c/master/w_960,c_limit/7_Si_Met.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131390beba73981475b61c/master/w_1280,c_limit/7_Si_Met.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131390beba73981475b61c/master/w_1600,c_limit/7_Si_Met.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;Edgar Degas, “The Little Fourteen-Year-Old Dancer”&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;As a former fourteen-year-old girl shrivelling under the male gaze, I find myself saddened and hoping it all worked out for her.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Palissy Ware plate.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313901181474410ec91ae/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/8_Si_Met.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313901181474410ec91ae/master/w_120,c_limit/8_Si_Met.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313901181474410ec91ae/master/w_240,c_limit/8_Si_Met.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313901181474410ec91ae/master/w_320,c_limit/8_Si_Met.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313901181474410ec91ae/master/w_640,c_limit/8_Si_Met.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313901181474410ec91ae/master/w_960,c_limit/8_Si_Met.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313901181474410ec91ae/master/w_1280,c_limit/8_Si_Met.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313901181474410ec91ae/master/w_1600,c_limit/8_Si_Met.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;Palissy Ware&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Truly unhinged ceramics.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A plate.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131391c62494e1a7c35709/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/9_Si_Met.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131391c62494e1a7c35709/master/w_120,c_limit/9_Si_Met.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131391c62494e1a7c35709/master/w_240,c_limit/9_Si_Met.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131391c62494e1a7c35709/master/w_320,c_limit/9_Si_Met.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131391c62494e1a7c35709/master/w_640,c_limit/9_Si_Met.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131391c62494e1a7c35709/master/w_960,c_limit/9_Si_Met.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131391c62494e1a7c35709/master/w_1280,c_limit/9_Si_Met.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131391c62494e1a7c35709/master/w_1600,c_limit/9_Si_Met.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Trying to imagine travelling back in time to a stuffy sixteenth-century household and being struck dead by this facehugger-esque nightmare plate in a china cabinet.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Man looking at a van Gogh painting.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313900b11c2dec59089b7/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/10_Si_Met.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313900b11c2dec59089b7/master/w_120,c_limit/10_Si_Met.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313900b11c2dec59089b7/master/w_240,c_limit/10_Si_Met.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313900b11c2dec59089b7/master/w_320,c_limit/10_Si_Met.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313900b11c2dec59089b7/master/w_640,c_limit/10_Si_Met.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313900b11c2dec59089b7/master/w_960,c_limit/10_Si_Met.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313900b11c2dec59089b7/master/w_1280,c_limit/10_Si_Met.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313900b11c2dec59089b7/master/w_1600,c_limit/10_Si_Met.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Van Gogh&#39;s sunflowers are for everyone.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Woman eating a scone next to a Grecian urn in a display case.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313911f9c02ae6f655dc3/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/11_Si_Met.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313911f9c02ae6f655dc3/master/w_120,c_limit/11_Si_Met.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313911f9c02ae6f655dc3/master/w_240,c_limit/11_Si_Met.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313911f9c02ae6f655dc3/master/w_320,c_limit/11_Si_Met.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313911f9c02ae6f655dc3/master/w_640,c_limit/11_Si_Met.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313911f9c02ae6f655dc3/master/w_960,c_limit/11_Si_Met.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313911f9c02ae6f655dc3/master/w_1280,c_limit/11_Si_Met.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313911f9c02ae6f655dc3/master/w_1600,c_limit/11_Si_Met.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;p >;A guard permits me to finish the last of my breakfast scone outside the “Van Gogh&#39;s Cypresses” exhibit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Inside:&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Guard shouting at someone not to take photos.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392c62494e1a7c3570b/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/12_Si_Met.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392c62494e1a7c3570b/master/w_120,c_limit/12_Si_Met.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392c62494e1a7c3570b/master/w_240,c_limit/12_Si_Met.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392c62494e1a7c3570b/master/w_320,c_limit/12_Si_Met.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392c62494e1a7c3570b/master/w_640,c_limit/12_Si_Met.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392c62494e1a7c3570b/master/w_960,c_limit/12_Si_Met.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392c62494e1a7c3570b/master/w_1280,c_limit/12_Si_Met.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392c62494e1a7c3570b/master/w_1600,c_limit/12_Si_Met.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Luckily, I&#39;ve evolved above such restrictions.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Two people standing in front of Vincent van Goghs “Newly Mowed Lawn with Weeping Tree.”&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131391a12b3bdc35742f8d/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/13_Si_Met.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131391a12b3bdc35742f8d/master/w_120,c_limit/13_Si_Met.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131391a12b3bdc35742f8d/master/w_240,c_limit/13_Si_Met.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131391a12b3bdc35742f8d/master/w_320,c_limit/13_Si_Met.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131391a12b3bdc35742f8d/master/w_640,c_limit/13_Si_Met.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131391a12b3bdc35742f8d/master/w_960,c_limit/13_Si_Met.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131391a12b3bdc35742f8d/master/w_1280,c_limit/13_Si_Met.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131391a12b3bdc35742f8d/master/w_1600,c_limit/13_Si_Met.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;Vincent van Gogh, “Newly Mowed Lawn with Weeping Tree”&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Everyone is very moved by van Gogh&#39;s cypress trees.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;People looking at van Goghs cypress trees.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513139232f613508748c4eb/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/14_Si_Met.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513139232f613508748c4eb/master/w_120,c_limit/14_Si_Met.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513139232f613508748c4eb/master/w_240,c_limit/14_Si_Met.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513139232f613508748c4eb/master/w_320,c_limit/14_Si_Met.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513139232f613508748c4eb/master/w_640,c_limit/14_Si_Met.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513139232f613508748c4eb/master/w_960,c_limit/14_Si_Met.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513139232f613508748c4eb/master/w_1280,c_limit/14_Si_Met.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513139232f613508748c4eb/master/w_1600,c_limit/14_Si_Met.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;People looking at van Goghs cypress trees.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513139262e026a283cb2ccf/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/15_Si_Met.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513139262e026a283cb2ccf/master/w_120,c_limit/15_Si_Met.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513139262e026a283cb2ccf/master/w_240,c_limit/15_Si_Met.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513139262e026a283cb2ccf/master/w_320,c_limit/15_Si_Met.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513139262e026a283cb2ccf/master/w_640,c_limit/15_Si_Met.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513139262e026a283cb2ccf/master/w_960,c_limit/15_Si_Met.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513139262e026a283cb2ccf/master/w_1280,c_limit/15_Si_Met.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6513139262e026a283cb2ccf/master/w_1600,c_limit/15_Si_Met.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;p >;(Except for this person, whose feelings are also valid.)&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Three people talking about van Gogh.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392fb546031cae02e3d/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/16_Si_Met.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392fb546031cae02e3d/master/w_120,c_limit/16_Si_Met.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392fb546031cae02e3d/master/w_240,c_limit/16_Si_Met.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392fb546031cae02e3d/master/w_320,c_limit/16_Si_Met.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392fb546031cae02e3d/master/w_640,c_limit/16_Si_Met.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392fb546031cae02e3d/master/w_960,c_limit/16_Si_Met.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392fb546031cae02e3d/master/w_1280,c_limit/16_Si_Met.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392fb546031cae02e3d/master/w_1600,c_limit/16_Si_Met.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Van Gogh “Landscape from SaintRmy.”&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392c62494e1a7c3570d/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/17_Si_Met.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392c62494e1a7c3570d/master/w_120,c_limit/17_Si_Met.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392c62494e1a7c3570d/master/w_240,c_limit/17_Si_Met.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392c62494e1a7c3570d/master/w_320,c_limit/17_Si_Met.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392c62494e1a7c3570d/master/w_640,c_limit/17_Si_Met.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392c62494e1a7c3570d/master/w_960,c_limit/17_Si_Met.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392c62494e1a7c3570d/master/w_1280,c_limit/17_Si_Met.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131392c62494e1a7c3570d/master/w_1600,c_limit/17_Si_Met.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Leaving the exhibit in an emotionally tender state, I am greeted by a gigantic vase featuring an inexplicable cartoon villain.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Woman looking up at Nicholas Sbastien Adams “Autumn.”&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131393f85db70321f0f899/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/18_Si_Met.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131393f85db70321f0f899/master/w_120,c_limit/18_Si_Met.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131393f85db70321f0f899/master/w_240,c_limit/18_Si_Met.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131393f85db70321f0f899/master/w_320,c_limit/18_Si_Met.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131393f85db70321f0f899/master/w_640,c_limit/18_Si_Met.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131393f85db70321f0f899/master/w_960,c_limit/18_Si_Met.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131393f85db70321f0f899/master/w_1280,c_limit/18_Si_Met.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131393f85db70321f0f899/master/w_1600,c_limit/18_Si_Met.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;Nicholas Sébastien Adam, “Autumn”&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;And also this.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Two people looking at JeanBaptiste Carpeauxs “Ugolino and His Sons.”&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313931f9c02ae6f655dc5/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/19_Si_Met.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313931f9c02ae6f655dc5/master/w_120,c_limit/19_Si_Met.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313931f9c02ae6f655dc5/master/w_240,c_limit/19_Si_Met.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313931f9c02ae6f655dc5/master/w_320,c_limit/19_Si_Met.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313931f9c02ae6f655dc5/master/w_640,c_limit/19_Si_Met.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313931f9c02ae6f655dc5/master/w_960,c_limit/19_Si_Met.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313931f9c02ae6f655dc5/master/w_1280,c_limit/19_Si_Met.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651313931f9c02ae6f655dc5/master/w_1600,c_limit/19_Si_Met.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;Jean-Baptiste Carpeaux, “Ugolino and His Sons”&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Ugolino is imprisoned with his kin and forced to decide between death by starvation and cannabilism. His agony is apparent in, well, everything, but especially in his interlaced toes.&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Woman melting.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131394fb546031cae02e3f/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/20_Si_Met.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131394fb546031cae02e3f/master/w_120,c_limit/20_Si_Met.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131394fb546031cae02e3f/master/w_240,c_limit/20_Si_Met.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131394fb546031cae02e3f/master/w_320,c_limit/20_Si_Met.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131394fb546031cae02e3f/master/w_640,c_limit/20_Si_Met.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131394fb546031cae02e3f/master/w_960,c_limit/20_Si_Met.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131394fb546031cae02e3f/master/w_1280,c_limit/20_Si_Met.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65131394fb546031cae02e3f/master/w_1600,c_limit/20_Si_Met.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I finally leave to brave the elements outside and discover that my mortal body remains unchanged by the experience.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 19:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Joe Biden’s Visit to a U.A.W. Picket Line Was a Powerful Political Gesture]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/joe-bidens-visit-to-a-uaw-picket-line-was-a-powerful-political-gesture]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-26T23:20:51.546Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/651342fc1181474410ec92eb/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Cassidy-Biden-UAW-Strike.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;At lunchtime on Tuesday, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/joe-biden&quot;>;Joe Biden&lt;/a>; became the first sitting US President to join a picket line. Outside General Motors&#39; Willow Run Redistribution Center, in Belleville, Michigan—not far from Detroit—Biden greeted a group of striking members of the United Auto Workers union. He told the workers that they had saved the automobile industry during the economic crisis of 2008-09 and made a lot of personal sacrifices. (These included taking wage cuts.) Now that the auto industry was doing “incredibly well,” Biden said through a bullhorn, “you should be doing incredibly well, too.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;It wasn&#39;t a new message. The day the strike began, Biden said that record profits at the Big Three US automakers—Ford, General Motors, and Stellantis—should mean record pay contracts for the UAW workers. But it&#39;s one thing to deliver remarks sympathetic to a union from behind a White House lectern. Flying on Air Force One to Detroit, taking a Presidential limousine to the Willow Run facility, standing alongside the striking employees, and appealing to the Big Three to “step up”—that is something else completely.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Appearing alongside Biden, Shawn Fain, the president of the UAW—whose relationship with the White House has sometimes been frosty—&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c-span.org/video/?530728-1/pres-biden-joins-uaw-picket-line-michigan&quot;>;described Biden&#39;s decision&lt;/a>; to join the picket line as “a historic moment.” Fain went on, “Our President chose to stand up with workers in our fight for economic and social justice.” Initially, Fain had kept his distance from the Administration after the strike began, rebuffing an effort by the White House to send two senior officials to Detroit as liaisons. But late last week, after he asked Biden to join a picket line and the President said he would, the union leader&#39;s attitude changed. When Air Force One hit the tarmac at Detroit Metro, Fain was there to greet him and to give him a black UAW baseball cap, which Biden wore outside the Willow Run facility. “Thank you, Mr. President, for coming,” Fain declared. “We know the President will do right by the working class.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;That is exactly the political message that the White House was trying to communicate by organizing the trip. Although Biden has long described himself as the most pro-union President in history, the UAW strike comes as he is facing growing political pressure—and as Donald Trump, his expected rival in 2024, has been trying to exploit the dispute for his own purposes. Trump is scheduled to make a speech in Michigan on Wednesday, before the second GOP Presidential debate, which he will not be attending. He will likely repeat his claim that the Biden Administration, by giving large subsidies to purchasers of electric vehicles, is destroying the jobs of the striking employees, who largely work at plants that make vehicles powered by gasoline and diesel.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;During the first Presidential debate in 2020, Trump said, “I think I&#39;m all for electric cars. I&#39;ve given big incentives for electric cars.” (He was referring to tax credits introduced during the Obama Administration.) But facts and history are immaterial to Trump, and some recent head-to-head polls have shown him ahead of Biden in the 2024 race. More than a year before the election, these polls arguably don&#39;t have much predictive value, but the White House knows that it needs to shore up Biden&#39;s working-class support in Michigan and other swing states.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Last week, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/republican-support-for-the-uaw-is-a-big-lol&quot;>;I pointed out&lt;/a>; that Biden does have a strong record on labor issues. Lacking sixty votes in the Senate, he couldn&#39;t pass the union-supported &lt;em >;PRO&lt;/em>; Act, which would make organizing unions easier and weaken the right-to-work laws that exist in twenty-seven states. But since he entered the White House, he has consistently expressed support for unions. And his appointees to the National Labor Relations Board, the agency entrusted with enforcing labor laws, have issued a series of rulings that should make it easier for nonunion workers to organize and harder for nonunion employers, such as Starbucks and Amazon, to intimidate them. If Trump were to win next year, these rulings would surely be reversed, despite his pro-worker bluster.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Can the Biden Administration get &lt;em>;this&lt;/em>; message across? In our splintered age, when many people consume only news and information that reinforce their political opinions, nothing is guaranteed. Even in this polarized environment, though, some events and images can break through and have a lasting impact. Biden&#39;s appearance on the UAW picket line could conceivably be one of them. Recent Democratic Presidents, including Barack Obama, tended to stay neutral in labor disputes, and Biden&#39;s decision to break with that tradition has offended at least one Wall Street Democrat. “For him to be going on a picket line is outrageous,” Steven Rattner, the chairman of Willett Advisors LLC, who led Obama&#39;s auto-industry task force, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcnews.com/politics/white-house/biden-makes-history-striking-auto-workers-picket-line-rcna117348&quot;>;told NBC News&lt;/a>;. “There&#39;s no precedent for it.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;That, of course, is why it was a powerful gesture. As Fain was delivering his remarks, in which he repeated that the auto strike represents a crusade against corporate greed and “the billionaire class,” Biden looked on. He fist-bumped one of the UAW members and draped his arm around the shoulder of another. After Fain had finished speaking, the President took the bullhorn again. “Let&#39;s keep going,” he told the striking workers. “You deserve what you&#39;ve earned, and you&#39;ve earned a hell of a lot more than you get paid now.” ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;2xjf3&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;lxtnx&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 08:06:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>