<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>纽约客</title><description>纽约客全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.newyoker.com <item><title><![CDATA[A Hedge-Fund Founder’s Obsessive Storytelling]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/books/under-review/a-hedge-fund-founders-obsessive-storytelling]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16T22:53:29.621Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65539919c116a2cd3e5437f0/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/Hitt-UnderReview-Ray-Dalio.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt; div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12. 5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4 H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt; svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/标题>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径 d =&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;2010 年春天，一个名为 Dealbreaker 的网站获得了一份值得注意的 PDF。 Dealbreaker 是一个效仿 Gawker 的八卦和新闻博客，专门关注华尔街和高级金融界出现的卡通人物和情节。这份PDF文件特别令人感兴趣，因为它涉及该省尚未产生的更加丰富多彩、独特和自大的人物之一：&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2011/07/25 /mastering-the-machine&quot;>;雷·达利奥&lt;/a>;，世界上最大的对冲基金之一桥水基金的创始人。该文件列出了 Dealbreaker 所称的“达利奥之道”和达利奥所称的“原则”，这是一份中篇小说长度的宣言，该博客声称桥水基金鼓励员工阅读、在日常生活中部署并定期引用。工作。 “如果你对布里奇沃特的达利奥之道一无所知，”Dealbreaker 观察到，“你可能会问自己‘这是什么狗屎？’” ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是“对冲基金非官方手册”的首次公开亮相。其中一个版本概述了两百多条一般规则，从简短的公理（“三思而行”）到有关达尔文竞争的长篇轶事，所有这些都汇编在一份设计混乱的文件中，大量使用了省略号、突出显示、下划线、粗体文本、图表和方程式，例如“现实+梦想+决心=成功的生活”。前面的一章描述了达里奥最喜欢的一个寓言，其中一群鬣狗攻击并吞食了一头角马。达利奥表示，有些人可能会认为鬣狗是“邪恶的”，因为“可怜的角马受苦并死去”。但事实上，这个结果对于双方来说都是好事。鬣狗是为了自身利益而行动，在食物链中发挥自己的作用。而且，作为更大生态系统的一部分，角马也会以一种迂回的方式获利。 “杀死并吃掉角马可以促进进化，”达里奥写道，“（即自然的改进过程）。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个故事旨在体现创始人的领导哲学。为了促进“自然的改进过程”，达利奥对桥水基金的员工实行了一套“彻底透明”的制度：据说批评是受欢迎的，甚至是鼓励的，只要批评是直接针对对象而不是在他们背后提出的。 “我相信，彻底的真相和彻底的开放对于这一快速进化过程的发生至关重要，”达利奥写道，“因为它可以防止产生隐藏议程并阻碍公开辩论的秘密性。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这些原则公开十三年后，《纽约时报》记者 Rob Copeland 发表了“&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Fund-Bridgewater-Associates- Unraveling-Street/dp/1250276934&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Fund-Bridgewater-Associates-Unraveling -Street/dp/1250276934&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Fund-Bridgewater-Associates-Unraveling-Street/dp/1250276934&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;该基金&lt;/a>;”，这本书将达里奥的传记和布里奇沃特的历史融为一体，对这些原则在实践中的运作方式进行了密切观察的调查。科普兰在《华尔街日报》工作了近十年，之后转投《泰晤士报》，并在其职业生涯中大部分时间撰写有关桥水基金等对冲基金的文章。他对公司的了解得益于深入的资料来源，借鉴了新的记录访谈、内部文件和多封泄露的电子邮件，其中一些直接导入到文本中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但达利奥已经显然，他没有以他的管理哲学所建议的那种自我毁灭的谦逊态度来接受科普兰的调查。 （《原则》的早期版本写道，“在桥水基金，人们必须非常重视了解真相，以至于他们愿意为了得到真相而羞辱自己。”）科普兰声称，在他向桥水基金通报“该基金，几名前工作人员收到了额外的报酬，这样他们就不会向媒体发表讲话。 （布里奇沃特称这“明显不真实”；达利奥的一位代表表示，这是“绝对错误的”。）达利奥没有配合这本书的报道，根据科普兰的说法，他和布里奇沃特还聘请了来自“不是一两个而是”的律师。三个白鞋律师事务所”威胁科普兰的出版商圣马丁出版社提起诉讼，要求赔偿数十亿美元。达利欧和布里奇沃特都认为，这本书对公司的描述不准确，包括达利欧原则的使用方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科普兰似乎很喜欢达利欧的反应。正如他在作者笔记中所写，“雷·达里奥不希望你读这本书。”但他对达里奥的描绘与这位对冲基金人轻易透露的自己的形象并没有太大出入。除了精心完善他的公理之外，达利奥还花了几十年的时间在几乎所有有他的媒体上公开发表自己的观点，阐述他的基金、他的哲学和重要的存在问题（他在一篇文章中写道：“什么是珠宝商？”）。在读完自己不喜欢的文章后，达里奥经常打电话给科普兰“训斥”他。 （达利奥通过一名代表表示，他们的谈话是尊重的。）但科普兰写道，这些所谓的长篇大论也使这位高管成为“记者的最终消息来源”——在电话中，达利奥不可避免地会透露一些信息。新事实，让他获得了另一个领先优势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1975 年，达利奥创立桥水基金时，他并没有太多资产。他是一位爵士音乐家的独生子，在科普兰所说的长岛郊区的工人阶级长大。他与财富的初次接触是在他担任球童的高尔夫球场。达利奥是一名中等学生，但很健谈，他以 C 的平均成绩考取了附近一所大学的试读生，并开始冥想，并提高了自己的平均绩点 (GPA)，足以帮助他在哈佛商学院获得一席之地。他在研究生就业市场上表现不佳，曾短暂监管过一家陷入困境的大宗商品公司，之后因涉嫌殴打老板和带脱衣舞娘参加工作活动等原因被一家经纪公司解雇。但达利奥在当球童时就拥有一些老钱人脉，而且碰巧正在和一位潜在的支持者约会。他即将成为的妻子芭芭拉 (Barbara) 是范德比尔特 (Vanderbilt) 家族成员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;达里奥 (Dalio) 创立桥水基金是为了提供商品咨询服务，而这种资产类别长期以来一直被视为不受欢迎的资产类别。科普兰写道，达里奥与旧财富的接近告诉他，大型机构投资者对增长最大化并不感兴趣，而对风险最小化更感兴趣。他最初的业务就是管理这种风险。如果一家公司依赖波动性大宗商品，他会通过投资可能抵消损失的资产来帮助他们稳定成本。随着时间的推移，该公司逐渐发展成为管理同时持有多头头寸（押注特定资产将会升值）和空头头寸（押注特定资产将会贬值）的投资组合。 “这实际上是一家对冲基金，”科普兰写道。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;在十九世纪七十年代初的几次市场崩盘之后，对冲基金已经过时了，但到了接下来的十年，它们又重新脱颖而出。科普兰认为，达里奥拥有良好的时机和优势。除了投资之外，达里奥还把自己标榜为宏观经济思想家，为客户和行业同行出版有关全球趋势和历史研究的时事通讯。作为一名预测者，达里奥经常失准。他倾向于每次都看到厄运和衰退。在一个值得注意的例子中，他警告国会委员会，美国正在进入下一次萧条，一位国会议员称其表现“比哈姆雷特父亲的鬼魂更可怕”。仅仅几周后，市场就开始反弹。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;即使 Dalio 犯了错误，桥水基金也表现出色，部分原因是公司的投资策略比他的预测更加系统。正如科普兰所说，达里奥在对全球货币、趋势和历史数据的广泛研究的基础上，制定了一套基本的“如果-那么”交易指南。在对冲基金的早期，很多交易都是基于心血来潮、本能和模糊的占卜行为，比如读带，以通过电报传输交易的行情纸带而得名。按照科普兰的说法，达里奥的系统化、基于研究的方法构成了“无可置疑的优势”。&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;像许多高级金融领域的居民一样，达里奥对行话产生了浓厚的兴趣，这都是他自己的行话和一般华尔街方言的发明。后者包括：“阿尔法”和“贝塔”。正如达里奥所说，贝塔值是“任何投资者都期望通过市场敞口获得的投资回报”。相比之下，阿尔法是“额外的果汁”——精明的投资者可以在贝塔收益之外添加任何东西。达里奥开始专注于创造“真正的阿尔法”。九十年代初，他在桥水基金内部开发了一只名为 Pure Alpha 的独立基金，这是一种投资工具，旨在有效地发挥所有作用，不间断。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管达利奥继续错误地预测经济末日，但几乎按年计算，桥水基金在成立之初的几年里增长迅速。科普兰写道，在九十年代，Pure Alpha 的资产每个财年大约翻一番。达利奥常年扮演诺查丹玛斯的角色并不总是表现不佳。当互联网泡沫破裂并导致经济陷入困境时，达利奥和桥水却毫发无伤。到 2003 年，达利奥跻身全球最富有的对冲基金经理之列，首次登上&lt;em>;机构投资者&lt;/em>;富豪榜，仅当年的估计收入就达到 1.1 亿美元。但这本书主要讲述的不是达里奥如何登上顶峰，而是他到达顶峰后对自己留下的遗产的痴迷。在这本三百多页的书中，达利奥在第五十九页首次考虑了自己的退休生活。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2005 年末，当达利奥首次宣布退休计划时，他已经五十六岁了——还没有退休年龄，但已经足够考虑没有他他的企业将如何运作。对冲基金是名牌商品；当这个名字退役时，投资往往会随之而来。因此，根据科普兰的说法，正是在那时，达里奥首先开始整理他的方法，不仅是投资方法，而且是一般领导力方法。他开始口授有关桥水基金理念和“核心价值观”的备忘录，并设计了一系列一般性戒律，根据科普兰的说法，这些戒律“归根结底是重视相互争论而不担心冒犯的能力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;早期版本的原则有两百七十七条。多年来，达利奥不断调整并添加到该列表中，即使在 2017 年的回忆录中发布了经过大幅修改的版本后，“&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Principles-Life- Work-Ray-Dalio/dp/1501124021&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Principles-Life-Work -Ray-Dalio/dp/1501124021”}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Principles-Life-Work-Ray-Dalio/dp/1501124021&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;原则：生活和工作&lt;/a>;”。它们充满了达里奥设计的术语。找到你的“盒子”意味着弄清楚你在公司中的角色，而失去你的盒子就是听起来的意思；那时，员工要么找到一个新的（“到达另一边”），要么被“分类”（解雇）。还有一些“叽叽喳喳的人”，他们只是重复陈旧的想法，而不是发明自己的想法。如果一个人在背后议论他人，他就是“狡猾的黄鼠狼”。然后还有“塑造者”——有远见的领导者，他们的确切属性有些模糊，但他们往往是公众人物，根据科普兰的说法，达里奥似乎主要是“在他们花了很长时间与他交谈之后”才任命的。&lt;/ p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;xw2p0j&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div 数据-node-id=&quot;zrfxlo&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper &quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;“基金”描绘了一个桥水基金，其中对原则的遵守创造了一种几乎不断抱怨的氛围，实际问题和琐碎竞争之间几乎没有区别。员工被要求找出任何缺陷，并在全公司的“问题日志”中报告。由于达利奥规定了每周发行配额，因此这些条目的范围从正常的担忧到对“自助餐厅沙拉吧里的豌豆枯萎”的争论。达利奥通过记录建筑物中的几乎所有内容来履行他对完全透明的承诺。当一名工作人员被指控犯有不当行为时，达利奥会进行公开审判，通常是在其他工作人员面前，而且几乎总是录音。他将视频上传到中央“透明图书馆”，其中一些视频被编辑成简短的培训视频。工作人员几乎每天都要观察他们并完成简短的测验，他们的答案似乎是自己提供的。一个具有代表性的是或否问题：“我们是否应该不惜一切代价掌握真相，以便如果一个人撒谎，他们就应该被解雇？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;按照科普兰的说法，达里奥的调查可能会变得非常残酷。他曾经斥责一位高级副手——一位冷漠而冷酷的女人，被称为“冰雪女王”——直到她崩溃，科普兰形容为“动物般的抽泣”。 （这位女士没有回应&lt;em>;纽约客&lt;/em>;的置评请求。）随后的培训视频标题为“痛苦+反思=进步”，成为求职者必看的视频。试验也可能变得相当复杂。达利奥的继承人格雷格·詹森曾一度与未来的联邦调查局局长、当时担任桥水基金总法律顾问的詹姆斯·科米合作，调查詹森的竞争对手之一、一位名叫艾琳·默里的高管。被指控的罪行是默里隐瞒了一名新员工的背景细节，并谎称与她的助理共同撰写了一封电子邮件。 （科米没有回应置评请求；默里的一位发言人表示，书中关于她的“存在一些事实错误和歪曲事实”，而且她并没有故意省略有关该员工的细节。）但科米和詹森转向了达里奥将其编辑成连续剧“剧集”，每周发布供全公司观看。根据科普兰的说法，该系列剧是“电视真人秀、肥皂剧和真实电影的结合”。达利奥称之为“艾琳谎言”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;达利奥原则的最终目标似乎不仅是创造一般公理，而且是一种计算系统，一系列 if-then 类型的规则，可以将人类行为的各个方面。科普兰写道，他指派了一个团队为员工制作“棒球卡”，即有效的个性化成绩单，公开记录员工在他的各种指标上的得分，并在两千人中进行记录。这个想法是根据达利奥设计的七十七种不同属性对人员进行排名，处理统计数据，如球员的打点。这些卡片发展成为复杂的“多页打印输出”，其中越来越难以量化的神秘属性，例如“毅力” ”、“个人披露”和“活在真实中”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;评分系统的激励结构，达利奥的意见可能导致任何统计数据直线下降，显然没有理由让员工有理由直言不讳地表达自己的观点。老板。正如《基金》所言，达里奥本人只有在极少数情况下才会收到诚实的反馈。科普兰讲述了达里奥邀请哈佛大学经济学家尼尔·弗格森到西港（桥水基金总部所在地）坐下来的一个例子。在一次采访中，弗格森回忆道，达里奥提出了他的最新理论，即经济也可以被编纂——历史必然是周期性的，通过了解其节奏和轮换，人们可以准确预测哪些国家会成功或失败。弗格森显然不同意。 “没有办法对历史进程进行建模，”他礼貌地说，“也绝对没有办法对重债国家做出的选择进行建模。”根据科普兰的说法，达里奥开始出现故障。他的头摇了摇头。他的腿在颤抖。他站起来尖叫道：“尼尔，你他妈的模特在哪儿？”人群鸦雀无声，客人也鸦雀无声。 “没有模型，”科普兰写道。 “这就是重点。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;似乎历史和人类思想中的非理性物质实际上抵制达里奥的编纂，但这并没有阻止他尝试。根据科普兰的说法，他的方法只是变得更加先进。他设计了多个应用程序——Dot Collector，用于桥水基金无休止的员工评估，以及Dispute Resolver，用于根据原则调解冲突——所有这些都被上传到公司发行的iPad上。这些不同的应用程序最终被收集到一个 Daliofied 软件程序中，这一努力的形式和名称一样经常发生变化。它的许多别名包括 Prince（“原则”）、PriiOS（“原则操作系统”）和 Vassal（农奴以上的封建阶级）。也许最贴切的名字是《未来之书》，它阐明了该项目的狂妄野心和达里奥对其可行性的古怪感觉。 “一旦未来之书上线，”科普兰写道，“它将解决布里奇沃特剩下的最紧迫的问题。”但《未来之书》已经成为过去：2021年，经过十多年和至少一亿美元，桥水悄悄“解雇了大部分致力于构建原理软件的剩余员工。”&lt; /p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div 数据-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;lf9plb&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div 数据-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;在 Copeland 早期关于该项目的一篇文章中，布里奇沃特的一名工作人员将其描述为“将雷的大脑变成计算机的尝试” ”——他的决策参考点在他退休后仍会持续存在。从某种意义上说，科普兰的书比创始人自己的努力更接近实现这一目标。 《基金》并没有提供创始人思想的完美模型，但它确实提供了达利奥心灵的生动写照：帮助他征服对冲基金世界的对系统和规则的痴迷最终使他分心。&lt;/ p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;根据 Copeland 的说法，Dalio 对原则的投入似乎与他的基金的成功成反比。达利奥的规则和将其编纂为不可能的任务开始占用对冲基金的大部分时间。科普兰声称，在其鼎盛时期，桥水基金的 2000 多名员工中，只有不到 20% 的人“被分配到研究或投资引擎”。 （Dalio 的发言人对此提出异议。）这种资源使用方式不会对公司有利：科普兰认为，当 Dalio 专注于 PriOS 和 Dot Collector 时，金融界的其他人已经赶上了他的步伐。基于研究的投资方法。桥水基金的表现不再远高于同行：在某些年份，Pure Alpha 的表现几乎不优于其他对冲基金； &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;而且，尽管 Dalio 早在 2005 年就宣布最终退休，但他在书中用大部分篇幅拒绝放弃任何立场。科普兰讲述了潜在高管的旋转门，他们为了获得最高职位而奋力拼搏，但最终失败了。达利奥花了数年时间培养他的门生詹森，但当达利奥发现詹森在背后议论时，这种前景也破灭了，最终导致了另一场精心设计的公开审判。直到疫情结束后，达利奥才正式辞职，以换取科普兰报告每年价值 10 亿美元的退出方案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《基金》并不是达利奥想象中的那本书。巩固他的遗产。庞大的通用管理指标纲要并不能解决未来所有的问题。这甚至不是他据称花了数年时间试图委托撰写的传记。 2011 年，据称达里奥试图说服作家沃尔特·艾萨克森 (Walter Isaacson) 撰写他的人生故事。很容易理解为什么达里奥可能希望将自己的名字添加到艾萨克森的&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/09/18/elon-musk-walter-isaacson-book-review&quot; >;主题列表&lt;/a>;，其中包括亨利·基辛格、阿尔伯特·爱因斯坦和史蒂夫·乔布斯。但艾萨克森显然并不认为达里奥是他的类型。桥水基金的几名员工表示他拒绝了。 （达利奥否认要求艾萨克森为他写传记；艾萨克森为这本书与科普兰进行了交谈，他说他“不记得向他提出过这样的要求。”）&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;达利奥确实和艾萨克森主题的普通人一样痴迷与图像。但他同样对自我披露有一种不同寻常的、几乎是反企业的亲和力，痴迷于创建档案。这种留下书面记录的冲动让他对像科普兰这样缺乏同情心的评估师敞开了大门。仅透明度图书馆就包含“数万小时”的音频和视频片段，描述了该基金的内部运作。一般的高管可能会认为这样的存储库是一种巨大的负担，但达利奥花了数年时间才减少了他的归档工作。 （2019 年，一位法律顾问建议，维护这样的宝藏“与最佳法律实践的另一端相反。”）很难想象还有什么记录比达利奥自己创造的记录更可怕了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在该书的后记中，科普兰讲述了他在 2009 年经济衰退期间大学毕业后不久，如何申请桥水基金的职位但遭到拒绝。这段十年前的经历似乎在达利奥对他的对手的理解中占据了重要地位，他不止一次地用后者的描述来形容他：“一位在桥水基金无法取得成功的愤愤不平的求职者，一心想从事某种工作。”报仇。”也许是为了避免这本书的出版，达里奥警告说，他可以对科普兰十几年前的布里奇沃特申请完全诚实。 “我们仍然保留着当时收集的笔记，”达利奥写道，“如果我们能了解这些笔记，我们很乐意将其公开。”即使退休了，他还是忍不住要拿收据。 ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;vq7gkv&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-隐藏=“true”>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;&lt; br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt; /a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 07:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[The Cassette-Tape Revolution]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/cultural-comment/the-cassette-tape-revolution]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16T21:13:14.574Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6555105c0669d65be3038719/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/Michaud-Cassette-Tapes.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >; &lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox= &quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312 L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4 H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存这个故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width =&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>; &lt;路径 d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M 23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt; /svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt; div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;针对华盛顿特区郊区的中学音乐欣赏课程，十九世纪七十年代末，我们的老师要求我们每人带一段录制的音乐，在教室的便携式电唱机上播放，这是一个石板蓝色的盒子，有一个像蟹爪一样的肥大的音臂。我确切地知道我想分享的录音：“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/music/2020/nov/11/she-made-music-jump-into-3d-wendy-carlos -the-reclusive-synth-genius&quot;>;Switched-On Bach&lt;/a>;”，温迪·卡洛斯 1968 年的专辑，我在父亲丰富的唱片收藏中发现了这张专辑。虽然我最近开始把零用钱花在齐柏林飞艇和比利·乔尔等人的专辑上，但我内心的一些马屁精确信，老师会更喜欢我选择的古典相邻曲目，而不是我的同学可能喜欢的当代调频广播曲目。带进来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过，有一个问题。我的父亲是一位狂热的发烧友，他拒绝让学校的电唱机毁坏他的卡洛斯专辑。他提出用他的卷盘式录音机录制“Switched-On Bach”。学校有这样的吗？第二天，老师确认了，但她警告说，她不知道如何操作。这取决于我。我父亲在家里给了我一个关于他的&lt;em>;TEAC&lt;/em>;的教程，但是当轮到我上课时——在其他所有孩子都在黑胶唱片上演奏了他们的选择之后——我无法制作学校的卷轴到卷轴机器好好工作。音乐的节奏加快了，就像阿尔文和花栗鼠的表演一样。当同学们笑起来时，我尴尬地瘫倒在地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当然，还有一个更简单的解决方案：盒式磁带。该盒式磁带的形状像一副扑克牌（或一包香烟），价格便宜、便于携带、易于使用，而且非常适合共享。卡带可以放在家用汽车的脚部空间或背包的底部。但它也被像我父亲这样的发烧友看不起。正如 Marc Masters 在他最近的书中指出的那样，“&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/High-Bias-Distorted-History-Cassette/dp/1469675986&quot; data-event-click=&quot; {“element”：“ExternalLink”，“outgoingURL”：“https://www.amazon.com/High-Bias-Distorted-History-Cassette/dp/1469675986”}&quot; href=&quot;https:// /www.amazon.com/High-Bias-Distorted-History-Cassette/dp/1469675986&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;高偏差：盒式磁带的扭曲历史&lt;/a>;，”盒式磁带“在它接触到的所有东西上留下了污迹”，增加了噪音和嘶嘶声，每次播放时音质都会下降。我父亲从未采用过录音带——他在九十年代转向了光盘——但对于我们这一代人来说，录音带的优点是显而易见的，而它的缺点很容易被忽视。在 &lt;em>;ArtForum&lt;/em>; 中撰写，&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.artforum.com/columns/audiocassettes-196616/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;: “ExternalLink”、“outgoingURL”：“https://www.artforum.com/columns/audiocassettes-196616/”}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.artforum.com/columns/audiocassettes-196616 /&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;徐华观察&lt;/a>;，“磁带开创了一个可以控制个人私人音景的时代”，现在我们都认为这是理所当然的。这种控制的新颖性对于我们这些听黑胶唱片长大的人来说是令人兴奋的。突然之间，任何拥有廉价磁带播放器的人都可以录制音乐、对其进行排序、分发，并且——也许是最有力的——擦除它并用其他东西替换它。如今，盒式磁带在很大程度上被视为怀旧的图腾，在当时具有启发性和革命性。它的颠覆性力量预示着数字时代将为音乐带来更大的结构性转变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;紧凑型录音带（全名）是由荷兰公司产品开发主管 Lou Ottens 构思的。飞利浦电子公司。 One day, in the early nineteen-sixties, frustrated after “fiddling with that damn reel-to-reel” (as a colleague later recalled), an exasperated Ottens told his design team to create a version of their reel-to-reel tape that was small and portable, with the spools of tape contained inside a case. He wanted it to fit in a pocket and imagined it would be used by journalists and nature lovers (the latter to record birds and other outdoor sounds). Phillips introduced its new cassette system in 1963 and the immediate response was underwhelming. Before long, however, imitations of their compact cassette player began cropping up across the globe, most frequently in Japan.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Ottens then made a decision that helped boost the format. To promote standardization of the cassette, Phillips waived royalties, allowing anyone to license the design for free as long as they adhered to the company&#39;s quality-control standards. This avoided the kind of schism that videotape would face during the VHS-Betamax war and insured that the Phillips cassette would be the dominant design. By the end of the sixties, eighty-five different manufacturers were producing cassette players, with sales of 2.5 million units. By 1983, cassettes were outselling LPs.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;The ascent of the cassette caused a major freak-out among record-company executives. Nearly anyone who has ever bought vinyl will be familiar with the cassette-and-crossbones image that was for many years printed on record sleeves, accompanied by the dire warning: “Home taping is killing music.” On both sides of the Atlantic, the recording industry sought, futilely, to make the duplication of music on cassette tapes illegal. Other proposals included a compensatory tax on blank tapes. A member of the National Association of Recording Merchandisers even went so far as to equate cassettes with recreational drug use: “Very soon it becomes a hobby. And after it becomes a hobby, it becomes a habit.” None of those strategies blunted the popularity of the cassette tape. As Masters observes, the “perception that home taping was illegal or at least immoral . 。 。 succeeded in making tapes seem even cooler and more rebellious.”&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;While the design of the audiocassette hasn&#39;t changed much since its inception, the machines used to play it have evolved in magnificent and unpredictable ways. There&#39;s a wonderful scene in Zack Taylor&#39;s 2016 film, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.cassettefilm.com/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.cassettefilm.com/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cassettefilm.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Cassette: A Documentary Mixtape&lt;/a>;,” in which Ottens examines a display of tape players in the Phillips archive, including a telephone-answering machine, a deck that could play a stack of cassettes in sequence, and the first AM/FM radio-cassette combo. The two most consequential innovations in the tape player, however, were the boom box and the Sony Walkman personal stereo. One allowed you to externalize your musical taste, the other to internalize it. (Indeed, a Walkman was often the best defense against the sonic assault of a boom box.)&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;swptzo&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;129evr&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;The cassette&#39;s democratization of music production and reproduction paved the way for new musical genres. None was more important than hip-hop. Long before rap made it to the airwaves, taped live performances by mcs and djs at parties in the Bronx circulated to the rest of the city—and, ultimately, the world—via cassette. Masters quotes Fred Brathwaite (aka Fab 5 Freddy) who recalled, “A big part of this hip-hop culture in the beginning was putting things in your face, whether you liked it or not. That was graffiti, or a break-dance battle right at your feet . 。 。 or this music blasting loud.” Unlike a record player—or the reel-to-reel tape player—the boom box was both portable and commensurate with the scale and the volume of the city. “Cassettes &lt;em>;were&lt;/em>; hip-hop,” Bobbito Garcia, of the Rock Steady Crew, says in Taylor&#39;s documentary.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;For other musicians, the limitations of the cassette became a creative boon. Keith Richards loved the effect he could achieve by recording his guitar on a cheap cassette player. “Playing an acoustic, you&#39;d overload the Phillips cassette player to the point of distortion so that when it played back, it was effectively an electric guitar,” he wrote in his memoir, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Life-Keith-Richards/dp/031603441X&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Life-Keith-Richards/dp/031603441X&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Life-Keith-Richards/dp/031603441X&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Life&lt;/a>;.” His guitar parts on the Rolling Stones&#39; hits “Jumpin&#39; Jack Flash” and “Street Fighting Man” were recorded in this way. “That grinding, dirty sound,” Richards reflected, “It&#39;s unexplainable.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In 1982, Bruce Springsteen used a &lt;em >;TEAC&lt;/em>; 144 four-track machine to record the stripped-down acoustic songs that became “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/culture-desk/the-original-wrecking-ball-bruce-springsteens-nebraska&quot;>;Nebraska&lt;/a>;.” The &lt;em >;TEAC&lt;/em>; was one of the first consoles that allowed musicians to do multi-track recording on a conventional cassette tape. (Springsteen used Maxells and mixed the recordings down on a water-damaged Panasonic boom box.) Though he originally intended those “Nebraska” tapes to be demos for a studio album, when Springsteen got into the studio with his band, he found that he couldn&#39;t reproduce the aura of those cassette recordings. “The slightest alteration really ruined it,” Springsteen told the writer and musician Warren Zanes. “The nature of the unbelievably basic equipment we used was just unique.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Though much eulogized in the decades since it was overtaken by the compact disk, the cassette tape, even in our digital era, is far from dead. As CDs in turn gave way to downloads and then to streaming, the cassette faded from the mainstream, but found refuge on the fringes, in the basements and bedrooms, the backs of zines and the depths of Bandcamp, the merch table in the alcove at the club (and, more recently, &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.urbanoutfitters.com/cassettes&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.urbanoutfitters.com/cassettes&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.urbanoutfitters.com/cassettes&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;at Urban Outfitters&lt;/a>;). A few years ago, cassettes even got their own annual promotion, like Record Store Day. (&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.cassetteweek.com/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.cassetteweek.com/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.cassetteweek.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;You just missed it&lt;/a>;.) Simple nostalgia is not enough to explain why the cassette endures so persistently. Again and again in Masters&#39;s book and Taylor&#39;s documentary, aficionados of the cassette tout its limitations and imperfections as essential to its ongoing appeal. Like human beings, the cassette tape is analog, flawed, and perishable. “Our bodies are not digital,” the former Sonic Youth front man Thurston Moore tells Taylor. “We&#39;re not robots.”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;eco9to&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;The second half of Masters&#39;s book is given over to documenting myriad groups of tape enthusiasts, collectors, and sharers, as well as the busy network of small labels that continues to release new music on cassette. Much of this work is experimental and non-commercial. (If you don&#39;t have access to a tape deck and would like to hear some of it, you could tune in to the rambunctious and nerdy &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://tabsout.com/&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://tabsout.com/&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://tabsout.com/&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Tabs Out Cassette Podcast&lt;/a>;, which will soon post its two hundredth monthly episode.) “High Bias” makes a persuasive case that all of this cassette-based activity functions as a sort of understory in the forest of music, a substructure in the shadows that nurtures and fortifies the canopy of successful commercial artists above.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;For me, however, the most revelatory chapter was on the cassette&#39;s potency and longevity in non-Western countries, many of which had state-controlled radio and music distribution systems. The cassette provided a way of subverting those authoritarian gatekeepers, spreading protest songs—or in some cases, dance music and wedding music—that were deemed improper, offensive, or dangerous. Masters profiles a group of “tape hunters” who have spent years searching the bazaars, kiosks, and market stalls of Asia, Africa, and the Middle East for musical novelty. It was while reading this chapter that I embraced “High Bias” as an extended, paperbound mixtape of cassette-based music. No longer owning a cassette player myself, I made a playlist (on Spotify, alas) of some of the artists featured by Masters, including the keyboardist Hailu Mergia, of Ethiopia; Omar Khorshid, an Egyptian composer and guitarist who recorded his albums in Lebanon; Sun City Girls, an experimental rock band from Phoenix; and the funky fusion of Ghana&#39;s Ata Kak. But the artist I&#39;ve most enjoyed discovering is Mamman Sani, a Nigerien-Ghanaian electronic-music pioneer, whose composition “&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/PYAi8h1Ir5c?si=NrWj6O1IE87NRiDD&quot;>;Five Hundred Miles&lt;/a>;”—originally recorded and distributed on cassette—calls to mind some of the selections Wendy Carlos played on “Switched-On Bach.” ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;32pjib&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 06:06:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[George Santos to Spend More Time with Imaginary Family]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/humor/borowitz-report/george-santos-to-spend-more-time-with-imaginary-family]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16T20:59:57.050Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65567ba3d82694afbcc21341/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Boro-Santos-11-16-24-social.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;WASHINGTON (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/humor/borowitz-report&quot;>;The Borowitz Report&lt;/a>;)—In an announcement that many in Washington felt was overdue, Representative George Santos said that he was resigning from Congress to spend more time with his imaginary family.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“As much as I&#39;ve loved this job, it&#39;s taken me away from my kids,” he said. “And to them I say: Blake, Kaylee, Agnes, Skip, Molly, Charlie, Leeann, and Rex, Daddy&#39;s coming home.”&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;He thanked his children for taking care of his many imaginary pets, including a marmot named Jerry and a python named Estelle.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;As for his future plans, he said that he would be leaving Congress “to go back to my first love: being a member of the Beatles.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“Today is an emotional day for me,” he said. “If I don&#39;t look emotional, it&#39;s because of the Botox.”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;lg82gdv&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;ja3ydq&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 05:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How Qatar Became the World’s Go-To Hostage Negotiator]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/how-qatar-became-the-worlds-go-to-hostage-negotiator]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16T18:15:21.735Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6554ede90f1de632623b28b6/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Simon-Qatar-Hostages.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Qatari negotiators in Doha thought they had a deal. It was late October, and for weeks they had been mediating between representatives of Hamas and the Israeli government to secure the release of the estimated &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/the-plight-of-the-hostages-and-the-rapidly-escalating-crisis-in-gaza&quot;>;two hundred and thirty hostages&lt;/a>; whom Palestinian militants had captured on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/11/06/israel-gaza-war-hamas&quot;>;October 7th&lt;/a>;. By that point, Hamas had released four hostages—an Israeli-American mother and daughter, and two Israeli women—as a result of agreements brokered by Qatar and Egypt. The Qataris had noted that, although there could be no explicit quid pro quo, Hamas could expect that freeing the hostages would facilitate the delivery of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/q-and-a/the-humanitarian-catastrophe-in-gaza&quot;>;humanitarian aid into Gaza&lt;/a>;, and lead to a pause in Israel&#39;s military invasion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;On October 25th, Hamas agreed to a deal to free fifty people, but Israeli officials had one more demand: the names of those who would be released. Hamas balked, claiming that, because the hostages were held by various factions, they did not have a complete record ready to hand over; to assemble one would require a days-long halt in the fighting. The Israelis interpreted this as a stalling tactic. Two days later, the deal collapsed. Within hours, the Israeli military launched its full-scale ground invasion of Gaza, which has been accompanied by a relentless aerial bombardment and intermittent communications blackouts, causing terrible suffering for Palestinian civilians. According to Gaza&#39;s health ministry, more than eleven thousand Palestinians have been killed since the start of the war.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;On Wednesday, Hamas and Israeli officials were &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/qatar-seeking-israel-hamas-deal-release-50-hostages-3-day-truce-sources-say-2023-11-15/&quot;>;reported&lt;/a>; to be once again close to a deal. The agreement, which was being brokered by Qatar, Egypt, and the US, would involve the release of fifty hostages in exchange for around the same number of Palestinians held in Israeli prisons, and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/how-would-a-humanitarian-pause-work-in-gaza&quot;>;ceasefire&lt;/a>; for several days. Qatar has been a particularly useful intermediary with Hamas because of its long-standing support for Gaza, for which it has provided what some estimates suggest is more a billion US dollars&#39; worth of aid since 2014. Qatari money has been used to help pay for fuel and government workers in Gaza, including the salaries of doctors and teachers. Qatar has also hosted an overseas political office for Hamas in Doha since 2012—a decision for which it has faced criticism from Israel and from some US lawmakers, but which it defends as having been made at the request of American officials, who hoped to establish a channel of communication. Today, that channel is integral—in addition to Israelis, Hamas&#39;s hostages include American, Thai, French, and British citizens; officials from those countries have all travelled to Doha in recent days, in the hopes of freeing their nationals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In the decades since 9/11, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/hostage-taking-and-the-use-of-children-and-the-vulnerable-in-war&quot;>;hostage-taking&lt;/a>; has become an increasingly prominent component of modern warfare. At the same time, governments, including those of Iran, Russia, China, and Venezuela, have detained foreign citizens on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/how-the-families-of-american-hostages-created-bipartisan-support-for-prisoner-swaps&quot;>;trumped-up criminal charges&lt;/a>; as a way to gain political leverage. (In the US, both kinds of cases are referred to the same authorities, and treated as instances of hostage-taking.) Qatari officials compare their role to that held by Swiss diplomats. For decades, the Swiss have been involved in international hostage negotiations, but in today&#39;s geopolitical landscape, the Qataris are in a more useful position.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In the Middle East, Qatar has presented itself as neutral, hosting a major US military base while also maintaining open lines of communication and, in some cases, direct relationships with the groups that the troops were fighting against. Qatar is also a major supplier of energy to the US, yet it maintains close ties with Iran, with whom it shares a major natural-gas field. This has allowed it to successfully intervene in cases where hostages have been held in Iran and Afghanistan. But recently Qatar has also begun to operate outside its usual sphere of influence. In 2021, it played an important role in winning the safe return of the American journalist &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/autocrats-not-terrorists-are-increasingly-taking-americans-hostage&quot;>;Danny Fenster&lt;/a>; from Myanmar. And, in October, Qatari officials helped negotiate the return of several Ukrainian children kidnapped by Russia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;But Qatar&#39;s role has not been without controversy. Qatar&#39;s first mediation efforts pertained to a wave of kidnappings carried out by Islamists in Iraq at the start of the insurgency that arose in response to the US-led invasion. Two French journalists, Georges Malbrunot and Christian Chesnot, were travelling from Baghdad to Najaf in August, 2004, when they were kidnapped by a group calling itself the Islamic Army in Iraq. Four months later, they were released in exchange for a multimillion-dollar ransom, according to a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.voanews.com/a/a-13-2006-05-22-voa8/324977.html&quot;>;report&lt;/a>; in the &lt;em>;Times&lt;/em>; of London. Malbrunot says that a senior Qatari official later confirmed to him that the ransom was paid, though not the exact amount. France and Qatar denied paying any ransom.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Although Malbrunot was grateful to Qatar for whatever role it played in securing his freedom, he went on to spend years investigating the country&#39;s role in financing political Islam around the world. In a 2019 book, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Qatar-papers-French-Christian-Chesnot-ebook/dp/B07QJ7TP6T?ref_=ast_author_dp&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Qatar-papers-French-Christian-Chesnot-ebook/dp/B07QJ7TP6T?ref_=ast_author_dp&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Qatar-papers-French-Christian-Chesnot-ebook/dp/B07QJ7TP6T?ref_=ast_author_dp&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Qatar Papers&lt;/a>;,” Malbrunot and Chesnot allege, based on secret documents, that Qatar was indirectly helping to finance Islamist groups—including those engaged in hostage-taking—while earning the gratitude of European governments for winning the release of their hostages. “It&#39;s part of their diplomacy of being friends with anybody,” Malbrunot told me, during an interview I conducted while researching a book on hostage policy. Though the country&#39;s officials say that they are guided by humanitarian principles and a desire to reduce conflict and promote stability, they have clearly used their leverage to gain influence and visibility, a posture which they believe enhances their security in a volatile region. “That&#39;s the double game, the gray zone,” Malbrunot said.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Qatar&#39;s practices have also rankled governments in the Middle East. In 2017, a group of Qatari falcon hunters who had been captured by members of an Iran-backed Shiite militia in southern Iraq were released, after tortuous negotiations that resulted in Qatar transferring hundreds of millions of dollars to Iraq. Soon after the deal, a coalition of Arab countries, led by Saudi Arabia, launched a regional blockade against Qatar over a long list of grievances, among them the allegation that the country was funding Islamist groups in Syria and Iraq. (Qatar has framed its payment to Iraq as being designated for the Iraqi government.)&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The question of how much Qatar continued to play the “double game” became more pressing as the United States&#39; approach to hostage negotiations has evolved. In the two-thousands, the US adhered to a staunch policy against making concessions to designated terrorist groups. Many of its officials interpreted this as a prohibition on negotiations. European countries, including Spain and Italy, were known to pay ransoms, and Washington was concerned by this practice, which it claimed incentivized kidnapping while channelling huge sums of money to insurgent and militant groups. But the Americans&#39; position was tested when, between 2012 and 2014, Islamic State militants captured a large group of Westerners in Syria. After the European governments paid ransoms, their hostages were freed; the Americans and the British, whose governments refused to pay, were murdered.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In 2014, the Obama Administration commenced a review of its hostage guidelines. Its policies regarding concessions or ransoms remained unchanged, but the review, which was completed the next year, clarified that negotiations were not forbidden, and Qatar subsequently became an essential player in such discussions. Since then, those involved in hostage-response efforts, both inside and outside the government, have come to describe the country&#39;s role as indispensable.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Christopher O&#39;Leary, who served as the director of hostage recovery for the US government from March, 2021, until September, 2023, said, “The Qataris are exceptional mediators, very motivated and very willing to assist with conflict resolution.” O&#39;Leary, who now works at the Soufan Group, a security consultancy involved in many hostage-recovery efforts, spent much of his career as an FBI agent focussed on counterterrorism. He recalls a period after 9/11 and into the Iraq War when government officials were concerned about potential Qatari support for Al Qaeda in Iraq stemming from influential figures in Qatar. The US&#39;s investigations were inconclusive, and Qatar was never sanctioned.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In recent years, as kidnappings of Americans have changed from an enterprise largely carried out by insurgent groups to one regularly employed by states (like Iran) and entities controlling territory (like Hamas), US officials seeking to recover Americans taken hostage have benefitted from Qatar&#39;s long-standing relationships. “I don&#39;t know when it shifted, but it&#39;s come a hundred and eighty degrees,” O&#39;Leary told me. During the two and half years that O&#39;Leary spent leading hostage recovery for the government, he worked closely with Qatari officials in negotiating the return of Americans from Iran, Afghanistan—starting in 2013, the Taliban had been permitted to maintain an office in Doha—and Mali. O&#39;Leary credits Qatari diplomats with winning the release, in 2022, of the American contractor &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/an-abandoned-american-hostage-finally-makes-it-home&quot;>;Mark Frerichs&lt;/a>;, who was held by the Haqqani network, an Afghan militant group linked to Pakistani intelligence, for more than two years, and who was released in exchange for a convicted drug trafficker, Haji Bashir Noorzai. Qatar has become so essential to managing such crises, O&#39;Leary told me, that it was included in a global hostage-crisis simulation led by the US earlier this year, alongside representatives of America&#39;s key European allies and the Five Eyes intelligence group.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;According to the White House, there are about ten Americans among the hostages; it clearly hopes that Qatar will be able to assist in brokering an agreement that brings them home. But, in recent days, Israel&#39;s military action in Gaza has become a sticking point in the negotiations: Israel claims that the severity of its attacks are putting pressure on Hamas to release the hostages, while the Qataris say they need a pause in the fighting to make a deal. “It&#39;s really frustrating and disappointing to see ourselves retracting from the progress that we have achieved,” a senior Qatari official told me in early November. “So that&#39;s why we&#39;ve been in close contact also with the Israelis to get to deëscalation, to pauses that will help us and will give us some space for the hostages&#39; release.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Hostage-taking is a cruel crime; it is also a violation of international humanitarian law. But hostage crises are not resolved through slogans or posturing, and rarely through rescue or military operations. In the vast majority of cases, they are resolved through negotiations—and, in order to negotiate, opposing parties need an effective interlocutor. “In addition to the contacts and reputation for securing these deals, you need the process, the skill set, and the division of labor,” Dani Gilbert, an assistant professor of political science at Northwestern University and a leading expert of hostage policy, told me. Being a successful hostage negotiator is “an influential position to be in. To be needed and valued by more powerful countries gives them the position of a real power player on a geopolitical issue that is getting a lot of attention.” Qatar may have reaped rewards from performing such work in recent years, but it has also proved that it can be a reliable and responsible conduit. One can only hope that, in Gaza, it can prove itself again. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;d4og86&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;2qzd7&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 03:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Define Genocide]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/news/q-and-a/how-to-define-genocide]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16T17:31:26.531Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6554ec99e33c47a0b2a5212f/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Chotiner-Bartov-Site-Social.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Last week, the &lt;em>;Times&lt;/em>; published an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2023/11/10/opinion/israel-gaza-genocide-war.html&quot;>;opinion piece&lt;/a>; by the historian Omer Bartov, which raised the question of whether Israel&#39;s military actions in Gaza constitute a genocide. “I believe that there is no proof that genocide is currently taking place in Gaza, although it is very likely that war crimes, and even crimes against humanity, are happening,” Bartov wrote. “That means two important things: First, we need to define what it is that we are seeing, and second, we have the chance to stop the situation before it gets worse.” (More than eleven thousand Palestinians have been killed, according to Gaza&#39;s Ministry of Health. A State Department official testified before Congress that it is “very possible” that the figure is even higher than reported.)&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Bartov, who was born in Israel and currently teaches at Brown University, is one of the foremost scholars of the Holocaust, as well as German policy during the Third Reich. In numerous books and essays, he has sought to explain how Nazi ideology manifested throughout Hitler&#39;s regime–and especially in its military. Bartov ended this latest piece by writing, “There is still time to stop Israel from letting its actions become a genocide. We cannot wait a moment longer.” I recently spoke by phone with Bartov. During our conversation, which has been edited for length and clarity, we discussed how precisely to define genocide, the importance of establishing intent when labelling something a genocide, and why a focus on terminology can be important in preventing mass atrocities.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;What distinguishes genocide from crimes against humanity or ethnic cleansing?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;There are clear differences in international law. War crimes were defined in 1949 in the Geneva Conventions and other protocols. They are serious violations of the laws and customs of war and international armed conflict, and they can be committed against either combatants or civilians. One aspect of this is the use of disproportionate force—that the extent of the harm done to civilians should be proportionate to your military goals. It could also be other things, such as the maltreatment of prisoners of war.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Crimes against humanity do not have a UN resolution, but they were defined by the Rome Statute, which is now the basis for the International Criminal Court. That talks about extermination or other crimes against civilian populations, and it does not have to happen in war, whereas war crimes obviously have to happen in the context of war.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Genocide is a bit of a strange animal because the Genocide Convention of 1948, on which it&#39;s based, defines genocide as the “intent to destroy, in whole or in part, a national, ethnical, racial or religious group, as such.” And this “as such” matters because what it means is that genocide is really the attempt to destroy the group and not the individuals in that group. It can be accomplished by killing members of the group. It can also be accomplished by other means such as starving them or taking away their children, or something that will bring about the extinction of the group rather than killing its individuals.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Yes, I was going to ask about the word “destroy,” and whether it is very clear that that means “kill.”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;No, it doesn&#39;t. Now, usually, not just in the popular imagination but also in law, often the association is with killing. When Raphael Lemkin was coming up with this term—he was a Polish Jewish lawyer who came to the United States during the Holocaust—he spoke specifically about a cultural genocide, which is when you really just destroy the group as a group. So let&#39;s say there may be Jewish people around, but they don&#39;t know that they&#39;re Jews anymore, or you take all their children away and therefore there won&#39;t be a continuation of that group. It doesn&#39;t necessarily mean killing. In Australia or Canada, where there was removal of children from Indigenous groups, that has been defined as genocide.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;The current example that people often use is what&#39;s happening to the Uyghur population in China, even though as far as we know there are no mass killing campaigns.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Yes, destroying their culture.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Is the term “ethnic cleansing” used more to talk about removing people from a certain territory?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yeah, so the difference between genocide and ethnic cleansing is roughly that in ethnic cleansing you want to move people from a territory that you want, and then they can go wherever they want. In a genocide, you target the group never mind where they are. But it should be said that ethnic cleansing actually does not have a clear definition in international law, and it comes under various other categories of crimes against humanity. There&#39;s no convention on ethnic cleansing. And the last very important thing about it is that ethnic cleansing usually or often has preceded genocide. That actually happened in the genocide of the Herero, starting in 1904, and the genocide of the Armenians, starting in 1915. The Holocaust arguably began as ethnic cleansing, as removing Jews from territories controlled by Germany, and then when there&#39;s no place to move them to, the Germans said, “Well, we might as well kill them.” So there is a connection between them.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;The Herero were people in what is modern-day Namibia, and you are referring to the German behavior toward them, correct?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;1560r&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;2bqf0j&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Right. The German Army is sent there to quell an uprising. The German general issues an extermination order. It&#39;s the first modern extermination order. But what he&#39;s basically telling them is that they should go to the Kalahari Desert, and obviously they are very likely to die there, especially because the Germans are busy plugging up all the watering holes there. So the genocide is accomplished by removing them from their territory into a desert. That is what the Ottoman authorities initially do to the Armenians. They just send them to the desert, through arid areas in what are now eastern Turkey, northern Syria, where many people die without being directly killed. That&#39;s the overlap between certain genocides and ethnic cleansing.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Let&#39;s say there&#39;s a terrorist attack on a country and the country starts bombing the territory from where the terrorist attack originated, and where it was planned, and in the process of doing so starts killing a large number of civilians. What would be the things that you would look for to determine if crimes against humanity or, more specifically, genocide was taking place?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The first, most important thing is that the definition of genocide begins with the words the “intent to destroy.” You need to identify intent, so that if this army goes off to bomb that area from which the terrorists came and its intent is to destroy the group that attacked them in a terrorist act, and it says, “This whole group has to be wiped out because they are all bloody terrorists,” that is an intent that can be then added to the actions themselves to produce what might be genocide. Whereas if they go and they say, “OK, these terrorists came from a particular group, they&#39;re in a particular town, they have particular camps, and we are going to bomb that organization, and in the course of that, we may also kill a lot of civilians, but what we are interested in is killing those particular terrorists,” then it could become war crimes or even crimes against humanity, but it might not be genocide.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;You write in your piece, “My greatest concern watching the Israel-Gaza war unfold is that there is genocidal intent, which can easily tip into genocidal action. On Oct. 7, Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said that Gazans would pay a &#39;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.haaretz.com/israel-news/2023-10-07/ty-article/.premium/israeli-prime-minister-netanyahu-we-are-at-war-we-will-win/0000018b-0978-dc5d-a39f-9f7cb7ee0000&quot;>;huge price&lt;/a>;&#39; for the actions of Hamas and that the Israel Defense Forces, or IDF, would turn parts of Gaza&#39;s densely populated urban centers &#39;&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-palestine-war-places-hamas-is-hiding-well-turn-them-into-rubble-warns-israel-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-4460729&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-palestine-war-places-hamas-is-hiding-well-turn-them-into-rubble-warns-israel-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-4460729&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.ndtv.com/world-news/israel-palestine-war-places-hamas-is-hiding-well-turn-them-into-rubble-warns-israel-pm-benjamin-netanyahu-4460729&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;into rubble&lt;/a>;.&#39; On Oct. 28, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npr.org/2023/11/07/1211133201/netanyahus-references-to-violent-biblical-passages-raise-alarm-among-critics#:~:text=NETANYAHU%3A%20(Through%20interpreter)%20You,from%20the%20Book%20of%20Samuel.&quot;>;he added&lt;/a>;, citing Deuteronomy, &#39;You must remember what Amalek did to you.&#39; As many Israelis know, in revenge for the attack by Amalek, the Bible calls to &#39;kill alike men and women, infants and sucklings.&#39; ” Can you talk more about this focus on what leaders say?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;There&#39;s a huge amount of that coming out from Netanyahu, who usually is more careful with his words. The President of the state of Israel, too, said it wasn&#39;t just Hamas but all the people of Gaza who are responsible. The Minister of Defense spoke about “human animals”—and it&#39;s not always clear if he means Hamas or Gazans. That&#39;s the kind of language that has been used in several genocides, where you dehumanize a group constantly. The Hutu were doing that about the Tutsi, the Nazis obviously were doing it about the Jews, and so forth. And just recently, Avi Dichter, who is a Likud minister, was saying, “We are now rolling out the Gaza Nakba.” That&#39;s a reference to the Nakba of 1948—the expulsion of the Palestinians. That&#39;s a clear intent of ethnic cleansing.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;sfi9rs&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;When you see this kind of verbiage constantly being put out by people—politicians, generals, and so forth—it makes you worry. First of all, it filters down to the soldiers. It incites people to more and more violence. It dehumanizes the population that they&#39;re fighting, and it&#39;s in a situation where you are attacking an organization that is deeply entrenched within very congested areas with numerous civilians. So all of that obviously makes you worry that this can become something more systematic.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Does the destruction have to be about the group&#39;s identity? Think of a leader who is very angry about a terrorist attack and just wants to get revenge and kill a lot of people, and doesn&#39;t care who happens to be on the ground in the city he&#39;s bombing versus someone who wants to kill people because they are members of the group.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Exactly. That is the distinction. And you can take an example. Let&#39;s say, after the Second World War, we had the Nuremberg Tribunal, right? This was, among other things, victor&#39;s justice. No one was being put on trial for carpet-bombing German and Japanese cities in which hundreds of thousands of civilians died. What was the strategy of the Americans and the Brits in bombing cities in Germany, or America in firebombing and then nuclear-bombing Japanese cities? The goal was not to destroy the German people as such, or the Japanese people as such. The goal was to win the war, and they were doing it by all means possible, and they were doing it very brutally, and one might very well have found these actions to be war crimes subsequently. But the goal was not genocide in the sense that they had no interest in destroying the Japanese people and culture, or the German people. And, in fact, right after the war, they started rebuilding those countries. So that&#39;s a distinction. Ethically, you may say, “War is horrible and people shouldn&#39;t do all those things,” but those are the legal distinctions, and, to my mind, they actually matter. It&#39;s important to make that distinction.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Why is it important?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;It&#39;s important to say, is this a first-degree murder or second-degree murder? Even when you&#39;re talking about violence, about vile actions, it helps to tell the difference. In this case in particular, the Germans killed a lot of civilians and the Americans killed a lot of civilians. Is there a difference between the two? I think it&#39;s important to make that distinction. It&#39;s even important to make the distinction between the Soviets killing a lot of people and what the Germans did. All kinds of conservatives ignore this distinction these days, where there&#39;s a new historiography saying, “Well, they were just like the Nazis.” The distinction is that if the Germans had ended the war as winners, they would&#39;ve actually enslaved and murdered millions and millions and millions more people. After the Soviets won the war against Germany, very brutally, with a lot of rapes and all that, East Germany was a dictatorship. But they were not killing people en masse anymore, so they were not genocidal. That makes a difference, even on the scale of morality where both things may be horrible.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;yja1fk&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;y0bzb&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;You said first- and second-degree murder, but maybe one analogy to draw would be hate crimes, which evoke a special revulsion, even if the utilitarian ends of a specific hate crime are the same as a regular crime.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;How do you think about a case where the intent may not be to destroy a people, but where those people are viewed as less human than you are, and you don&#39;t care how many of them die. How do we think about that in the context of genocide?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Even if your intent is not to destroy the group as such, but functionally that&#39;s what you&#39;re doing, and much of your rhetoric is about treating those people as subhuman, then you are in that kind of gray zone between a well-planned, thought-out genocide, which is on the one extreme, and something that gradually becomes that. But it&#39;s a fine distinction. I don&#39;t think that the policymakers in Israel are actually thinking genocide. They&#39;re using that language and they&#39;re using policies that are pushing in that direction, but they&#39;re not thinking of themselves as carrying out genocide.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Part of what is happening on the ground is if you displace large numbers of people from their homes, if you then cram them into a much smaller territory, you destroy the homes from which they came, if they receive not enough infrastructure, food, water, medical care, and they start dying in large numbers, your goal may have been to win a military campaign and to do it as ruthlessly and quickly as possible knowing that your political clock is running out, but the result begins to look more and more like genocide.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Why did you want to write this piece now? You&#39;ve explained why you think it&#39;s morally important to recognize genocide as distinct from other things, but is there some more practical reason?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yeah, look, the obvious reason is that when you study genocide, you always look back and say, “There were all these signs that it&#39;s going to happen, and why was nobody doing anything about it, or at least warning that it&#39;s about to happen?” And usually there were people issuing warnings. Instead of waiting until something happens, it&#39;s better to warn.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;The violence is on a very different scale from anything that has happened before in Gaza. The mentality is different. The rage is different. And once you start speaking about it, it may actually have an effect, both on those who can stop it on the outside, especially the American Administration, and on some people on the inside, who say, “Wait, I mean, we are getting ourselves into something that we didn&#39;t intend to do.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;You served in the IDF, correct?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yes, I did.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Where were you stationed and when?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Well, I was conscripted in January, 1973, so I served in the war of &#39;73, which I was lucky enough to spend on the Jordanian front. Happily, the Jordanians did not attack us in that war. And then I was transferred to the so-called Syrian Enclave. This was in the aftermath of the war, when the Israeli forces were deep in Syria. And so I spent several weeks in First World War-type positions, getting shelled every day and losing people around me.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;eq1vng&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Do you think serving changed your relationship to Israel?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;No. No. There were two things that affected me. One was the outbreak of the 1973 war. When I was in high school, in the early seventies, and I was in a kind of progressive high school in Tel Aviv, we were already protesting against the occupation and marching and saying, “Occupation corrupts.” There were peace feelers being put out at the time by Egypt, by Anwar Sadat. Moshe Dayan, the former Defense Minister, famously said, “Better Sharm el-Sheikh without peace than peace without Sharm el-Sheikh,” meaning, “Better to keep Sinai. We don&#39;t need the peace. We are strong enough, because look what we did to them in &#39;67.” And then the war happened. Three thousand Israeli soldiers were killed, ten thousand were wounded. Members of my generation carry that sort of PTSD to this day. And, in fact, October 7th, I think, woke that in many of them. They were really sort of shaken twice over because of what happened in &#39;73.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;And so, the first thing that I thought about was that war. There were many of us who thought that war could have been avoided. The leadership suffered from what I call the euphoria of power. And that&#39;s exactly what has happened now. War taught me that there are wars that can be avoided. You think you can keep what you have because you&#39;re strong enough to be able to keep it, and eventually it blows up in your face.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;The second thing was that I served a little bit as an occupation soldier. I was a platoon leader, walking down the street with a line of soldiers behind me in the sun. People are hiding behind their windows looking at you, and they&#39;re terrified of you. You are a little scared of them, too, because you don&#39;t know if they&#39;re going to throw some grenade at you or whatever. You feel that you have no business being there. You feel like, “Why am I there?” I really distinctly remember that sensation. Several generations of young Israelis have spent most of the military service as policemen, policing an occupied population. What does that do to the occupied and what does that do to the occupier? There&#39;s a mutual dehumanization going on that ends up with such horrors as we saw and we are still seeing. It&#39;s a slow process, but it is that kind of moral corruption that I think I started sensing already as a very young man. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;r2objp&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 02:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Daily Cartoon: Thursday, November 16th]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/cartoons/daily-cartoon/thursday-november-16th-dress-for-the-weather]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16T15:57:46.081Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655639395f65083c5f1da0de/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/A28443.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Buy &lt;em>;New Yorker&lt;/em>; Cartoons »&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;favdtq&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;k5vg4g&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 01:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Taking It to the Streets]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/cartoons/blitts-kvetchbook/taking-it-to-the-streets]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16T16:47:53.269Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655634837d10bdf89a37e607/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/20231116_Blitt_kvetchbook_Counter_Protestors.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A series of protests and counterprotests becomes smaller and smaller.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655644116c39740b0b970a69/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/2023_11_16_Blitt_kvetchbook_Protest_vertical.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655644116c39740b0b970a69/master/w_120,c_limit/2023_11_16_Blitt_kvetchbook_Protest_vertical.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655644116c39740b0b970a69/master/w_240,c_limit/2023_11_16_Blitt_kvetchbook_Protest_vertical.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655644116c39740b0b970a69/master/w_320,c_limit/2023_11_16_Blitt_kvetchbook_Protest_vertical.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655644116c39740b0b970a69/master/w_640,c_limit/2023_11_16_Blitt_kvetchbook_Protest_vertical.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655644116c39740b0b970a69/master/w_960,c_limit/2023_11_16_Blitt_kvetchbook_Protest_vertical.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655644116c39740b0b970a69/master/w_1280,c_limit/2023_11_16_Blitt_kvetchbook_Protest_vertical.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655644116c39740b0b970a69/master/w_1600,c_limit/2023_11_16_Blitt_kvetchbook_Protest_vertical.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;http://www.condenaststore.com/~/cartoon-bank?utm_medium=referral&amp;amp;utm_source=NewYorker&amp;amp;utm_content=daily-cartoon-mod&amp;amp;AID=1247905545&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Buy &lt;em>;New Yorker&lt;/em>; Cartoons »&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;zqsdp&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;6u4nyd&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 17 Nov 2023 01:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Is “The Golden Bachelor” Too Good to Be True?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/podcast/critics-at-large/is-the-golden-bachelor-too-good-to-be-true]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16T11:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/650b59e2f49b447c4924fa7b/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/CAL-WEB.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;figure data-testid=&quot;IframeEmbed&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;IframeEmbedContainer&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;iframe height=&quot;120&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-scripts allow-popups allow-same-origin&quot; title=&quot;Embedded Frame&quot; src=&quot;https://playlist.megaphone.fm/?e=CNE9461985142&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay *; encrypted-media *; clipboard-write; autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&quot;>;&lt;/iframe>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;Listen and subscribe:&lt;/em>; &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/critics-at-large-%7C-the-new-yorker/id1704902371&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/critics-at-large-%7C-the-new-yorker/id1704902371&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/critics-at-large-%7C-the-new-yorker/id1704902371&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Apple&lt;/a>; | &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/show/2SPRInxtPCz2nmvKgHLWDt&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://open.spotify.com/show/2SPRInxtPCz2nmvKgHLWDt&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/show/2SPRInxtPCz2nmvKgHLWDt&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Spotify&lt;/a>; | &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://link.chtbl.com/tnycriticsatlarge&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://link.chtbl.com/tnycriticsatlarge&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://link.chtbl.com/tnycriticsatlarge&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Wherever You Listen&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/newsletter/goings-on&quot;>;Sign up&lt;/a>; to receive our weekly cultural-recommendations newsletter.&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;p >;Reality television is all about artifice, and contestants on “The Bachelor” often seem more interested in becoming influencers than in finding a spouse—but “The Golden Bachelor,” a new spinoff starring a seventy-two-year-old widower named Gerry, has been hailed for its surprising sincerity. On this episode of Critics at Large, the staff writers Vinson Cunningham, Naomi Fry, and Alexandra Schwartz discuss how the show eschews—and, at times, reinforces—the tropes that have polarized viewers of the ABC franchise, and what a genre known for its phoniness can reveal about actual human emotions and experiences. The hosts consider other depictions of sex and romance at this stage of life, including Philip Roth&#39;s memorable rendering of an older man&#39;s libido in “The Dying Animal” and HBO&#39;s “And Just Like That . 。 。 ,” a rare look at older &lt;em>;women&#39;s&lt;/em>; erotic prospects. Then, they take a step back to examine how series like “The Bachelor” have shaped our conception of love stories writ large. “The Golden Bachelor” &#39;s insistence on the vitality of its contestants can feel like a step forward, but what does it mean that the show is so fixated on what Schwartz calls “a second teen-agerdom”? “The boomers set a model for what it is to be young that persists for all the generations that have followed,” she says. “Now here they are again, saying, &#39;We&#39;re here; yes, we&#39;re older; and we want to get old in our own way.&#39; ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;New episodes drop every Thursday. Follow Critics at Large &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://link.chtbl.com/tnycriticsatlarge&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://link.chtbl.com/tnycriticsatlarge&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://link.chtbl.com/tnycriticsatlarge&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;wherever you get your podcasts&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;xtbnss&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;pnqp68&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 19:06:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[More Accurate Names for the Bodily Systems as I’ve Got Older]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/humor/daily-shouts/more-accurate-names-for-the-bodily-systems-as-ive-got-older]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16T11:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551051f61952da865f4bf8/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/0_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The Skeletal System:&lt;/strong>; The “Nobody Told Me How Achy My Joints Were Going to Feel After Twenty-Five” System&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Hand on knee emanating a bullseye of pain.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6555105112f28da31d63e8af/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/1_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6555105112f28da31d63e8af/master/w_120,c_limit/1_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6555105112f28da31d63e8af/master/w_240,c_limit/1_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6555105112f28da31d63e8af/master/w_320,c_limit/1_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6555105112f28da31d63e8af/master/w_640,c_limit/1_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6555105112f28da31d63e8af/master/w_960,c_limit/1_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6555105112f28da31d63e8af/master/w_1280,c_limit/1_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6555105112f28da31d63e8af/master/w_1600,c_limit/1_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;The Muscular System:&lt;/strong>; The “I Should Really Start Stretching More” System&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Woman stretching fingers toward toes.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510518b615ed57e2ca887/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/2_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510518b615ed57e2ca887/master/w_120,c_limit/2_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510518b615ed57e2ca887/master/w_240,c_limit/2_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510518b615ed57e2ca887/master/w_320,c_limit/2_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510518b615ed57e2ca887/master/w_640,c_limit/2_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510518b615ed57e2ca887/master/w_960,c_limit/2_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510518b615ed57e2ca887/master/w_1280,c_limit/2_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510518b615ed57e2ca887/master/w_1600,c_limit/2_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;The Endocrine System:&lt;/strong>; The “I&#39;m Going to Blame My Hormones for My Bad Mood Because I Don&#39;t Want to Address What My Bad Mood Is Actually About” System&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Woman stretching fingers toward toes.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510518b615ed57e2ca887/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/2_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510518b615ed57e2ca887/master/w_120,c_limit/2_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510518b615ed57e2ca887/master/w_240,c_limit/2_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510518b615ed57e2ca887/master/w_320,c_limit/2_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510518b615ed57e2ca887/master/w_640,c_limit/2_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510518b615ed57e2ca887/master/w_960,c_limit/2_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510518b615ed57e2ca887/master/w_1280,c_limit/2_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510518b615ed57e2ca887/master/w_1600,c_limit/2_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;The Urinary System:&lt;/strong>; The “I&#39;m a Full-Grown Adult, but I Held It for Too Long and Now It&#39;s an Emergency” System&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Woman holding legs together because of a fullbladder.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551051dfa51939a44d99b1/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/4_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551051dfa51939a44d99b1/master/w_120,c_limit/4_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551051dfa51939a44d99b1/master/w_240,c_limit/4_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551051dfa51939a44d99b1/master/w_320,c_limit/4_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551051dfa51939a44d99b1/master/w_640,c_limit/4_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551051dfa51939a44d99b1/master/w_960,c_limit/4_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551051dfa51939a44d99b1/master/w_1280,c_limit/4_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551051dfa51939a44d99b1/master/w_1600,c_limit/4_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;The Cardiovascular System:&lt;/strong>; The “Checking My Pulse When I&#39;m Stressed to See if I&#39;m Having a Heart Attack Even Though I Have No Reason to Believe That I Am” System&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Woman taking her pulse and stress sweating.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551051f61952da865f4bf9/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/5_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551051f61952da865f4bf9/master/w_120,c_limit/5_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551051f61952da865f4bf9/master/w_240,c_limit/5_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551051f61952da865f4bf9/master/w_320,c_limit/5_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551051f61952da865f4bf9/master/w_640,c_limit/5_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551051f61952da865f4bf9/master/w_960,c_limit/5_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551051f61952da865f4bf9/master/w_1280,c_limit/5_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551051f61952da865f4bf9/master/w_1600,c_limit/5_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;The Digestive System:&lt;/strong>; The “Whole Milk Makes My Tummy Hurt, but Cream Cheese on My Bagel Is Fine” System&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Hand holding a bagel with cream cheese and a hand holding a glass of milk.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551052349065d413014599/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/6_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551052349065d413014599/master/w_120,c_limit/6_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551052349065d413014599/master/w_240,c_limit/6_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551052349065d413014599/master/w_320,c_limit/6_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551052349065d413014599/master/w_640,c_limit/6_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551052349065d413014599/master/w_960,c_limit/6_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551052349065d413014599/master/w_1280,c_limit/6_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65551052349065d413014599/master/w_1600,c_limit/6_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;The Lymphatic System:&lt;/strong>; The “Claiming I&#39;m Not a Hypochondriac While Still Compulsively Checking to See if I Have a Rare Autoimmune Disease” System&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Woman looking at WebMd on laptop.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510532c35084e0937a030/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/7_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510532c35084e0937a030/master/w_120,c_limit/7_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510532c35084e0937a030/master/w_240,c_limit/7_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510532c35084e0937a030/master/w_320,c_limit/7_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510532c35084e0937a030/master/w_640,c_limit/7_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510532c35084e0937a030/master/w_960,c_limit/7_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510532c35084e0937a030/master/w_1280,c_limit/7_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510532c35084e0937a030/master/w_1600,c_limit/7_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;The Integumentary System:&lt;/strong>; The “Wait, Have I Always Had a Mole Here?” System&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Woman looking at moles on her wrist and thigh.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510531e7e180bae4a83a8/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/8_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510531e7e180bae4a83a8/master/w_120,c_limit/8_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510531e7e180bae4a83a8/master/w_240,c_limit/8_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510531e7e180bae4a83a8/master/w_320,c_limit/8_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510531e7e180bae4a83a8/master/w_640,c_limit/8_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510531e7e180bae4a83a8/master/w_960,c_limit/8_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510531e7e180bae4a83a8/master/w_1280,c_limit/8_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510531e7e180bae4a83a8/master/w_1600,c_limit/8_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;The Respiratory System:&lt;/strong>; The “Pretending I&#39;m Not Completely Winded After Walking Up a Single Flight of Stairs” System&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Woman out of breath while walking up stairs.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510538670f33dfc7831e7/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/9_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510538670f33dfc7831e7/master/w_120,c_limit/9_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510538670f33dfc7831e7/master/w_240,c_limit/9_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510538670f33dfc7831e7/master/w_320,c_limit/9_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510538670f33dfc7831e7/master/w_640,c_limit/9_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510538670f33dfc7831e7/master/w_960,c_limit/9_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510538670f33dfc7831e7/master/w_1280,c_limit/9_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/655510538670f33dfc7831e7/master/w_1600,c_limit/9_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;The Reproductive System:&lt;/strong>; The “I Hope Society Doesn&#39;t Collapse Before I Get My IUD Taken Out” System&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Woman sitting on floor and clutching knees to chest.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6555105393f86d34d222f0d8/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/10_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6555105393f86d34d222f0d8/master/w_120,c_limit/10_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6555105393f86d34d222f0d8/master/w_240,c_limit/10_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6555105393f86d34d222f0d8/master/w_320,c_limit/10_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6555105393f86d34d222f0d8/master/w_640,c_limit/10_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6555105393f86d34d222f0d8/master/w_960,c_limit/10_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6555105393f86d34d222f0d8/master/w_1280,c_limit/10_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6555105393f86d34d222f0d8/master/w_1600,c_limit/10_Gourley_bodilysystems.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;The Nervous System:&lt;/strong>; The Nervous System&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 19:06:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Hostage-Taking and the Use of Children and the Vulnerable in War]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/hostage-taking-and-the-use-of-children-and-the-vulnerable-in-war]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-16T00:30:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6553f79b6086f3c3f4a2d925/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Coll-Hostages-Peter-Van-Agtmael.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;On October 7, 1985, in Alexandria, Egypt, four armed members of a faction of the Palestine Liberation Front boarded the Achille Lauro, an Italian cruise ship that was touring the Mediterranean.劫机者抓住了船长，将乘客赶进餐厅，并宣称，除非以色列在当天下午三点之前释放 50 名巴勒斯坦囚犯，否则他们将开始处决人质。当最后期限过去后，劫机者却将六十九岁的犹太裔美国人利昂·克林霍夫 (Leon Klinghoffer) 解散，他的中风史使他几乎只能坐在轮椅上。他们将克林霍弗转移到外面的甲板上，劫持小组的头目尤瑟夫·马吉德·莫尔奇 (Youssef Majed Molqi) 开枪射中了他的头部和胸部。 Molqi then ordered two of the ship&#39;s crew to throw Klinghoffer&#39;s body and wheelchair into the sea.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Klinghoffer&#39;s murder became an infamous touchstone in the nineteen-eighties era of made-for-TV hijackings, a time when armed liberation movements in the Middle East demonstrated the asymmetric power of spectacular mass hostage-taking. Terrorists of that era wanted “a lot of people watching, not a lot of people dead,” as the &lt;em >;RAND&lt;/em>; Corporation analyst Brian Jenkins put it in 1974, because they sought to call attention to their cause without alienating sympathizers.然而，劫机者还专门针对犹太人和美国人进行了处决，以此作为一种战略沟通形式。 As Molqi later testified at trial, after he was captured, “I chose Klinghoffer, an invalid, so that they would know that we had no pity for anyone, just as the Americans, arming Israel, do not take into consideration that Israel kills women and children of our people.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;That Molqi&#39;s nihilism resonates today in the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/the-plight-of-the-hostages-and-the-rapidly-escalating-crisis-in-gaza&quot;>;hostage crisis&lt;/a>; embedded in Israel&#39;s war with Hamas in Gaza is one depressing indicator among many of repetitive patterns of violence between Israel and stateless Palestinians, in the context of Israel&#39;s occupation of the West Bank and its immiseration of Gaza.然而这场特殊的战争却给人一种历史倒退的感觉。 When Hamas and its allies killed about twelve hundred Israelis on &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/11/06/israel-gaza-war-hamas&quot;>;October 7th&lt;/a>; and retreated to Gaza with more than &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/letter-from-israel/the-long-wait-of-the-hostages-families&quot;>;two hundred and thirty captives&lt;/a>;, the group revived the sort of hostage spectacle common in the Middle East from the late nineteen-sixties through to the eighties—a drama in which the fate of innocents is determined amid a competition of coercive public narratives.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;It isn&#39;t clear how much of a plan for large-scale kidnapping Hamas had put together in advance of its operation, but the group quickly began producing hostage videos and social-media posts to publicize its achievement.乔治敦大学专门研究恐怖主义历史的教授布鲁斯·霍夫曼（Bruce Hoffman）表示，与自杀式爆炸或军事式袭击不同，劫持人质“是一种在人质命运得到解决之前一直出现在新闻中的恐怖袭击”。告诉我。人质对峙持续时间较长，可以让绑匪为释放囚犯或其他让步进行长时间的讨价还价，例如停火，正如哈马斯现在通过卡塔尔的调解和美国的参与所做的那样。 In such circumstances, Hoffman noted, capturing the most vulnerable civilians—“babies, small children, the elderly, the infirm”—can increase the militants&#39; leverage because it raises the sense of urgency around rescuing the victims.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In the current crisis, a sizable number of children and the elderly, ranging in age from less than a year old to eighty-six, are being held in captivity in an active war zone. Hamas and its allies may have seized more than thirty children, according to lists of suspected kidnapping victims published by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/world-middle-east-67053011&quot;>;BBC&lt;/a>; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.haaretz.com/israel-news/2023-10-22/ty-article-magazine/hostages-held-by-hamas-the-names-of-those-abducted-from-israel/0000018b-55f8-d5d2-afef-d5fdd04e0000&quot;>;&lt;em>;Haaretz&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>;.周一，白宫透露，其中一名被扣为人质的儿童是一名三岁的美国公民，他的父母在袭击中被杀，他因此成为孤儿。多达 25 名 65 岁以上的人也可能被抓获，尽管尚不清楚这些人是否都还活着。 Hamas features these most vulnerable hostages in its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/news-desk/the-hamas-propaganda-war&quot;>;propaganda&lt;/a>; videos. 11 月 9 日，哈马斯的盟友伊斯兰圣战组织发布了一张照片，其中描绘了 77 岁的汉娜·卡齐尔和 13 岁的亚吉尔·雅科夫。卡齐尔坐在轮椅上。两人在基布兹尼尔奥兹袭击期间被绑架； according to &lt;em>;Haaretz&lt;/em>;, Katzir&#39;s husband was murdered there.人权观察称哈马斯和伊斯兰圣战组织发布的最新视频和早期视频是“一种不人道待遇，相当于战争罪”。 Omar Shakir, the organization&#39;s Israel and Palestine director, said that “instead of filming a child under duress, the groups should release him safely to his family.”&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;In our social-media-soaked world of interconnected crises, we have grown accustomed to an iconography of children&#39;s suffering in war and humanitarian emergencies—images deployed to make vivid and emotionally insistent what might otherwise be ignored or rationalized.在加沙冲突期间，政治领导人和记者经常强调在以色列对加沙地带的反击中丧生的巴勒斯坦儿童人数非常多——据加沙卫生部称，迄今为止已有四千多名巴勒斯坦儿童丧生。 The Secretary-General of the UN, António Gutterres, emphasized that Gaza was becoming a “graveyard for children” when he recently called for a humanitarian &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/how-would-a-humanitarian-pause-work-in-gaza&quot;>;ceasefire&lt;/a>;. This week, the fate of &lt;a href=&quot;https://edition.cnn.com/2023/11/13/middleeast/gaza-babies-incubators-al-shifa-hospital-israel-intl-hnk/index.html&quot;>;premature babies&lt;/a>; being treated in an incubator in Gaza City&#39;s besieged Al-Shifa hospital has presented a visually arresting image of the consequences of Israel&#39;s bombing and ground campaign, which, according to the ministry, has killed more than eleven thousand people altogether. As &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2023/11/12/world/middleeast/gaza-hospitals-shifa.html&quot;>;Israeli soldiers closed in&lt;/a>; on Al-Shifa, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/13/israeli-forces-at-gates-of-gaza-main-hospital-hundreds-trapped-israel-hamas&quot;>;hundreds of people—including dozens of babies—&lt;/a>;were trapped inside, and, according to local health officials, patients died because doctors were unable to work while the hospital was under attack.然而，以色列声称，周三当其士兵接近希法并进入该设施时，以色列采取了谨慎的行动。 Meanwhile, Tzipi Hotovely, the right-wing former settlements minister now serving as Israel&#39;s Ambassador to the United Kingdom, had &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://news.sky.com/video/gaza-shifa-hospital-is-hamas-hq-says-israeli-ambassador-13008006&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://news.sky.com/video/gaza-shifa-hospital-is-hamas-hq-says-israeli-ambassador-13008006&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://news.sky.com/video/gaza-shifa-hospital-is-hamas-hq-says-israeli-ambassador-13008006&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;told Sky News&lt;/a>; on Tuesday, “This is not an innocent hospital. This is actually a military base, using the patients as human shields.”&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;The prominent place of elderly hostages in the crisis has a less familiar moral texture than the centrality of children.人质中可能有多达七名八十多岁的老人，其中包括八十五岁的亚法·阿达尔(Yaffa Adar)。阿达尔在尼尔奥兹的基布兹独自居住，需要一名护理人员帮助日常洗澡和服药，在被抓获后，她被武装人员用高尔夫球车带走。她的表情虽然含糊但冷静，与恐怖主义档案中的任何图像一样引人注目。 “他们不会看到她受到羞辱、害怕或受伤，”当我问她看这些照片时看到了什么时，雅法的孙女阿德瓦·阿达尔告诉我。 “她会让他们看到她是一个人。”阿达尔补充道，“很难理解你怎么能进入一个八十五岁老妇人的家，她不能伤害你，甚至不能保护自己，而且你不是离开，而是选择劫持她作为人质。 I don&#39;t get how a human being can be so detached from basic compassion.”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;3gwen6&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;kfp228&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;The stories of the lives of the older hostages—some of whom are longtime kibbutzniks and social reformers—connect the present catastrophe to Israel&#39;s traumatic birth and oft-disrupted rise.迪扎·海曼 (Ditza Haiman) 是一名 84 岁的退休社会工作者，据信在尼尔奥兹 (Nir Oz) 被绑架。 75 岁的亚历山大·丹西格 (Alexander Dancyg) 是波兰大屠杀幸存者的儿子，他移民到以色列，在耶路撒冷大屠杀纪念馆和教育中心工作了几十年，在那里他促进了以色列与波兰之间的对话。 Shoshan Haran, a sixty-seven-year-old plant biologist who was reportedly abducted from the kibbutz at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/news/dispatch/the-devastation-of-beeri&quot;>;Be&#39;eri&lt;/a>;, is the founder of Fair Planet, a group that distributes seeds in the Global South.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;In Gaza, of course, similar Palestinian lives have been shattered since October 7th.肾病专家哈曼·阿洛 (Hammam Alloh) 在以色列空袭中身亡，他拒绝从加沙北部撤离以继续治疗患者。 Izzeldin Abuelaish, a sixty-eight-year-old doctor who was born in Gaza&#39;s Jabalia refugee camp, &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.independent.ie/irish-news/gaza-strip-is-lifeless-and-childless-says-doctor-who-lost-25-family-members-in-one-day/a69935841.html&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.independent.ie/irish-news/gaza-strip-is-lifeless-and-childless-says-doctor-who-lost-25-family-members-in-one-day/a69935841.html&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.independent.ie/irish-news/gaza-strip-is-lifeless-and-childless-says-doctor-who-lost-25-family-members-in-one-day/a69935841.html&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;told the &lt;em>;Irish Independent&lt;/em>;&lt;/a>; that an Israeli strike killed twenty-five of his family members. Wael Dahdouh, a fifty-three-year-old Al Jazeera journalist, has covered the war even after Israeli strikes killed his wife, their son, their daughter, and a grandson.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In Qatar, diplomats and spy chiefs are engaged in what President Joe Biden&#39;s national-security adviser, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/10/16/trial-by-combat&quot;>;Jake Sullivan&lt;/a>;, speaking to “Face the Nation” on Sunday, called “active negotiations” to release the hostages. Abu Ubaida, a spokesman for the Izz al-Din al-Qassam Brigades, the military wing of Hamas, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/hamas-armed-wing-discussed-releasing-70-hostages-return-5-day-truce-2023-11-13/&quot;>;said on Monday&lt;/a>; that Qatar has been trying to broker a deal to release up to seventy hostages held in Gaza in exchange for two hundred Palestinian children and seventy-five women imprisoned by Israel, as well a five-day truce. In remarks on Saturday, the Israeli Prime Minister, Benjamin Netanyahu, reiterated past statements that there would be “no ceasefire without the return of our hostages.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Some sort of deal would seem probable, given the interests of the parties, but whatever the outcome, Hamas has proved again that, tragically, mass kidnapping works, at least in the short term.它为激进组织提供了参与国际外交的机会，从而解放了他们的同志并建立了政治信誉。 And it allows small or marginal outfits like Islamic Jihad to grab sustained attention and spread their own myths through global media.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The occasion of Leon Klinghoffer&#39;s murder inspired an opera, “&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2014/11/03/long-wake&quot;>;The Death of Klinghoffer&lt;/a>;,” by the composer John Adams and the librettist Alice Goodman.它于 1991 年首次亮相，并引起了持久的争议，部分原因是它的创作者通过提供巴勒斯坦人被剥夺的背景故事以及让劫机者唱出自己的观点，将阿奇·劳罗号劫持人质事件置于背景之中。也许从一开始就被认为是操纵公共景观的谋杀案中创作出雄心勃勃的艺术本质上是不可行的。但是，在克林霍夫的身体和轮椅落入海中的震惊中，以及在哈马斯继续发布的视频中俘虏的面孔中，大多数人将超越政治历史的缩影，看到不必要的人类痛苦，以及这些痛苦的背后，犯罪。 ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;bvwste&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 09:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[We’ve Been Wrong to Worry About Deepfakes (So Far)]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/podcast/political-scene/weve-been-wrong-to-worry-about-deepfakes-so-far]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-15T21:30:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/637541f2b19ab8521b9fe1c2/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/The%20Political%20Scene%20In%20Conversation.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;figure data-testid=&quot;IframeEmbed&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;IframeEmbedContainer&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;iframe height=&quot;120&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-scripts&quot; title=&quot;Embedded Frame&quot; src=&quot;https://player.simplecast.com/1e016431-e8fa-4a95-af56-010a3f1c4f25?dark=false&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay *; encrypted-media *; clipboard-write; autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&quot;>;&lt;/iframe>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;Listen and subscribe:&lt;/em>; &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.apple?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.apple?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.apple?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Apple&lt;/a>; | &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.spotify?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.spotify?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.spotify?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Spotify&lt;/a>; | &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.google?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.google?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.google?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Google&lt;/a>; | &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Wherever You Listen&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/newsletter/news-politics&quot;>;Sign up&lt;/a>; to receive our twice-weekly News &amp;amp; Politics newsletter.&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;p >;Deepfakes, videos generated or manipulated by artificial intelligence, allow people to create content at a level of sophistication once only available to major Hollywood studios.自从七年前第一批深度造假出现以来，专家们一直担心被篡改的视频会破坏政治，或者更糟糕的是，使所有视觉证据失去合法性。 In this week&#39;s issue of &lt;em>;The New Yorker&lt;/em>;, Daniel Immerwahr, a professor of history at Northwestern University, explores why little of this has come to pass.尽管深度假货很现实，但人们似乎对自己被欺骗时有良好的本能。 But Immerwahr makes the case that our collective imperviousness to deepfakes also points to a deeper problem: that our politics rely on emotion rather than evidence, and that we don&#39;t need to be convinced of what we already believe.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;You can read &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/11/20/a-history-of-fake-things-on-the-internet-walter-j-scheirer-book-review&quot;>;Daniel Immerwahr&#39;s essay&lt;/a>; in &lt;em>;The New Yorker&#39;s&lt;/em>; first-ever &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/11/20&quot;>;special issue about artificial intelligence&lt;/a>;—out now.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;0iugwl&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;0f4aeh&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 06:06:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>