<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>纽约客</title><description>纽约客全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> https://www.newyoker.com <item><title><![CDATA[The Worrying Democratic Erosions in South Korea]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/the-worrying-democratic-erosions-in-south-korea]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-30T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6511b1fe8f784d053bb60e6c/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/Kim-SK-Relations-Press.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt; div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12. 5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4 H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt; svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/标题>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径 d =&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;美国人可能不太了解韩国总统尹锡烈，但有些人会注意到他并不是一个糟糕的歌手。 4月，当乔·拜登和吉尔·拜登在华盛顿特区招待尹正和他的妻子金建熙参加国宴时，尹正以东亚风格表演了一首怀旧歌谣来讨好自己。在一轮音乐表演中，应拜登的邀请，他将麦克风放在唇边，并&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.c-span.org/video/?527721-1/south-korean-president- yoon-sings-american-pie&quot;>;推出了&lt;/a>;他最喜欢的歌曲之一，Don McLean 的《American Pie》的无伴奏版本：“很久很久以前，我仍然记得/如何那些音乐曾经让我微笑。”拜登微笑着挥舞着拳头。尹看起来是一个快乐的政治家和美国的最终盟友。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩国被广泛视为美国制造的民主国家，与日本一起支持美国在东亚乃至世界各地对抗中国的努力。八月，当拜登在戴维营会见尹恩惠和日本首相岸田文雄时，这种三边团结得到了公开展示。但是，自去年上任以来，在以不到百分之一的优势当选后，尹这位没有政治经验的职业检察官开始剥夺对女性的保护、结社和组织的权利，以及最引人注目的是新闻自由。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;问题大约在一年前开始，也就是尹上任几个月后，当时他被发现在纽约的比赛场边对着一个热麦克风骂脏话。联合国大会。 “如果国会里的那些混蛋不通过这项法案，拜登就会被羞辱，”他用韩语说，显然指的是资助全球健康计划的立法。 （尹的批评者已经给他起了个绰号“一天失态”。）韩国电视广播公司 MBC 最先报道了这一事件。尹的发言人进入否认模式，表示总统使用了一个与“拜登”押韵的词（&lt;em>;nallimyeon&lt;/em>;，意思是驱逐），并且该评论是针对韩国立法机构，而不是韩国政府。美国国会。尹的盟友对 MBC 及其附属记者提起刑事诽谤诉讼。 （MBC 称这是一次“报复性调查”。）两个月后，尹禁止 MBC 加入其参加东南亚国家联盟和 20 国集团会议的航班上的媒体库。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;尹此后，他加强了对媒体的攻击。今年 5 月，警方突击搜查了报道这一热门言论的 MBC 记者林贤珠 (Im Hyeon-ju) 的家。 （这次她被指控的罪行是将有关韩国法务部长的个人信息转发给另一名记者。）本月早些时候，检察官从调查媒体 Newstapa 和电视网络 JTBC 的办公室以及从几名记者。所称理由再次是对尹某的刑事诽谤。 2022 年初，Newstapa 报道了一段录音采访，其中有消息来源称，时任高级检察官的尹掩盖了一项银行和房地产计划。尹称这段采访为假新闻，声称该录音带可能被篡改，并指责 Newstapa 和 JTBC 在总统选举前夕传播该采访，以破坏他的竞选活动。韩国记者协会和其他媒体团体将最近的突击搜查比作“军事行动”，并谴责执政党无视“法治”。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;尹政府并不总是以这样的敌意对待媒体。韩国的报纸和电视频道具有明显的政治色彩，尹恩惠对与其保守的人民力量党结盟的媒体表现出偏爱。有一次，他的政府监督了对广播监管者韩相赫(Han Sang-hyuk)的起诉和解雇，韩相赫曾审查朝鲜电视台(TV Chosun)的许可证，该网络的报道倾向于右翼宣传。 （韩否认了这些指控。）接替韩的人现在承诺清除韩国互联网上所有他认为“假新闻”的内容。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true &quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Yoon 还从事一些小型的声誉管理活动。去年，韩国文化部谴责当地一项漫画比赛，该比赛将尹画成一辆由他的妻子、女商人和社交名流驾驶的火车，并为一名青少年颁奖。 （在总统竞选期间，她发誓要把任何说她丈夫坏话的记者关进监狱；她的母亲目前因在房地产交易中伪造财务文件而入狱。）政府庆祝了最近开设的“儿童花园”——位于首尔市中心的国防部大院，尹将总统办公室迁至此处——通过分发描绘尹和他的妻子受到包括小狗在内的不同群体的奉承的彩色纸。&lt;/p>;&lt;对许多人来说，尹的自我陶醉和急于针对媒体的态度让人想起该国上世纪中叶的军事独裁统治，这种独裁统治一直持续到十九世纪八十年代。地方和国家检察官追捕记者、出版商、学生活动人士、劳工组织者和普通民众，作为庞大的反共拉网的一部分。其中许多检察官为警方的逮捕和酷刑提供了便利，其范围仍在分类中。为尹氏政府工作的检察官利用调查权恐吓和威胁逮捕自由派反对党的政客，其中包括去年与尹氏竞选的李在明。李在选举后不久就因贿赂和腐败而受到调查；他否认所有指控，并进行了二十四天的绝食，称新政府是“检察官独裁”。最近，韩国立法机构投票推翻了李明博的主权豁免权，允许逮捕他。 （法院后来驳回了逮捕令。）尹的检察官还追查了进步工会的领导人。今年年初，警方突击搜查了数十个工会办公室和私人住宅，指控劳工官员违反了韩国的国家安全法，并强迫建筑公司使用工会工人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尹就任总统后，许多韩国人参加过十九世纪七八十年代“人民”民主运动的人无法相信这个国家愿意选举一名检察官。在其职业生涯早期，尹曾处理过南部城市大邱的重要腐败案件；后来，他在享有盛誉的首尔检察官办公室晋升，并于 2019 年被自由派总统文在寅任命为国家检察长。尹很快开始追查有利于人民力量党的案件。他将自己定位为文在寅的主要对手，并抓住了 2022 年总统竞选的机会。 （韩国总统的任期仅限五年。）在竞选期间，尹恩惠利用了对女性的强烈反对，将韩国对住房成本上升和向上流动性下降的不满归咎于女权主义。他承诺取消性别平等和家庭部（这一举措现已悬而未决），并废除文在寅制定的性别配额，该配额要求总统内阁中女性占百分之三十。除了尹氏对工会的攻击之外，他的劳动部还将很快关闭数十个移民支持中心，移民是韩国劳动力中日益增长和必要的一部分，而韩国的出生率是世界上最低的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >; 在公开场合，拜登并没有流露出对尹恩惠专制倾向的任何担忧。昆西研究所的杰克·维尔纳告诉我：“尹当选时，许多外交政策机构都感到高兴。”与中国孤注一掷的竞争战略意味着要容忍该地区其他非自由政府的发展。沃纳说，白宫没有处理这样一个事实：“是威权主义者欢迎我们在外交政策上采取的方向。”印度的纳伦德拉·莫迪尽管煽动印度教民族主义暴力、取消克什米尔的自治地位并审查媒体，但仍受到华盛顿的款待。在拜登最近访问期间，越南总统武文上没有受到针对压制新闻界和民间社会的批评；几天后，河内警方逮捕了一名环保人士。尹正也在将韩国推向镇压的方向，回到独裁统治的糟糕旧时光，而他的美国伙伴却没有提出抗议。 ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;vf3f7i&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; >;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;2ml6ub&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt; div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ side>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live= “礼貌” aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/article>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 19:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[The Quiet Revolution of the Sabbath]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-weekend-essay/the-quiet-revolution-of-the-sabbath]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-30T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/64cc1500f2c9e3423ae74484/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/Cep_Sabbath.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt; div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2. 95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/s vg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存这个故事&lt;/ span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span>;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d= “M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d =“M23 3” H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt; /span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;这是一个我不确定姐姐是否会让我讲述的故事。我来自一个经常去教堂的家庭，但有一天我姐姐没有去教堂做礼拜，尽管我们其他人都去了。她没有生病。事实上，她与“生病”相反：最近被确认，她只是决定行使一项她认为通过确认而拥有的权利，即无缘无故地呆在家里，除了她想这样做。我肯定觉得这令人震惊——不仅是她的决定，还有我们父母遵守的意愿——尽管我无法真正回忆起崇拜前的感受，因为崇拜后发生的事情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当时，我们乡村小教堂的圣所与团契大厅仅由一个门口隔开。门左高右低，凹凸不平，自从有人告诉我一个关于木匠基督帮助他的父亲约瑟夫纠正弯曲门框的杜撰故事以来，我一直很喜欢这一事实。我每周在礼拜时都会看那扇门。很长一段时间，它就在讲坛后面，所以我在整个讲道过程中都会看着它，期待着类似的奇迹，等待右角升起与左角相遇，或者左角落下与右角相遇。每当我走过的时候，我都会用手指在它倾斜的框架上上下拖动。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我最早的一些记忆就是关于那扇门的：七岁的一个圣诞夜，我带着一头我大小的毛绒毛驴跌跌撞撞地穿过门；最后，我长到了足够高的程度，可以触摸到它弯曲的角了。当我跨过门槛走向祭坛前敞开的教母棺材时，我哭了。作为侍僧，他躲过教堂，在会众充满希望的静默中点燃蜡烛。当我进入另一个庇护所时，我很少会首先想到那扇门。我们这座有一百多年历史的教堂最近翻修的一个奇妙之处在于，他们选择不把门关上，所以即使今天在礼拜时，我发现自己盯着它，尽管现在讲坛已经在它的上面了。左边。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当你穿过那扇弯曲的门口进入联谊会大厅时，你会发现一个圣器收藏室、浴室、厨房、主日学校房间和一间小办公室。当我小的时候，办公室里总是有两张折叠椅，供出纳员清点产品，还有一个小脚凳，供像我这样的孩子使用，他们喜欢坐着，而他们的父母整理支票，堆放现金，并在加法机上添加所有数字;如果我们幸运的话，有零散的硬币可以分类装进信封，或者，如果我们真的很幸运，足够装一卷纸。教堂里有我用过的第一台复印机，还有一把看起来像砍刀的切纸机。这三件技术——复印机、计算器和切割机——就放在办公室里的电话旁边，我父亲在姐姐呆在家里的那天就用电话给她打电话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我父亲只是个孩子。牧师查看了我姐姐的情况，但是，在听到他的谈话后，牧师向他要了电话。我就在他们旁边，我只能想象当她突然发现自己不是在与我们的父亲交谈，而是在与我们的牧师交谈时，她的感受如何。他只有一个问题要问她：“你还记得第三条诫命吗？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果你不是天主教徒或路德宗，那么所讨论的诫命实际上是第四条。刻有十诫的石板没有编号，因此顺序存在一些争议。无论如何，我们的牧师正在谈论安息日的问题以及如何遵守它。这也是美国电影制片人马丁·多布尔梅尔 (Martin Doblmeier) 拍摄的一部纪录片的主题，该纪录片在过去几个月一直在公共电视台和在线流媒体上播出。多布尔迈尔制作了十几部有关宗教的纪录片，包括专门针对莱因霍尔德·尼布尔、亚伯拉罕·约书亚·赫歇尔和霍华德·瑟曼等神学家的传记电影；关于基督复临安息日会的三部曲；以及诸如“宽恕的力量”和“牧师”之类的跨信仰探索。这些主题电影调查了跨传统的当代灵性，探讨了阿米什人、佛教、犹太教和穆斯林信仰中的宽恕，或采访了在监狱、肉类加工厂和战区工作的各种牧师。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在《安息日》中，多布尔迈尔在全国各地迅速走动，咨询了深思熟虑的社会学家和神学家，捕捉了夏令营和社区花园的美丽和乐趣，在&lt;em>;LIFE&lt;/em>; Adventist等地方与神职人员和教区居民交谈伯克利教堂；曼哈顿的斯蒂芬·怀斯自由犹太教堂；密西西比州南杰克逊基督复临安息日会教堂；纽约大学伊斯兰中心；和洛杉矶的La Iglesia de Nuestra Señora la Reina。观众可以比较圣礼、洗礼、聚礼祈祷、会众聚餐和安息日餐，同时观看大学生第一次远离家人制定自己的安息日纪律，以及拥有数十年经验的牧师改变他们对安息日的看法。 &lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;这部纪录片有时感觉像是一场旋风之旅，但众所周知，旋风可以产生智慧。 《安息日》首先观察现代生活的匆忙疲惫和无处不在的压力——我们的数字成瘾、我们的倦怠文化、我们的抑郁——然后唤起电影核心思想的圣经根源，将安息日呈现为治疗我们文化困境的一种可能的补救措施。在《创世记》中，上帝创造了世界之后就休息了；在《出埃及记》中，上帝命令以色列人休息：“六日你们要劳苦作你一切的工，但第七日是向耶和华你们上帝当守的安息日。你不能在上面做任何工作。”影片中出现的改革拉比阿米尔·赫希 (Ammiel Hirsch) 认为，第四诫是“一个革命性的概念”，“改变了人类历史”，因为它被认为是第一次宗教或政治权威，而不是要求工作，需要休息。&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;罗马人蔑视这种做法，诽谤犹太人懒惰，但即使在犹太教内部，古代世界对休息诫命的解释也各不相同，人们不仅在什么构成适当的崇拜方面存在分歧，而且在什么构成不适当的工作方面也存在分歧。福音书中最有争议的一些争论是耶稣和宗教领袖之间关于他在安息日所做的事情，不仅治愈和创造奇迹，而且有一天只是和他饥饿的门徒一起拾取谷物。在那一天，基督以大卫王为榜样，吃了祝圣饼，告诉法利赛人：“安息日是为人设立的，人不是为安息日设立的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些都不是微不足道的分歧，他们一直坚持到现在，甚至在一些基本问题上，包括上帝打算让人类在哪一天停止劳动。在犹太教中，安息日从周五日落开始，到周六日落结束；穆斯林庆祝聚木节，周五聚集在一起进行集体祈祷。我们从《使徒行传》中得知，耶稣的早期追随者开始在星期日聚集，公元 321 年，君士坦丁将星期日正式定为罗马帝国的休息日：“在太阳的神圣日子里，让长官和居住在城市的人们休息一下，关闭所有车间。”今天的基督徒仍然主要在星期日敬拜，尽管基督复临安息日会和基督复临安息日会在星期六遵守安息日。&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;即使在同一信仰中，遵守也有多种形式，那些遵守安息日的人进行不同程度的身体和精神休息、私人聚餐或公共敬拜、个人形成或集体服务、默祷或积极学习。但这部电影提供的一个受欢迎的纠正是坚持认为，对于信徒来说，在这个神圣的日子里发生的任何事情都对一周中的所有其他日子都很重要。 “安息日不仅仅是一种虔诚的教导，”杜克大学教授诺曼·维尔兹巴（Norman Wirzba）解释道。 “问题在于生命的意义。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种对安息日深刻重要性的认识是清教徒来到美国的部分原因。他们严格的安息日信仰使他们与英国当局发生冲突，特别是在詹姆斯国王于 1617 年出版《体育之书》之后，他在书中鼓励他的臣民参加周日早上的礼拜，下午跳舞、游戏和娱乐。对于清教徒来说，这种侵犯显然破坏了第四条诫命，当他们可以的时候，他们通过了安息日法律来保护主日——在弗吉尼亚，早在1610年，就颁布了法令“任何男人或女人都不得敢于违反或破坏此类禁令被称为“蓝色法律”，尽管现在没有人记得为什么；也许是因为它们印刷或装订的纸张颜色，或者是因为殖民时代颜色的贬义，如蓝袜或后来的变体，如蓝鼻子——那些正经或正派的人。类似的法律不断涌现，并在接下来的三个世纪中持续存在，规范了全美各地在主日的商业、劳动和娱乐活动。偶尔的例外，即保留某些行业或排除某些活动，在各地的州立法机构中得到了通过，但只有在冷战期间，当学校祈祷和公民展示宗教肖像受到联邦法院的质疑时，蓝色法律才成为也是一个严重的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个又一个的案例认为，周日休市的法律违反了第一修正案的平等保护条款和确立条款。 1961 年，最高法院在麦高恩诉马里兰州一案中裁定，如果蓝色法律服务于世俗目的，则该法律并不违宪，并且选择星期日作为公共休息日是合理的做法，可以说，此事就此了结。一个实际的选择，而不是基督教的优待。首席大法官厄尔·沃伦写道：“所有宗教信仰的人和无宗教信仰的人都将周日视为家庭活动、拜访朋友和亲戚、晚睡、被动和主动娱乐、外出就餐等的时间。”在其他几个代表就该问题做出的决定中。 “周日是与其他日子不同的一天。原因无关紧要；事实是存在的。要求一个国家选择一个共同的休息日，而不是大多数人自愿选择的休息日，这对于执法目的似乎是不现实的，而且可能不利于公共福利。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使有该法律由于保护得到保障，安息日法律在随后的几十年里在全国各地被修改和废除。在一些州，企业主成功地辩称，这些法律在同一行业中的应用反复无常（例如，仅适用于一定规模的商店），或者对某些行业不公平（例如，汽车销售，但不是露营车销售）；在其他州，监管机构承认他们不堪重负，无法执行法律；几乎在所有地方，经济压力都普遍存在，安息日法的批评者认为收入正在流失，税金正在被放弃。尽管如此，蓝色法律并没有消失。一些州仍然限制周日打猎、赛马或出售酒类，《安息日》的一个片段专门介绍了该国最后一个仍然更广泛地限制购物的县。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该县不是不是宾夕法尼亚州的兰卡斯特，也不是犹他州的盐湖城。它是新泽西州的卑尔根县，是美国最富有的州之一最富有的县之一，也是帕拉默斯的所在地，该县的零售额比美国任何其他邮政编码都多。每年有数以千万计的人在该市的四个大型购物中心购物，每年带来约 60 亿美元的收入。新泽西州自 1693 年起就在全州范围内制定了蓝色法律，卑尔根县在 1959 年特别选择了这些法律，当时小企业与神职人员和其他相关居民联合起来，支持该县的当地禁令；就在 1993 年，居民投票决定保留蓝色法，继续禁止周日销售各种物品，包括电器、建筑材料、汽车、服装、电子产品和家具。对于 Costco 等一些零售商来说，这意味着欢迎顾客，但只允许他们购买某些商品，从而封锁整个过道；对于许多其他人来说，这意味着完全关门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;接受《安息日》采访的卑尔根县蓝法倡导者提出了各种非财务理由，要求他们的商店在周日关门，从人流量减少等单调的原因到崇高的理由例如加强社区和促进健康。马丁·多布尔梅尔 (Martin Doblmeier) 对基督复临安息日会信徒进行的采访中也提到健康和长寿，他们每周六守安息日，并将精神健康与身体健康联系起来。他们大多是素食主义者，定期锻炼身体，戒酒和吸毒，并在周六共享公共餐点并专注于经文和服务；研究表明，它们可以降低患糖尿病、癌症和高血压的风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;蓝色法律的批评者长期以来，他们一直认为，它们只有益于那些在周日参加宗教仪式的个人，而不是整个社区或更广泛的创造物。但世俗工会争取周日停业，以此作为保证疲惫工人休息的一种方式，无论他们是否在当天或任何其他日子参加宗教仪式，部分理由是必须选择一天或一组日期，而不是因为一种促进宗教的手段，但也是为了保证工作之余的休息。这些活动家并不认为自己是某一特定宗教的倡导者或任何其他宗教的敌人，而只是工人免受经济剥削的保护者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对排他主义的担忧虽然在一个重视多元化的社会中是合理的，但已经使人们害怕拥护共同的休息日，尽管最初在摩西律法中，安息日是所有人共享的，无论他们的宗教信仰如何。这一天不仅是为犹太人民设立的，也是为犹太人民设立的。申命记中写道：“六日你要劳苦作你一切的工；但第七日是向耶和华你神守的安息日。你、你的儿子、你的女儿、你的仆人、你的婢女、你的牛、你的驴、你的任何牲畜、你城里的寄居者，都不可在其中做任何工作，让你的男仆和女仆也能像你一样休息。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这连串的内容包括通常的嫌疑人——你和你的孩子——但也包括更多的人：你的仆人、你的牛和你的驴，甚至陌生人在你们中间。每个人都应该有一个安息日，不仅仅是那些崇拜你的方式的人；安息日不仅是为了你和你的人，也是为了所有人。 “我在圣经中找不到任何一个例子，上帝将安息日赐给个人，”普林斯顿神学院教授内森·斯塔基在纪录片中说。 “这始终是为了社区。这是为了整个创造。这是为了神的子民的聚集。完整的安息日是社区的一项活动。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们从自己的经验中了解这种必要性：唯一有效的休战是集体休战。因此，如果家里或办公室里的每个人都拔掉插头，拔掉电源的效果最好，而当我们社会尽可能多的人被允许观察假期时，当市场、银行和邮局关闭以及所有其他地方关闭时，假期才是最像假期的。繁忙的商业世界尽力接受大多数商业可以等待的事实。多元化的承诺为经济压力提供了掩护，我们不再争论不同的休息日，而是更多地接受不能休息、不能放弃收入或失去业务；反对安息日往往披着世俗主义的外衣，但其动机却是贪婪。&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;9kgekhr&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true &quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div 数据-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;mkyksg&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div 数据-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;当我们考虑安息日的根本起源时，这种反对就更容易理解了。多布尔迈尔的纪录片最引人入胜的是，它恢复了强制休息的理念是如何融入托拉中更大的正义理念的。他参观了马萨诸塞州北安普顿的丰盛农场，在那里，以色列圣会 (B&#39;nai Israel) 在一座前救济院的旧址上征用了一英亩的城市土地，并采用受哈拉奇法 (Halachic law) 启发的方法对其进行了改造；后来，会众在附近又增加了半英亩土地。免费的社区收获计划反映了 &lt;em>;Pe&#39;ah&lt;/em>; 的昂贵定义，允许邻居和有需要的人在收获期间收获辣椒、西红柿、浆果、罗勒、大蒜、香草、土豆和许多其他作物季节，拉比大卫塞登伯格解释了农场如何遵守&lt;em>;shmita&lt;/em>;，即所谓的安息日中的安息日，这适用于土地本身。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;em>;shmita&lt;/em>; em>;命令地球每七年休息一次，并且同样应免除债务。学者们对古代以色列实行这种禧年的程度存在分歧，但在《利未记》和《申命记》中，命令是免除邻居之间存在的任何债务并分享所需的一切：“张开你的手”，经文谈到这个安息年，他说：“为你们境内的贫穷和有需要的邻舍。”如此宽容和慷慨的计划很难满足企业利益。 neither is a weekly rehearsal that echoes and culminates in that grand Sabbath, whatever day you heed it.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;If we regularly took an entire day off from the work and the worry of our lives, we might think about doing it more often; moreover, we might think about how much more others need time to rest, too. Rabbi Abraham Joshua Heschel once wrote that for Jews, whose sacred architecture isn&#39;t only physical but temporal, “Sabbaths are our great cathedrals.” “Six days a week,” he observed, “we wrestle with the world, wringing profit from the earth; on the Sabbath we especially care for the seed of eternity planted in the soul.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;One need not be religious to find such language arresting, to be stopped by that metaphor and moved by the arc of human history, in all its glory and failures. My wife is a Jewish atheist who has lately taken to baking challah and lighting Shabbat candles on Fridays. I start my Sundays, as best as I am able, with worship, generally at that same church where I first learned the commandments; three generations of my family have worshipped in those home-town pews, and I confess a stubborn preference for being there, where even the headstones in the graveyard are carved with familiar names, and when babies are baptized, I generally know their parents and grandparents and sometimes even great-grandparents. Other times I find my way to some unfamiliar sanctuary, wherever I am for work or whatever has carried me away from home.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;My sister isn&#39;t really a churchgoer these days, and I assumed that she would be embarrassed by the story I wanted to share from our childhood when I told her about Doblmeier&#39;s documentary. She wasn&#39;t at all. Instead, she told me, I was wrong: our pastor&#39;s question had never struck her as admonishing, only loving. She understood that someone who had devoted his life to the Sabbath was asking her to consider it anew, which she has never stopped doing, even if rarely in pews. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;8p89mq&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 19:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Embarrassing Injuries of Middle Age]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/humor/daily-shouts/embarrassing-injuries-of-middle-age]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-30T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a347ef26f0f1de69b32/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/0_Flake_injury.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Woman in bathrobe gesturing toward a dress on fire.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a36e0da3f4b0716068b/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/1_Flake_injury.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a36e0da3f4b0716068b/master/w_120,c_limit/1_Flake_injury.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a36e0da3f4b0716068b/master/w_240,c_limit/1_Flake_injury.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a36e0da3f4b0716068b/master/w_320,c_limit/1_Flake_injury.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a36e0da3f4b0716068b/master/w_640,c_limit/1_Flake_injury.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a36e0da3f4b0716068b/master/w_960,c_limit/1_Flake_injury.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a36e0da3f4b0716068b/master/w_1280,c_limit/1_Flake_injury.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a36e0da3f4b0716068b/master/w_1600,c_limit/1_Flake_injury.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Woman squatting and holding hip.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a38ccac7a934af62216/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/2_Flake_injury.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a38ccac7a934af62216/master/w_120,c_limit/2_Flake_injury.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a38ccac7a934af62216/master/w_240,c_limit/2_Flake_injury.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a38ccac7a934af62216/master/w_320,c_limit/2_Flake_injury.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a38ccac7a934af62216/master/w_640,c_limit/2_Flake_injury.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a38ccac7a934af62216/master/w_960,c_limit/2_Flake_injury.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a38ccac7a934af62216/master/w_1280,c_limit/2_Flake_injury.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a38ccac7a934af62216/master/w_1600,c_limit/2_Flake_injury.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Hungover woman leaning on table.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a389fb4ab14714711f5/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/3_Flake_injury.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a389fb4ab14714711f5/master/w_120,c_limit/3_Flake_injury.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a389fb4ab14714711f5/master/w_240,c_limit/3_Flake_injury.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a389fb4ab14714711f5/master/w_320,c_limit/3_Flake_injury.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a389fb4ab14714711f5/master/w_640,c_limit/3_Flake_injury.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a389fb4ab14714711f5/master/w_960,c_limit/3_Flake_injury.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a389fb4ab14714711f5/master/w_1280,c_limit/3_Flake_injury.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a389fb4ab14714711f5/master/w_1600,c_limit/3_Flake_injury.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Woman squeezing legs together to avoid peeing.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a37d324cac0c81eacb6/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/4_Flake_injury.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a37d324cac0c81eacb6/master/w_120,c_limit/4_Flake_injury.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a37d324cac0c81eacb6/master/w_240,c_limit/4_Flake_injury.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a37d324cac0c81eacb6/master/w_320,c_limit/4_Flake_injury.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a37d324cac0c81eacb6/master/w_640,c_limit/4_Flake_injury.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a37d324cac0c81eacb6/master/w_960,c_limit/4_Flake_injury.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a37d324cac0c81eacb6/master/w_1280,c_limit/4_Flake_injury.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a37d324cac0c81eacb6/master/w_1600,c_limit/4_Flake_injury.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Woman pulling tape off of her neck.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a38d324cac0c81eacb8/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/5_Flake_injury.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a38d324cac0c81eacb8/master/w_120,c_limit/5_Flake_injury.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a38d324cac0c81eacb8/master/w_240,c_limit/5_Flake_injury.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a38d324cac0c81eacb8/master/w_320,c_limit/5_Flake_injury.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a38d324cac0c81eacb8/master/w_640,c_limit/5_Flake_injury.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a38d324cac0c81eacb8/master/w_960,c_limit/5_Flake_injury.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a38d324cac0c81eacb8/master/w_1280,c_limit/5_Flake_injury.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a38d324cac0c81eacb8/master/w_1600,c_limit/5_Flake_injury.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Woman struggling to open a pickle jar.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a3accac7a934af62218/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/6_Flake_injury.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a3accac7a934af62218/master/w_120,c_limit/6_Flake_injury.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a3accac7a934af62218/master/w_240,c_limit/6_Flake_injury.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a3accac7a934af62218/master/w_320,c_limit/6_Flake_injury.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a3accac7a934af62218/master/w_640,c_limit/6_Flake_injury.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a3accac7a934af62218/master/w_960,c_limit/6_Flake_injury.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a3accac7a934af62218/master/w_1280,c_limit/6_Flake_injury.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a3accac7a934af62218/master/w_1600,c_limit/6_Flake_injury.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Man holding phone and pinky throbbing.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a3963c2b80b2ce46695/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/7_Flake_injury.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a3963c2b80b2ce46695/master/w_120,c_limit/7_Flake_injury.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a3963c2b80b2ce46695/master/w_240,c_limit/7_Flake_injury.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a3963c2b80b2ce46695/master/w_320,c_limit/7_Flake_injury.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a3963c2b80b2ce46695/master/w_640,c_limit/7_Flake_injury.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a3963c2b80b2ce46695/master/w_960,c_limit/7_Flake_injury.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a3963c2b80b2ce46695/master/w_1280,c_limit/7_Flake_injury.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174a3963c2b80b2ce46695/master/w_1600,c_limit/7_Flake_injury.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >; &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 19:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“Purlie Victorious” Hustles for Social Justice]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/10/09/purlie-victorious-theatre-review]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-30T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6517013c3d7db55fbbeb4e07/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/231009_r43137.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;The Reverend Purlie Victorious Judson (Leslie Odom, Jr.), the hero of Ossie Davis&#39;s 1961 comedy, “Purlie Victorious: A Non-Confederate Romp Through the Cotton Patch”—revived on Broadway at the Music Box Theatre, directed by Kenny Leon—is, above all else, a hustler. You might know somebody like this: He blusters onto the stage of your life, pouring out plans before he&#39;s properly introduced himself, energized toward some vista that only he can see. He puts an arm over your shoulder and tries to convince you that you&#39;re on your way there together, as partners, but in his mind&#39;s eye, you can tell, he&#39;s up in the pulpit and you&#39;re down in the seats. Half of what he says sounds cockamamie, but something about him—his personal history, perhaps, or a kind of animal endurance in his bearing—persuades you that, somehow, he&#39;ll get what he wants.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In the case of this show, most of what Purlie wants is a fair shake for Black people. He&#39;s an itinerant minister who has come back to the postbellum Georgia plantation where he grew up. He wants to rally the people there—who now work as sharecroppers for Ol&#39; Cap&#39;n Cotchipee (the intensely funny Jay O. Sanders)—to take back their local church, Big Bethel. He cooks up a scheme that will, with one stroke, get them the deed to the church and free his family from their impossible debts to Ol&#39; Cap&#39;n.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Purlie&#39;s a benign enough con man whose con is social justice. He talks sonorously, in a nearly constant preacher&#39;s cadence; he always seems to be skiing downhill, with great skill and heedless abandon, toward some grand, irrefutable point. When he gets really wound up, he adopts a half-sung, high-flown, heavily syncopated tone whose aim is less to emphasize an argument than to stoke a frenzy in a row of invisible congregants. At a peak moment, he rattles off this rhyming confection: “Let us, therefore, stifle the rifle of conflict, shatter the scatter of discord, smuggle the struggle, tickle the pickle, and grapple the apple of peace!”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;It&#39;s clear that the clergy isn&#39;t his first racket, and it might not be his last. “Last time you was a professor of Negro philosophy,” his sister-in-law, Missy (Heather Alicia Simms), says, with a hint of acid in her voice. “You got yourself a license?” As the play unfolds, we watch Purlie oscillate between courage and cowardice, brilliance and haplessness, forthrightness and a penchant for telling tall tales. His plan is to pass off a girl whom he captivated via one of his sermons, Lutiebelle Gussie Mae Jenkins (Kara Young), as his long-lost cousin, Bee, and trick Ol&#39; Cap&#39;n into handing over a five-hundred-dollar inheritance that he owes the family.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Purlie&#39;s brother, Gitlow (the always impressive Billy Eugene Jones), works for Ol&#39; Cap&#39;n and plays his role as the Good Negro, singing and shuffling, to a T. He&#39;s been given the farcical title Deputy-for-the-Colored. Another Black member of Ol&#39; Cap&#39;n&#39;s household is Idella (Vanessa Bell Calloway), who has raised Ol&#39; Cap&#39;n&#39;s son, Charlie (Noah Robbins), as if he were her own. Purlie&#39;s got to corral all these co-racialists—and their divergent loyalties—and lead them all toward reclaiming Big Bethel.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In creating Purlie, Davis took two long-lasting tropes of communal Black life and twinned them in a single body. On the one hand, Purlie is reminiscent of Father Divine, or, later, the Reverend Ike—a flashy, overconfident preacher who makes lofty promises of prosperity and wins wild, irrational allegiance from Black masses grown tired of living like the lowly Jesus. On the other hand, he&#39;s decided on a career as a self-appointed, semi-professional spokesman for the race. He&#39;s T. D. Jakes and Al Sharpton all at once, a study in the uses and abuses of oratory in Black life.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;A creature like Purlie, made up of cultural memory and social satire, is often hard to play. Cliché and niche obscurity, the Scylla and Charybdis of in-group commentary, lie to either side of the role. But Odom guides his performance cannily, playing each of Purlie&#39;s notes with a musician&#39;s tonal perfection. Sometimes he&#39;s an overbearing tuba, sometimes he&#39;s an earnest flute. Odom makes plain at every impasse that, sure, Purlie cares about his image, about collecting disciples—but that he also wakes up each morning with his mind on real freedom for his people.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;“Purlie Victorious” is also an investigation of the allure of text in American life. There&#39;s lots of to-do about documents. Purlie&#39;s preaching draws richly from the American past instead of from the Bible. “I preached the New Baptism of Freedom for all mankind, according to the Declaration,” he tells Missy, describing the sermon that drew Lutiebelle to his flock, “taking as my text the Constitution of the United States of America, Amendments First through Fifteenth, which readeth as follows: &#39;Congress shall make no law—&#39; ”&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Charlie, Ol&#39; Cap&#39;n Cotchipee&#39;s egalitarian, integrationist son, constantly refers to statutes. Integration is “the law of the land,” he says to his father, “and I intend to obey it!” The rightful inheritance that Purlie means to purloin by madcap deception is another promissory note whose power drives the action of the play. This obsession with text alienates Purlie and Charlie, and anybody who&#39;d follow them, from the more sensual, instinctual culture of the formerly slaveholding South. Guys like Ol&#39; Cap&#39;n Cotchipee and, in a different way, Gitlow Judson can&#39;t be bothered with the nuances of the law or the declamations of the Declaration: their rules, long held, are unwritten. You know where you fit in by following patterns deeply rooted in the past. Between Blacks and whites there&#39;s something “no Supreme Court in the world can understand,” Ol&#39; Cap&#39;n says.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;It&#39;s funny, then, that this production&#39;s greatest asset, by far, is its emphasis on physical comedy. Odom finds a lyricism in Purlie&#39;s body that&#39;s not always evident in his rhetoric. Jones pairs Gitlow&#39;s nostalgic singing of Negro work songs with a dancer&#39;s precision, allowing his body to convey an ironic subversion: even the most archetypal Uncle Tom might have wordless designs on a brighter future. The whole company moves in choreographed tandem—one bit, at a particularly melodramatic moment, has them running up and downstage like relay racers, skidding with cartoonish exaggeration.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Then there&#39;s Kara Young, whose turn as Lutiebelle is a pinnacle of her burgeoning career. Young&#39;s performances in recent plays such as C. A. Johnson&#39;s “All the Natalie Portmans,” Lynn Nottage&#39;s “Clyde&#39;s,” and last year&#39;s revival of Martyna Majok&#39;s “Cost of Living” showed off her otherworldly comic chops, which she grounds in what feels like a small, true place of personal pain. Here, though, in Lutiebelle, Young has found a perfect vehicle to transmit all the aspects of her talent.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Lutiebelle is a poor, sweet young woman who feels unequal to the task of impersonating Purlie&#39;s cousin Bee—Bee was a beautiful college girl, and Lutiebelle doesn&#39;t consider herself pretty, or smart—but she&#39;s been waiting for a long time, it seems, for a chance at adventure. She was abandoned by her parents at an early age, and it takes almost nothing for her to fall in love with Purlie and his talk. She worries and pines and pouts and puts on airs and tries to learn—in this way, she&#39;s almost a metaphor for an entire race trying to squirm itself, by hook or by crook, toward higher ground.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Young plays Lutiebelle with a physical and emotional energy reminiscent of Lucille Ball&#39;s or Carol Burnett&#39;s. She acts big and broad, then pulls the string of her imagination right back, showing how small, everyday hurt, the kind we all carry around, can fuel a great fire of productive delusion. Young&#39;s approach to acting is like the sophisticated engine of a sleek sports car—she floors the pedal around perilous curves and somehow stops on a dime. There&#39;s nobody quite like her in the theatre, or anywhere else, these days.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Kenny Leon, with his flair for showmanship and sizzle, is the ideal director to match Young&#39;s indomitable energy. His frenetic pacing and elaborate physical setups create a framework in which her intricate riffs can add up to a meaning that stretches beyond the text. Young&#39;s hilarious, heartening Lutiebelle fulfills a hope shared by lovers of performance and workers for social peace—that freedom might be found not only on a page but written in a body, and on the heart. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;zzoko&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;t9b86&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 19:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[They Studied Dishonesty. Was Their Work a Lie?]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/10/09/they-studied-dishonesty-was-their-work-a-lie]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-30T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65176ddda984d2fda84e8d66/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/231009_r43126web-site_rd.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;The half-bearded behavioral economist Dan Ariely tends to preface discussions of his work—which has inquired into the mechanisms of pain, manipulation, and lies—with a reminder that he comes by both his eccentric facial hair and his academic interests honestly. He tells a version of the story in the introduction to his breezy first book, “Predictably Irrational,” a patchwork of marketing advice and cerebral self-help. One afternoon in Israel, Ariely—an “18-year-old military trainee,” according to the &lt;em>;Times&lt;/em>;—was nearly incinerated. “An explosion of a large magnesium flare, the kind used to illuminate battlefields at night, left 70 percent of my body covered with third-degree burns,” he writes. He spent three years in the hospital, a period that estranged him from the routine practices of everyday life. The nurses, for example, stripped his bandages all at once, as per the cliché. Ariely suspected that he might prefer a gradual removal, even if the result was a greater sum of agony. In an early psychological experiment he later conducted, he submitted this instinct to empirical review. He subsequently found that certain manipulations of an unpleasant experience might make it seem milder in hindsight. In onstage patter, he referred to a famous study in which researchers gave colonoscopy patients either a painful half-hour procedure or a painful half-hour procedure that concluded with a few additional minutes of lesser misery. The patients preferred the latter, and this provided a reliable punch line for Ariely, who liked to say that the secret was to “leave the probe in.” This was not, strictly speaking, optimal—why should we prefer the scenario with bonus pain? But all around Ariely people seemed trapped by a narrow understanding of human behavior. “If the nurses, with all their experience, misunderstood what constituted reality for the patients they cared so much about, perhaps other people similarly misunderstand the consequences of their behaviors,” he writes. “Predictably Irrational,” which was published in 2008, was an instant airport-book classic, and augured an extraordinarily successful career for Ariely as an enigmatic swami of the but-actually circuit.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Ariely was born in New York City in 1967 and grew up north of Tel Aviv; his father ran an import-export business. He studied psychology at Tel Aviv University, then returned to the United States for doctoral degrees in cognitive psychology at the University of North Carolina and in business administration at Duke. He liked to say that Daniel Kahneman, the Nobel Prize-winning Israeli American psychologist, had pointed him in this direction. In the previous twenty years, Kahneman and his partner, Amos Tversky, had pioneered the field of “judgment and decision-making,” which revealed the rational-actor model of neoclassical economics to be a convenient fiction. (The colonoscopy study that Ariely loved, for example, was Kahneman&#39;s.) Ariely, a wily character with a vivid origin story, presented himself as the natural heir to this new science of human folly. In 1998, with his pick of choice appointments, he accepted a position at MIT Despite having little training in economics, he seemed poised to help renovate the profession. “In Dan&#39;s early days, he was &lt;em>;the&lt;/em>; most celebrated young intellectual academic,” a senior figure in the discipline told me. “I wouldn&#39;t say he was known for being super careful, but he had a reputation as a serious scientist, and was considered the future of the field.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The new discipline might have lent itself to a tragic view of life. Our preferences were arbitrary and incoherent; no narrator was reliable. What differentiated Ariely was his faith that we could be managed. “It is very sad that we are fallible, myopic, vindictive, and emotional,” he told me by e-mail. “But in my view this perspective also means, and this is the optimistic side, that we can do much better.” Take, for example, cheating. If people are utility-maximizing agents, they will fleece as much as they can get away with. Ariely believed, to the contrary, that a potential cheater has to balance two conflicting desires: the urge to max out his gains and the need to see himself as a good person. In experiments, Ariely found that most people cheat when given the opportunity—but just a little. Ariely, who does not shy from cutesiness, called this the “fudge factor.” In turn, he proposed, people might just need to be reminded that they aspire to be decent. In one of his most famous experiments, he asked students to score their own math tests. Half the students had first been asked to list the Ten Commandments. Although most could recall only a few, Ariely found that, in this group, “nobody cheated.” The insight was simple, the intervention subtle, and the consequences enormous.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Ariely came to owe his reputation to his work on dishonesty. He offered commentary in documentaries on Elizabeth Holmes and pontificated about Enron. As Remy Levin, an economics professor at the University of Connecticut, told me, “People often go into this field to study their own inner demons. If you feel bad about time management, you study time inconsistency and procrastination. If you&#39;ve had issues with fear or trauma, you study risk-taking.” Pain was an obvious place for Ariely to start. But his burn scars heightened his sensitivity to truthfulness. Shane Frederick, a professor at Yale&#39;s business school, told me, “One of the first things Dan said to me when we met was &#39;Would you ever date someone who looked like me?&#39; And I said, &#39;No fucking way,&#39; which was a really offensive thing to say to someone—but it weirdly seemed to charm Dan.” From that moment, Frederick felt, Ariely was staunchly supportive of his career. At the same time, Ariely seemed to struggle with procedural norms, especially when they seemed pointless. Once, during a large conference, John Lynch, one of Ariely&#39;s mentors, was rushed to the hospital. Ariely told me that only family members were allowed to visit. He pretended that his scarring was an allergic reaction and, once he was admitted, spent the night by Lynch&#39;s side. In his telling, the nurse was in on the charade. “We were just going through the motions so that she could let me in,” he told me. But a business-school professor saw it differently. “Dan was seen as a hero because he had this creative solution,” she said. “But the hospital staff, even though they knew this wasn&#39;t a real allergic reaction, weren&#39;t allowed to not admit him. He was just wasting their time because he felt like he shouldn&#39;t have to follow their rules.”&lt;/p>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;a data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.newyorker.com/cartoon/a25933&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/cartoon/a25933&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;“Well technically I have an abrasive personality and a tendency to alienate everyone around me but sure lets go with...&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/651765567ef26f0f1de69c0f/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/231009_a25933.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/651765567ef26f0f1de69c0f/master/w_120,c_limit/231009_a25933.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/651765567ef26f0f1de69c0f/master/w_240,c_limit/231009_a25933.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/651765567ef26f0f1de69c0f/master/w_320,c_limit/231009_a25933.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/651765567ef26f0f1de69c0f/master/w_640,c_limit/231009_a25933.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/651765567ef26f0f1de69c0f/master/w_960,c_limit/231009_a25933.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/651765567ef26f0f1de69c0f/master/w_1280,c_limit/231009_a25933.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/651765567ef26f0f1de69c0f/master/w_1600,c_limit/231009_a25933.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/a>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Well, technically, I have an abrasive personality and a tendency to alienate everyone around me, but, sure, let&#39;s go with &#39;lone wolf.&#39; ”&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Cartoon by Jake Thompson&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;button aria-label=&quot;Copy link to cartoon&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Button&amp;quot;}&quot; data-testid=&quot;Button&quot; type=&quot;button&quot;>;&lt;span >;Copy link to cartoon&lt;/span>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Copy link to cartoon&lt;/title>;&lt;g clip-path=&quot;url(#clip0_3732_178637)&quot;>;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; clip-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M16.3488 10.5017C16.2107 10.7357 16.2926 11.035 16.5318 11.17C16.7709 11.3052 17.0767 11.225 17.2148 10.991L18.4648 8.87225C19.5694 7.00002 18.9139 4.60601 17.0007 3.52508C15.0875 2.44415 12.6412 3.08562 11.5366 4.95785L9.53657 8.34782C8.432 10.22 9.08751 12.6141 11.0007 13.6949C11.1888 13.8012 11.382 13.8908 11.5785 13.9642C11.7819 14.0403 12.0058 13.9485 12.1147 13.764C12.2794 13.4849 12.1103 13.1276 11.8083 12.9992C11.7041 12.9549 11.6014 12.9044 11.5007 12.8475C10.0658 12.0368 9.57417 10.2413 10.4026 8.83712L12.4026 5.44715C13.2311 4.04298 15.0658 3.56187 16.5007 4.37257C17.9356 5.18327 18.4272 6.97878 17.5988 8.38295L16.3488 10.5017ZM7.6526 13.4983C7.79067 13.2643 7.70873 12.965 7.46959 12.8299C7.23044 12.6948 6.92464 12.775 6.78657 13.009L5.53657 15.1278C4.432 17 5.0875 19.394 7.00068 20.475C8.91385 21.5558 11.3602 20.9144 12.4648 19.0422L14.4648 15.6521C15.5694 13.78 14.9139 11.3859 13.0007 10.305C12.8127 10.1988 12.6195 10.1091 12.4229 10.0357C12.2195 9.95975 11.9956 10.0515 11.8867 10.236C11.7221 10.5151 11.8911 10.8724 12.1932 11.0008C12.2973 11.0451 12.4 11.0956 12.5007 11.1525C13.9356 11.9632 14.4272 13.7587 13.5988 15.1628L11.5988 18.5529C10.7704 19.957 8.93555 20.4382 7.50068 19.6274C6.0658 18.8167 5.57417 17.0212 6.4026 15.6171L7.6526 13.4983Z&quot; fill=&quot;black&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/g>;&lt;defs>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip0_3732_178637&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip1_3732_178637&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;/defs>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/button>;&lt;div role=&quot;dialog&quot;>;&lt;div aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; role=&quot;presentation&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;p aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;Link copied&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;button aria-label=&quot;Shop&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Button&amp;quot;}&quot; data-testid=&quot;Button&quot; type=&quot;button&quot;>;&lt;span >;Shop&lt;/span>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Shop&lt;/title>;&lt;g clip-path=&quot;url(#clip0_3732_178638)&quot;>;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; clip-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 3H2V4H4.23828L6.99617 15.2631C7.11483 15.6982 7.50998 16 7.96094 16H18.0365C18.4875 16 18.8826 15.6982 19.0013 15.2631L20.9648 7.26312C21.1383 6.62698 20.6594 6 20 6H10V7H20L18.0365 15H7.96094L5.03652 3H4.58055H4ZM10.0365 19C10.0365 19.5523 9.58881 20 9.03652 20C8.48424 20 8.03652 19.5523 8.03652 19C8.03652 18.4477 8.48424 18 9.03652 18C9.58881 18 10.0365 18.4477 10.0365 19ZM11.0365 19C11.0365 20.1046 10.1411 21 9.03652 21C7.93195 21 7.03652 20.1046 7.03652 19C7.03652 17.8954 7.93195 17 9.03652 17C10.1411 17 11.0365 17.8954 11.0365 19ZM18.0365 19C18.0365 19.5523 17.5888 20 17.0365 20C16.4842 20 16.0365 19.5523 16.0365 19C16.0365 18.4477 16.4842 18 17.0365 18C17.5888 18 18.0365 18.4477 18.0365 19ZM19.0365 19C19.0365 20.1046 18.1411 21 17.0365 21C15.932 21 15.0365 20.1046 15.0365 19C15.0365 17.8954 15.932 17 17.0365 17C18.1411 17 19.0365 17.8954 19.0365 19Z&quot; fill=&quot;black&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/g>;&lt;defs>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip0_3732_178638&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip1_3732_178638&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;/defs>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p >;A decade or so into his career, Ariely&#39;s focus shifted to applied research. A former affiliate told me that Ariely once said, “Some behavioral economist is going to win the Nobel Prize—what do I have to do to be in contention?” (Ariely denies wondering whether he would get the Nobel Prize.) In the spring of 2007, he asked an insurance company if he could replace its ordinary automobile-policy review form with experimental versions of his own. Customers had an incentive to underreport their annual mileage, in order to pay lower premiums. Half the participants were to receive a form that asked them to sign an honesty declaration at the end. The other half were to receive an alternate version, which instructed them to sign a pledge at the beginning. The following year, on his first book tour, Ariely addressed a crowd at Google, where he was later contracted to advise on a behavioral-science project, and referred in passing to the experiment&#39;s results. Those who signed at the beginning, he said, had been more candid than those who signed at the end. “This was all about decreasing the fudge factor,” he said. In 2009, Ariely noted in the &lt;em>;Harvard Business Review&lt;/em>; that the insurance company had updated its own forms to exploit his finding. He hadn&#39;t yet published the study, which, given its obvious importance, might have seemed peculiar. But, at the time, nothing appeared to indicate that the results weren&#39;t trustworthy. “People who go through a tragedy like Dan, with his burn—they have an insight into what&#39;s important in life,” the filmmaker Yael Melamede, who collaborated with Ariely on a documentary about dishonesty, told me. “He was very aware of the dangerous desire to make experiments go your way, to bend reality to your benefit.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Despite a good deal of readily available evidence to the contrary, neoclassical economics took it for granted that humans were rational. Kahneman and Tversky found flaws in this assumption, and built a compendium of our cognitive biases. We rely disproportionately on information that is easily retrieved: a recent news article about a shark attack seems much more relevant than statistics about how rarely such attacks actually occur. Our desires are in flux—we might prefer pizza to hamburgers, and hamburgers to nachos, but nachos to pizza. We are easily led astray by irrelevant details. In one experiment, Kahneman and Tversky described a young woman who had studied philosophy and participated in anti-nuclear demonstrations, then asked a group of participants which inference was more probable: either “Linda is a bank teller” or “Linda is a bank teller and is active in the feminist movement.” More than eighty per cent chose the latter, even though it is a subset of the former. We weren&#39;t &lt;em>;Homo economicus;&lt;/em>; we were giddy and impatient, our thoughts hasty, our actions improvised. Economics tottered.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Behavioral economics emerged for public consumption a generation later, around the time of Ariely&#39;s first book. Where Kahneman and Tversky held that we unconsciously trick ourselves into doing the wrong thing, behavioral economists argued that we might, by the same token, be tricked into doing the right thing. In 2008, Richard Thaler and Cass Sunstein published “Nudge,” which argued for what they called “libertarian paternalism”—the idea that small, benign alterations of our environment might lead to better outcomes. When employees were automatically enrolled in 401(k) programs, twice as many saved for retirement. This simple bureaucratic rearrangement improved a great many lives.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Thaler and Sunstein hoped that libertarian paternalism might offer “a real Third Way—one that can break through some of the least tractable debates in contemporary democracies.” Barack Obama, who hovered above base partisanship, found much to admire in the promise of technocratic tinkering. He restricted his outfit choices mostly to gray or navy suits, based on research into “ego depletion,” or the concept that one might exhaust a given day&#39;s reservoir of decision-making energy. When, in the wake of the 2008 financial crisis, Obama was told that money “framed” as income was more likely to be spent than money framed as wealth, he enacted monthly tax deductions instead of sending out lump-sum stimulus checks. He eventually created a behavioral-sciences team in the White House. (Ariely had once found that our decisions in a restaurant are influenced by whoever orders first; it&#39;s possible that Obama was driven by the fact that David Cameron, in the UK, was already leaning on a “nudge unit.”)&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The nudge, at its best, was modest—even a minor potential benefit at no cost pencilled out. In the Obama years, a pop-up on computers at the Department of Agriculture reminded employees that single-sided printing was a waste, and that advice reduced paper use by six per cent. But as these ideas began to intermingle with those in the adjacent field of social psychology, the reasonable notion that some small changes could have large effects at scale gave way to a vision of individual human beings as almost boundlessly pliable. Even Kahneman was convinced. He told me, “People invented things that shouldn&#39;t have worked, and they were working, and I was enormously impressed by it.” Some of these interventions could be implemented from above. Brian Wansink, a researcher at Cornell, reported that an attractive wire rack and a lamp increased fruit sales at a school by fifty-four per cent, and that buffet diners likely consumed fewer calories when “cheesy eggs” weren&#39;t immediately at hand. Other techniques were akin to personal mind cures. In 2010, the Harvard Business School professor Amy Cuddy purported to show that subjects who held an assertive “power pose” could measurably improve their confidence and “instantly become more powerful.” In advance of job interviews, prospective employees retreated to corporate bathrooms to extend their arms in victorious V&#39;s.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In 2017, Thaler won the Nobel Prize for his analysis of “economic decision-making with the aid of insights from psychology.” Some policy nudges did not ultimately survive empirical scrutiny (though early studies showed that making organ donation opt-out rather than opt-in would cause the practice to become more widespread, long-term evaluations suggested that it had little effect), but the bulk of them held up. By that point, however, a maximalist version of the principle—easily absorbed by viral life-hack culture—had become commonplace. Ariely, for his part, predicted that nudges were just the beginning, and held out for more ambitious social engineering. He told me, “I thought that in many cases paternalism is going to be necessary.” At the end of “Predictably Irrational,” he writes, “If I were to distill one main lesson from the research described in this book, it is that we are pawns in a game whose forces we largely fail to comprehend.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;Haaretz&lt;/em>; once called Ariely “the busiest Israeli in the world.” I met him several times in the past year, although he agreed to speak on the record mostly in writing. A stimulating and slightly unnerving interlocutor, he has coarse black bangs, tented eyebrows, and the frank but hooded aspect of an off-duty mentalist or a veteran card-counter. “Predictably Irrational” considerably expanded his sphere of influence. He started a lab at Duke called the Center for Advanced Hindsight, which was funded by BlackRock and MetLife. He had a wife and two young children in Durham, but spent only a handful of days a month in town. In a given week, he might fly from São Paulo to Berlin to Tel Aviv. At talks, he wore rumpled polos and looked as though he&#39;d trimmed his hair with a nail clipper in an airport-lounge rest room. He has said that he worked with multiple governments and Apple. He had ideas for how to negotiate with the Palestinians. When an interviewer asked him to list the famous names in his phone contacts, he affected humility: “Jeff Bezos, the CEO of Amazon—is that good?” He went on: the CEOs of Procter &amp;amp; Gamble and American Express, the founder of Wikipedia. In 2012, he said, he got an e-mail from Prince Andrew, who invited him to the palace for tea. Ariely&#39;s assistant had to send him a jacket and tie via FedEx. He couldn&#39;t bring himself, as an Israeli, to say “Your Royal Highness,” so he addressed the Prince by saying “Hey.”&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Ariely seemed to know everything and everyone. “What an amazing life to lead,” a former doctoral student in his lab said. “It was like &#39;The Grand Budapest Hotel.&#39; ” He told people that he&#39;d climbed Annapurna and rafted down the Mekong River. But he was also attentive. “Every single time I went into the room and interacted with Dan, it was unbelievably enjoyable,” the student said. At one talk, he auctioned off a hundred-dollar bill, with the stipulation that the second-highest bidder would also have to pay. The winner owed a hundred and fifty dollars; the loser owed a hundred and forty-five dollars for nothing. Both might have felt like idiots, but Ariely wasn&#39;t scornful; he sympathized. His knowledge of human behavior could be burdensome. “It makes daily interactions a little difficult,” he said. “I know all kinds of methods to convince people to do things I want them to do.” He told me, “Just imagine that you could separate the people who are your real friends from the people who want something from you. 。 。 。 And now ask yourself if you really want to know this about them.”&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;One of his frequent collaborators was Francesca Gino, a rising star in the field. Gino is in her mid-forties, with dark curly hair and a frazzled aspect. She grew up in Italy, where she pursued a doctorate in economics and management. Members of her cohort remember her dedication, industry, and commitment. She first came to Harvard Business School as a visiting fellow, and, once she completed her Ph.D., in 2004, she stayed on as a postdoc. She later said that she went to Harvard for a nine-month stint and never left. This story elides a few detours. By the end of her postdoc, in 2006, she had yet to publish an academic paper, and Harvard did not extend an offer. One of her mentors at Harvard, a professor named Max Bazerman, helped make introductions; she eventually landed a postdoc at Carnegie Mellon. A senior colleague who knew her at the time told me, “That entire experience could plausibly have left her with a keen sense of the fragility and precariousness of academic careers.” At last, she seemed to find her footing, and it soon looked as though she could get almost any study to produce results. She secured a job at UNC, where she entered a phase of elevated productivity. According to her CV, she published seven journal papers in 2009; in 2011, an astonishing eleven.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Ariely and Gino frequently collaborated on dishonesty. In the paper “The Dark Side of Creativity,” they showed that “original thinkers,” who can dream up convincing justifications, tend to lie more easily. For “The Counterfeit Self,” she and Ariely had a group of women wear what they were told were fake Chloé sunglasses—the designer accessories, in an amusing control, were actually real—and then take a test. They found that participants who believed they were wearing counterfeit sunglasses cheated more than &lt;em>;twice&lt;/em>; as much as the control group. In “Sidetracked,” Gino&#39;s first pop-science book, she seems to note that such people were not necessarily corrupt: “Being human makes all of us vulnerable to subtle influences.” In 2010, she returned to Harvard Business School, where she was awarded an endowed professorship and later became the editor of a leading journal. She dispensed page-a-day-calendar advice on LinkedIn: “Life is an unpredictable journey. 。 。 。 The challenge isn&#39;t just setting our path, but staying on it amidst chaos.” She was a research consultant for Disney, and a speakers bureau quoted clients between fifty and a hundred thousand dollars to book her for gigs. In 2020, she was the fifth-highest-paid employee at Harvard, earning about a million dollars that year—slightly less than the university&#39;s president.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Gino drew admiring notice from those who could not believe her productivity. The business-school professor said, “She&#39;s not just brilliant and successful and wealthy—she has been a kind, fun person to know. She was well liked even by researchers who were skeptical of her work.” But she drew less admiring notice, too—also from people who could not believe her productivity. As one management scholar told me, “You just cannot trust someone who is publishing ten papers a year in top journals.” Other co-authors, as collateral beneficiaries, weren&#39;t sure what to think. One former graduate student thought that she caught Gino plagiarizing portions of a literature review, but tried to convince herself that it was an honest error. Later, in a study for a different paper, “Gino was, like, &#39;I had an idea for an additional experiment that would tie everything together, and I already collected the data and wrote it up—here are the results.&#39; ” The former graduate student added, “My adviser was, like, &#39;Did you design the study together? No. Did you know it was going to happen? No. Has she sent you the data? No. Something off is happening here.&#39; ” (Gino declined to address these allegations on the record.)&lt;/p>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;a data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.newyorker.com/cartoon/a25894&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/cartoon/a25894&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;They Studied Dishonesty. Was Their Work a Lie&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517655b620cff0823f2c3aa/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/231009_a25894.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517655b620cff0823f2c3aa/master/w_120,c_limit/231009_a25894.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517655b620cff0823f2c3aa/master/w_240,c_limit/231009_a25894.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517655b620cff0823f2c3aa/master/w_320,c_limit/231009_a25894.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517655b620cff0823f2c3aa/master/w_640,c_limit/231009_a25894.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517655b620cff0823f2c3aa/master/w_960,c_limit/231009_a25894.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517655b620cff0823f2c3aa/master/w_1280,c_limit/231009_a25894.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517655b620cff0823f2c3aa/master/w_1600,c_limit/231009_a25894.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/a>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Cartoon by Liana Finck&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;button aria-label=&quot;Copy link to cartoon&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Button&amp;quot;}&quot; data-testid=&quot;Button&quot; type=&quot;button&quot;>;&lt;span >;Copy link to cartoon&lt;/span>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Copy link to cartoon&lt;/title>;&lt;g clip-path=&quot;url(#clip0_3732_178637)&quot;>;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; clip-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M16.3488 10.5017C16.2107 10.7357 16.2926 11.035 16.5318 11.17C16.7709 11.3052 17.0767 11.225 17.2148 10.991L18.4648 8.87225C19.5694 7.00002 18.9139 4.60601 17.0007 3.52508C15.0875 2.44415 12.6412 3.08562 11.5366 4.95785L9.53657 8.34782C8.432 10.22 9.08751 12.6141 11.0007 13.6949C11.1888 13.8012 11.382 13.8908 11.5785 13.9642C11.7819 14.0403 12.0058 13.9485 12.1147 13.764C12.2794 13.4849 12.1103 13.1276 11.8083 12.9992C11.7041 12.9549 11.6014 12.9044 11.5007 12.8475C10.0658 12.0368 9.57417 10.2413 10.4026 8.83712L12.4026 5.44715C13.2311 4.04298 15.0658 3.56187 16.5007 4.37257C17.9356 5.18327 18.4272 6.97878 17.5988 8.38295L16.3488 10.5017ZM7.6526 13.4983C7.79067 13.2643 7.70873 12.965 7.46959 12.8299C7.23044 12.6948 6.92464 12.775 6.78657 13.009L5.53657 15.1278C4.432 17 5.0875 19.394 7.00068 20.475C8.91385 21.5558 11.3602 20.9144 12.4648 19.0422L14.4648 15.6521C15.5694 13.78 14.9139 11.3859 13.0007 10.305C12.8127 10.1988 12.6195 10.1091 12.4229 10.0357C12.2195 9.95975 11.9956 10.0515 11.8867 10.236C11.7221 10.5151 11.8911 10.8724 12.1932 11.0008C12.2973 11.0451 12.4 11.0956 12.5007 11.1525C13.9356 11.9632 14.4272 13.7587 13.5988 15.1628L11.5988 18.5529C10.7704 19.957 8.93555 20.4382 7.50068 19.6274C6.0658 18.8167 5.57417 17.0212 6.4026 15.6171L7.6526 13.4983Z&quot; fill=&quot;black&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/g>;&lt;defs>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip0_3732_178637&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip1_3732_178637&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;/defs>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/button>;&lt;div role=&quot;dialog&quot;>;&lt;div aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; role=&quot;presentation&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;p aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;Link copied&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;button aria-label=&quot;Shop&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Button&amp;quot;}&quot; data-testid=&quot;Button&quot; type=&quot;button&quot;>;&lt;span >;Shop&lt;/span>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Shop&lt;/title>;&lt;g clip-path=&quot;url(#clip0_3732_178638)&quot;>;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; clip-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 3H2V4H4.23828L6.99617 15.2631C7.11483 15.6982 7.50998 16 7.96094 16H18.0365C18.4875 16 18.8826 15.6982 19.0013 15.2631L20.9648 7.26312C21.1383 6.62698 20.6594 6 20 6H10V7H20L18.0365 15H7.96094L5.03652 3H4.58055H4ZM10.0365 19C10.0365 19.5523 9.58881 20 9.03652 20C8.48424 20 8.03652 19.5523 8.03652 19C8.03652 18.4477 8.48424 18 9.03652 18C9.58881 18 10.0365 18.4477 10.0365 19ZM11.0365 19C11.0365 20.1046 10.1411 21 9.03652 21C7.93195 21 7.03652 20.1046 7.03652 19C7.03652 17.8954 7.93195 17 9.03652 17C10.1411 17 11.0365 17.8954 11.0365 19ZM18.0365 19C18.0365 19.5523 17.5888 20 17.0365 20C16.4842 20 16.0365 19.5523 16.0365 19C16.0365 18.4477 16.4842 18 17.0365 18C17.5888 18 18.0365 18.4477 18.0365 19ZM19.0365 19C19.0365 20.1046 18.1411 21 17.0365 21C15.932 21 15.0365 20.1046 15.0365 19C15.0365 17.8954 15.932 17 17.0365 17C18.1411 17 19.0365 17.8954 19.0365 19Z&quot; fill=&quot;black&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/g>;&lt;defs>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip0_3732_178638&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip1_3732_178638&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;/defs>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p >;In late 2010, Gino was helping to coördinate a symposium for an Academy of Management conference, on “behavioral ethics,” which listed Ariely as a contributor. At the time, Gino and Bazerman were researching moral identity. Ariely&#39;s findings with the car-insurance company remained unpublished, but his talks had made the rounds, and his field study seemed like the perfect companion piece for joint publication. “I suggest we add them as co-authors and write up the paper for a top tier journal,” Gino later wrote, by e-mail.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;02wev&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;The paper, which was published in 2012, became an event. Signing the honesty pledge at the beginning, Ariely found, reduced cheating by about ten per cent. The Obama Administration included the paper&#39;s findings in an annual White House report. Government bodies in the UK, Canada, and Guatemala initiated studies to determine whether they should revise their tax forms, and estimated that they might recoup billions of dollars a year. Kahneman told me that he saw no reason to disbelieve the results, which were clearly compatible with the orientation of the field. “But many things that might work don&#39;t,” he told me. “And it&#39;s not necessarily clear a priori.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Near the end of Obama&#39;s first term, vast swaths of overly clever behavioral science began to come unstrung. In 2011, the Cornell psychologist Daryl Bem published a journal article that ostensibly proved the existence of clairvoyance. His study participants were able to predict, with reasonable accuracy, which curtain on a computer screen hid an erotic image. The idea seemed parodic, but Bem was serious, and had arrived at his results using methodologies entirely in line with the field&#39;s standard practices. This was troubling. The same year, three young behavioral-science professors—Joe Simmons, Leif Nelson, and Uri Simonsohn—published an actual parody: in a paper called “False-Positive Psychology,” they “proved” that listening to the Beatles song “When I&#39;m Sixty-Four” rendered study participants literally a year and a half younger. “It was hard to think of something that was so crazy that no one would believe it, because compared to what was actually being published in our journals nothing was that crazy,” Nelson, who teaches at UC Berkeley, said. Researchers could measure dozens of variables and perform reams of analyses, then publish only the correlations that happened to appear “significant.” If you tortured the data long enough, as one grim joke went, it would confess to anything. They called such techniques “p-hacking.” As they later put it, “Everyone knew it was wrong, but they thought it was wrong the way it&#39;s wrong to jaywalk.” In fact, they wrote, “it was wrong the way it&#39;s wrong to rob a bank.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The three men—who came to be called Data Colada, the name of their pun-friendly blog—had bonded over the false, ridiculous, and flashy findings that the field was capable of producing. The discipline of judgment and decision-making had made crucial, enduring contributions—the foundation laid by Kahneman and Tversky, for example—but the broader credibility of the behavioral sciences had been compromised by a perpetual-motion machine of one-weird-trick gimmickry. Their paper helped kick off what came to be known as the “replication crisis.” Soon, entire branches of supposedly reliable findings—on social priming (the idea that, say, just thinking about an old person makes you walk more slowly), power posing, and ego depletion—started to seem like castles in the air. (Cuddy, the HBS professor, defended her work, later publishing a study that showed power posing had an effect on relevant “feelings.”) Some senior figures in the field were forced to consider the possibility that their contributions amounted to nothing.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;In the course of its campaign to eradicate p-hacking, which was generally well intended, Data Colada also uncovered manipulations that were not. The psychologist Lawrence Sanna had conducted studies that literalized the metaphor of a “moral high ground,” determining that participants at higher altitudes were “more prosocial.” When Simonsohn looked into the data, he found that the numbers were not “compatible” with random sampling; they had clearly been subject to tampering. (Sanna, at the time, acknowledged “research errors.”) Simonsohn exposed similar curiosities in the work of the Flemish psychologist Dirk Smeesters. (Smeesters claimed that he engaged only in “massaging” data.) The two men&#39;s careers came to an unceremonious end. Occasionally, these probes were simple: one of the first papers that Data Colada formally examined included reports of “-0.3” on a scale of zero to ten. Other efforts required more recondite statistical analysis. Behind these techniques, however, was a basic willingness to call bullshit. Some of the papers in social psychology and adjacent fields demonstrated effects that seemed, to anyone roughly familiar with the behavior of people, preposterous: when maids are prompted to think of their duties as exercise, do they really lose weight?&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Kahneman graciously conceded that he had been wrong to endorse some of this research, and told me, of Data Colada, “They&#39;re heroes of mine.”But not everyone was supportive. Data Colada&#39;s harshest critics saw the young men as jealous upstarts who didn&#39;t understand the soft artistry of the social sciences. Norbert Schwarz, an éminence grise of psychology, interrupted a presentation about questionable research practices at a conference, and later called the burgeoning reform movement a “witch hunt.” A former president of the Association for Psychological Science, in a leaked editorial, referred to such efforts as “methodological terrorism.” When Data Colada posted about Amy Cuddy, it was taken as evidence of borderline misogyny. The Harvard psychologist Daniel Gilbert referred to the “replication police” as “shameless little bullies”; others compared Data Colada to the Stasi. Simonsohn found this analogy hurtful and offensive. “We&#39;re like data journalists,” he said. “All we can do is inform people with power. The only power you have is being right.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Simmons, Nelson, and Simonsohn maintain a standing Zoom date once a week. Recently, they invited me to join. They&#39;ve been working together long enough to finish one another&#39;s sentences—the only real pleasure in what they do. Their work can be demoralizing, and after each successive fraud investigation they swear off the practice. “It&#39;s pleasant for maybe an hour,” Simonsohn, who teaches at the Esade Business School, in Barcelona, told me. “You notice how they did it, and it feels great, like you wrote a mystery novel. But then everything feels bad.” Simmons, a professor at Wharton, added, “We have this unfortunate fraud detector in our brain. Obviously, it&#39;s just an internal alarm and you have to then check, but you see results sections that stand out as &#39;No no no, that&#39;s not a thing.&#39; ” He remarked that Nelson had sent him a screenshot of a figure from a journal; with only a glance, Simmons would have bet his house that the data were fake, but the men didn&#39;t plan to pursue the case. “At this point, it&#39;s like an affliction,” Simmons said. “But if you see it you see it, and then it&#39;s hard to look the other way.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;There is a propensity to write off such misconduct as a victimless crime. In the spring of 2021, Data Colada was contacted by Zoé Ziani, a recent Ph.D. recipient whose professional trajectory offered an example of the practice&#39;s collateral damage. Ziani is slight and angular, but she projects considerable tensile strength. She grew up in a working-class neighborhood of Paris; her parents had not graduated from college, but she was enchanted by academia. “People were paid just to think and talk about how things work,” she told me. Assessing the fallout of the financial crisis, she found herself wondering how an entire industry could have developed a culture of malfeasance. “Nobody reacted before the worst happened,” she said. “Nobody raised their hands to say, &#39;This is really risky, and we should stop.&#39; ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In graduate school, Ziani took up the question of how individuals form and exploit professional networks—such as the ones she had to assemble from nothing. One recent high-profile contribution to the networking literature was a paper by Gino. Some participants had been asked to think of a time they had networked in an “instrumental” way, and then to fill in the blanks for prompts such as “W _ _ H,” “SH _ _ ER,” and “S _ _ P.” These people were more likely to complete the prompts with such cleaning-related words as “WASH,” “SHOWER,” and “SOAP”—in other words, networking made them feel literally unclean.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Ziani found Gino&#39;s results implausible, and assumed that they had been heavily p-hacked. She told me, “This crowd is used to living in a world where you have enough degrees of freedom to do whatever you want and all that matters is that it works beautifully.” But an adviser strongly suggested that Ziani “build on” the paper, which had appeared in a top journal. When she expressed her doubts, the adviser snapped at her, “Don&#39;t ever say that!” Members of Ziani&#39;s dissertation committee couldn&#39;t understand why this nobody of a student was being so truculent. In the end, two of them refused to sign off on her degree if she did not remove criticisms of Gino&#39;s paper from her dissertation. One warned Ziani not to second-guess a professor of Gino&#39;s stature in this way. In an e-mail, the adviser wrote, “Academic research is like a conversation at a cocktail party. You are storming in, shouting &#39;You suck!&#39; ”&lt;/p>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;a data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.newyorker.com/cartoon/a27975&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/cartoon/a27975&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;“You know what I like about them Youd never guess they have kids”&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517655dd324cac0c81eae14/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/231009_a27975.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517655dd324cac0c81eae14/master/w_120,c_limit/231009_a27975.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517655dd324cac0c81eae14/master/w_240,c_limit/231009_a27975.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517655dd324cac0c81eae14/master/w_320,c_limit/231009_a27975.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517655dd324cac0c81eae14/master/w_640,c_limit/231009_a27975.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517655dd324cac0c81eae14/master/w_960,c_limit/231009_a27975.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517655dd324cac0c81eae14/master/w_1280,c_limit/231009_a27975.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517655dd324cac0c81eae14/master/w_1600,c_limit/231009_a27975.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/a>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“You know what I like about them? You&#39;d never guess they have kids!”&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Cartoon by Carolita Johnson&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;button aria-label=&quot;Copy link to cartoon&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Button&amp;quot;}&quot; data-testid=&quot;Button&quot; type=&quot;button&quot;>;&lt;span >;Copy link to cartoon&lt;/span>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Copy link to cartoon&lt;/title>;&lt;g clip-path=&quot;url(#clip0_3732_178637)&quot;>;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; clip-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M16.3488 10.5017C16.2107 10.7357 16.2926 11.035 16.5318 11.17C16.7709 11.3052 17.0767 11.225 17.2148 10.991L18.4648 8.87225C19.5694 7.00002 18.9139 4.60601 17.0007 3.52508C15.0875 2.44415 12.6412 3.08562 11.5366 4.95785L9.53657 8.34782C8.432 10.22 9.08751 12.6141 11.0007 13.6949C11.1888 13.8012 11.382 13.8908 11.5785 13.9642C11.7819 14.0403 12.0058 13.9485 12.1147 13.764C12.2794 13.4849 12.1103 13.1276 11.8083 12.9992C11.7041 12.9549 11.6014 12.9044 11.5007 12.8475C10.0658 12.0368 9.57417 10.2413 10.4026 8.83712L12.4026 5.44715C13.2311 4.04298 15.0658 3.56187 16.5007 4.37257C17.9356 5.18327 18.4272 6.97878 17.5988 8.38295L16.3488 10.5017ZM7.6526 13.4983C7.79067 13.2643 7.70873 12.965 7.46959 12.8299C7.23044 12.6948 6.92464 12.775 6.78657 13.009L5.53657 15.1278C4.432 17 5.0875 19.394 7.00068 20.475C8.91385 21.5558 11.3602 20.9144 12.4648 19.0422L14.4648 15.6521C15.5694 13.78 14.9139 11.3859 13.0007 10.305C12.8127 10.1988 12.6195 10.1091 12.4229 10.0357C12.2195 9.95975 11.9956 10.0515 11.8867 10.236C11.7221 10.5151 11.8911 10.8724 12.1932 11.0008C12.2973 11.0451 12.4 11.0956 12.5007 11.1525C13.9356 11.9632 14.4272 13.7587 13.5988 15.1628L11.5988 18.5529C10.7704 19.957 8.93555 20.4382 7.50068 19.6274C6.0658 18.8167 5.57417 17.0212 6.4026 15.6171L7.6526 13.4983Z&quot; fill=&quot;black&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/g>;&lt;defs>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip0_3732_178637&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip1_3732_178637&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;/defs>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/button>;&lt;div role=&quot;dialog&quot;>;&lt;div aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; role=&quot;presentation&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;p aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;Link copied&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;button aria-label=&quot;Shop&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Button&amp;quot;}&quot; data-testid=&quot;Button&quot; type=&quot;button&quot;>;&lt;span >;Shop&lt;/span>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Shop&lt;/title>;&lt;g clip-path=&quot;url(#clip0_3732_178638)&quot;>;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; clip-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 3H2V4H4.23828L6.99617 15.2631C7.11483 15.6982 7.50998 16 7.96094 16H18.0365C18.4875 16 18.8826 15.6982 19.0013 15.2631L20.9648 7.26312C21.1383 6.62698 20.6594 6 20 6H10V7H20L18.0365 15H7.96094L5.03652 3H4.58055H4ZM10.0365 19C10.0365 19.5523 9.58881 20 9.03652 20C8.48424 20 8.03652 19.5523 8.03652 19C8.03652 18.4477 8.48424 18 9.03652 18C9.58881 18 10.0365 18.4477 10.0365 19ZM11.0365 19C11.0365 20.1046 10.1411 21 9.03652 21C7.93195 21 7.03652 20.1046 7.03652 19C7.03652 17.8954 7.93195 17 9.03652 17C10.1411 17 11.0365 17.8954 11.0365 19ZM18.0365 19C18.0365 19.5523 17.5888 20 17.0365 20C16.4842 20 16.0365 19.5523 16.0365 19C16.0365 18.4477 16.4842 18 17.0365 18C17.5888 18 18.0365 18.4477 18.0365 19ZM19.0365 19C19.0365 20.1046 18.1411 21 17.0365 21C15.932 21 15.0365 20.1046 15.0365 19C15.0365 17.8954 15.932 17 17.0365 17C18.1411 17 19.0365 17.8954 19.0365 19Z&quot; fill=&quot;black&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/g>;&lt;defs>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip0_3732_178638&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip1_3732_178638&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;/defs>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p >;Ziani complied, but her professional relationships had deteriorated, and she soon left the cocktail party for good. When she told me these stories, in a wood-panelled bar at a historic hotel in Boulder, Colorado, she covered her face to cry. Simmons told me that he could name countless people who had similar experiences. “Some people are hurt by this stuff and they don&#39;t even know. They think they&#39;re not good enough—&#39;It must be me&#39;—so they leave the field,” he said. “That&#39;s where I started to get angry. How many Zoés are there?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Ziani had moved to Colorado, in 2020, for her husband&#39;s job. In the spring of 2021, she set out to replicate Gino&#39;s study. She asked for the data, and, after some delay, received it. That April, she used an online survey platform to re-create the experiment. It took a few days, and she found none of the reported effects. She also determined, more worrisomely, that there was almost no way the paper&#39;s effect size could have been naturally generated. “I knew there was something fishy there,” Ziani said. “More than fishy.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;She and a collaborator (who wished to remain anonymous, for fear of professional retribution) approached Data Colada. The team had had its own doubts about Gino since 2014, but had concluded that a full investigation was more trouble than it was worth. Now, however, they scrutinized her previous work, and found multiple instances of data that seemed to be misbehaving. Ziani said, “The magnitude of the fraud was potentially so gigantic that they didn&#39;t want to be merely one hundred per cent sure but one thousand per cent sure.”&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;One day, Ziani came across the field study from the car-insurance paper. This data was the fishiest of all, and she sent the file to Data Colada in triumph. On a Zoom call, Simonsohn looked more closely and realized, “Hey, wait a minute. This wasn&#39;t Francesca?” The study had been conducted by Ariely. Later, they opened the file for Gino&#39;s contribution to the same paper, and that, too, seemed incommensurable with real data. It was difficult not to read this as a sign of the field&#39;s blight. Simmons told me, “We were, like, Holy shit, there are two different people independently faking data on the same paper. And it&#39;s a paper about &lt;em>;dishonesty&lt;/em>;.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In 2021, the Data Colada team sent a dossier to Harvard that outlined an array of anomalies in four of Gino&#39;s papers. In her lab study for the car-insurance paper, for example, several observations seemed to be out of order, in a way that suggested someone had moved them around by hand. Those data points, they found, were disproportionately responsible for the result. The team was unable to conceive of a benign explanation for this pattern. They had examined only four papers but noted “strong suspicions” about some of her published data going as far back as 2008. On October 27, 2021, Harvard notified Gino that she was under investigation, and asked her to turn over all “HBS-issued devices” by 5 &lt;em >;PM&lt;/em>; that day. According to Gino, the police were called to oversee the process.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;There had always been some bewilderment about Gino. Multiple people told me they found it abnormal that Gino so closely guarded her data at every step of the process. One former co-author said, “HBS is so hierarchical, it&#39;s like the military, and it was unheard of for the more senior person to do the bitch work and let the junior person have the lofty thoughts. But, then again, if I had done the grunt work, we would not have found significant results.” The networking paper that had originally drawn Ziani&#39;s scrutiny had also seemed dubious to the former graduate student. “There were all kinds of red flags about her sample size, significance, and effect size, and I was, like, &#39;No way, I&#39;m done with this person,&#39; ” she said. Another professor I spoke to didn&#39;t buy one of Gino&#39;s early papers. “When you look at it, it just makes no sense,” he said. But, he added, “even in safe spaces in my world, to bring up that someone is a data fabricator—it&#39;s, like, &#39;Our friend John, do you think he might be a cannibal?&#39; ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Concerns, however, had been raised. In 2012, Lakshmi Balachandra, now a professor at Babson, told Bazerman, Gino&#39;s mentor, that her work seemed too good to be true. Balachandra said, “He basically said to me, &#39;Oh, she&#39;s such a hard worker, you could learn a lot from her.&#39; ” (Bazerman declined to comment about this on the record.) In 2015, a graduate student lodged a complaint against Gino and one of her colleagues, alleging, primarily, that Gino and the colleague created a tense and belittling environment. The more unsettling charge, though, was that Gino had repeatedly refused to share the raw data from their experiments. Once, after the student didn&#39;t hand over an analysis during a long weekend, Gino ran the study herself and produced much stronger results. On multiple occasions, the student voiced concerns to a faculty review board that Gino was playing games with data, but the board was unresponsive. A three-month investigation concluded, in a confidential report, that none of the people involved had acquitted themselves particularly well, but that no action was warranted. “What incredibly low standards Harvard Business School must have to not take concerns about data manipulation seriously,” she wrote. (Harvard declined to comment on personnel matters.)&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Gino has maintained that she never falsified or fabricated data. In a statement, her lawyer said, “Harvard&#39;s complete and utter disregard for evidence, due process, confidentiality and gender equity should frighten all academic researchers. And Data Colada&#39;s vicious take-down is baseless.” (She declined to comment on other matters on the record.) Lawrence Lessig, a law professor at Harvard, told me he is certain that Gino is innocent. “I&#39;m convinced about her because I know her,” he said. “That&#39;s the strongest reason why I can&#39;t believe this has happened.”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;zbaso7&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;This spring, Harvard finalized a twelve-hundred-page report that found Gino culpable. As part of its investigation, Harvard obtained the original data file for one of Gino&#39;s studies from a former research assistant. An outside firm compared that to the published data and concluded that it had been altered not only in the ways Data Colada had predicted but in other ways as well. Gino&#39;s defense, in that case, seems to be that the published data are in fact the real data, and that the “original” data are somehow not. Data Colada titled a blog post about her alleged misdeeds “Clusterfake.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;According to Gino, she was summoned to the office of the dean, who explained that she would be placed on administrative leave, and that he was instituting perhaps unprecedented proceedings to revoke her tenure. She wept. The dean told her, “You are a capable, smart woman. I am sure you&#39;ll find other opportunities.” That day, journal editors were advised to begin the retraction process.&lt;/p>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;a data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.newyorker.com/cartoon/a25841&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/cartoon/a25841&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;“If we see any of my bear friends pretend Im mauling you.”&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65176560620cff0823f2c3ac/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/231009_a25841.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65176560620cff0823f2c3ac/master/w_120,c_limit/231009_a25841.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65176560620cff0823f2c3ac/master/w_240,c_limit/231009_a25841.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65176560620cff0823f2c3ac/master/w_320,c_limit/231009_a25841.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65176560620cff0823f2c3ac/master/w_640,c_limit/231009_a25841.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65176560620cff0823f2c3ac/master/w_960,c_limit/231009_a25841.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65176560620cff0823f2c3ac/master/w_1280,c_limit/231009_a25841.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/65176560620cff0823f2c3ac/master/w_1600,c_limit/231009_a25841.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/a>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“If we see any of my bear friends, pretend I&#39;m mauling you.”&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Cartoon by Paul Noth&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;button aria-label=&quot;Copy link to cartoon&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Button&amp;quot;}&quot; data-testid=&quot;Button&quot; type=&quot;button&quot;>;&lt;span >;Copy link to cartoon&lt;/span>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Copy link to cartoon&lt;/title>;&lt;g clip-path=&quot;url(#clip0_3732_178637)&quot;>;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; clip-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M16.3488 10.5017C16.2107 10.7357 16.2926 11.035 16.5318 11.17C16.7709 11.3052 17.0767 11.225 17.2148 10.991L18.4648 8.87225C19.5694 7.00002 18.9139 4.60601 17.0007 3.52508C15.0875 2.44415 12.6412 3.08562 11.5366 4.95785L9.53657 8.34782C8.432 10.22 9.08751 12.6141 11.0007 13.6949C11.1888 13.8012 11.382 13.8908 11.5785 13.9642C11.7819 14.0403 12.0058 13.9485 12.1147 13.764C12.2794 13.4849 12.1103 13.1276 11.8083 12.9992C11.7041 12.9549 11.6014 12.9044 11.5007 12.8475C10.0658 12.0368 9.57417 10.2413 10.4026 8.83712L12.4026 5.44715C13.2311 4.04298 15.0658 3.56187 16.5007 4.37257C17.9356 5.18327 18.4272 6.97878 17.5988 8.38295L16.3488 10.5017ZM7.6526 13.4983C7.79067 13.2643 7.70873 12.965 7.46959 12.8299C7.23044 12.6948 6.92464 12.775 6.78657 13.009L5.53657 15.1278C4.432 17 5.0875 19.394 7.00068 20.475C8.91385 21.5558 11.3602 20.9144 12.4648 19.0422L14.4648 15.6521C15.5694 13.78 14.9139 11.3859 13.0007 10.305C12.8127 10.1988 12.6195 10.1091 12.4229 10.0357C12.2195 9.95975 11.9956 10.0515 11.8867 10.236C11.7221 10.5151 11.8911 10.8724 12.1932 11.0008C12.2973 11.0451 12.4 11.0956 12.5007 11.1525C13.9356 11.9632 14.4272 13.7587 13.5988 15.1628L11.5988 18.5529C10.7704 19.957 8.93555 20.4382 7.50068 19.6274C6.0658 18.8167 5.57417 17.0212 6.4026 15.6171L7.6526 13.4983Z&quot; fill=&quot;black&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/g>;&lt;defs>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip0_3732_178637&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip1_3732_178637&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;/defs>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/button>;&lt;div role=&quot;dialog&quot;>;&lt;div aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; role=&quot;presentation&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;p aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;Link copied&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;button aria-label=&quot;Shop&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Button&amp;quot;}&quot; data-testid=&quot;Button&quot; type=&quot;button&quot;>;&lt;span >;Shop&lt;/span>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Shop&lt;/title>;&lt;g clip-path=&quot;url(#clip0_3732_178638)&quot;>;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; clip-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 3H2V4H4.23828L6.99617 15.2631C7.11483 15.6982 7.50998 16 7.96094 16H18.0365C18.4875 16 18.8826 15.6982 19.0013 15.2631L20.9648 7.26312C21.1383 6.62698 20.6594 6 20 6H10V7H20L18.0365 15H7.96094L5.03652 3H4.58055H4ZM10.0365 19C10.0365 19.5523 9.58881 20 9.03652 20C8.48424 20 8.03652 19.5523 8.03652 19C8.03652 18.4477 8.48424 18 9.03652 18C9.58881 18 10.0365 18.4477 10.0365 19ZM11.0365 19C11.0365 20.1046 10.1411 21 9.03652 21C7.93195 21 7.03652 20.1046 7.03652 19C7.03652 17.8954 7.93195 17 9.03652 17C10.1411 17 11.0365 17.8954 11.0365 19ZM18.0365 19C18.0365 19.5523 17.5888 20 17.0365 20C16.4842 20 16.0365 19.5523 16.0365 19C16.0365 18.4477 16.4842 18 17.0365 18C17.5888 18 18.0365 18.4477 18.0365 19ZM19.0365 19C19.0365 20.1046 18.1411 21 17.0365 21C15.932 21 15.0365 20.1046 15.0365 19C15.0365 17.8954 15.932 17 17.0365 17C18.1411 17 19.0365 17.8954 19.0365 19Z&quot; fill=&quot;black&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/g>;&lt;defs>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip0_3732_178638&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip1_3732_178638&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;/defs>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p >;In September, NBC premièred a prime-time procedural called “The Irrational,” starring the “Law &amp;amp; Order” veteran Jesse L. Martin as a behavioral scientist, inspired by Ariely, who helps solve crimes. “Understanding human nature can be a superpower, which is why the FBI ends up calling me,” Martin&#39;s character says. A trade-publication article about the show accidentally described Ariely&#39;s first book as a work of fiction, which inspired Richard Thaler to joke on Twitter, “I have known for years that Dan Ariely made stuff up but now it turns out that it is ok because his book was a novel!” Ariely has also just published a new book, “Misbelief.” In 2020, he writes, the Israeli government sought his help with pandemic-lockdown strategy. “&lt;em >;Covid&lt;/em>; in many ways was the highlight of my career,” he told me. He says that he suggested prompting people to wear masks through the altruistic message of “protect others.” He proposed an app-based solution to the rise in domestic violence: children, invited to imagine themselves as superheroes, were encouraged to report disturbances at home. That summer—in an anecdote left out of his book—he told the Israeli press he had suggested that the Army infect soldiers on a base with the coronavirus as an experiment. (Ariely said that his comments were taken out of context and that this was initially someone else&#39;s idea. The former head of the Israel Defense Forces&#39; personnel directorate confirmed that he had a “very short” conversation with Ariely and “denied his request immediately.”)&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;He writes that he soon became the subject of Israeli &lt;em >;covid&lt;/em>;-denialist conspiracy theories: in a “parallel universe,” he and his “Illuminati friends” were “in cahoots with Bill Gates” to collaborate “with multiple governments to control and manipulate their citizens.” He was called the “chief consciousness engineer” of the “&lt;em >;Covid&lt;/em>;-19 fraud.” One conspiracist posted a photo of Ariely&#39;s burns, he wrote in a draft of the book, and said that his suffering had made him “want to take revenge on the world and kill as many people as possible.” Ariely describes late-night hours spent engaging with trolls online, offering, in one case, to provide his tax returns as proof that his government services were pro bono. The book thrums with a newfound pessimism; Ariely seems to have lost faith in his old parlor tricks. “It&#39;s been a very, very tough few years being exposed to the darkest corners of the Internet and the darkest aspects of human nature,” he told me. It never seems to have occurred to him that the vanity and disdain behind a certain kind of social engineering—keeping the buffet treats just out of reach—might exacerbate ambient resentments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;It remained unclear, however, how potent those interventions had ever been. As the Data Colada team members learned more about the insurance paper, they found that it had long had an asterisk attached to it. In February, 2011, at the beginning of the collaboration, Ariely had sent an Excel file with the insurance company&#39;s data to Nina Mazar, a frequent co-author, for analysis. She found that the results pointed in the wrong direction—people who had signed at the beginning were &lt;em>;less&lt;/em>; honest. Ariely responded that, in making “the dataset nicer” for her, he had relabelled the condition names, accidentally switching them in the process. He instructed her to switch them back. (When asked recently, Ariely reiterated this account, though he added that someone in his lab might have retyped the condition names for him.)&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Later, when Bazerman reviewed a draft, he was struck by something else. The over-all numbers suggested that people drove an average of twenty-four thousand miles a year, about twice what he would have expected. When asked about this, Ariely was vague: “We used an older population mostly in Florida—but we can&#39;t tell how we got the data, who was the population (they were all AARP members)—and we also can&#39;t show the forms.” This still seemed odd—why would retirees drive more than commuters? Work on the paper halted. Mazar eventually relayed that the mileage data might have reflected not one but multiple years of driving. Bazerman told me, “It was only then that I kept my name on the paper.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Four years after publication, Bazerman received an e-mail from a guy named Stuart Baserman, who worked at an Internet insurance company, and had noticed the similar surname on the paper. (Bazerman&#39;s wife suggested that he and Baserman take a DNA test. “Cousin Stu” is now Bazerman&#39;s favorite cousin.) Baserman asked if the paper&#39;s results would hold in an online setting. But several experimental attempts failed, as did a subsequent high-powered lab replication of Gino&#39;s initial lab study. The effect just wasn&#39;t there. (The Guatemalan government, with help from the “nudge unit” in the UK, had also tried to replicate a version of Ariely&#39;s field study with the insurance company, using tax forms, and found no results.)&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Writing up the failed replication, one of the authors noticed something strange in Ariely&#39;s field-study data: there was a large difference between the baseline mileage—the odometer readings taken prior to the study—of the two cohorts. This seemed like a fatal randomization error. The journal&#39;s editors asked if the authors wanted to retract the original publication. Ariely and Gino were against the idea at the time. Ariely predicted that, if anything, it was the second paper that might have to be retracted. “My strong preference is to keep both papers out and let the science process do its job,” he wrote. He and Mazar were continuing to explore the value of honesty pledges. A former senior researcher at the lab told me, “He assured us that the effect was there, that this was a true thing, and I was convinced he completely believed it.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;It didn&#39;t take long for Ziani and Data Colada to determine that the odometer readings were inauthentic. In real life, the distribution of how much people drive looks more or less like a bell curve. This data, however, formed a uniform distribution—the same number of people drove about a thousand miles as did twelve thousand miles as did fifty thousand. Most people, when asked to fill out a form, round off unwieldy numbers to the nearest hundred or thousand. But there were few round numbers in the data set. In a small additional kink, the data were written in two different fonts: Calibri and Cambria. In August, 2021, Data Colada detailed these issues in a blog post. The evidence was overwhelming, and all the paper&#39;s authors agreed immediately that the data were bogus. In statements, each disowned any responsibility. Gino, unaware that she was also being investigated by Data Colada, praised the team for its determination and skill: “The work they do takes talent and courage and vastly improves our research field.” Ariely, apparently taken aback, underscored that he had been the only author who handled the data. He then seemed to imply that the findings could have been falsified only by someone at the insurance company.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The insurance company in question, which was revealed to be the Hartford, was surprised to find that it had anything to do with the now infamous study. According to an agreement that Ariely signed in 2007, he was not allowed to refer to any of the company&#39;s data without permission—permission that, according to the company, he had neither sought nor received. (Ariely said that he would never share something without approval.) In the paper, the data had been attributed to a company in the “southeastern United States,” which now smacked of deliberate misdirection. “We have been based in Connecticut, and not the Southeast, for more than two hundred years,” a company spokesperson told me. The Hartford had, in fact, completed a small pilot study at Ariely&#39;s request, but it hadn&#39;t been fruitful: there was no discernible difference between those who signed at the top and those who signed at the end. The company never updated its forms, as Ariely had claimed. In May of 2008, about two months before Ariely discussed the results at Google, the Hartford sent him a single data set. During the next ten months, the company said, Ariely wrote at least five times to request additional odometer data, but it provided nothing. In February of 2009, all contact with Ariely ceased. (Ariely says that he has limited recollection of this time, and no paper trail.)&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Recently, I obtained the original file of the insurance company&#39;s data. It contains odometer readings for about six thousand cars. These readings are assigned to three different conditions. About half the people were given the company&#39;s “original,” standard form, as a control. (This form couldn&#39;t be tracked down.) On the experimental forms, which have the perfunctory look of a social scientist&#39;s survey materials, a quarter of the participants were instructed to sign a prominent “Pledge of Honesty” at the end, and the remainder to sign one at the beginning. By the time Ariely sent the file to Mazar, three years later, the contents had been transformed. Now the file included about twenty thousand cars, in only two conditions. A comparison of the two files confirms that the data were put through the wringer. About half the cars in the “original” cohort were reassigned to the other conditions, but many appear to have been simply dropped. Among the remaining cars, many never made it to the new file at all, and around half of those that did had their conditions changed. Observations for at least fourteen thousand made-up cars were manufactured, presumably, as Data Colada conjectured, with the help of Excel&#39;s random-number generator—the bulk of which appeared in a different font. According to an unpublished Data Colada analysis, six hundred and fifty of the odometer readings were manually swapped between conditions, which generated the study&#39;s effect. But something went awry along the way, and it wasn&#39;t until Mazar switched the condition labels that the experiment appeared to succeed. Although Ariely told Mazar that he had renamed the conditions, their names are unchanged between the two files. What, then, had he been doing when he was making “the dataset nicer” for her?&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Ariely has consistently denied any role in the data manipulation. “I care about understanding what makes us tick, and I would never falsify any data on any experiment,” he told me. He disavowed any involvement in the “history” of the data, saying that he merely served as a conduit for the file; he claimed that his co-authors and the members of his lab also had access to it. Investigators of data fraud rarely have recourse to the equivalent of surveillance-camera footage, so the culprit&#39;s identity may never be known with certainty. In September, 2021, the Hartford sent Ariely a cease-and-desist letter, warning him that, if he continued to suggest that “The Hartford had any role in the erroneous research published in the study,” it would pursue legal action. In the past two years, Ariely has nevertheless continued, privately in English and publicly in Hebrew, to implicate a nameless figure at the Hartford. As the former senior researcher told me, “What Dan says is that he thinks it was just some low-level employee who was doing someone a favor at the insurance company, but they don&#39;t know who it was, and they can&#39;t find out. ” This theory is possible; a crooked or inept employee might have taken the file, wangled it to serve Ariely&#39;s hypothesis, and then re-sent it using a non-Hartford e-mail address. It would then have had to escape Ariely&#39;s notice that six thousand observations across three conditions had become twenty thousand observations across only two. (Ariely said that this was the first time he had heard of the third condition, though it was mentioned in the Hartford&#39;s cease-and-desist letter.) Recently, since Gino was put on leave, Ariely has privately speculated that she could have been responsible. He has also mused to colleagues that a lab member could have made the changes. He told Data Colada, however, that he had been the only one to handle the data, and it would have been an enormous risk for a junior researcher to take. (Ariely said that he would never accuse anyone without evidence.) The metadata for the Excel file that he sent to Mazar note that it was created, and last edited, by a user named Dan Ariely.&lt;/p>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;a data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.newyorker.com/cartoon/a27448&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/cartoon/a27448&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;“You can just leave it on that crag thanks.”&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517656316b6e0afb263d337/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/231009_a27448.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517656316b6e0afb263d337/master/w_120,c_limit/231009_a27448.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517656316b6e0afb263d337/master/w_240,c_limit/231009_a27448.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517656316b6e0afb263d337/master/w_320,c_limit/231009_a27448.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517656316b6e0afb263d337/master/w_640,c_limit/231009_a27448.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517656316b6e0afb263d337/master/w_960,c_limit/231009_a27448.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517656316b6e0afb263d337/master/w_1280,c_limit/231009_a27448.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517656316b6e0afb263d337/master/w_1600,c_limit/231009_a27448.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/a>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“You can just leave it on that crag, thanks.”&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Cartoon by Lila Ash&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;button aria-label=&quot;Copy link to cartoon&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Button&amp;quot;}&quot; data-testid=&quot;Button&quot; type=&quot;button&quot;>;&lt;span >;Copy link to cartoon&lt;/span>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Copy link to cartoon&lt;/title>;&lt;g clip-path=&quot;url(#clip0_3732_178637)&quot;>;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; clip-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M16.3488 10.5017C16.2107 10.7357 16.2926 11.035 16.5318 11.17C16.7709 11.3052 17.0767 11.225 17.2148 10.991L18.4648 8.87225C19.5694 7.00002 18.9139 4.60601 17.0007 3.52508C15.0875 2.44415 12.6412 3.08562 11.5366 4.95785L9.53657 8.34782C8.432 10.22 9.08751 12.6141 11.0007 13.6949C11.1888 13.8012 11.382 13.8908 11.5785 13.9642C11.7819 14.0403 12.0058 13.9485 12.1147 13.764C12.2794 13.4849 12.1103 13.1276 11.8083 12.9992C11.7041 12.9549 11.6014 12.9044 11.5007 12.8475C10.0658 12.0368 9.57417 10.2413 10.4026 8.83712L12.4026 5.44715C13.2311 4.04298 15.0658 3.56187 16.5007 4.37257C17.9356 5.18327 18.4272 6.97878 17.5988 8.38295L16.3488 10.5017ZM7.6526 13.4983C7.79067 13.2643 7.70873 12.965 7.46959 12.8299C7.23044 12.6948 6.92464 12.775 6.78657 13.009L5.53657 15.1278C4.432 17 5.0875 19.394 7.00068 20.475C8.91385 21.5558 11.3602 20.9144 12.4648 19.0422L14.4648 15.6521C15.5694 13.78 14.9139 11.3859 13.0007 10.305C12.8127 10.1988 12.6195 10.1091 12.4229 10.0357C12.2195 9.95975 11.9956 10.0515 11.8867 10.236C11.7221 10.5151 11.8911 10.8724 12.1932 11.0008C12.2973 11.0451 12.4 11.0956 12.5007 11.1525C13.9356 11.9632 14.4272 13.7587 13.5988 15.1628L11.5988 18.5529C10.7704 19.957 8.93555 20.4382 7.50068 19.6274C6.0658 18.8167 5.57417 17.0212 6.4026 15.6171L7.6526 13.4983Z&quot; fill=&quot;black&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/g>;&lt;defs>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip0_3732_178637&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip1_3732_178637&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;/defs>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/button>;&lt;div role=&quot;dialog&quot;>;&lt;div aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; role=&quot;presentation&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;p aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;Link copied&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;button aria-label=&quot;Shop&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Button&amp;quot;}&quot; data-testid=&quot;Button&quot; type=&quot;button&quot;>;&lt;span >;Shop&lt;/span>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Shop&lt;/title>;&lt;g clip-path=&quot;url(#clip0_3732_178638)&quot;>;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; clip-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 3H2V4H4.23828L6.99617 15.2631C7.11483 15.6982 7.50998 16 7.96094 16H18.0365C18.4875 16 18.8826 15.6982 19.0013 15.2631L20.9648 7.26312C21.1383 6.62698 20.6594 6 20 6H10V7H20L18.0365 15H7.96094L5.03652 3H4.58055H4ZM10.0365 19C10.0365 19.5523 9.58881 20 9.03652 20C8.48424 20 8.03652 19.5523 8.03652 19C8.03652 18.4477 8.48424 18 9.03652 18C9.58881 18 10.0365 18.4477 10.0365 19ZM11.0365 19C11.0365 20.1046 10.1411 21 9.03652 21C7.93195 21 7.03652 20.1046 7.03652 19C7.03652 17.8954 7.93195 17 9.03652 17C10.1411 17 11.0365 17.8954 11.0365 19ZM18.0365 19C18.0365 19.5523 17.5888 20 17.0365 20C16.4842 20 16.0365 19.5523 16.0365 19C16.0365 18.4477 16.4842 18 17.0365 18C17.5888 18 18.0365 18.4477 18.0365 19ZM19.0365 19C19.0365 20.1046 18.1411 21 17.0365 21C15.932 21 15.0365 20.1046 15.0365 19C15.0365 17.8954 15.932 17 17.0365 17C18.1411 17 19.0365 17.8954 19.0365 19Z&quot; fill=&quot;black&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/g>;&lt;defs>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip0_3732_178638&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip1_3732_178638&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;/defs>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p >;Ariely, with his vaudevillian flair and commitment to provocation, had never been a perfect fit for the academy. Throughout his career, he performed studies that no one else would have had the courage, or the recklessness, to pursue. One study put survey questions to subjects who were actively masturbating. (Ariely found that men, in a state of excitement, could imagine being aroused by a twelve-year-old girl, animals, and shoes.) Another looked into people&#39;s attitudes about dildos and other sex toys. He once proposed outfitting service workers with protuberant fake nipples to see how the devices would affect tips.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In 2005, Ariely ran an experiment at MIT in which electric shocks were administered to Craigslist volunteers, who had been told that they were testing the efficacy of a painkiller. One of the participants was subjected to more than forty shocks of increasing strength, and broke down in tears. She claims that an assistant in a lab coat told her that she would forfeit payment if she backed out. (The assistant doesn&#39;t recall saying this.) The worst part was the final dehoaxing: in notes from the time, she wrote, “I was informed that there was no pain killer; that they were testing placebos and that all the information that I had been given was fabricated.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;If you sympathized with Ariely, this represented a return to the glory days of dashing mid-century social psychology. A less charitable interpretation was that the rules were in place for good reason. “I think he didn&#39;t think very highly of his subjects. And I was young, but I wasn&#39;t that gullible,” the participant told me. She complained, and the university found that Ariely&#39;s assistant lacked human-subjects training, which an administrator called a “very serious violation.” Ariely says that he was suspended from data collection for a year. According to the participant&#39;s e-mails from the time, Ariely called her three or four times a day in the hope that they might come to a private resolution, and eventually offered a two-thousand-dollar payment to make the whole thing go away. (Ariely says that he offered only to buy her “a book on the placebo effect.”) He soon agreed—for his own reasons, he said—to leave MIT (A spokesperson for the university declined to comment on personnel matters.) In an e-mail to some of his collaborators, he wrote, “Attached is the most painful paper in the world. Not so much for the subjects but for me.”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;7ziqj&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;The car-insurance study was not the only example of iffy data in Ariely&#39;s work. A few years ago, a team of researchers in Hong Kong looked into a well-known 2004 paper about the differences between social and monetary norms, and found that some numbers didn&#39;t make sense. Ariely could not locate the original data, and conceded that he had used a “strange” statistical approach. The journal appended a formal “Expression of Concern” to the original paper.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;In 2018, two researchers in the Netherlands coördinated an extensive international effort to replicate Ariely&#39;s Ten Commandments study, enlisting twenty-five labs. Their results found that asking participants to recall the Ten Commandments led, if anything, to a slight &lt;em>;increase&lt;/em>; in dishonesty. (Ariely holds that this replication was imperfect.) The researchers also encountered a medley of inconsistencies in the way that Ariely had described the study over the years. It was an embellishment to claim, even given the data he initially published, that the intervention had eliminated cheating &lt;em>;entirely&lt;/em>;. Ariely maintained that the study had been conducted at UCLA, by a professor named Aimee Drolet Rossi. When I spoke to Rossi, she told me that she had never participated in the study: “I thought, well, first, what a joke! I don&#39;t believe that study, and I certainly didn&#39;t run it.” UCLA issued a statement saying that the study hadn&#39;t taken place there. Last year, Ariely, having learned that an Israeli television program was investigating the case, wrote to Rossi, “Do you remember who was the RA that was running the data collection sessions in 2004 and 2005?” Rossi replied, “There was none. That&#39;s the point.” Ariely says that the study took place, and it&#39;s possible that it did, in some form. He told me he now remembers that the surveys were collected at UCLA but processed by an assistant at MIT, which might explain the mixup. He could not provide the assistant&#39;s identity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Ariely purported to have learned, from a dental-insurance company, that dentists agree on the presence of a cavity only about half the time. But the insurance company said that it didn&#39;t even collect such data. The Israeli TV documentary, reported by the journalist Itay Rom, dwelled on this allegation, among many others. Ariely was left feeling unfairly persecuted. Yet he has remained almost lackadaisical in his own defense. Ariely has described the use of a modified paper shredder, which allowed him to track when individuals cheated, even when they thought that the evidence had been destroyed. In 2021, researchers expressed doubt that it was even possible to modify a paper shredder in such a way. Ariely&#39;s response was maddeningly fuzzy. On the other hand, a version of the shredder appears to function in a documentary from 2015.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Ariely often claims poor recall. In some instances, though, he remains alert to context. In the American press, he has consistently said that he was burned at the age of eighteen, when he presumably would have been in the Israeli Army, by a magnesium flare. In 2008, around the time of the press tour for “Predictably Irrational,” the &lt;em>;Times&lt;/em>;, CNN, and NPR reported that he had been injured in a military exercise, and he never corrected the record. (Ariely said that he has never given inaccurate information about his injury.) But in the Israeli media, which could more easily verify military service, he has said that he was burned in an accident as part of the activities of a youth group. Documents from a court ruling in Israel confirm that the accident occurred in an apartment, where kids were mixing chemicals for a nighttime fire ceremony. In more recent years, he has reconciled these two accounts by saying that he was injured, at seventeen, in a youth-group activity during which a magnesium flare exploded. The former senior researcher said, “How do you swim through that murky area of where is he lying? Where is he stretching the truth? What is he forgetting or misremembering? Because he does all three of those things very consistently. So when it really matters—like with the auto insurance—which of these three things is it?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;One of the confounding things about the social sciences is that observational evidence can produce only correlations. To what extent is dishonesty a matter of character, and to what extent a matter of situation? Research misconduct is sometimes explained away by incentives—the publishing requirements for the job market, or the acclaim that can lead to consulting fees and Davos appearances. As one senior faculty member told me, of bridging the academic and corporate worlds, “You see what the money can buy you, you fly business class on work trips. It tickles you in that little place, and you need to have more of it.” The difference between p-hacking and fraud is one of degree. And once it becomes customary within a field to inflate results, the field selects for researchers inclined to do so. The business-school professor told me that this temptation might be more acute among researchers studying the subject: “You&#39;re thinking about it day in and day out and looking at the prevalence of it, and what you&#39;re finding out is normal people cheat on their taxes and cheat on their spouses, so it feels like people are cheating everywhere.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“I know this because I fell into the temptation,” she went on. Late one evening, years ago, she was working on a paper in her office. She had run so many studies that had worked, and she had no doubt that the effect she was investigating was real. The paper was key to her career, and she was doubled over with stress. One final study was so close to coming together, but the effect wasn&#39;t quite there. She remembers the moment with absolute clarity. “I thought, Do I tamper with the data?”她说。 “We were studying &lt;em>;deceit&lt;/em>;. I finally said to myself, &#39;OK, you can do this bad thing, and then you can put that away in a lockbox in your mind where it never gets opened, and you will never do this again.&#39; And that is exactly what I did, and I am so mortified.” The paper was a collaboration with Gino. The professor had a breakdown in Gino&#39;s office, and recalled that Gino forgave her instantly, telling her that she was not a bad person. They pulled the paper before publication. “She may well have been doing exactly the same thing,” the professor said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The senior colleague told me he could imagine that Gino, early in a career that felt highly contingent, had been similarly led astray. “Having a job at Harvard is really wonderful, and everybody in the world thinking you&#39;re a genius is pretty darn fun,” he said. “I don&#39;t know when she may have started engaging in fraud, but once she learned to sing to the evidence that way, and get it to play her song, I can imagine that it&#39;s impossible to stop.” As part of one survey, she gave participants gift cards to purchase her book on Amazon and tell her what they thought. (As a former participant wrote on Reddit, “Good pay. Shit book. Sorry to see her go.”) Academic psychologists are generally resistant to clinical interpretations, but it&#39;s difficult not to read a lot of Gino&#39;s later work as the return of the repressed. There&#39;s the title of her 2018 book, “Rebel Talent: Why It Pays to Break the Rules at Work and in Life,” or her 2014 paper, now retracted, called “Evil Genius? How Dishonesty Can Lead to Greater Creativity.” The former graduate student told me, “On the one hand, she was this meek Italian woman who used to make polenta for guests—you would never have suspected her. On the other, some of the things she wrote . 。 。 it&#39;s like she&#39;s trying to tell us something.”&lt;/p>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;a data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.newyorker.com/cartoon/a27910&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/cartoon/a27910&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;“Dont make me change the color temperature from soft white to harsh cool cause things will get ugly.”&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517656616b6e0afb263d339/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/231009_a27910.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517656616b6e0afb263d339/master/w_120,c_limit/231009_a27910.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517656616b6e0afb263d339/master/w_240,c_limit/231009_a27910.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517656616b6e0afb263d339/master/w_320,c_limit/231009_a27910.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517656616b6e0afb263d339/master/w_640,c_limit/231009_a27910.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517656616b6e0afb263d339/master/w_960,c_limit/231009_a27910.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517656616b6e0afb263d339/master/w_1280,c_limit/231009_a27910.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/cartoons/6517656616b6e0afb263d339/master/w_1600,c_limit/231009_a27910.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/a>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;“Don&#39;t make me change the color temperature from soft white to harsh cool, &#39;cause things will get ugly.”&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Cartoon by Lynn Hsu&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;button aria-label=&quot;Copy link to cartoon&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Button&amp;quot;}&quot; data-testid=&quot;Button&quot; type=&quot;button&quot;>;&lt;span >;Copy link to cartoon&lt;/span>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Copy link to cartoon&lt;/title>;&lt;g clip-path=&quot;url(#clip0_3732_178637)&quot;>;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; clip-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M16.3488 10.5017C16.2107 10.7357 16.2926 11.035 16.5318 11.17C16.7709 11.3052 17.0767 11.225 17.2148 10.991L18.4648 8.87225C19.5694 7.00002 18.9139 4.60601 17.0007 3.52508C15.0875 2.44415 12.6412 3.08562 11.5366 4.95785L9.53657 8.34782C8.432 10.22 9.08751 12.6141 11.0007 13.6949C11.1888 13.8012 11.382 13.8908 11.5785 13.9642C11.7819 14.0403 12.0058 13.9485 12.1147 13.764C12.2794 13.4849 12.1103 13.1276 11.8083 12.9992C11.7041 12.9549 11.6014 12.9044 11.5007 12.8475C10.0658 12.0368 9.57417 10.2413 10.4026 8.83712L12.4026 5.44715C13.2311 4.04298 15.0658 3.56187 16.5007 4.37257C17.9356 5.18327 18.4272 6.97878 17.5988 8.38295L16.3488 10.5017ZM7.6526 13.4983C7.79067 13.2643 7.70873 12.965 7.46959 12.8299C7.23044 12.6948 6.92464 12.775 6.78657 13.009L5.53657 15.1278C4.432 17 5.0875 19.394 7.00068 20.475C8.91385 21.5558 11.3602 20.9144 12.4648 19.0422L14.4648 15.6521C15.5694 13.78 14.9139 11.3859 13.0007 10.305C12.8127 10.1988 12.6195 10.1091 12.4229 10.0357C12.2195 9.95975 11.9956 10.0515 11.8867 10.236C11.7221 10.5151 11.8911 10.8724 12.1932 11.0008C12.2973 11.0451 12.4 11.0956 12.5007 11.1525C13.9356 11.9632 14.4272 13.7587 13.5988 15.1628L11.5988 18.5529C10.7704 19.957 8.93555 20.4382 7.50068 19.6274C6.0658 18.8167 5.57417 17.0212 6.4026 15.6171L7.6526 13.4983Z&quot; fill=&quot;black&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/g>;&lt;defs>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip0_3732_178637&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip1_3732_178637&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;/defs>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/button>;&lt;div role=&quot;dialog&quot;>;&lt;div aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; role=&quot;presentation&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;p aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;Link copied&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;button aria-label=&quot;Shop&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;Button&amp;quot;}&quot; data-testid=&quot;Button&quot; type=&quot;button&quot;>;&lt;span >;Shop&lt;/span>;&lt;div >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Shop&lt;/title>;&lt;g clip-path=&quot;url(#clip0_3732_178638)&quot;>;&lt;path fill-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; clip-rule=&quot;evenodd&quot; d=&quot;M4 3H2V4H4.23828L6.99617 15.2631C7.11483 15.6982 7.50998 16 7.96094 16H18.0365C18.4875 16 18.8826 15.6982 19.0013 15.2631L20.9648 7.26312C21.1383 6.62698 20.6594 6 20 6H10V7H20L18.0365 15H7.96094L5.03652 3H4.58055H4ZM10.0365 19C10.0365 19.5523 9.58881 20 9.03652 20C8.48424 20 8.03652 19.5523 8.03652 19C8.03652 18.4477 8.48424 18 9.03652 18C9.58881 18 10.0365 18.4477 10.0365 19ZM11.0365 19C11.0365 20.1046 10.1411 21 9.03652 21C7.93195 21 7.03652 20.1046 7.03652 19C7.03652 17.8954 7.93195 17 9.03652 17C10.1411 17 11.0365 17.8954 11.0365 19ZM18.0365 19C18.0365 19.5523 17.5888 20 17.0365 20C16.4842 20 16.0365 19.5523 16.0365 19C16.0365 18.4477 16.4842 18 17.0365 18C17.5888 18 18.0365 18.4477 18.0365 19ZM19.0365 19C19.0365 20.1046 18.1411 21 17.0365 21C15.932 21 15.0365 20.1046 15.0365 19C15.0365 17.8954 15.932 17 17.0365 17C18.1411 17 19.0365 17.8954 19.0365 19Z&quot; fill=&quot;black&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/g>;&lt;defs>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip0_3732_178638&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;clipPath id=&quot;clip1_3732_178638&quot;>;&lt;rect width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; fill=&quot;white&quot;>;&lt;/rect>;&lt;/clipPath>;&lt;/defs>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p >;An enduring mystery is that, if Gino faked the data, she seems to have done so on top of a staggering amount of actual work. Sam Swift, a New York City tech executive who worked alongside her at Carnegie Mellon, told me, “It seems way easier to fake research than to do research, so you might want to set yourself up with a relaxed life style—just make up your results and go to the beach.” He continued, “There is a work ethic that intersects with this ethical disorientation that I think is maybe not obvious.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Some observers have complained that Ariely, a charismatic man, has received gentler treatment than Gino. This phenomenon may also reflect the affection of his colleagues. Ariely is unfailingly generous: he gave holiday gifts and paid for extravagant ski trips and beach retreats; he provided a BMW and a twenty-thousand-dollar coffee machine for his lab members to use. When a prospective student told him that Harvard was willing to provide a better financial package, he offered a personal loan for the difference. He created what was, by all accounts, a compelling and fun work environment—foosball and office Segways—where people felt free to indulge their wildest experimental notions. He was, both literally and figuratively, an electrifying presence. Another former postdoc said, “On days he came into the lab, people would be, like, &#39;He&#39;s here!&#39; and go line up at his door, and his door was always open.” John Lynch, one of Ariely&#39;s mentors, said, “My experiences with Dan have been completely positive, and I have never seen anything remotely questionable in his scientific conduct.” A lot of Ariely&#39;s work—on helping people save money, for example—still seems to be valid, and perhaps meaningful. The former doctoral student told me, “The thing that I love about Dan was his ability, whenever you were talking with him, to so quickly distill something into an idea. It&#39;s like you&#39;re talking about the fabric of the universe every time.”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;7b73oj&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Yet some believed that Ariely had always had a tortuous relationship with the truth. When Ariely gained public renown, it seemed as though empirical results became a mere prelude to lively storytelling. The former senior researcher told me that she once heard him talking on the radio about a study his lab had conducted. “His numbers were wrong,” she said. Beyond this, she continued, “he misstates entire findings, he talks about research that doesn&#39;t replicate—he just doesn&#39;t really care that much about the facts. It was, like, &#39;No, you can&#39;t make these outrageous claims—you&#39;re a scientist!&#39; ” (Ariely said that his papers adhere to academic standards, but that he sometimes simplifies how he communicates about his work for a general audience.)&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Ariely and Gino found that creative people cheat more. And people will cheat and lie more when they see people on their own “team” cheating and lying around them. A month after he sent the modified file to Mazar, Ariely applied for, and later won, an NIH grant to look into dynamics that “may compromise the ethicality of scientific reporting.” Gino co-authored a resulting paper, which focussed on dishonesty more generally, and flagged that people cheat as a misguided act of altruism, to help others who could benefit. Honesty researchers have found that fewer people lie about a coin flip—a binary outcome—than exaggerate the number on a die roll, reporting that they rolled a four when they actually rolled a three, especially if a four had come up on a test roll. Ariely has long used conclusions like these to maintain that most people lie a bit. Other researchers argue that the averages are misleading: most people don&#39;t really lie much, but some people are prone to lie a lot. It now seems as though the “fudge factor” was less of an explanation of a phenomenon than a license for it—yet another just-so story about why a little deceit isn&#39;t so bad after all. “I&#39;ll tell you what the research on dishonesty says, but all that came from Dan and Francesca!” the former senior researcher said. “It&#39;s like everything we know about this situation comes from the data that might have been fabricated.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Ariely has told me that, “because of my injury and pain in my hands,” it has been decades since he processed data himself. It&#39;s true that those who have worked with Ariely in the years since the car-insurance paper have had a hard time reconciling the fraud allegations with the fact that none of them ever saw him get anywhere close to data. In a 2013 interview, Ariely talked about how much he had enjoyed drinking a glass of wine while analyzing data for a study published in 2008. But by the time he arrived at Duke, a former lab employee told me, “Dan was way too famous to worry about the publication process. There were papers I could barely get him to read.” And, according to several people I spoke to, the work completed by his lab in the past decade or more has been thorough and robust. He hired people who were serious about upstanding research practices; guidelines were instituted to, for example, keep raw data and edited data separate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Ariely sometimes spoke about a “Ulysses contract,” a way to feel a temptation without giving in to it. “Maybe this was his version of binding himself to the mast,” the former senior researcher said. “I don&#39;t know if it&#39;s true, but it&#39;s consistent. There are people who are the lifetime fraudsters, and then maybe there are people who had a fraud phase and then recovered and never did it again.” The former senior researcher explained that Ariely was well aware that he lacked an inclination to tell the truth at all costs. Perhaps, she continued, he had accepted safeguards to protect himself from his own worst impulses—an example, in other words, of taking his own scholarship seriously. “He encourages good data practices in other people and really cares about the right things. If Dan met another Dan, he wouldn&#39;t trust that Dan.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;In August, Gino filed a twenty-five-million-dollar lawsuit, claiming that she had been defamed by Data Colada and wrongly terminated by Harvard. (A Harvard spokesperson said, “Professor Gino has raised allegations in her lawsuit that Harvard vigorously and vehemently denies. We believe that Harvard ultimately will be vindicated.”) Even if the defamation counts are dismissed soon, Gino&#39;s suit will cost Data Colada tens of thousands of dollars in legal fees. The research community has rallied behind the members of Data Colada; a group of colleagues set up a GoFundMe on their behalf, which raised almost two hundred thousand dollars in twenty-four hours. Ariely&#39;s lab has lost two of its biggest funders, and morale is low. Although he remains brash and witty in conversation, he also has an aspect of melancholic self-pity. He wrote to me, in reference to the confusion around the Ten Commandments experiment, “When I was thinking of how to promote Misbelief, I had the idea of creating a misbelief and exposing it on the day of the book&#39;s publication, but maybe this is the way of karma to give me this anyway.” In May of 2022, according to a confidential document, Duke completed an initial inquiry. Investigators concluded that there was “sufficient evidence of the alleged misconduct to warrant a full investigation.” (Ariely and a Duke spokesperson declined to comment on the existence of an investigation.)&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Joe Simmons has been working on a blog post, which Data Colada will probably never publish, called “The Fraud Is Not the Story.” He notes, at the outset, that there is “a very large body of behavioral research that is true and important.” But, he says, there is also a lot of work that is “completely divorced from reality, populated with findings about human beings that cannot be true.” In the past few years, some eminent behavioral scientists have come to regret their participation in the fantasy that kitschy modifications of individual behavior will repair the world. George Loewenstein, a titan of behavioral science and a co-author of Ariely&#39;s masturbation paper, has refashioned his research program, conceding that his own work might have contributed to an emphasis on the individual at the expense of the systemic. “This is the stuff that CEOs love, right?” Luigi Zingales, an economist at the University of Chicago, told me. “It&#39;s cutesy, it&#39;s not really touching their power, and pretends to do the right thing.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;At the end of Simmons&#39;s unpublished post, he writes, “An influential portion of our literature is effectively a made-up story of human-like creatures who are so malleable that virtually any intervention administered at one point in time can drastically change their behavior.” He adds that a “field cannot reward truth if it does not or cannot decipher it, so it rewards other things instead. Interestingness. Novelty. Speed.影响。 Fantasy. And it effectively punishes the opposite. Intuitive Findings. Incremental Progress. Care. Curiosity. Reality.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The Data Colada guys have always believed that the replication crisis might be better understood as a “credibility revolution” in which their colleagues would ultimately choose rigor. The end result might be a field that&#39;s at once more boring and more reputable. That sanguine attitude has been tested by a cascade of corruption. In the weeks after the Gino revelations, some of her co-authors have audited their work, although Gino did not provide original data files for comparison. They wanted to figure out who had collected and analyzed which data, and to exonerate the innocent—especially young people, whose work for the job market or tenure might have been fatally tainted. In one paper, which had several co-authors, data of the apparently unnatural variety were newly uncovered. Although the details aren&#39;t fully clear, Gino seems to have had nothing to do with it. The data may have been altered by another professor. The suspicions have been reported to the university. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 19:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Watching the Southern Tip of Manhattan Change, for Forty Years]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/photo-booth/watching-the-southern-tip-of-manhattan-change-for-forty-years]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-30T10:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb9245a65e510b13d10/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-15.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save this story&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save this story&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save this story&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;A falling off can indicate decline or diminishment, often gradual—the petering out of a business, for instance, or the decay of a once marvellous building. Or it can refer to something abrupt, absolute. The ancient Greeks perceived such a falling off as the literal end of the world, the point beyond which humans could not go; they imagined the land mass as a vast island or disk surrounded by a boundless ocean, what the poet Pindar called “the untrodden sea.” Both senses haunt Barbara Mensch&#39;s photographic history of lower Manhattan, in particular the Fulton Fish Market, which, for a time, was an island unto itself.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A man standing in a fish market.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb56a07ec7575029ebe/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-05.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb56a07ec7575029ebe/master/w_120,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-05.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb56a07ec7575029ebe/master/w_240,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-05.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb56a07ec7575029ebe/master/w_320,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-05.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb56a07ec7575029ebe/master/w_640,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-05.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb56a07ec7575029ebe/master/w_960,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-05.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb56a07ec7575029ebe/master/w_1280,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-05.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb56a07ec7575029ebe/master/w_1600,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-05.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Fulton Fish Market, 1982.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GroupCalloutWrapper&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Two men with fish hooks.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb3d7db55fbbeb5125/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-20.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb3d7db55fbbeb5125/master/w_120,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-20.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb3d7db55fbbeb5125/master/w_240,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-20.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb3d7db55fbbeb5125/master/w_320,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-20.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb3d7db55fbbeb5125/master/w_640,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-20.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb3d7db55fbbeb5125/master/w_960,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-20.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb3d7db55fbbeb5125/master/w_1280,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-20.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb3d7db55fbbeb5125/master/w_1600,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-20.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;South Street, 1982.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A man with a fish hook on his shoulder smoking a cigarette.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb5e0da3f4b07160709/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-06.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb5e0da3f4b07160709/master/w_120,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-06.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb5e0da3f4b07160709/master/w_240,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-06.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb5e0da3f4b07160709/master/w_320,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-06.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb5e0da3f4b07160709/master/w_640,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-06.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb5e0da3f4b07160709/master/w_960,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-06.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb5e0da3f4b07160709/master/w_1280,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-06.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb5e0da3f4b07160709/master/w_1600,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-06.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Fulton Fish Market, 1982.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Men pulling chipped ice near a demolished dock.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb3d7db55fbbeb5126/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-19.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb3d7db55fbbeb5126/master/w_120,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-19.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb3d7db55fbbeb5126/master/w_240,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-19.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb3d7db55fbbeb5126/master/w_320,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-19.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb3d7db55fbbeb5126/master/w_640,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-19.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb3d7db55fbbeb5126/master/w_960,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-19.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb3d7db55fbbeb5126/master/w_1280,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-19.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb3d7db55fbbeb5126/master/w_1600,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-19.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;The destruction of Beekman Dock, 1983.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;Mensch&#39;s new book of black-and-white photographs, “&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Falling-Off-Place-Transformation-Lower-Manhattan/dp/1531504396&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://www.amazon.com/Falling-Off-Place-Transformation-Lower-Manhattan/dp/1531504396&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Falling-Off-Place-Transformation-Lower-Manhattan/dp/1531504396&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;A Falling-Off Place: The Transformation of Lower Manhattan&lt;/a>;,” documents the market and the southern tip of Manhattan across more than forty years, beginning in the early nineteen-eighties. Around the same time, Mensch moved into a fifth-floor loft in a nineteenth-century maritime warehouse on Water Street, where she still lives and works. Its windows on one side look out on the anchorage of the Brooklyn Bridge, just across the street. The enclave of her seaport neighborhood is pressed up against the East River and was once studded with piers and docks that served as landing places for the myriad fishing vessels that brought in thousands of pounds of seafood every day.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Mensch was drawn to the nighttime theatre of the market—the rows of fluorescent lights and fish bins on the selling floor, the busy camaraderie of the workers, and what she called the “Rube Goldberg contraption” in the icehouse, which broke up huge pieces of ice into fine chips that were delivered via chute to men with barrows outside. She knew the city planned to demolish certain structures around the fish market, and she felt an urgency to document everything before it no longer existed. She tried visiting a few times at night but was chased off, not because she was a woman but because the area was being scrutinized in a way it hadn&#39;t been before. The Mob had been part of the fabric of the fish market for decades, and in the early nineteen-eighties federal investigators were pursuing a broad investigation into the market&#39;s criminal ties. When Rudy Giuliani took over as US Attorney for the Southern District of New York, in 1983, he made organized crime a top priority. Paranoia was rife down on South Street, and strangers like Mensch were viewed with suspicion.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Men working at night at a fish market.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7ceac455e1c82006b/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-08.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7ceac455e1c82006b/master/w_120,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-08.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7ceac455e1c82006b/master/w_240,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-08.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7ceac455e1c82006b/master/w_320,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-08.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7ceac455e1c82006b/master/w_640,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-08.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7ceac455e1c82006b/master/w_960,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-08.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7ceac455e1c82006b/master/w_1280,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-08.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7ceac455e1c82006b/master/w_1600,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-08.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;In front of the New Market Building, 1982.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GroupCalloutWrapper&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A man leaning against a pole.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7ccac7a934af6221c/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-09.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7ccac7a934af6221c/master/w_120,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-09.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7ccac7a934af6221c/master/w_240,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-09.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7ccac7a934af6221c/master/w_320,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-09.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7ccac7a934af6221c/master/w_640,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-09.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7ccac7a934af6221c/master/w_960,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-09.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7ccac7a934af6221c/master/w_1280,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-09.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7ccac7a934af6221c/master/w_1600,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-09.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Mikey the Watchman, 1981.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A man holding a cigarette.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb8e0da3f4b0716070d/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-12.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb8e0da3f4b0716070d/master/w_120,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-12.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb8e0da3f4b0716070d/master/w_240,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-12.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb8e0da3f4b0716070d/master/w_320,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-12.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb8e0da3f4b0716070d/master/w_640,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-12.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb8e0da3f4b0716070d/master/w_960,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-12.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb8e0da3f4b0716070d/master/w_1280,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-12.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb8e0da3f4b0716070d/master/w_1600,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-12.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;A retired Fulton Fish Market worker, 1982.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;Men at a bar.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb93d7db55fbbeb5122/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-13.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb93d7db55fbbeb5122/master/w_120,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-13.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb93d7db55fbbeb5122/master/w_240,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-13.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb93d7db55fbbeb5122/master/w_320,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-13.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb93d7db55fbbeb5122/master/w_640,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-13.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb93d7db55fbbeb5122/master/w_960,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-13.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb93d7db55fbbeb5122/master/w_1280,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-13.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb93d7db55fbbeb5122/master/w_1600,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-13.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;The Paris Bar, on South Street, across from the Fulton Fish Market, 1980.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;She spent some two years making inroads with the market workers, visiting them as they worked at night, at first, hiding her Rolleiflex camera inside her jacket. In order to show the bosses the kind of project she hoped to do (and to convince them that she wasn&#39;t a federal agent), she came armed with monographs by artists such as Darius Kinsey, who, with the help of his wife, produced photographs of the logging industry in the Pacific Northwest from the turn of the century until 1940. Kinsey made portraits of lumberjacks posing with crosscut saws and reclining in crevasses carved into the trunks of massive firs. He captured teams of oxen dragging logs along a skid road and a sweeping view of men dwarfed by a steam donkey that, in turn, looks inconsequential amid the soaring old-growth forest. Drawing inspiration from Kinsey, Mensch wanted to produce a visual essay of a place and its community across an extended period of time. Only by immersing herself in the activity of the waterfront could she begin to understand its depth.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Once she&#39;d gained access, Mensch found herself talking to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2009/03/02/talk-it-up&quot;>;Damon Runyon&lt;/a>; types with names such as Mombo, Johnny Deadman, and Mikey the Watchman in joints like the Paris Bar, Dirty Ernie&#39;s, and Sloppy Louie&#39;s, the restaurant that Joseph Mitchell made famous in a 1952 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/1952/06/28/the-cave-joseph-mitchell&quot;>;Profile&lt;/a>;, in this magazine, of its proprietor. Mensch&#39;s bewitching portraits of individual salesmen and unloaders are of a piece with Mitchell&#39;s sympathetic character studies—tonal representations of personalities that are inseparable from their environs.&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Mensch was in the streets until seven in the morning, when white-collar workers headed to Lower Manhattan&#39;s financial institutions. A photograph from 1983 shows the cultural clash that occurred in these early hours, as the rest of the city came alive. The nineteenth century is just visible in the background, walled off by plywood fencing: the masts of the South Street Seaport Museum&#39;s tall ships rise like barren pines, and iron-and-brick waterfront warehouses appear crisp and silvery in the bright early light. In the foreground, a clean-cut man with a briefcase strides across the potholed asphalt. The shutter can&#39;t keep up with his brisk motion, and his form blurs at the edges.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A man in a suit walking by a construction site.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb89fb4ab1471471273/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-11.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb89fb4ab1471471273/master/w_120,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-11.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb89fb4ab1471471273/master/w_240,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-11.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb89fb4ab1471471273/master/w_320,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-11.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb89fb4ab1471471273/master/w_640,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-11.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb89fb4ab1471471273/master/w_960,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-11.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb89fb4ab1471471273/master/w_1280,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-11.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb89fb4ab1471471273/master/w_1600,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-11.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Near Pearl Street, 1983.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GroupCalloutWrapper&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A pile of cobblestones.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7bec0ec46cd34764a/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-10.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7bec0ec46cd34764a/master/w_120,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-10.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7bec0ec46cd34764a/master/w_240,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-10.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7bec0ec46cd34764a/master/w_320,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-10.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7bec0ec46cd34764a/master/w_640,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-10.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7bec0ec46cd34764a/master/w_960,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-10.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7bec0ec46cd34764a/master/w_1280,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-10.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb7bec0ec46cd34764a/master/w_1600,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-10.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Cobblestones from the nineteenth century, appropriated for a revitalization plan, 1983.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A locker room.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb54de28b11496af9b/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-18.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb54de28b11496af9b/master/w_120,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-18.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb54de28b11496af9b/master/w_240,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-18.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb54de28b11496af9b/master/w_320,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-18.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb54de28b11496af9b/master/w_640,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-18.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb54de28b11496af9b/master/w_960,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-18.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb54de28b11496af9b/master/w_1280,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-18.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174ebb54de28b11496af9b/master/w_1600,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-18.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Upstairs locker room above Carmine&#39;s Bar &amp;amp; Grill, 1982.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A man standing in a fogfilled street.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb9bec0ec46cd34764c/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-16.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb9bec0ec46cd34764c/master/w_120,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-16.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb9bec0ec46cd34764c/master/w_240,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-16.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb9bec0ec46cd34764c/master/w_320,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-16.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb9bec0ec46cd34764c/master/w_640,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-16.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb9bec0ec46cd34764c/master/w_960,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-16.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb9bec0ec46cd34764c/master/w_1280,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-16.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb9bec0ec46cd34764c/master/w_1600,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-16.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Schermerhorn Row, 1999.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;With the Brooklyn Bridge acting as a bulwark, this slice of New York was tucked away from the rest of the city. But modernity couldn&#39;t be kept at bay. Mensch&#39;s photographs of men weighing fish, hauling bags of mussels, and pulling wooden barrows filled with ice are interspersed with shots of the destruction of Beekman Dock and of mounds of century-old cobblestones ripped up to be repurposed in so-called revitalization plans. This era in the book is punctuated by a grim sequence of photographs. In 1982, Mensch captured a handwritten sign in the locker room over Carmine&#39;s Bar &amp;amp; Grill, on Beekman Street, that reads “&lt;em >;FUCK THE CORPORATION&lt;/em>;.” “That&#39;s the story,” she told me. “They knew what was coming.” On the following spread, two crowded images from 1985 mark the opening of a commercial complex on the new Pier 17—throngs of shoppers and sightseers eager to visit the seaport mall.&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Mensch catalogues the spasmodic conversion of lower Manhattan during the next decade. An ornamented Victorian clock gathers dust on Duane Street, and an obliterating fog envelops a security guard along Schermerhorn Row. Floods, demolition, and arson clear the way for glass-and-concrete condominiums and chauffeured limousines. The ultimate destruction comes on September 11, 2001, an event that Mensch documented as it was happening. Her captions throughout the book give only minimal information, but occasionally her grief becomes visible, as when she writes, of the intersection of Maiden Lane and Fletcher Alley, in 2003, “Centuries ago, a babbling brook ran through here; today this location is the site of a new luxury tower.”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A man standing in an alley.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb53d7db55fbbeb5120/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-04.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb53d7db55fbbeb5120/master/w_120,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-04.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb53d7db55fbbeb5120/master/w_240,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-04.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb53d7db55fbbeb5120/master/w_320,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-04.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb53d7db55fbbeb5120/master/w_640,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-04.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb53d7db55fbbeb5120/master/w_960,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-04.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb53d7db55fbbeb5120/master/w_1280,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-04.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb53d7db55fbbeb5120/master/w_1600,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-04.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;Maiden Lane and Fletcher Alley, 2003.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;In 2005, she photographed the market&#39;s last hours at its two-century-old lower-Manhattan location. In one photograph, a thin coating of snow and a handful of lights in the deserted market building brighten the center of the image, a beacon in the November night. In the background, the dark form of the Brooklyn Bridge disappears behind the market, but the necklace lights along the bridge&#39;s cables appear to fasten onto the building&#39;s second story, a link across the few blocks between them. The photograph becomes an intimate portrait of two landmarks that grew up in the city together, intertwined.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;One of Mensch&#39;s photographs from 2020, when the city tore down both the Tin Building and the New Market Building, illustrates the cross-hatching of historical periods characteristic of New York. The rigging used to demolish the New Market Building presses up against the picture plane so that it appears magnified, a monumental array of intersecting lines and forms resembling a David Smith sculpture. Behind it, the radiating suspension cables of the Brooklyn Bridge are a delicate web hovering roof-like over low-lying buildings and a sloping stretch of the FDR Farther in the distance, competing in scale with the bridge&#39;s west tower, is a rippling glass skyscraper, derisively called the cheese grater, which opened in 2019.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;What is lost and what is gained in such transformations? Mensch doesn&#39;t address the question directly, but it&#39;s not hard to see what sort of answer she might give. The book&#39;s final photographs, from the past couple of years, depict several new high-rises that seem indifferent to the people below—people perhaps unmoored by a city that no longer affords the familiarity of distinct neighborhoods. Mensch includes a vista of the cheese grater, here cutting a lonely path into the sky far above more modest buildings, jutting upward from the city like the handle of a sledgehammer.&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;GenericCallout&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;A landscape view of lower Manhattan.&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb563c2b80b2ce46713/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-01.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb563c2b80b2ce46713/master/w_120,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-01.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb563c2b80b2ce46713/master/w_240,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-01.jpg 240w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb563c2b80b2ce46713/master/w_320,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-01.jpg 320w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb563c2b80b2ce46713/master/w_640,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-01.jpg 640w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb563c2b80b2ce46713/master/w_960,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-01.jpg 960w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb563c2b80b2ce46713/master/w_1280,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-01.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65174eb563c2b80b2ce46713/master/w_1600,c_limit/Ruddick-Mensch-01.jpg 1600w&quot; sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;The east side of lower Manhattan, 2020.&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 19:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[What to See in the New York Film Festival’s First Week]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-front-row/what-to-see-in-the-2023-new-york-film-festivals-first-week]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-30T00:31:10.032Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65171b95d5d8efe5ebe5bf97/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/brody-nyff-evil%20does%20not%20exist.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article- body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height =&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot; M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H 20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/ span>;&lt;span >;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >; &lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存这个故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot; >;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid =&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;纽约电影节于周五开始。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-front-row/third-highlights-from-the-first-week-of-the-2022-new-york-film-festival&quot;>;正如我去年指出的，电影节的主要片单越来越多地转向好莱坞大人物的电影。 （今年的开幕之夜带来了托德·海恩斯的《五月十二月》，由娜塔莉·波特曼和朱丽安·摩尔主演。）所以，现在，我将重点关注独立和国际电影制片人的电影，他们的名字尚未为大多数观众所熟知，但他们的作品值得（并且需要）节日展示带来的认真关注。 （放映的最佳影片之一，《所有土路的盐味》，是雷文·杰克逊的首部故事片，今年在圣丹斯电影节首映；&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the- front-row/the-two-best-films-i-saw-at-sundance&quot;>;我当时就写过它&lt;/a>;，并且会在更接近其&lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https:/ /a24films.com/films/all-dirt-roads&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://a24films.com/films/all- dirty-roads&quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://a24films.com/films/all-dirt-roads&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;11 月 3 日院线上映&lt;/a>;。）&lt;/p >;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;滨口龙介的&lt;/strong>;最新电影&lt;strong>;《邪恶不存在》&lt;/strong>;（10 月 5 日、10 月 7 日和 10 月 11 日）都是一部伟大的电影本身以及对电影制片人之前杰作的回顾性阐释——“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/richard-brody/a- Five-hour-japanese-film-captures-the-agonizing-intimacies -of-daily-life&quot;>;欢乐时光&lt;/a>;，从 2015 年开始，以及“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-front-row/drive-my-car-评论-a-murakami-adaptation-about-sex-lies-and art&quot;>;驾驶我的车&lt;/a>;”，该片赢得了 2022 年奥斯卡最佳国际影片奖。在这部新电影中，滨口大胆地以电影戏剧的方式影片以一长串图像开始，这些图像并没有讲述太多故事，让观众不断猜测。开场场景发生在白雪皑皑的森林中，摄影机似乎从树顶坠落到地面。然而，人们逐渐清楚，森林是从地面观看的——相机固定地向上看，同时不断向前移动，这是步行者无法做到的。不过，有一个步行者：一个女孩正在穿过树林，最终伴随着电锯的声音。接下来的场景可以被认为是绝对毫无意义的，也可以被认为是绝对崇高的，这种二分法被证明是电影的道德核心。一名男子用电锯将长木头锯成较短的木块。然后，他将每一块立在宽树桩的光滑表面上，用斧头将其劈开，然后继续处理下一块。这一切都是在一个长镜头中完成的，在镜头的最后，这个男人有一堆整齐的柴火。他退后一步，点了一支烟，沉思了一下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果这部电影完全由这样的序列组成，我就会置身于一个平静的、类似纪录片的观察的电影天堂。但有一个故事——尽管滨口在进一步的专注观察序列中逐渐展开了这个故事——这个故事使这种观察成为其重点。另一名男子也加入其中，他们从附近一条小溪中取水装满塑料水箱，然后将水箱装入汽车中。卫生官员或科学家采集样本？不：樵夫拓海（大美香仁，首次担任职业演员，曾担任滨口的副导演）正在帮对方取水，以便在对方和对方妻子经营的一家餐馆里做面条。 （拓海还向餐厅提供了他采摘的当地特产野生芥末叶——这个简短的场景提供了另一种形式的审美诱惑，与电影的视觉效果相呼应。）送水后，拓海开车去了附近的一家餐馆。去学校接他的小女儿花（西川亮饰），但她已经离开了。他追上她，带她在树林里散步，向她指出事情并分享他关于植物和动物的知识。最终，滨口耐心地建立了这种错综复杂、根深蒂固的乡村生活唤起，引入了一个威胁其存在的因素——一位计划在该地区开设豪华露营度假村的商人的两名代表的到来。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;浜口也是剧本的编剧，他与《驾驶我的车》的配乐作曲家石桥英子一起构思了这部电影，石桥英子住在电影发生地的村庄附近。与滨口之前的杰作一样，该剧的重点是对话。看着他对一次漫长的村庄会议的精心细致的描述，包括拓海和餐馆老板一家在内的居民与代表们对峙，我觉得这个场景仿佛取自弗雷德里克·怀斯曼的一部纪录片，他经常对机构和社区进行分析通过如此广泛的民主辩论而出现。但这里的对话与滨口其他电影的对话有一个微妙的区别：通常，对话会引发戏剧性；而通常情况下，对话会引发戏剧性。在这里，它具体化了电影背后的纪录片元素中潜藏的戏剧性。精心设计的对话场景——最令人难忘的场景之一，主要以一个紧张的长镜头拍摄，聆听两位代表在车里进行广泛的忏悔讨论——散发着一种精神光环，既反映了乡村的自然风光，也反映了拓海的精神光环。自己的准神秘权威。审美领域（无论是视觉美感还是品格高贵）与追求实用性和实用性、工业发展和专业地位的现代化动力的内在对立，决定了情节的利害关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div >;&lt;p>;在《邪恶不存在》中，滨口的戏剧结构和视觉风格比他之前的电影更加大胆和独特，但这一次，他无法完全坚持着陆。没有剧透，但结局既模糊又突然，暗示了范围问题。 《欢乐时光》长达五个小时，《驾驶我的车》将近三个小时，它们的长度自然符合其辩证复杂性的渐进节奏；相比之下，《邪恶不存在》只有一百零六分钟，这种相对简短的感觉就像是人为的截断。结局掩盖了一个缺失的——或者说无法想象的——额外的一个小时，这个小时将遵循电影中大量密切观察的细节及其逻辑结果。但这几乎无关紧要；导致快速结束的满足感是如此独特和强烈，以至于他们几乎可以为电影赢得未完成杰作的不寻常地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;仍然来自电影《水中》。&quot; src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65171b9a16b6e0afb263d1bd/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/brody-nyff-in%2520water.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65171b9a16b6e0afb263d1bd/ master/w_120,c_limit/brody-nyff-in%20water.jpg 120w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65171b9a16b6e0afb263d1bd/master/w_240,c_limit/brody-nyff-in%20water.jpg 240w, https: //media.newyorker.com/photos/65171b9a16b6e0afb263d1bd/master/w_320,c_limit/brody-nyff-in%20water.jpg 320w，https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65171b9a16b6e0afb263d1bd/master/w_640,c_limit/brody -nyff-in%20water.jpg 640w，https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65171b9a16b6e0afb263d1bd/master/w_960,c_limit/brody-nyff-in%20water.jpg 960w，https://media.newyorker.com /photos/65171b9a16b6e0afb263d1bd/master/w_1280,c_limit/brody-nyff-in%20water.jpg 1280w，https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65171b9a16b6e0afb263d1bd/master/w_1600,c_limit/brody-nyff-in%20水。 jpg 1600w&quot; Sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span>;照片由电影协会提供&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed >;&lt;p>;对图像与对话关系的大胆处理也是&lt;strong>;《在水中》&lt;/strong>;的一大标志（10月17日） 1 月 1 日和 10 月 2 日），这是一部由多产的韩国电影制片人洪尚秀制作的精彩原创电影。 （这是他为电影节带来的两部新作品之一。）与洪的大部分作品一样，《在水中》围绕首尔的电影业及其独立外围地区展开，其主角是一位名叫 Seoung-mo 的年轻导演兼演员（申锡浩）所面临的危机反映了洪自身实践的要求。 Seoung-mo 自掏腰包与一位女演员（金承润饰）和一位前导演（河成国饰）在一个海边小镇待了一周，目的是制作（并主演）一整部影片。本周拍摄短片。他带着一个关于女演员的故事的总体想法到达，但对此失去了信心。当三人在岩石海滩上漫步时，他看到一名女子捡起游客留下的垃圾，并根据这个人的想法即兴创作了一个场景。 Seoung-mo 和另外两名参与者之间有一些个人背景故事，而且他也有一场浪漫的戏剧在旁边发生——所有这些不仅为角色关于受挫的野心的蜿蜒讨论，甚至为看似简单的事情增添了情感层次。关于食物和住宿的决定。与洪的大多数电影一样，大部分对话都是以静态的长镜头展开，但构图犀利、表演敏感，充满了生活和戏剧性。但洪还添加了一种滑稽和大胆的扭曲，使许多图像稍微失焦，模糊了细节，但没有模糊人物。这具有使对话更加突出的奇怪效果，就好像它被刻在屏幕上一样。洪利用这种比喻来增强人物对话的情感影响，创作了一部构思大胆的电影，结局充满激情，年轻电影制片人的艺术和个人烦恼与电影形式相结合，达到一种严峻而暧昧的兴奋。&lt;/ p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;图片 >;&lt;img alt=&quot;仍然来自电影《做某事的时间已经过去的感觉》 src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65171ba2d324cac0c81eac30/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/brody-nyff-feeling%2520that%2520the %2520time.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65171ba2d324cac0c81eac30/master/w_120,c_limit/brody-nyff-feeling%20that%20the%20time.jpg 120w，https://media.newyorker .com/photos/65171ba2d324cac0c81eac30/master/w_240,c_limit/brody-nyff-feeling%20that%20the%20time.jpg 240w，https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65171ba2d324cac0c81eac30/master/w_320,c_limit/brody- nyff-feeling%20that%20the%20time.jpg 320w，https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65171ba2d324cac0c81eac30/master/w_640,c_limit/brody-nyff-feeling%20that%20the%20time.jpg 640w，https： //media.newyorker.com/photos/65171ba2d324cac0c81eac30/master/w_960,c_limit/brody-nyff-feeling%20that%20the%20time.jpg 960w，https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65171ba2d324cac0c81eac30/master/w_1280 ，c_limit/brody-nyff-feeling%20that%20the%20time.jpg 1280w，https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65171ba2d324cac0c81eac30/master/w_1600，c_limit/brody-nyff-feeling%20that%20the%20time。 jpg 1600w&quot;sizes=&quot;100vw&quot;/>;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;span>;摄影：Barton Cortright/Magnolia Pictures 提供&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/ inline-embed>;&lt;p>;对于洪的主人公来说，在自己的画面中表演是一种自我分析的形式，对于居住在布鲁克林的作家兼导演&lt;strong>;乔安娜·阿诺&lt;/strong>;来说也是如此。主演她的忧郁喜剧&lt;strong>;“做某事的时间已经过去的感觉”&lt;/strong>;（10月17日） 5 日和 10 月 7 日）。她扮演安，一位三十多岁的女性，在一个模糊的教育、模糊的技术、极端官僚的公司环境中工作。她与父母（由阿诺自己的父母扮演）之间的关系既紧张又令人窒息，他们都是老派的左撇子，有时很真诚，有时又明显地吹毛求疵。她还与一个名叫艾伦（斯科特·科恩饰）的男人发生了令人毛骨悚然的毫无浪漫的性关系，她寻求被他支配和羞辱。电影的中心是安寻求一种相互尊重的浪漫关系，这种关系也可以提供她从服从中获得的性快感。一路走来，安时而受到压制，时而被过度压制（比如一个男人堵住了她的嘴，把她打扮成他所谓的“操猪”）；她的工作不令人满意，她的朋友不理解，她生活的各个部分都没有重叠。阿诺笔下的安和其他人物既坦率又小心谨慎，言语娴熟又简洁——在坦白中含糊其辞，在回避中也坦白坦白。表演也表现出克制的坦率，产生了不自觉的表现力，阿诺（他也是一名电影摄影师，尽管不是这部电影的）将这些与微妙的对抗性构图相匹配；安经常赤身裸体，阿诺的图像坦率而朴素地描绘了角色的脆弱甚至羞辱，没有添加任何内容，也没有分享安所谓的主人的主导视角。电影中的场景通常是片段式的停电草图，将痛苦和热情浓缩成快速抓住它们的泡沫。结果是一部独特而辛酸的电影，它提供了证据表明优雅的状态可能远非优雅。&lt;/p>;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;feature-default&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;image&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:feature-default&quot;>;&lt;figure >;&lt;div >;&lt;span >;&lt;picture >;&lt;img alt=&quot;仍然来自电影《虚假战争》的预告片&quot; src=&quot;https://media .newyorker.com/photos/65172854d5d8efe5ebe5c06d/master/w_1600%2Cc_limit/brody-nyff-phony%2520wars.jpg&quot; srcSet=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65172854d5d8efe5ebe5c06d/master/w_120,c_limit/布罗迪- nyff-phony%20wars.jpg 120w，https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65172854d5d8efe5ebe5c06d/master/w_240,c_limit/brody-nyff-phony%20wars.jpg 240w，https://media.newyorker.com/照片/65172854D55EBE5C06D/MASTER/W_320，C_LIMIT/BRODY-NYFF-PHONY％20Wars.jpg 320W，https://media.newyorker.com/photos/photos/photos/65172854d8emby-limryfory fllody yllyfory flloydy/140 _6d406dbrody ％20wars.jpg 640w，https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65172854d5d8efe5ebe5c06d/master/w_960，c_limit/brody-nyff-phony%20wars.jpg 960w，https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65172854d5d8efe5ebe5c06d/master/w_1280 ,c_limit/brody-nyff-phony%20wars.jpg 1280w, https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65172854d5d8efe5ebe5c06d/master/w_1600,c_limit/brody-nyff-phony%20wars.jpg 1600w&quot; 尺寸 = &quot;100vw&quot; />;&lt;/picture>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;span>;照片由 Kino Lorber 提供&lt;/span>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Jean-吕克·戈达尔于 2022 年 9 月去世，享年 91 岁。在生命的最后几年，他正在改编法国作家查尔斯·普利斯尼尔 (Charles Plisnier) 1937 年的小说《假护照》，并传达了他的作品材料——故事板式的拼贴画、一些实景镜头和音频剪辑——交给他的助手法布里斯·阿拉尼奥 (Fabrice Aragno)，并明确指示他们进行编辑。结果就是这部 19 分钟的电影&lt;strong>;“一部永远不存在的电影的预告片：假战争”&lt;/strong>;（10 月 2 日至 4 日），它像是对戈达尔最后几十年作品的提炼和阐释。 。正如戈达尔在画外音中所说，在小说中，被共产党开除的托洛茨基主义者普利斯尼尔“描绘了一幅他在 1920 年左右认识的当代活动家的肖像，无论是想象的还是真实的。”戈达尔提到，这部小说让他想要将自己最近的、支离破碎的风格与更古典的东西结合起来，就像让-皮埃尔·梅尔维尔的第一部故事片一样，“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/goings- on-about-town/movies/silence-sea&quot;>;大海的寂静&lt;/a>;”（1949），一部关于法国乡村家庭和与他们同住的纳粹德国军官之间互动的戏剧。但他的电影更具暗示性和推测性——视觉和声音的拼贴勾勒出广泛的历史思考。里面有图像和文字片段（一张年轻女子的彩色照片粘贴在普利斯尼尔书的一个段落的复印件上，人物的黑白照片似乎是一个世纪前的），还有戈达尔后来的一些作品的音乐和声音片段电影（包括“我们的音乐”和“电影社会主义”）。参考文献包括左翼内部的自相残杀冲突，尤其是在西班牙内战期间；法国在阿尔及利亚战争中的行动以及由此引发的法国左派反战运动；第二次世界大战和大屠杀；汉娜·阿伦特和巴勒斯坦；波斯尼亚战争和俄罗斯对乌克兰的持续攻击。晚年的戈达尔开始痴迷于历史。他不完全是一个阴谋理论家，但他无疑是一个阴谋理论家，他看到了贯穿电影本身历史的地下模式和联系，从而证明了电影视觉的巨大生产力。新电影中的一段引用维斯瓦瓦·辛波斯卡（Wisława Szymborska）的银幕文字写道：“最短暂的时刻也拥有辉煌的过去”；因此，戈达尔后来的作品就像考古学一样，探索了潜伏在他拍摄的瞬间中的社会和艺术过去的强大图像库。这段“预告片”既反映了他对现存图像（包括他自己的图像）的强大重新处理，以将档案和个人记忆结合起来，也反映了他以自己的形象创造新古典电影的强烈愿望。 ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;21w0o&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; >;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;y0bde&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt; div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ side>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live= “礼貌” aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/文章>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 09:06:01 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Remembering Dianne Feinstein, and Biden Clashes with the Hard Right]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/podcast/political-scene/remembering-dianne-feinstein-and-biden-clashes-with-the-hard-right]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29T23:53:33.367Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/63755311573147b2b8a3132b/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/The%20Political%20Scene%20B%20Glasser%20Mayer%20Osnos%20From%20Washington.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso -pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width= &quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;标题>;保存&lt;/标题>;&lt;路径d =&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>; &lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存&lt;/标题>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径 d =&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;保存&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt; div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;figure data-testid=&quot;IframeEmbed&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;IframeEmbedContainer&quot; >;&lt; div >;&lt;iframe height=&quot;120&quot; width=&quot;100&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-scripts allowed-same-origin&quot; title=&quot;嵌入式框架&quot; data-src=&quot;https://www.wnyc.org/widgets/ondemand_player /thenewyorker/?share=1#file=/audio/json/1368337&quot;allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;allow=&quot;自动播放*;加密媒体*；剪贴板写入；自动播放;全屏;画中画&quot;>;&lt;/iframe>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;收听并订阅：&lt;/em>; &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https:// pod.link/EAxjj.apple?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;元素&quot;:&quot;外部链接&quot; ”,“传出URL”:“https://pod .link/EAxjj.apple?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.apple?pdst_键=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot;rel= “nofollow noopener” target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Apple&lt;/a>; | &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.spotify?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst _label=bj0vajYd”数据-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.spotify?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34ad f2&amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.spotify?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank &quot;>;Spotify&lt;/a>; | &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj.google?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp; ”:“外部链接” ,“outgoingURL”:“https://pod.link/EAxjj.google?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd”href =“https://pod.link/EAxjj.google?pdst_key =df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Google&lt;/a>; | &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://pod.link/EAxjj?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot; :“外部链接”,” ;outgoingURL”：“https://pod.link/EAxjj?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;pdst_label=bj0vajYd”}&quot; href=&quot;https://pod.链接/EAxjj?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=83a946fcfb264355b29c24a0dd34adf2&amp;amp; ;pdst_label=bj0vajYd&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;无论您在哪里收听&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt; /div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/newsletter/news-politics&quot;>;&lt;em>;注册&lt;/ em>;&lt;/a>; &lt;em>;接收我们每周两次的新闻和新闻政治通讯。&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;p>;华盛顿圆桌会议：美国历史上任职时间最长的女参议员黛安·范斯坦于周四去世，享年九十岁。 《纽约客》特约撰稿人 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/susan-b-glasser&quot;>;Susan B. Glasser&lt;/a>;、&lt;a href=&quot; https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/jane-mayer&quot;>;简·梅尔&lt;/a>;和&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/contributors/evan-osnos&quot;>;埃文·奥斯诺斯&lt; /a>; 请记住这位来自旧金山的民主党人，他在 9/11 事件后留下了枪支管制和反对酷刑被拘留者的倡导者的遗产。梅耶尔在本周的节目中回忆道，尽管她担心批评该计划对国家安全的影响，但她还是努力争取发布有关中央情报局审讯计划的六千七百页报告。 “但她凭着自己的直觉去做了，”梅耶尔说，“然后委托进行了一项研究，以令人难以置信的方式展示了该计划的实质内容。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同样在本周，拜登总统在亚利桑那州立大学发表演讲时，称共和党人“对我们民主制度的实体构成威胁”，对“我们国家的性格”构成威胁。 “我认为我从未听过一位总统觉得有必要在演讲中说，‘我支持和平权力移交，’”奥斯诺斯说。 “但这实际上是目前所需要的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid =&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;nrtiqj&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role= “演示” aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;y9bb&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true &quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>; &lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt; div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 08:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[The Powerful New York Law That Finally Brought Trump to Book]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/news/our-columnists/the-powerful-new-york-law-that-finally-brought-trump-to-book]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29T20:45:14.659Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6516e4b454de28b11496af04/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/Cassidy-Trump-NYC-Assets.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt; div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12. 5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4 H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存此故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt; svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/标题>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径 d =&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;在纽约法院裁定唐纳德·特朗普通过夸大其价格而持续犯有欺诈行为后前总统称发布该裁决的法官阿瑟·F·恩戈伦(Arthur F. Engoron)“精神错乱”，并指责提起此案的纽约总检察长利蒂西亚·詹姆斯(Letitia James)是种族主义者。&lt;/p>;&lt;鉴于这一判决可能会禁止特朗普在纽约做生意，并迫使他放弃对该州一些珍贵商业资产的控制权——包括特朗普大厦和华尔街 40 号——他的愤怒也就不足为奇了。但至少他的部分愤怒应该针对一位已去世 35 年多的共和党同胞：雅各布·贾维茨 (Jacob Javits)，他现在因以他的名字命名的会议中心而闻名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从 1957 年到1971年，贾维茨担任纽约州参议员，但在此之前他担任的职位目前由詹姆斯担任。作为纽约总检察长，他赢得了愿意与强大利益集团较量的自由派检察官的声誉。 1956 年，即他任职的最后一年，他敦促州立法机构通过一项新法律，赋予他的办公室权力，对那些“屡次从事欺诈或非法行为或以其他方式表现出持续欺诈或非法行为的企业”进行调查并采取行动。业务的进行、进行或交易。”总检察长办公室援引纽约行政法第 63(12) 条这一广泛法规，提起了多项诉讼，从指控三家公交公司违反纽约市关于怠速的规定，到指控埃克森美孚在气候带来的商业风险方面误导投资者。改变。 “该法规赋予总检察长追究她或他认为具有欺诈性的任何行为的权力，”Stroock &amp; Co. 律师杰里·H·戈德费德 (Jerry H. Goldfeder) 说。斯特洛克安德鲁·科莫担任纽约总检察长时担任公共诚信特别顾问的拉万律师事务所 (Lavan LLP) 告诉我。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在 2018 年当选之前，詹姆斯称特朗普为“骗子”，并承诺“将一盏明灯照进他房地产交易的每一个黑暗角落”。上任后，她对特朗普的业务展开了调查，去年9月针对唐纳德·特朗普的诉讼&quot;>;她根据《行政法》第 63(12) 条对特朗普、他的三个最大的孩子、他的两名雇员以及他的一些公司提起民事诉讼，其中她声称特朗普在向银行和保险公司等交易对手提交的财务报表中虚报了他的许多资产（包括他的建筑物、高尔夫球场和特朗普大厦顶层公寓）的价值数十亿美元。&lt;/p >;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;特朗普的律师试图让案件被驳回，理由是诉讼时效已过，詹姆斯没有资格提起诉讼，因为特朗普向其发送估值报表的金融机构从未提出投诉或遭受任何损失。特朗普在证词中声称，这些估值声明“一文不值”，而且每个人都知道这一点，因为它们附有一份限定声明，该声明称，如果将其资产投放市场，他的资产不一定能达到列出的估值。 p>;&lt;p>;恩戈隆在周二公布的长达三十五页的判决书中驳斥了这些论点。他指出，第63（12）条并没有要求政府证明造成经济损失或被告的行为意图欺诈。持续提交夸大的财务报表本身就满足了该法对欺诈的定义，并且包含模糊的、不可执行的免责声明“不能用于隔离被告所了解的特定事实的欺诈行为，即使是针对经验丰富的接收者，”恩戈龙&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;在此基础上，恩戈隆拒绝了特朗普团队驳回此案的请求，并批准了司法部长关于部分简易判决的动议——一项未经全面审判而做出的决定——根据第 63(12) 条，特朗普和其他被告应对欺诈行为负责。恩戈隆写道，特朗普的文件“明显包含被告在商业中使用的欺诈性估值，满足了 OAG 确定被告承担法律责任的责任”。 “被告回应称：文件并没有说明他们所说的内容；不存在“客观”价值这样的东西；从本质上讲，法院不应该相信自己的眼睛。”&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Engoron 继续指出，即使尽管他去年任命了一名独立监察员来监督特朗普的业务，但“被告在开展业务时继续传播虚假和误导性信息。”他批准了詹姆斯取消特朗普在纽约的部分营业执照的请求，并表示他将任命另一名独立监察员来监督特朗普的业务，并可能监督这些业务的出售或解散。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这样看来，特朗普长期以来因其可疑商业交易而逃避法律责任的能力已经结束，他在纽约的公司业务也可能因此结束。 （在周三的进一步听证会上，恩戈隆告诉特朗普的律师，他还没有准备好就特朗普企业到底会发生什么做出裁决。）特朗普的律师表示，他们将对裁决提出上诉，但目前这位前总统已被打上了烙印。一个不适合在他长大和生活了七十多年的州做生意的诈骗犯。 （他现在是佛罗里达州居民。）&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;恩戈隆的裁决决定了本案的核心问题：特朗普及其公司是否存在欺诈行为。詹姆斯的其余行为将于周一开始审判，其中包括保险欺诈指控，并可能导致经济处罚。 （周四，上诉法院驳回了特朗普律师推迟审判的努力。）&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最引人注目的部分，也是这一切的真正丑闻，是数十年来它在商界广为人知。和新闻界认为特朗普经常夸大其资产的价值。当商业记者 Timothy L. O&#39;Brien 在 &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/TrumpNation-Donald-Timothy-L-OBrien/dp/044669617X&quot; data-event 中写下此内容时-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;outgoingURL&quot;:&quot;https://www.amazon.com/TrumpNation-Donald-Timothy-L-OBrien/dp/044669617X&quot;}&quot; href= “https://www.amazon.com/TrumpNation-Donald-Timothy-L-OBrien/dp/044669617X” rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;2005 年特朗普职业生涯的账户&lt;/a>;，特朗普起诉 O &#39;布莱恩并在法庭上追捕他多年，直到法官驳回诉讼。直到 2019 年，特朗普的一位前助手 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/tag/michael-cohen&quot;>;迈克尔·科恩&lt;/a>; 在国会提出了同样的主张证词表明检察官对此感兴趣。前曼哈顿地区检察官小赛勒斯·万斯 (Cyrus Vance, Jr.) 的调查人员基于詹姆斯在提起民事案件时使用的大部分相同证据，相信他们已经针对特朗普立案了一个可以获胜的刑事案件。但万斯的继任者阿尔文·布拉格决定停止调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当然，今天特朗普在四个不同的法院面临着无数的刑事指控——总共九十一个，其中包括&lt;a href=&quot; https://www.newyorker.com/news/daily-comment/alvin-bragg-donald-trump-and-the-pursuit-of-low-level-crimes&quot;>;布拉格办公室的三十四项罪名&lt;/a>; 2016 年，特朗普向成人电影明星斯托米·丹尼尔斯 (Stormy Daniels) 行贿所引发的案件。然而，事实证明，由于雅各布·贾维茨 (Jacob Javits)，长期以来一直有一项法律旨在将特朗普这样的骗子绳之以法。预订，至少在民事意义上是这样。为什么之前没有人用过呢？这是一个好问题。但是，终于有人做到了，而且迄今为止的结果令人震惊。 ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;fsofyj&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot; >;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;5qc6lr&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt; div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/ side>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live= “礼貌” aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt; /div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/文章>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 05:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Olivia Rodrigo on the Meanings of “Guts”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/culture/the-new-yorker-interview/olivia-rodrigo-on-the-meanings-of-guts]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29T19:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/65148c0fb43cd9cd22fd8697/16:9/ w_1280,c_limit/NYRH-Olivia-Rodrigo.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >; &lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;书签&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox= &quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312 L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4 H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存这个故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;保存这个故事&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width =&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;保存此故事&lt;/title>; &lt;路径 d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt;路径 d=&quot;M 23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/路径>;&lt; /svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span>;保存此故事&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt; div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;奥利维亚·罗德里戈 (Olivia Rodrigo) 可以说是汽车史上最著名的驾驶执照的拥有者。 &lt;em>;新冠病毒&lt;/em>;在她刚满十七岁的时候席卷了世界。罗德里戈是一名加州孩子，是一名在家接受教育的儿童演员，也是一名教师和家庭治疗师的女儿，她一直坚持自己的歌曲创作，直到一年后，她制作了《驾驶执照》。这首歌以其直接、深情的方式表达了分手后的孤独、愤怒和解放，很快就在 Spotify 上引起了轰动，一周内的播放量达到了 8000 万次。当疫情缓和，罗德里戈开始在公共场合表演时，她有了斯威夫特式的经历，看到数以万计的歌迷唱着她首张专辑中的歌词，“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/” 2021/06/07/how-olivia-rodrigo-became-pops-brightest-new-star&quot;>;Sour&lt;/a>;”，和她一起——一夜成名，即使在流行音乐界也是罕见的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;罗德里戈与制作人和词曲作者丹·尼格罗合作，现在已经二十岁了，并且推出了另一张单音节专辑，名为“&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com” /culture/listening-booth/olivia-rodrigos-star-making-guts&quot;>;胆量&lt;/a>;。”专辑中最受欢迎的单曲是“Vampire”，它也点亮了排行榜。这是一首愤怒的歌曲，针对的是“吸血鬼，名利混蛋，/像一个该死的吸血鬼一样让我流血”。贾·托伦蒂诺 (Jia Tolentino) 为《Vogue》&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vogue.com/article/olivia-rodrigo-august-cover-2023-interview&quot;>;封面故事&lt;/a>;拍摄&lt;em>;Vogue&lt;/em>; ，准确地理解了罗德里戈的音乐，写道：“她并没有生活在泡泡糖储物柜门童话故事的领域，也没有积极地宣称自己是前卫和成熟的。她只是捕捉到了二十岁的感觉，在这个年纪，你有时会燃烧着可笑的欲望，为被视为美丽而兴奋，为别人的期望而愤怒。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;罗德里戈的音乐知识是深入，她的英雄遍布地图：&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2023/05/22/carole-king-on-capitol-hill&quot;>;卡罗尔·金&lt;/a >;、&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/culture-desk/long-live-the-greatest-hits-album&quot;>;白色条纹&lt;/a>;、&lt;a href=&quot;https ://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2020/03/23/fiona-apples-art-of-radical-sensitivity&quot;>;菲奥娜·苹果&lt;/a>;，艾拉妮丝·莫莉塞特，洛德，&lt;a href=&quot;https:// /www.newyorker.com/sports/sporting-scene/kelce-swift-is-a-dream-pairing-for-the-nfl&quot;>;泰勒·斯威夫特&lt;/a>;，圣文森特。她从小就在迪士尼电视节目《Bizaardvark》和《歌舞青春：音乐剧：系列》中扮演主角，在舞台和媒体采访方面有着非同寻常的未经训练的指挥能力。我们最近在 Zoom 上花了一个小时讨论 &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://link.chtbl.com/qOucM248&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&quot;element&quot;:&quot;ExternalLink&quot;,&quot;出站URL“：”https://link.chtbl.com/qOucM248“}”href =“https://link.chtbl.com/qOucM248”rel =“nofollow noopener”target =“_blank”>;纽约客电台小时&lt;/a>;。罗德里戈在她位于曼哈顿的新公寓里加入了我们的谈话，为了篇幅和清晰度，我们对谈话进行了编辑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;你对纽约有点陌生，对吧？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;是的，我是。我几个月前刚刚得到这套公寓。我仍在探索，但我喜欢它；这是有史以来最伟大的城市。这里源源不断地有如此多的灵感。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;所以您已经永远离开了洛杉矶？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline -recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;我不这么认为。我的意思是，我认为洛杉矶永远是我的第一个家，但我喜欢尽可能经常来这里。这是最伟大的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;我不知道，纽约在音乐上是否更适合你？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;是的，我真的认为它是一种奇怪的方式，我记得人们总是告诉我这一点——我认识的词曲作者。他们会说，“哦，你必须去纽约。这太鼓舞人心了。”我会翻白眼，然后说：“好吧，当然，我明白了，我明白了。”但实际上我们在格林威治村的 Electric Lady Studios 制作了这张专辑“Guts”的一半 - &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;所以你和 Jimi Hendrix 在同一个房间录音？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;是的，没错。所有这些令人难以置信的唱片都是在那些房间里制作的，只是——我不知道，你肯定能感受到墙壁里的魔力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;在过去的日子里，&lt;a href =&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/culture/culture-comment/a-close-read-of-the-beatles-in-get-back&quot;>;披头士乐队&lt;/a>;过去常去录音室，并且，三天后，一张唱片就出来了。现在效果如何？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>;&lt;p>;我的意思是，我不能代表所有人，但我花了很长时间来制作这张唱片“Guts”。真正的工作可能花了一年或一年半的时间。当我开始专辑制作过程时，我有很多保留意见。 《Sour》取得了非常出乎意料、非常令人赞赏的成功，接下来的事情面临着巨大的压力。我脑子里有所有这些声音——我认为人们会喜欢的，不想让人们失望。因此，我花了一段时间才到达一个地方，我终于觉得自己可以发挥创造力，并开始写我想在广播中听到的歌曲，这应该始终是您制作任何东西时的首要关注点。&lt; /p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;您是否害怕成为一击奇迹？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;是的，我的意思是，这太疯狂了。它发生在我职业生涯中如此年轻的时候。我发行了这张专辑，并赢得了格莱美奖，当时我十九岁，我当时想，哇，我已经做了很多我想做的事情。我才十九岁。但是，在某种程度上，这也是一种自由。也许这听起来很奇怪，但在上一张专辑周期中完成这些事情真是太好了。我非常感谢当时发生的一切，以及所有打开的大门。但是，在某种程度上，想到“现在我可以为自己创作音乐”也很好。你知道我的意思？我觉得我现在可以做任何事了。&lt;/p>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;你是在迪士尼表演长大的。你曾出演过《Bizaardvark》和《歌舞青春》节目——小时候你就已经在电视界崭露头角。你是否一直怀有成为一名独唱歌手、成为一名词曲作者的野心、渴望和热情？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;完全是。我一直很喜欢写歌。那是我的初恋，我年轻时的第一个激情。我记得四岁左右的时候，我就我四岁的问题创作了所有这些疯狂的歌曲。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;你还记得吗？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;哦，天哪。我妈妈有一段视频，内容是我在超市里唱着失去父母的故事，这对四岁的人来说是一次非常痛苦的经历。我可以想象为什么我会感动地写一首关于它的歌。但是，当我十二岁或十三岁的时候，我开始表演，但我开始在钢琴上弹奏歌曲并学习如何根据和弦写歌曲，从那时起一切就开始起飞了。我爱上了它，从那时起它就成了我的生活。这是这份工作中我最喜欢的部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;你似乎拥有——甚至在你比现在年轻得多的时候——拥有广泛的倾听意识。很多事情都传入了你的耳朵。它们是什么？你为什么要听你正在听的东西？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;是的，我非常信任我的父母对我的音乐品味的认可。我的父母喜欢九十年代的另类摇滚。我是听着《Smashing Pumpkins》、《Hole and the White Stripes》长大的，而且，从很小的时候起，我就爱上了很多女创作歌手。我意识到这就是我想要遵循的血统。我记得大概十三岁的时候，我和妈妈一起去旧货店，第一次买了卡罗尔·金的《Tapestry》，然后就开始玩了。至死。我会一遍又一遍地播放它，并获得所有这些帕特·贝纳塔尔的唱片并一遍又一遍地播放它们，还有乔尼·米切尔，而且，我不知道，我只记得当我很小的时候，有什么东西在我的脑海中响起，就像，哇，这些都是我想效仿的女孩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;回想起来，你写的第一首歌是什么让你觉得，现在，这是&lt;em>;的东西&lt;/em>;。这不只是开玩笑——这可以带我去某个地方？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;我的意思是，我写了我年轻时在客厅里闲逛时唱了很多歌，但我实际上记得写过《驾驶执照》。我记得那种感觉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;这首歌大受欢迎。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我非常感谢那首歌。它以当时我完全无法想象的方式使我的职业生涯飞速发展。但我只记得写下那句话，感觉我真的表达了一些东西。我觉得那首歌里有很多我自己的影子，我记得我的感觉得到了恰当的体现，那是一种非常美丽的感觉。我记得我走进录音室向我的制作人展示这首歌，并逐字对他说：“我想我刚刚写了我写过的最喜欢的歌曲。”他说，“好吧，坐下来玩吧。”&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;o10lzs&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data- testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;说说写作的经历。效果如何？因为我喜欢它的原因之一是它的开始如此直接。它决定了年龄，它决定了心情，它决定了你在第一行的位置。这是怎么发生的？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是非常具体的。我的意思是，在写这首歌的前几天，我确实拿到了驾照，我很喜欢我新发现的自由。所以我开车在我家附近转悠，听着悲伤的歌曲，哭着思考这段关系，然后我就坐在钢琴前——我是一个非常情绪化的女孩，就像现在一样——然后我就在钢琴前哭了。我写了那首歌。我确实相信创造力有时是超越你的。这就像我们作为自负的人类无法控制的魔法。那是我职业生涯和创意生活中非常神奇的时刻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;当您刚拿到驾照时，是什么让您在车里感到如此悲伤？我是泽西岛的孩子；你是加州孩子。一些关于驾驶的事——我不知道那是什么。它释放了一些东西。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;确实如此。当我第一次拿到驾照时，我思考了很多这个问题。我认为开车是你真正独处的唯一时间之一，尤其是作为一个青少年，当你和父母住在家里时。但直到今天我仍然喜欢它。你可以在车里做任何事。你可以听任何你想听的。你可以大声尖叫，没有人会听到你的声音。你的邻居不会敲墙让你闭嘴。我认为也许正是这种孤立感激发了你的这些感受。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;你在《周六夜现场》发行后多久在《周六夜现场》中表演了《驾驶执照》？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;哦，天哪，真的很快。 《周六夜现场》是我的第一场演出之一。我想我发行了那首歌，并在伦敦的全英音乐节和“SNL”上表演，这是我歌手兼作曲家职业生涯中的前两场表演，回想起来，这是相当狂野的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;那是我第一次听说你的时候。我当时正在看《周六夜现场》，今天我又看了一遍录像带。当你即将走上舞台，面对数以百万计的观众时，你脑子里在想什么？你在发抖吗？你感觉怎么样？你脑子里在想什么？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我很害怕。我什至不打算摆出一副样子。我很勇敢。我很害怕。我记得在更衣室里——《周六夜现场》的更衣室是有史以来最酷的地方。墙上挂满了您所有英雄的照片，他们曾与您在同一个舞台上表演过。我刚刚完全崩溃了。我很紧张，很害怕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;崩溃是什么意思？因为你确实在舞台上成功了！&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我确实成功了！我当时正在哭。谢天谢地，我的制作人就在那里，我非常爱和信任他，我向他哭泣。我就像，“我不知道我是否能做到。我不知道我是否能做到。我很害怕。”他就像是，“你明白了。我爱你。你能行的。”所以那一刻他的支持对我来说意义重大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;一旦你张开嘴，音乐开始响起，你会平静下来吗？作为一个人，作为一个在镜头前的人体，知道你所知道的，那感觉如何？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在电视上表演节目和表演歌曲有很大不同。我更喜欢表演节目。我认为你可以进入一种流动状态，并且能量正在被交换。当你在电视上表演时，有时会有点困难，因为只有一两首歌，你必须从一开始就参与其中，这只是一种不同的体验。但我仍在学习和成长，能走到今天我感到很幸运。幸运的是，人们愿意坐在人群中聆听。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;你的第一张专辑让我印象深刻，因为它在某种程度上与大流行时期有联系。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data- attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;是的。实际上，大部分歌曲都是我在大流行期间写的，我将很多歌曲归功于这种隔离，就像我们之前讨论的那样。事实上，我告诉自己，只要大流行持续，我就会每天写一首歌——因为，你知道，我们认为大流行将持续两周。所以我想，我能做到。原来是，就像，永远。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;那是十四首歌！&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;[&lt;em>;笑。&lt;/em>;]是的。但我这样做了大约五六个月，这确实帮助我磨练了我的歌曲创作技巧，并在我的写作中遵守了纪律。另外，我认为人们可能想在大流行期间听到所有那些悲伤的歌曲。我认为，作为一个集体，我们所有人都面临着由于新环境而无法处理的情绪，我们无法分散自己的注意力。所以，是的，我认为大流行绝对是这张专辑的重要组成部分。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;当你写一首歌时，无论悲伤还是不悲伤，其中有多少是直接来自你的灵魂，或者其中有多少有时是一个角色？在我看来，两者都可以。歌曲创作可以做到这两点。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data- node-id=&quot;w9smq&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;是的，我认为两者都可以。我认为这不一定是相互排斥的。我认为我是一个非常多面的人，有时我觉得我想要变得超级讽刺和讽刺，我感到愤怒和恼火。而且，其他时候，我真的很感伤，想写一首吉他民谣。我认为发挥个性的不同方面很有趣，但我总是尽力让它在灵魂层面上显得真诚和真实。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;感觉如何就像，当你站在舞台上，在一大群观众面前，在一大群观众面前唱一首像《驾驶执照》这样的民谣时？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这真的很疯狂。我想这种感觉大概永远不会变老。这就是音乐的力量。你在客厅里用二十分钟写了一首歌，然后一年后你在一万人面前，他们知道每个词。只是——音乐就是这么神奇。它对人类的触动达到了我认为任何其他媒介都无法做到的程度。我非常感激能够为我的工作做到这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;你的心跳加速吗？当你唱“Vampire”之类的歌曲时，你的头顶会飞到人群中吗？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt; >;是的。我的意思是，你知道什么很酷吗？我最喜欢唱的歌曲是真正愤怒的歌曲，尤其是在巡演时。我喜欢在观众席上往外看，有时我会看到这些女孩，她们很年轻，只有七八岁，她们尖叫着这些愤怒的歌曲，变得如此兴奋和愤怒，我只是认为这是有史以来最酷的事情。这不是你在街上看到的东西，但它太酷了，人们可以通过音乐来表达所有这些情感。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;如果你必须想到一个时刻或一个图像，你的上一次巡演深深烙印在你的记忆、你的大脑中，它会是什么？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;格拉斯顿伯里。在格拉斯顿伯里的表演令人难以置信。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;这是英国最大的户外音乐节。&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;是的。这实际上是我参加的第一个音乐节，而且我必须参加。太棒了。这是我玩过的最多的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;有多少人？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哦，我想大概有六万人或类似的东西。想想都觉得很疯狂。那是我职业生涯中非常伟大的时刻。最高法院&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2022/07/04/we-are-not-going-back-to-the-time-before-roe-we-are -going-somewhere-worse&quot;>;在我上台的前一天推翻了罗伊诉韦德案&lt;/a>;，那天我和莉莉·艾伦向最高法院献上了“Fuck You”。我记得我感到非常生气，周围有很多朋友都很生气，不知道该做什么或该说什么。在那一刻，音乐对我们来说就是一个出口，望向人群，看到每个有同样感受的人——这让我想起了音乐的真正目的是什么。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;你意味着释放和情感力量？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;一切：抗议、释放和团结。看到一群人唱这首歌，并分享那一刻的情感，真是太棒了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;让我们来谈谈你的新专辑。当你写你的第一张专辑《Sour》时，作为一个年轻人，你有太多想要表达的东西，想要发泄出来、摆脱内心的想法。现在的奥利维亚·罗德里戈（Olivia Rodrigo）与坐下来写“Sour”的那个有什么不同？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哦，天哪，她是世界的不同。我在十七岁到二十岁之间就发生了很大的变化。在那段时间里，你成长了。我感觉自己三年内成长了二十五岁。所以，是的，她非常不同。但我绝对记得坐下来尝试写第二张专辑时的恐惧，并想，哦，天哪，我不再是一个经历第一次心碎的十七岁女孩了。这是一种普遍相关的经历。我怎样才能做出一些人们可以支持的东西？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;是否有写一些东西来匹配甚至超越你刚刚所做的事情的压力？或者是因为明星和其他一切带来的一切，你的生活变得更加奇怪了百分之两百？你脑子里的对话是什么样的？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;是的。我认为两者兼而有之。你知道人们总是这样说，“你唯一的竞争对手就是过去的自己。”我不知道这是否一定适合我。我不知道我怎样才能取得如此疯狂、意想不到的成功。我给自己施加了很长一段时间的压力。杰克·怀特是我心目中的大英雄——我第一次见到他大约在一年前——他给我写了一封信，其中提出了一些建议。其中之一是你唯一的工作就是写你想在广播中听到的音乐。我确实在与所有压力作斗争：Twitter 上的人们会喜欢这首歌的听起来吗？我脑子里全是这些东西。我记得读过这篇文章，它确实点燃了我内心的某些东西。这真的很有帮助。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;你之前说过，有时你会在二十分钟内写出一首歌。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2016/10/17/leonard-cohen-makes-it-darker&quot;>;伦纳德·科恩&lt;/a>;花了数年时间写下《哈利路亚》。这对你有什么作用？你身边有笔记本吗？你真的很快就能把它打掉吗？创作过程是怎样的？&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node -id=&quot;37n98p&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>; &lt;div >;&lt;p >;我非常喜欢莱昂纳德·科恩的故事。对我来说，每首歌都是不同的。我的意思是，有些歌曲很容易唱出来，而你会说，哇，谢谢你，宇宙！这刚刚落在我的腿上。谢谢！非常感激。其他歌曲则需要一些润色。在这张专辑《Guts》中，我真正学会了如何将歌曲创作视为一门手艺，而不仅仅是像我十七岁时那样在钢琴上倾注心血。 These songs definitely took longer to write, and we just sat with them for a little longer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;You took a poetry class at USC?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;Yeah.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;When was that, and why did you do that?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;That was last year. I mean, I was homeschooled my whole life. There&#39;s a song on the album called “Ballad of a Homeschooled Girl”—it&#39;s about me dealing with the consequences of that. I was homeschooled my whole life, and I always wanted to go to college. I was always very curious. There&#39;s so much that I want to know in this world. I really enjoyed taking that class. I&#39;ve always been super interested in poetry, and I&#39;ve been writing it for a long time. It was really informative, and I feel very grateful that I got that opportunity. We actually turned one of the poems that I wrote as an assignment in the poetry class into a song on the album, called “Lacy.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Are there any poems or poets that you read that are helpful to you? Not just as a human being but as an artist?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yeah. I mean, you brought up Leonard Cohen. I read lots of his poetry while I was making “Guts.” I think he&#39;s incredible. That&#39;s an endless well of inspiration. And I wrote the poem “Lacy” with inspiration from the poem “Daddy,” by Sylvia Plath.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;On the show “Girls”—which . 。 。 I don&#39;t know if you&#39;ve watched “Girls.”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I haven&#39;t watched it yet. Everyone&#39;s been recommending it to me, though. I really need to.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;So Lena Dunham is the creator of it, and she&#39;s also the star of the show, and she&#39;s a searching young woman. She wants to be a writer, and at a certain point she announces to her parents, “I think I may be the voice of my generation. Or at least a voice. Of a generation.” And now you&#39;re being branded, whether you like it or not, the voice of a generation, the voice of Gen Z. What do you make of all that?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;I tend to not think about it, just because it&#39;s kind of a scary thought. I don&#39;t think of myself that way. I just try to be as much myself as I possibly can, and try to do the best work I can. I mean, it&#39;s obviously super flattering when people say that. I love my generation. I am proud to be a part of it. So I guess it&#39;s a good thing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Social media makes its presence known in your songs. Do you also look at social media to see how people are perceiving you? It seems like a big burden.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yeah, that&#39;s an understatement. It&#39;s definitely a burden. I&#39;ve gotten better at it the more that I&#39;ve been on it. It&#39;s a part of this job that I think is a necessary evil. There are some parts of social media that are awesome. I love connecting with people who I normally wouldn&#39;t have gotten the chance to, but it is weird. And I feel like I&#39;m growing in front of people, which is really strange. I&#39;ve been in front of people for a long time, and sometimes it can be stifling to feel like you&#39;re always being seen. But I don&#39;t know. I have a good relationship with it these days.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Tell me about that burden.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I think for a long time I felt like I couldn&#39;t make mistakes, or I felt pressure to be a good role model. I grew up on these kids&#39; shows where being a good role model is very important—as it should be. And I always felt like I couldn&#39;t be a normal kid and go out and do stupid things and make mistakes and learn. At the end of the day, making mistakes is the only way you do learn. But in this album, in particular, I&#39;m grappling with those feelings and talking about the mistakes that I did end up making, and am being open and honest about them. And that was kind of cathartic for me.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Like what, for example?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I mean, there&#39;s a song, “Making the Bed,” that I really love. One of the lyrics is “Sometimes I feel like I don&#39;t wanna be where I am, / Gettin&#39; drunk at a club with my fair-weather friends.” That&#39;s the chorus. And I was kind of nervous to say that—I&#39;m twenty years old, which is not “of age” yet, I guess. And I was nervous to put that one out there. I&#39;m always so conscious that young kids are listening to my music, and people&#39;s parents are listening to my music. But, at the end of the day, all of my heroes are my heroes because they are unapologetically who they are, and they express themselves without fear of being criticized. So that&#39;s what I try to tell myself.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;There comes a time with a lot of artists that you idolize—Leonard Cohen, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/magazine/2022/10/31/a-unified-field-theory-of-bob-dylan&quot;>;Bob Dylan&lt;/a>;—they get sick of hearing about themselves being described as the voice of a generation. They rebel at that, and then they want to do what they want to do, and an audience doesn&#39;t always like it. Do you feel that for a third album, and a fourth album, you have to fulfill the expectations of your fans, of people that are out there in the crowd and buying records and all those things?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;RowWrapper&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;3nx1ff&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;p >;It&#39;s a really great question. I suppose I won&#39;t know until I embark on making my third record, but I think one of the biggest goals in my career, a real point to emphasize, is that I always want to be challenging myself. I want to make music that&#39;s ever-evolving. And even if people don&#39;t like that, well—all of my favorite artists are people whose every album is a choice, and something ambitious. So, if I can do that my whole career, I&#39;ll be very happy.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Are there particular artists that you look to and you say, I like the way that person evolved not only as an artist but as a person and as an independent being?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yeah, I mean, I really idolize Alanis Morissette. I think she&#39;s amazing, and I think her records are so human and perfectly capture what it is to be human. And I think they&#39;re really healing.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Have you ever met her?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Yeah, I&#39;ve met her a few times, and she is wonderful. She&#39;s one of my inspirations on a human level. I think she&#39;s handled her career with such grace and warmth, and has a groundedness to her that I really appreciate. She&#39;s a bit of a guiding light for me.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;On this album, on “Guts,” you seem to be reaching back even further in history. The opening track, which is about the impossible standards of being a woman in America, starts out kind of Joni Mitchell but then turns abruptly midway into a song that sounds like the riot-grrrl scene. How do you position your music in a longer tradition of rebellion?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I love that question. I think female rebellion music, for lack of a better description, is my favorite music ever. I&#39;ve been obsessed with the riot-grrrl punk scene for a while, and “All-American Bitch” was my stab at trying to write a song like that. I feel a lot of kinship toward women, and I love writing songs about these female feelings of anger and resentment that aren&#39;t so easily expressible in everyday life. It&#39;s one of my favorites on the album.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;How do you look at your now reasonably distant past? You read about a lot of women who were on TV as kids, and they look back on their early careers and feel sad about the experience, and exploited. Do you feel that you got through all that and were decently treated, and that it was a healthy experience, or there were downsides to it as well?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I do. I can certainly see how people wouldn&#39;t have that experience. I think it&#39;s a very strange way to grow up. I feel really lucky that I was surrounded by wonderful people. My parents are wonderful and so grounded, and are always looking out for me. I just owe everything to them. I don&#39;t think that I would have the attitude toward it that I do if it wasn&#39;t for them. But, yeah, it is really strange, and you sacrifice a lot. I didn&#39;t have a normal childhood, so that I could have that career. I&#39;m really grateful for everything that happened. But it&#39;s definitely—it&#39;s a give-and-take, just like everything in life.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;What did you miss most?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I actually realized this year how much I missed—or I feel like I missed out on—going to high school, and being around people my own age. That camaraderie feels important to me. I grew up on sets where I was around forty-five-year-old guys all the time. So I had a relatively lonely childhood. Which is OK I mean, that&#39;s why I turned to writing songs and making music and all of that. But that&#39;s definitely one of the pitfalls.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;And fame at the level that you&#39;re experiencing it now, which is pretty rare—is it lonely, or is it something else?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I don&#39;t know what it is. Gosh, I feel incredibly lucky to have great people around me, but it certainly is trickier navigating social life and relationships of any kind. It&#39;s definitely something that I have to put more thought into. But social life and relationships are hard regardless of what your career is.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;And how much do you care and not care about the kind of fame that&#39;s outside of you, but very present? You had to deal with this kind of back-and-forth about Taylor Swift, for example. Can you brush it off pretty easily, or does it get to you?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;It depends on the day. I think that, ever since “Drivers License” came out, I&#39;ve been keen on separating Olivia the person and Olivia the persona—the person that people criticize even when they don&#39;t know me. And that&#39;s really helped. That keeps me grounded.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Is there a theme that does connect the titles of your two albums, “Sour” and “Guts”? They&#39;re some of the bluntest album titles that I know.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I know. They pack a punch.&lt;/p>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;inline-recirc&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Maybe indigestion or something.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;[&lt;em>;Laughs.&lt;/em>;] Yeah, I love four-letter words of all kinds. I love swear words, too, clearly, which is very evident in my albums. I think they&#39;re cool and succinct. And I&#39;d actually had the name “Guts” for a while. I had it when I was writing “Sour.” I thought it was a cool word that meant a lot of things. “Guts” can mean bravery, and “trusting your gut”—intuition. And “spilling your guts” is telling everyone your secrets. So it&#39;s a word that I&#39;ve always really loved.&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;When you&#39;re making these records, do the songs that eventually take off—are those the ones that you&#39;re expecting to take off? Do you know when you have a hit?&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;You never really know, especially in today&#39;s pop landscape. I feel like so many of the biggest pop songs are songs that maybe wouldn&#39;t have been a pop hit fifteen years ago. And I love that. I love that people are itching for something a little different. But, yeah, I think you don&#39;t really know until it comes out. I&#39;m always surprised by which songs people gravitate toward. ♦&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 04:06:01 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Olivia Rodrigo, the Voice of Generation Z; Plus, Stephen Kotkin on Ending the War in Ukraine]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://www.newyorker.com/podcast/the-new-yorker-radio-hour/olivia-rodrigo-the-voice-of-generation-z-plus-stephen-kotkin-on-ending-the-war-in-ukraine]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-29T19:00:00.000Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.newyorker.com/photos/6515a24ad50e12024b152869/16:9/w_1280,c_limit/NYRH-Olivia-Rodrigo-NEW.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;article >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attribute-verso-pattern=&quot;article-body&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div data-attr-viewport-monitor=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;button id=&quot;bookmark&quot; aria-label=&quot;Save&quot; >;&lt;span >;&lt;svg width=&quot;24&quot; height=&quot;24&quot; viewBox=&quot;0 0 24 24&quot; fill=&quot;none&quot; xmlns=&quot;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&quot;>;&lt;title>;Save&lt;/title>;&lt;path d=&quot;M20 23.9508L12.5 19.7312L5 23.9508V2.95081H14V3.93211H6V22.1845L12.5 18.5536L19 22.1845V8.83866H20V23.9508Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;path d=&quot;M23 3H20V0H19V3H16V4H19V7H20V4H23V3Z&quot;>;&lt;/path>;&lt;/svg>;&lt;/span>;&lt;span >;Save&lt;/span>;&lt;/button>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;ArticlePageChunks&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-journey-hook=&quot;client-content&quot; data-testid=&quot;BodyWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;inline-embed name=&quot;&quot; attrs=&quot;[object Object]&quot; childTypes=&quot;iframe&quot; contentType=&quot;callout:&quot;>;&lt;figure data-testid=&quot;IframeEmbed&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;IframeEmbedContainer&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;iframe height=&quot;120&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-scripts allow-same-origin&quot; title=&quot;Embedded Frame&quot; data-src=&quot;https://www.wnyc.org/widgets/ondemand_player/thenewyorker/?share=1#file=/audio/json/1368223/&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay *;加密媒体*；剪贴板写入；自动播放;全屏; picture-in-picture&quot;>;&lt;/iframe>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p>;&lt;em>;Listen and subscribe:&lt;/em>; &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://pod.link/the-new-yorker-radio-hour.apple?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=ffd8259540a4405c8e8d80846d54030a&amp;amp;pdst_label=dXapIafQ&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://pod.link/the-new-yorker-radio-hour.apple?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=ffd8259540a4405c8e8d80846d54030a&amp;amp;pdst_label=dXapIafQ&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://pod.link/the-new-yorker-radio-hour.apple?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=ffd8259540a4405c8e8d80846d54030a&amp;amp;pdst_label=dXapIafQ&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Apple&lt;/a>; | &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://pod.link/the-new-yorker-radio-hour.spotify?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=ffd8259540a4405c8e8d80846d54030a&amp;amp;pdst_label=dXapIafQ&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://pod.link/the-new-yorker-radio-hour.spotify?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=ffd8259540a4405c8e8d80846d54030a&amp;amp;pdst_label=dXapIafQ&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://pod.link/the-new-yorker-radio-hour.spotify?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=ffd8259540a4405c8e8d80846d54030a&amp;amp;pdst_label=dXapIafQ&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Spotify&lt;/a>; | &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://pod.link/the-new-yorker-radio-hour.google?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=ffd8259540a4405c8e8d80846d54030a&amp;amp;pdst_label=dXapIafQ&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://pod.link/the-new-yorker-radio-hour.google?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=ffd8259540a4405c8e8d80846d54030a&amp;amp;pdst_label=dXapIafQ&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://pod.link/the-new-yorker-radio-hour.google?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=ffd8259540a4405c8e8d80846d54030a&amp;amp;pdst_label=dXapIafQ&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Google&lt;/a>; | &lt;a data-offer-url=&quot;https://pod.link/the-new-yorker-radio-hour?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=ffd8259540a4405c8e8d80846d54030a&amp;amp;pdst_label=dXapIafQ&quot; data-event-click=&quot;{&amp;quot;element&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;ExternalLink&amp;quot;,&amp;quot;outgoingURL&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;https://pod.link/the-new-yorker-radio-hour?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=ffd8259540a4405c8e8d80846d54030a&amp;amp;pdst_label=dXapIafQ&amp;quot;}&quot; href=&quot;https://pod.link/the-new-yorker-radio-hour?pdst_key=df1e65c3eb684bbabcda953605e811ee&amp;amp;pdst_group=ffd8259540a4405c8e8d80846d54030a&amp;amp;pdst_label=dXapIafQ&quot; rel=&quot;nofollow noopener&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Wherever You Listen&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;em>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newyorker.com/newsletter/podcasts&quot;>;Sign up&lt;/a>; to receive our weekly newsletter of the best New Yorker podcasts.&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;hr/>;&lt;/inline-embed>;&lt;p >;The pop singer and songwriter Olivia Rodrigo&#39;s rise to fame was meteoric. She talks with David Remnick about her models for songwriting, dealing with social media as a young celebrity, and how it feels to be branded the voice of Generation Z. Plus, the Russia scholar Stephen Kotkin says that, realistically, Ukraine must come to accept the loss of some Russia-held territory in exchange for security guarantees. But the US must do more to threaten Vladimir Putin&#39;s hold on power.&lt;/p>;&lt;h2 >;Olivia Rodrigo Talks with David Remnick&lt;/h2>;&lt;figure data-testid=&quot;IframeEmbed&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;IframeEmbedContainer&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;iframe height=&quot;120&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-scripts allow-same-origin&quot; title=&quot;Embedded Frame&quot; data-src=&quot;https://www.wnyc.org/widgets/ondemand_player/thenewyorker/?share=1#file=/audio/json/1368224/&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay *; encrypted-media *; clipboard-write; autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&quot;>;&lt;/iframe>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p >;The pop artist&#39;s rise to fame was meteoric. She talks about her models for songwriting, dealing with social media as a young celebrity, and getting out from the shadow of Disney.&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;h2 >;Should Biden Push for Regime Change in Russia?&lt;/h2>;&lt;figure data-testid=&quot;IframeEmbed&quot; >;&lt;div data-testid=&quot;IframeEmbedContainer&quot; >;&lt;div >;&lt;iframe height=&quot;120&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; sandbox=&quot;allow-scripts allow-same-origin&quot; title=&quot;Embedded Frame&quot; data-src=&quot;https://www.wnyc.org/widgets/ondemand_player/thenewyorker/?share=1#file=/audio/json/1368225/&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay *; encrypted-media *; clipboard-write; autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture&quot;>;&lt;/iframe>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/figure>;&lt;p >;The Russia scholar Stephen Kotkin says that Ukraine must exchange Russia-held territory for security guarantees. But the US must also threaten Putin&#39;s hold on power.&lt;/p>;&lt;hr />;&lt;p >;&lt;em>;The New Yorker Radio Hour is a co-production of WNYC Studios and The New Yorker.&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;aside style=&quot;position:absolute;top:auto;height:auto&quot; data-testid=&quot;PersistentAsideWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;puu5mcj&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div data-node-id=&quot;bglzss&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;aside data-testid=&quot;PaywallInlineBarrierWrapper&quot;>;&lt;div role=&quot;presentation&quot; aria-live=&quot;polite&quot; aria-hidden=&quot;true&quot;>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/aside>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;div >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/article>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 30 Sep 2023 04:06:01 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>