<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[一周的心情｜本周小记精选]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3945]]><description> &lt;div>;15 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Question from ONE Editorial Department&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>; It&#39;s been a week, how are you? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; ONE Friendly Answer&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1 ;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A week has passed and I heard a new echo in the tree hole. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FvdYh-loWk2NC9B3_T4V6ASFwPom &quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FvdYh-loWk2NC9B3_T4V6ASFwPom&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data -original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmfB49wpXZvGA0vqig3Lu_txwySZ&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmfB49wpXZvGA0vqig3Lu_txwySZ&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false &quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FouKSJGHEf2RyV71UkcqRa5Q6IAK&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FouKSJGHEf2RyV71UkcqRa5Q6IAK&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FupyxAyr12QK15K299FBOsxd_QhJ&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http ://image.wufazhuce.com/FupyxAyr12QK15K299FBOsxd_QhJ&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FrS0rTC95nlI0 -C5Zytkcha86qje&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FrS0rTC95nlI0-C5Zytkcha86qje&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fj-AUmzOqfpenF3RuQyc83LgFSNt&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fj-AUmzOqfpenF3RuQyc83LgFSNt&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable= &quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FhMM9ZJoTY6NRMLN-6aOE5gVCLkw&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce. com/FhMM9ZJoTY6NRMLN-6aOE5gVCLkw&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Frwx-_Gh2HXQrchwt0fQwUKhrLKn&quot; data- source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Frwx-_Gh2HXQrchwt0fQwUKhrLKn&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http ://image.wufazhuce.com/FkYCJO3EZNdLgMSSMbr4JnPcduRf&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FkYCJO3EZNdLgMSSMbr4JnPcduRf&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author =&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fj0Zn5owv2A-Ic1tn3WWzlTTfzXV&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fj0Zn5owv2A-Ic1tn3WWzlTTfzXV&quot;>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FswLVWZFBvDiYvun4GKViDgdVa2Z&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http:// image.wufazhuce.com/FswLVWZFBvDiYvun4GKViDgdVa2Z&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FvNdzqvBdbw465xImeRjOH3ZSBIZ&quot; data- source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FvNdzqvBdbw465xImeRjOH3ZSBIZ&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http:/ /image.wufazhuce.com/FnTq7SYIchHm7oS4gHlDyJ3N_3VJ&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FnTq7SYIchHm7oS4gHlDyJ3N_3VJ&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot; &quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fnza52rgoFlu8nZR1qtPpkoFQU36&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fnza52rgoFlu8nZR1qtPpkoFQU36&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable= &quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FqGkNDkrF1Jk2tAne49A6E3xsbFV&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/ FqGkNDkrF1Jk2tAne49A6E3xsbFV&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FtiN3yr7APT4oMW1_nUCTEM1G8dj&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src= &quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FtiN3yr7APT4oMW1_nUCTEM1G8dj&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com /FpIvQSDP0J8bLtjoAylPIt3Oqcm_&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpIvQSDP0J8bLtjoAylPIt3Oqcm_&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; Editor in charge: Zhou Ziheng onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Click on the &quot;pen&quot; below the daily signature on the homepage to leave your life moments and your unexplainable feelings in the tree hole. . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8 &quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Complex The cutest people in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3937&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;The mood of the week | Selected notes of the week&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Question and Answer&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3935 &quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;The mood of the week | Selected notes of the week&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table >; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3945)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我与父亲走过最远的地方]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6124]]><description> &lt;div>;15 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text／Look look&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FhfCPBwemT7zqJG7AJtkmDf6Sc8A&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FhfCPBwemT7zqJG7AJtkmDf6Sc8A&quot;>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Many people have heard about the work of running large trucks. They are representatives of labor intensity. One of the people who are most vulnerable to bullying by gangsters. The dirt road in the mountains and the guardrail in the city are the real gap in life. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My father is &quot;playing&quot; with carts, the village master said so. They don’t talk about “running” a big car or “driving” a big car, they say they are “playing” with a big car. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I don’t have much ability, I only know how to drive, and I have been driving all my life. &amp;rdquo;Father said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From &quot;Dongfeng Semi-trailer&quot; to &quot;Steyr&quot;, he traveled all over the country in a car that did not belong to him. People come and go, everything changes, but what remains unchanged is the road that stretches in front of my father&#39;s eyes, from dusk to early morning, and from early morning to dusk. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the few days when he came home, I listened to him tell stories on the road at the dinner table and in bed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the Xing&#39;an Mountains, in the snow that was up to my thighs, I pulled out logs as thick as a log and loaded them into the car. &quot;The snow is falling like a fan!&quot; &amp;rdquo;He said. On the bank of the Songhua River, I tied a wrist-thick iron chain to the tire and followed the wheel tracks of the car in front of me on the frozen river. The wind blew up the broken snow on the ice, like undulating water ripples. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Will it fall? &amp;rdquo;I asked. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Stop talking nonsense! &amp;rdquo;My mother slapped me on the mouth. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;The first time I crossed the river, my legs were trembling. After a few miles ashore, I still couldn’t press the accelerator. I felt like I was still on the ice. Later, I got used to it. At more than 20 degrees below zero, the rocks are frozen like ice, and frozen like rocks. &amp;rdquo;Dad said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Once, my father drove out of customs and was checked. Give the police 200 yuan. If you don&#39;t want it, you have to pay a fine. Dad said he was a little policeman with a red face and no beard. Dad got out of the car, took his hands out of his arms, and took off his gloves. The little finger and ring finger of his left hand were already black, and the whole hand looked like a half-molded eggplant. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The little policeman looked at it, touched it, and said, &quot;Let&#39;s go, there will be no fine.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dad was overjoyed and thanked him as he headed back to the car. The little policeman stopped his father and said, &quot;What are you doing?&quot; Follow me and get amputated. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dad was confused. He knew that his hands were cold, hurt, and then no longer hurt, and were numb, and then no longer numb. He believed that if he walked a little further south, his hands would turn a rosy color. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dad said: &quot;No, brother.&quot; You can&#39;t intercept it, there are two children at home! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The little policeman started his motorcycle and said, &quot;Hurry up!&quot; You can&#39;t keep your arm all night long. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I pay the fine, I pay, I go home... I just go home... I just go home! &amp;rdquo;Dad was about to drive in a panic. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The little policeman got angry and dragged his father by the collar to the side of the road. Dad staggered and finally slipped and fell to his knees in the snow. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Rub! &amp;rdquo;The little policeman said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Rub it, rub it hard, rub it quickly! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dad knelt on the ground, holding up the white or dirty snow and rubbing it desperately. The snow is no longer snow, it is misty hope. That hope is like snow, it melts when you pick it up, and pick it up again after it melts. The hands were no longer hands, they were his two children. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That day, my father cried and rubbed himself in the snow for two hours until he felt hot. &quot;It&#39;s as hot as a soldering iron,&quot; Dad said. The blood flowed again and the finger was saved. Dad wiped away his tears and sweat, struggled to get up, and looked around, but there was no trace of the little policeman. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He suddenly mentioned this matter one night or in the morning, mentioning it in just a few words. Compared to my father, I am much more verbose. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I was 12 years old, hair began to grow on my top and bottom, and I began to see the world, my father, and myself differently. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I learned to smoke, would go out to drink at night, grow my hair and paint it, try to taste every beautiful girl’s tongue, read &quot;Three Gates&quot; and &quot;Like a Boy Speeding&quot;, and felt For the first time in my life, I have yearning, and for the first time I feel freedom. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then during the summer vacation, I put an ugly report card in front of my father. This time, I didn&#39;t cry like before. I endured every punch of his with patience and pride, thinking I was like a hero! Finally, my father was defeated like an army and hid in the room for a long time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;No words for a night. At dawn, my father woke me up and said, &quot;Come on, give me a ride!&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I sat on the motorcycle with fear and no idea why. Amidst a crisp clicking sound, my father and I drove away into the distance in the morning light... The town where the car stopped is at the foot of the mountain. There are many mountains and little land here, so food cannot be grown. It used to be the poorest place. Later, people discovered that stones were more valuable than grain, and this became a wealthy place again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A detonator was buried in the mountain, and at the push of a button, rocks poured down like an avalanche. The stone pullers were waiting below, fighting for a good spot. Often the defeated person leaves, but the victorious person is killed by flying rocks. Until they were smashed to death, they thought the flying things were money! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The stone is pulled down and cut into slabs in a small workshop. It was this kind of slate that my father was hauling this time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The man pushing the circular saw was shirtless, took off his mask, and his mouth was full of black and blue. He shouted to the inside: &quot;Load the car!&quot; &amp;rdquo;Five or six middle-aged women filed out. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dad said: &quot;Three will do.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;No, at least five. &amp;rdquo;said a woman. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I can match both! &amp;rdquo;Dad said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This would save his boss sixty dollars. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The car was very high, and the steps reached to my waist. I climbed up to the cab with difficulty and found a person lying on the bed. Seeing me, he sat up. He sat up, startling me. His face is old and saggy, and his hair is gray. Under his gray hair, a scar ran diagonally across the bridge of his nose, like a gecko lying on his nose. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dad said: &quot;Call uncle!&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I timidly shouted: &quot;Uncle!&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The gecko twisted its body--he smiled. He took out an apple from nowhere, wiped it with a towel, and stuffed it into my hand. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The car started driving, and its destination was at the border of Shanxi and Shaanxi. It unloaded the slate and went to Shenmu to pull coal. The uncle was driving, and the father was huddled in the crib, like soaked fungus packed in a bowl. My father and uncle would take turns driving this way, driving day and night, and deliver the goods to the owner in the afternoon of the day after tomorrow. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On both sides of the road are neat and dense weeping willows. When the wind blows, the branches and leaves sway, like a girl drying her hair by the stream. In the fields, crops humbly lower their heads, waiting for the harvest time to turn from weeds into dry food. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Further to the northwest, there are more mountains. Those mountains were cut with knives and axes, and the three-dimensional geometric shapes were inserted straight into the ground and rushed into the sky. Only a few stubborn trees grew out of the top. The mountain wall is smooth but steep. Looking up, I feel that I am as small as the mountain is high. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Dad, the mountains here are different from the mountains at home. &amp;rdquo;I said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;This is also our mountain. The &quot;mountain&quot; in Shandong is this mountain, and the &quot;mountain&quot; in Shanxi is also this mountain. &amp;rdquo;Dad said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The next day, it will be too late. The lights gradually brightened, like sparks igniting fire one by one. Dad looked in the direction of the flames and said, &quot;Taiyuan!&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before seeing Taiyuan, the largest city I had ever seen was Jining. I have already begun to imagine the flashing neon lights and the flowing carriages and horses in Taiyuan City, as well as the cool girls and mellow vinegar. But our car inadvertently turned a corner in front of the bustling city, and skimmed along the outskirts of the city. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said: &quot;Dad, I want to go to Taiyuan to visit.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dad said: &amp;ldquo;When you have the ability, go and see for yourself, our car can’t get in. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I realized that the city’s roads do not belong to heavy trucks, and the city’s fireworks do not belong to truck drivers. I finally understood why my father always said that he had been everywhere, but he had never been anywhere. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At night, there are more cars and driving becomes slower. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The uncle asked: &quot;Are you at the toll station?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dad said: &amp;ldquo;The official ones haven’t arrived yet. Maybe check the car! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The uncle asked: &amp;ldquo;Did the public investigate? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dad said: &amp;ldquo;Who knows? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The train of cars is like a dragon, with no head in front and no tail behind, moving its body slowly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At this moment, many old people emerged from the gaps in the vehicles, with handkerchiefs on their heads and sticks in their hands, followed by one or two gray-faced children, holding high the fallen enamel jars. , there are scattered dimes and coins in the jar. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dad cursed, reached out from under the seat and pulled out a tea can, poured it into his hand with a splash, and put two coins into each passing pot. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The uncle asked: &quot;Isn&#39;t it okay to give me a piece?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dad said: &amp;ldquo;Then there are still children! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I think of my grandma, who once led me to knock on the door of a neighbor&#39;s house on a drizzly morning or a sunny afternoon. Say a few words and get two steamed buns or a bowl of thick porridge. At that time, I had an extra sister, and there was an extra hole in the pot. I don’t know where my parents went. Grandma picked up a chipped bowl from the broken ground and led me out of the alley while we were eating. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The night is like a curtain. The car stopped in a large courtyard. The colorful lights in the courtyard were flashing, and the light sign at the door was flashing, saying: &quot;Eat, stay, fill up with water, refuel.&quot; The light signs that can be seen everywhere on this street opened up the corner of the night. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A woman who needs heavy makeup to support her appearance is wearing a floral skirt, with the flesh of her chest almost bulging out, and she warmly greets every guest who comes in. It can be seen that she is very familiar with each guest, and even knows their family members very well. She knows where the guests come from and where they are going. She also knows every man who has his mouth full of food and wine while twisting his waist to serve food. Flirting wildly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Only to me, she is a stranger. The strangeness makes her curious and asks questions curiously. Dad blocked her outstretched arm and told her that this was my son, a student. She looked at me in surprise, turned around and asked how the uncle&#39;s son was doing. The uncle smiled and said, he was still the same. Everyone seems to be happy when they come here, eating, drinking, bragging, and laughing from the chest. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The food was served. The portions were generous and the buns were as big as a brick. Dad said these are called steamed buns, and each one weighs two kilograms. The woman put all the dishes on the table and sat down on the bench with several bottles of beer between her fingers. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Invite the baby to drink. ’ she said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I don’t drink. &amp;rdquo;I said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Like your father, a prude, have a drink! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I looked at my dad. He drank a cup and wiped his mouth. I also picked up the cup, drank a cup and wiped my mouth. I looked at my dad again. He was picking up vegetables to eat. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The woman said: &quot;Old Shao is a prude. Who doesn&#39;t know that you are running a big car?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The woman then said: &quot;There is a good man in the sports car, who is your father.&quot; After school, I disobeyed and went to work in Guangdong, returning home at the end of the year... My father ate less and drank more, while I ate more and drank less. The uncle and the woman were sitting close to each other, just drinking, occasionally moving their chopsticks, like the occasional laughter and sighing in the long intertwining of words! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I asked for a room with two beds. The uncle said he would go look after the car and sleep in the car. The room would be given to me and him. Dad didn&#39;t refuse and took me into the house. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Halfway through sleep, I woke up thirsty. Dad was snoring loudly, so I went out to find some water. Through the broken screen window in the corridor, I saw the uncle and a man smoking under the dim light. A pipe was connected from the belly of the car like an umbilical cord. The other end is connected to a gasoline drum, and a weighbridge is placed under the oil drum. I watched for a while, then found a tap at the end of the corridor and drank from it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The woman came out of the room with a hand stuck in her chest. At the end of the hand was the face of a strange man half hidden in the door. When she saw me, she was startled and quickly pulled out her hand. The door closed, cutting off the man&#39;s eyes and smile. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The woman lowered her head and brushed her skirt, raised her head to straighten her hair, and said, &quot;What are you doing up so late?&quot; &amp;rdquo;It’s like teaching his son a lesson. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I didn’t say anything. I saw the white flesh pulled out from the arm. I saw the hem of the skirt flashing, looming, and the white flesh was revealed. She passed me by, grabbed my crotch, and then let go, smiling twice - I had an erection just now. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I bounced away, and the sudden and intense shame and anger made my whole body stiff. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Go back to the house and go to sleep! &amp;rdquo;She touched my head again and said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then he twisted his body and disappeared around the corner. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Back in the room, Dad woke up and leaned on the back of the bed to smoke. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What are you doing? &amp;rdquo;he asked. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Drink some water. &amp;rdquo;I said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then there was silence, only the sound of smoking and the flickering of cigarette butts. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Don’t run around when you have nothing to do. &amp;rdquo;As he said, he was about to go out. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Dad! &amp;rdquo;I called him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What’s wrong? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I...I saw the uncle pulling a pipe, he was stealing oil! &amp;rdquo;I said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dad paused and said, &quot;Children should stay away from adults&#39; matters!&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Open the door and a rectangular light shines through. The door closed and the light was wiped away, like a stain. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After a while, the uncle came in. Seeing that I was not asleep, he smiled vaguely. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Xiao Xun, why aren’t you sleeping yet? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Can’t sleep. &amp;rdquo;I said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What do you mean, we two are having sex? &amp;rdquo;He said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He must have seen me when he was stealing gas. With this confirmation, I became at a loss what to do and panicked, as if it was me who stole the oil and not him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He went to bed quietly. A series of bed boards creaked and he lay down. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Uncle, what do you do with your face? &amp;rdquo;I asked quietly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Ouch! My own son will cut him off! &amp;rdquo;The uncle said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;My son, your brother. I just got married the year before last and had a baby boy last year. This year, I broke my waist while working on a construction site. The doctor said it was broken and I should go home and recover. Half a year later, my daughter-in-law ran away. Unable to think about it, he crawled to the kitchen and took a kitchen knife to wipe his neck. I went to grab it, but he slashed my face with the knife, and then his eyeball was gone. &amp;rdquo;He said it calmly, as if he was cutting someone else. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;It’s better now. My grandson is older and I don’t want to die so much. hey-hey! &amp;rdquo;He said, and he smiled. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I am sixty, kid. The boss won&#39;t let me do it, and the guys are bothering me. I&#39;m dazzled, and the sports car doesn&#39;t work anymore, so it&#39;s just your father and me who work together. &amp;rdquo;He said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;No one wants to drive a sports car with your father! &amp;rdquo;He said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Why? &amp;rdquo;I asked. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;He doesn’t steal oil! &amp;rdquo;The uncle said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That night, I could not fall asleep again for a long time, so I got up to pee again, and listened with bated breath in the corridor. There was nothing but intermittent cries, and more &quot;umbilical cords&quot; were pulled up in the yard. Someone shouted loudly, and I hurriedly returned to the house. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Someone whispered in the light dream, chaotic things came one after another, and faces were fleeting. Railings, lights, stairs, bed curtains, I stood on the cliff, drowning in the water. Until a hand, a slender and gentle hand grasped my lower body. In an instant, his head burst out of the water and his body plummeted away. The consciousness is floating in the air, and the pleasure is overwhelming. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first time in my life - I ejaculated! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We set off at dawn, it was groggy, the sun was blushing, mist lingered in the mountains, and a few low buildings were located at the foot of the mountains, like squatting old people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Suddenly, there was a sudden brake, and the body and thoughts stretched, shaking like jelly and then paused. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dad roared out the window: &quot;What a bear?&quot; wanna die! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The car was blocked by a red and white wooden stake, trying its best to imitate a roadblock in a toll booth. Two people shouted: &quot;Two hundred, two hundred!&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;It’s a dog’s day! &amp;rdquo;The two adults in the car cursed at the same time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dad swung in the direction, trying to go around. The two of them each hold one end and move the stake back and forth, knowing that you don&#39;t dare to push it over. One of them picked up a piece of brick and said, &quot;Bang!&quot; &quot;It hit the car with a bang.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What a fucking idiot! Try smashing another one. Dad shouted, unbuckled his seat belt, picked up the hammer, kicked the door open and jumped out of the car. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;It’s a dog’s day! Smash it again? I&#39;ll kill you! &amp;rdquo;Dad rushed up with the hammer in hand. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two of them were scolding and retreating, saying nothing more than: &quot;Just wait, I will remember you, let&#39;s see if you can pass.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The uncle jumped out of the car quickly like an old monkey, grabbed my dad’s waist and dragged him back. Throw out two hundred dollars. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Still not move away? &amp;rdquo;The uncle shouted. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The wooden stakes were removed, Dad cursed, the car started to drive again, and the cars behind him also started to drive. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Why not check the back? &amp;rdquo;I asked the uncle. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;They are local! &amp;rdquo;The uncle said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;If he doesn’t stop me, I will beat him for two fucking days! &amp;rdquo;Dad said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Stop showing off, I’ll drive! &amp;rdquo;The uncle said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The delivery location is at the top of the mountain. The mountain is very big, the road is very narrow, and there is a mountain wall on one side and a cliff on the other. It makes people cautious, not daring to cross the threshold even half a step. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It has been a steep uphill climb, and I can clearly feel the pressure exerted by the back of the chair on my body. The car in front stopped. The uncle stopped the car and quickly applied the handbrake. Unexpectedly, as soon as his foot left the brake pedal, the car shook slightly backwards, and there was a clicking sound. The uncle hurriedly stepped on his foot again and did not dare to move. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Old Shao, come here, my legs are numb. &amp;rdquo;The uncle shouted. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My dad and uncle changed places and continued the tug-of-war with gravity. Stop and go, stepping on the clutch and brakes one step at a time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than ten years later, one summer night, my father came to my new home in the city for the first time. As soon as I entered the community, there was a sudden power outage, the earth instantly turned dark, and there was a scream from upstairs. Thinking of my child, I rushed up the stairs. My father could follow me at first, but then there was no sound. I stepped into the house and comforted my wife and children. In a flash, the earth lit up again, and when I found my father again, he was sitting on the stairs of the seventh floor, holding his knees and crying. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I shouted: &quot;Dad!&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He stood up, covering up his panic with sullenness, and said, &amp;ldquo;What are you doing buying a building for such a high price? I can&#39;t even climb a flight of stairs. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His knees had already been damaged in the endless stampeding. I asked myself, how could I so naturally abandon my father and choose my son. The son still has his mother, but the only father is me! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We didn’t climb to the top of the mountain until the sunset. There is a depression or small basin surrounding the top of the mountain, and a Guanyin stands prominently in the middle of the basin. His whole body is snow-white, his eyebrows are kind and his eyes are downcast, and the afterglow of the setting sun spreads over his body, giving him a burst of golden light. He looked down at the world with solemnity and great compassion in his eyes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Where is this? &amp;rdquo;I asked Dad. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Attractions! &amp;rdquo;Dad said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;A rich man’s yard! &amp;rdquo;The uncle said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The journey down the mountain was uneventful. Halfway up the mountain, I saw a car overturned in a ditch, twisted like a piece of fried dough. The driver sat on the tilted front of the car, with a blood-stained towel wrapped around his head, smoking a cigarette, as if sitting on the field of his home guarding late-ripening wheat. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dad drove the car upright, turned down the mountain, and headed northwest. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Shenmu&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;Shenmu&amp;rdquo;, what a good name! When it grows on the ground it is called a tree, when it is buried underground it is called a sacred tree, but when it is dug out it is called &quot;coal&quot;? It’s gone as soon as it burns! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shenmu is a county. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The uncle said: &quot;Don&#39;t look at it as a county, it is the broadest county.&quot; There is no charge for children to go to high school, and there is also free lunch, and there is milk in the lunch. &amp;rdquo;There was sadness and envy in his words. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What about our county? &amp;rdquo;I asked. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Our county? &amp;rdquo;The uncle stared exaggeratedly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Ouch! Jiaxiang County - Break the pig pen! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the early morning, my father stopped the car in a small coal mine in the outer suburbs of Shenmu. The ground here is dark, the water is dark, and even the morning is dark. Ragged work clothes were piled up in the dilapidated canteen, and a group of workers were taking the last puff of their choking cigarettes. The sound of &quot;dang~dang~dang&quot; sounded, and they put down their cigarettes, straightened up, and walked toward the wellhead, cursing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After breakfast, my father, uncle and I were sitting in the car. There are a dozen cars waiting in front. Dad was asleep and snoring loudly. The uncle picked up the thermos and said to fetch water. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I stuck my head out of the window and watched the gusts of wind blowing up the coal dust. That’s when Heiwa appeared in the rearview mirror. He was carrying a basket, had no shirt on, and had a pair of military green rubber shoes on his feet. He strode forward, tracing the carriage with his fingers and drawing a straight line in the dirt. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said: &quot;Don&#39;t touch my car.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was frightened and jumped two meters away. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Whatever you do, (scare) (me) jumps, be careful (I) beat you! &amp;rdquo;He said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I asked him: &quot;What are you doing?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He looked at me and said, &quot;What for?&quot; I still need you to take care of it! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As he said that, he strode away again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Where do you come from? &amp;rdquo;He turned around and asked. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Shandong! &amp;rdquo;I said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Come on down. &amp;rdquo;He greeted me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hei Wa took me to a cinder pile. He sprinted up, ran a few more steps, and stopped, with cinders dripping down like water. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Heiwa looked for coal in the cinders that had not yet turned into slag. When he found it, he threw it down and asked me to put it into the basket for him. Then he asked me to help him carry it to another larger pile of coal. The coal piled here looked like stones. Heiwa poured the coal in the basket onto it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In this way, I followed him, going back and forth. I realized that I was a free labor force, and I did not resist. On the one hand, he was also a child, and on the other hand, I was really afraid of him beating me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hei Wa said he would pay fifty cents for picking up a basket. As long as he picks up 704 baskets, he can pay for his tuition. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Your dad won’t pay your tuition? &amp;rdquo;I asked. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Well (my) eldest (father) is dead! &amp;rdquo;He said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Have you learned the quadratic equation? &amp;rdquo;I asked. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Yes, two return trips for one yuan! &amp;rdquo;He said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At lunchtime, my father found me, sweating all over, and kicked me. Hei Wa glanced at it and climbed up the coal pile again. He didn&#39;t throw away the coal and held it in his arms. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Why are you running around? I’ve been looking for you for a long time. Let’s go and eat! Look, you are in trouble. &amp;rdquo;Dad grabbed me and hurried away. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the road, there were women carrying poles, and they walked to the mouth of the well. The miners at the door took the poles with their bare arms and opened the cage cloth, revealing a basket of food. The miner grinned, his eyeballs and teeth frighteningly white. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was not until dinner time that the car drove into the mine gate. The excavator shoveled the coal into the truck bucket one by one, causing dust to fly. We hid in the cab and closed the doors and windows tightly, feeling the ground shaking. Coal is like a piece of cake, and a car is like an ant. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After loading the coal, the car drove out of the gate. On the road, I saw Hei Wa walking bumpily with a basket on his arm. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I stuck my head out and shouted: &quot;Hei Wa, I&#39;m leaving!&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hei Wa also saw me, put the basket full of coal on the ground, and swung his arms high. Under the illumination of the car lights, I suddenly realized how thin he was, and his waving hand looked like a second hand. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hei Wa! I never saw him again. Later, I asked my father several times, have you seen Hei Wa again? Dad also said no. I think he must have gone to school and passed the Shenmu test, so it doesn&#39;t cost anything to go to school. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was almost midnight when we walked from Shenmu to the junction of Shaanxi and Shanxi. The uncle craned his neck to follow the headlights, and I was about to fall asleep. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Lao Shao, Lao Shao. &amp;rdquo;The uncle called to his father, his voice anxious. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The uncle pointed to the rearview mirror. I don’t know when there were several light spots on both sides of the car, and they were still getting closer. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dad took the steering wheel and said, &quot;I&#39;ll drive.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He looked at me again and said, &amp;ldquo;Hurry up! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I grabbed the handle and watched the light spots behind me flickering left and right, bright and dim. Dad leaned forward, his eyes wide and his cheeks bulging. Drive the car fast. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The car turned into a boat, bumping and undulating on the bumpy road. I bounced out of my seat and fell back down. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Dad, slow down, slow down. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Dad, slow down, slow down, I’m scared! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The car stopped, and almost instantly, several motorcycles blocked the car lights. Several people pointed and shouted: &quot;Come down, come down.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dad fumbled from his bag and found a cigarette. He handed it down through the car window and said, &quot;Brother, you see, this is your first trip. You haven&#39;t paid yet. You have to smoke a pack of cigarettes first.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A man climbed up, took the cigarette and threw it away. He reached in, opened the locked door, and slapped Dad hard in the face. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I asked you to run, but you were driving very fast, so why didn’t you run? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Get the money! hurry up! &amp;rdquo;The man grabbed his father&#39;s collar and said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;How do you do it? Why do you hit someone? &amp;rdquo;The uncle shouted. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Let’s go down and talk. &amp;rdquo;Dad took the man&#39;s hand away. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The man saw me, turned around and shouted to the car: &quot;Hey!&quot; And a doll! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dad got out of the car, and the uncle shivered and put on his shoes. I asked in a panic: &quot;What are you doing? Let&#39;s call the police... let&#39;s call the police!&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You......don&#39;t worry, stay there, don&#39;t move! &amp;rdquo;The uncle also got out of the car. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The cars next to me passed by slowly, and the sound of hitting and yelling was mixed with the sound of brakes and exhaust. I was just like the uncle said, motionless. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After a while, the man just climbed up, rummaged around in the cab, and saw me. He yelled: &quot;What are you looking at?&quot; Close your eyes! &amp;rdquo;I quickly closed my eyes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The man shouted: &quot;No, he must be hiding.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The passenger door opened and I was dragged out of the car. I saw my father and uncle being pressed against the car. I was so frightened that my body kept shaking and my voice became trembling. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I shouted: &quot;Dad... A punch, a heavy muffled sound. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;It’s a dog’s day! Put the baby down, give me the baby! &amp;rdquo;Dad roared. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Get the money! &amp;rdquo;The person dragging me shouted. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Take money... Dad slapped me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;If you have money... Here you go...&quot; It&#39;s the uncle. The uncle shouted with a cry, his voice full of grievances. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Let go of me! &amp;rdquo;The uncle roared to the left and right. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几只不同的手移开。大爷先提了提裤子，颤巍巍解着腰带，就是一截绳子。大爷一手提着下坠的裤子一手往裤裆里摸索着。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;快点！ &amp;rdquo;一声呵斥。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;裤子整个掉到脚踝，大爷也不再遮掩，把手伸进内裤，掏出一卷钱来，在半空中举着。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;给你&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;给你们&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;把孩子放了&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;拿着&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;拿着啊！ &amp;rdquo;裤子缠在脚上，大爷缓慢地挪着步子，把钱向前递着，像递出一颗心脏。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一时竟无人去接。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我身子一松，那人把我推给父亲，走到大爷面前站住。他看了看钱又看了看大爷，把身子弯下去，像在鞠躬。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;这个老逼，裤头里缝了个布袋，哈哈&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;那人直起身大笑。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周围的人也跟着笑了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;亏你个老逼能想出来。 &amp;rdquo;说着一巴掌打大爷头上。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;把钱夺过来揣怀里，转身给了少年一个耳光。说：&amp;ldquo;妈哩个逼，这是钱！就算他从腚沟子里抠出来&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;也是钱！ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拥堵的车越来越多，汽笛声不绝于耳，车灯照过来，尘土无所遁形，肆意纷飞。在光与土中，爸爸和大爷上来了，他们额头有汗，嘴角带血。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;爸爸说：&amp;ldquo;快走，快走，挡人家路了。 &amp;rdquo;说着把车发动起来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;下回再跑，还揍你！ &amp;rdquo;摩托车上飘来一句话，一溜烟跑远了&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我怯生生喊：&amp;ldquo;爸！ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;没事，别害怕，要钱哩！给他就是了。 &amp;rdquo;爸爸说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;为什么不报警？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你们为什么不报警？ &amp;rdquo;我质问道。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;报警抓他们啊，抓他们啊！ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;抓他们啊，嘴都打破了。抓他们啊，我要杀了他们啊，我动都没敢动啊，呜呜呜&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;啊&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;我从惊惧和屈辱和羞愧中反应过来，嚎啕大哭。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;没事了，儿子，别哭了，你没事就行，别哭了啊！ &amp;rdquo;爸爸拍着我肩膀。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大爷说：&amp;ldquo;这是看见他爹挨揍心疼了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;又抹着眼泪说：&amp;ldquo;年龄大了眼窝子浅，孩唻，回去可得好好学习，别跟你爹还有我一样，受这洋罪。还有我那命苦的孩啊！ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;大哥，下趟再去吃顿杠子馍吧！ &amp;rdquo;爸爸说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大爷擦了眼泪，别过头去。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过了一会，大爷说：&amp;ldquo;老邵啊&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;老邵&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;你哪都好，就是太实在了！ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;爸爸告诉我，大爷交出去的是他卖油的钱，而运费一直藏在车里。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;又经过了一夜加一天的路程，连着几天的困乏全部涌来，回去的路还有记忆都在我的酣睡中变得模糊。那是一场巨大的睡眠，好像过了一个世纪，醒来时惶恐和孤独瞬间裹挟了我，似乎整个世界已经把我抛弃。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;望向车窗外，西山的云彩燃烧着，光线黏稠的不像话。切割石板的声音又尖利的传来，白色的粉尘在道路上翻腾，爸爸正从远处走过来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;顿时放下心来，我回来了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;后视镜里的我把脸靠近，我俩相对而视。刹那感觉镜子里的人不是我。他的刘海长了，一直垂到鼻尖，唇上青色的绒毛挂着汗珠，脸上有汗水划过的痕迹。眼白很白，眸子很黑，嘴角抿着，有点欠揍。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;哦！这就是我啊！ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;爸爸的老板来了，我喊一声&amp;ldquo;表叔&amp;rdquo;。爸爸把结的钱给他，又委托表叔把我送回家，爸爸不久后又要启程。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;表叔应允，说：&amp;ldquo;正好去看个人，顺路。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;表叔把车开过来，说：&amp;ldquo;等一会啊，我去买俩烧鸡。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;爸爸赶忙给妈妈打去电话，说：&amp;ldquo;把孩子送过去了，你去揪点菜，给孩子买了两个烧鸡，多揪点啊！ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我小心翼翼地坐上表叔的小轿车，看着父亲在车前站着，目送我离去。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他那时是40岁往上的年纪，宽额阔眼，脸面黝黑，胡须蓬乱地从鬓角连到下颚，头发挤在一起向左边偏去，左耳插着一根烟。穿着一身洗得泛白的迷彩服，裤腕卷起，一双黑布鞋粘满白色的尘土。他立在那里，身姿挺拔，双目炯炯&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到了村口，母亲已等在那里，一手提着一包蔬菜，我从车上下来，母亲把菜放到车上。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;表叔寒暄两句，一加油门，绝尘而去！ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;妈妈问：&amp;ldquo;鸡呢？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我也在想：&amp;ldquo;鸡呢？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;责任编辑：梅不谈&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;征稿信息见@ONE一个工作室置顶微博。更多编辑部的有趣日常请关注小红书：ONE一个编辑部。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FlDEKiv6uAHSPfGVZI4mSCWg180l&quot; alt=&quot;Look look&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Look look &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;抖音@Look look&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;一个多写了一点字的高铁司机。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;关注&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;相关推荐&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/4595&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;续养&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 阿虎&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/5468&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;拖拉机赛车手&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 李浩然&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6124)&quot;>;点击可下载ONE一个app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4026]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4168]]><description>&lt;div>;15 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fl18176jmVgxEvTIez_1udYlJsbm&quot; alt=&quot;首页图&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4026&lt;/span>;摄影| Kyle Head&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;15&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oct. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;想要从讨厌的地方飞出来，就得有藏起来的翅膀。&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>