<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[你觉得真心的保质期有多久？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3964]]><description> &lt;div>;2 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; ONE Studio Question&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p >;How long do you think the shelf life of sincerity is? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Zhu Deyong replied&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fq9nUt6bqIl-zj-zuR1Np57ASRmJ&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fq9nUt6bqIl-zj-zuR1Np57ASRmJ&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Nana onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Deyong’s Q&amp;A column &quot;Me≠We&quot; is exclusively updated on the &quot;ONE&quot; APP. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmPuzv4rbuXt8DD2ZiWPWVY5GDQ3 &quot; alt=&quot;Zhu Deyong&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Zhu Deyong&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;Weibo@朱德yong&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style =&quot;&quot;>;Cartoonist. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Question and Answer&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/question/3958&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Is it okay not to grow up, boss? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3948&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What was the last time you cried? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3942&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;At which moment did your childhood end? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3964)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 07:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[蒙面纪]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6144]]><description> &lt;div>;2 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Huang Yuning&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data -author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FqiqiRPlrRG5Z3Ama-pa2GEhWbWT&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FqiqiRPlrRG5Z3Ama-pa2GEhWbWT&quot;>; &lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Looking back at the future world, it is called the &quot;Mask Era&quot; During the catastrophic period, human memory is only a fog. Can we find the answer by looking back in time and space with the help of technology? Perhaps, it is difficult for humans to learn lessons from history, because the past can also be modified or deleted. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;One&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wear a virtual mask At that moment, I saw Qiao Yisi who had just entered the cubicle on my right through the surveillance camera. A cloud of fog suddenly spread in front of my eyes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Ms. Qi Nanyan, all your indicators are normal. Your slight discomfort is a normal phenomenon when you are about to enter the scene and will not have any negative impact on your health. &amp;rdquo;The cochlear implant reverberated with a soft tone, vaguely hearing the main theme of a classic science fiction film. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I feel like my discomfort is far more than mild. But I couldn’t tell how much of it came from the sudden tightening of the retro mask’s elastic band, and how much of it came from Qiao Yisi’s face. The smart devices in this room instantly detected my mental activity, and the camera focused on the light gray mole on his right eyebrow bone. I remember, ten years ago, he had the last argument with me. His facial muscles were twisted at a strange angle, pulling the mole ridiculously, and a red light appeared around it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qiao Yisi’s expression froze after three seconds. I know he also saw me through the surveillance camera. The corners of his mouth twitched a few times, probably saying a few words. He is the kind of person who will feel that he lacks depth once he speaks too clearly, and no smart device will give appropriate feedback. I slowed down my speech and protested clearly and accurately: &quot;Can I ask for a different partner?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Your partner was carefully selected and your match is almost perfect. There couldn&#39;t be more perfect data than this. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fuck you perfection. In the world of Joyce and I, nearly perfect score means falling into the abyss at the moment when you are about to reach for the stars. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Your heartbeat is slightly accelerated, and the parameters are within the upper limit of the preparation phase. This is a normal phenomenon that is about to enter the historical virtual time and space. You don&#39;t need to be nervous, close your eyes, sit quietly, and take deep breaths to help transition modes more smoothly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I should actually have thought of the possibility of meeting Qiao Yisi here. I told myself that I had not, never secretly expected to see him again here. I quickly called up Qiao Yisi&#39;s current identity on my phone. After our divorce, he really regained his former major. Historical research restorer, special level, specializing in masked history. Well, it’s still the same Qiao Yisi who is always working no matter how many clones there are in the virtual space. After the experiment is over, once he steps out of the virtual world, his papers, results, and smile on the podium will all turn out to be colorful bubbles like a basin of water with detergent thrown into it under the sun. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Of course I know how important Qiao Yisi’s work is. Thirty-eight years ago, a global digital catastrophe completely changed history, or in other words, changed the way &quot;history&quot; is stored. A hacker group that has not yet been detected has precisely attacked human digital files, especially causing a near-destructive blow to graphics and images. Since then, libraries and archives have begun to receive sufficient government funding and private donations, and paper documents and photos have once again become indispensable carriers of memory-because the harm of sporadic fires is far less than that of large-scale fires. Large-scale digital terrorist attacks. However, the damage that has been done is difficult to make up for. Those once vivid memories, all the moments that were thought to be preserved at that time and place, have been permanently deleted, leaving not even a scrap of paper or a wisp of smoke. Qiao Yisi was born in that year, and this coincidence seemed to be the only reason for him to choose his major. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was born with a mission, he said. The right corner of his mouth twitched slightly, as if with sarcasm, which destroyed all the touching power that might have been evoked when he said this. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Why did the mask era, which began in the 1930s and lasted for nearly eighty years, become the hardest hit area in this digital terrorist attack? Qiao Yisi talked about a lot, but I only remember two: First, the comprehensive upgrading of human memory carriers almost started at that time - people gradually became accustomed to tying everything about themselves to their mobile phones and immersed themselves in something. In an optimistic illusion that everyone can control memory. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;People at that time found that every moment could be broadcast live to the whole world, or thrown on the cloud, and they no longer bothered to use their brains or any tangible entity to store it. Memorized. So much so that when we look back now, the physical archives and materials from that period are much less than before. ” Qiao Yisi said thoughtfully. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secondly, &quot;That period of history was originally like a fog.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mist? What&#39;s the meaning? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Fog is just fog, the kind of thing where you can vaguely see the outline but can’t tell the boundaries. &amp;rdquo;Speaking of this, Qiao Yisi himself seemed to have fallen into a fog, and his words were filled with moisture. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;In the opinion of some people, this period of history should be forgotten. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;People’s opinions about the Masked Era are always confusing. All I know is that humans at that time were besieged by waves of microorganisms, starting from the respiratory tract and gradually spreading to the digestive tract, skin and blood. The corresponding chemical countermeasures - whether it is prevention or treatment - are always slow. After cheering for a new drug for a while, people always have to return to the oldest physical method of isolation. There are various versions of casualty figures, and the statistical calibers vary so much that you don&#39;t know which one to believe. The remaining records are filled with accusations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All kinds of protective equipment became a symbol of that period, sometimes fought for, sometimes abandoned, periodically appearing in the pitiful few paper documents and images. From masks and face shields to protective clothing and filter membranes, styles and materials are constantly being updated, which has become the most important basis for experts to judge the year. There have even been several local wars over new protective materials. All protective equipment starts from the mouth, nose and entire face, so it is reasonable to use &quot;mask&quot; to collectively refer to that era. However, by the later stage of the &quot;Mask Era&quot;, the covered part had already extended to the whole body. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I saw several original art masks covered with graffiti through the glass showcase in a museum (mostly online museums), I felt that human beings were living increasingly absurdly. In ancient times we had dinosaurs and chalk, in ancient times we had bronze. In modern times, we can only use masks to mark an era of amnesia. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;We lack first-hand information. What was the living situation of people during those gloomy eighty years? What were they thinking? We seem to know and yet we don&#39;t seem to know. &quot;At that time, Qiao Yisi was like a true thinker. No matter whether he was holding an ancient book or a soft pillow, he seemed to have grasped the lever that could move history. Ten years later, through the surveillance camera, I saw this expression on his face again. He must be the main creator of the large-scale virtual reality academic experiment &quot;The Masked Age&quot;, I have no doubt about it. More than ten years ago, he had a friend who was a well-known entertainment software designer in the VR industry. It is said that after making enough money in the past two years, he switched to cooperating with academic institutions. It was probably Qiao Yisi who had the connection. I even remember the man&#39;s name was Wu Jun. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As for me - I am just a curious volunteer in the pilot project of this large experiment. They said that this experiment requires sensitive writers who can quickly enter the situation and be good at detaching later, preferably women. They say that female writers&#39; ability to capture details is very important in restoring that important historical memory. I said yes, I qualify. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I lied, I did not meet the last condition. I&#39;m not sure how long it will take to get out of the overly realistic experience. If this experiment is as &quot;unparalleledly realistic&quot; as its operation instructions suggest, and reproduces that &quot;vacant historical detail&quot; for the first time, my consciousness may be trapped in that mess for a long time. I thought I would throw up, my stomach would shrink into weird shapes, and I wouldn&#39;t be able to write anything. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You have signed a confidentiality authorization agreement. In other words, during the entire experiment, we have the right to use your physical data, brainwave images and conversation records for academic research, and guarantee not to disclose any of your privacy to any third party. These usage rights do not include your VR videos. In order to reduce your concerns about historical time and space, we will not record virtual videos throughout the process. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Confirm. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Please confirm again. Selecting the semi-immersive mode means that you can always maintain a clear sense of time during the entire experiment. Your current identity and memory will conflict with the situation in the experiment to a certain extent. It&#39;s a shame that you won&#39;t be able to fully experience the realism of this experiment. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I confirm... So Joe - I mean my partner, what mode did he choose? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;No one answered me. The music in the cochlea begins to change, the melody line gradually blurs, and the notes stick to each other. A series of dissonant intervals with an overly strong electronic feel. These scattered elements eventually coalesce into a sound similar to whooshing through a tunnel. I lay flat in the sleeping cabin, closed my eyes according to the prompt, and allowed the sound to gather a hurricane, sucking me into the world of the Masked Era (120 to 200 years ago). &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Two&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The streets are empty. But this kind of emptiness still carries traces of being full not long ago, and it is completely different from the kind of emptiness I am used to. In the real world where I live, virtual reality technology has made breakthrough developments in the past ten years, and many people have spent more time in sleep cabins than outside. In the virtual world, they can go to Chicago for an academic conference in the morning and go surfing in Tahiti in the afternoon. In reality, the streets are really empty - you occasionally take a walk there, and you are surrounded by a safe and confused atmosphere. This aura is so stable, as if it originates from eternity and leads directly to the future. But in the sky one or two hundred years ago, there was hidden uneasiness that was about to emerge. The glass curtain wall of the commercial building reflected the dazzling sunlight boringly. I turned sideways to avoid the direct sunlight, and my eyes fell on a row of store signs. McDonald&#39;s. HUAWEI Digital Experience Center. A showroom for some Japanese and Korean brand cars. No wonder, I thought. Since this experiment is going to flaunt the fidelity of details, these superficial things, which are the easiest to do, must be done enough. After all, as we all know, the last sunset of the era of globalization falls on those highly similar and indistinguishable street scenes of the &quot;Era of Masks.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the city&#39;s landmark buildings will never appear - I have seen this in the experiment guide. Virtual reality scenes will abandon all markers that allow you to accurately locate time and space. You can&#39;t judge from the explosion marks on the Millennium Bridge that you are standing in London in 2088, nor can you expect to guess that you are trapped in the predicament of the early 22nd century (microorganisms are raging) from the distant snowy view of the pyramids. , rapid climate change and the resulting disputes will soon make the negative growth of the earth&#39;s total population exceed the warning level). Yes, you can&#39;t. In this experiment, you don&#39;t know what night it is, and you can&#39;t tell where you are on the earth. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Times have changed. If mankind has learned any lessons from those years, it is: put aside what should be shelved, blur what should be blurred, and use the time cost of mutual accusations to solve practical problems. The rights and wrongs of the Masked Chronicle, various true and false traceability behaviors entangled with political intentions, gave rise to unexpected secondary disasters. So much so that, now, even if it is an academic VR experiment, it must carefully avoid all hidden dangers that violate political correctness and protect this well-kept scar in human history. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;We do not participate in value judgments. Our research object is not historical events, but daily life. In our view, the Masked Period is a whole in the time dimension. As for the spatial dimension, that is the entire earth. Our destiny is connected and we all live the same life. &amp;rdquo;Not surprisingly, the slogans in the guides are always so empty and correct. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In short, I feel that my body is standing on a chaotic virtual coordinates, and about half of my consciousness is still stuck in the real world. Some slight centrifugal force seemed to pull me up from the ancient streets at any time. I took a hard breath through the mask, and finally I didn&#39;t let myself hang dangling in the air like a balloon. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Have you worn it for a long time? Qi Nanyan, you need to regulate your breathing. But don’t take it off—Qiao Yisi’s voice seems to come from far and near, and the distortion gradually decreases. In fact, I realized, his coordinates were right next to mine. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I can&#39;t believe he&#39;s here with me. As soon as we opened our mouths, the other person&#39;s name - the name one or two hundred years from now - came out naturally. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qiao Yisi’s tone contained a bit of the nervousness I was familiar with, but it seemed to be given new content. He muttered something, half of which was the latest protection guidelines issued by the city, and half of which was the newly updated case data. This is a typical performance of information overflow when entering an experiment, and it is completely normal. Qiao Yisi&#39;s choice was obviously the opposite to mine. He was in full immersion mode. During the process of entering the sleep chamber, a large amount of environment settings and background knowledge were input through the brain-computer interface, temporarily overwriting his existing memory of the real world. He is sinking wholeheartedly into a certain stage of the Masked Era. He will unconditionally accept all the chaos and anxiety of that era, accept the partner assigned to him by the program, and the entire story line about this partner. I thought about what I would do if this damn program gave me a vulgar personality. The kind of sweet and sensible wife who will definitely shut up when she should be silent. The woman I never became in reality. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I didn’t expect him to choose this way. As a historical research restorer of the Masked Chronicles, his research results (the fragments of history left behind by family memories, a collection of unclear and even contradictory oral accounts) are woven into the storyline and image scenes of the entire VR experiment; But he himself had to put aside the sophisticated external perspective, give up his sense of security, and run naked in the experiment. In other words, he will be severely squeezed and ridiculed by the historical details of his &quot;repair&quot;, and what he can get from this experience is a direct reaction of all thoughts, emotions and bodies uploaded in real time. I even had some doubts that my encounter with him was not a coincidence. As a member of the experiment&#39;s development team (and possibly a consultant), he has access to the list of volunteers. I imagine he would have convinced himself that emotion must give way to valuable historical research. From any angle, we are the most suitable and matching partners. The dislocation of the roles of rationality and sensibility can spark unexpected sparks. I remember him saying such incomprehensible things before. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His excitement, which was obviously in a state of stress, was like a magnetic wind, picking me up and stuffing me dizzy into an off-road vehicle with luggage piled in the back seat. He stepped on the accelerator and the car went ten kilometers. In just these five minutes, I roughly pieced together the story that the brain-computer interface had instilled in him from the turbulence of information that was constantly flowing out of Qiao Yisi. We have been married for five years, have no children, and have a cat - currently sleeping happily in a transparent backpack in the back seat. Our relationship was a bit strained - which was totally unoriginal. Our city has seen a recent surge in cases and deaths, along with entirely new symptoms. Once the virus enters through the respiratory tract, it may invade every corner of the body and quickly trigger immune hyperactivity. The stronger the immune system, the greater the intensity of this hyperactivity. Most of the victims are young adults. They are like sycamore trees that stretch their branches and leaves ignorantly in the face of the typhoon, and are falling one by one. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This city is becoming the center of a new round of virus mutation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I think, at this pace, the city will soon enter sleep mode. He glanced at the news that kept popping up on his digital watch and muttered to himself: &quot;Fortunately, I just got a pass.&quot; There&#39;s enough time. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All the passively received information was finally synthesized in my consciousness. &amp;ldquo;Are we... running away? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You were strangled by the mask and your brain was deprived of oxygen, right?...Didn’t we agree? We&#39;re going out of town. What time has it been? Stop being willful, okay? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even Qiao Yisi felt that things were getting out of control, so she had to quickly turn up the volume of the car stereo to try to swallow the last sentence. It&#39;s like there is a thick code book between Qiao Yisi and me. The word &quot;willful&quot; alone is enough to restart all the unpleasant memories from ten years ago. In my imagination, everyone&#39;s consciousness is a small building with seven or eight floors. If these memories are suspended on my sixth level, then they should be buried in Joyce&#39;s vault - they were squeezed, crushed, and scattered by his full immersion mode, but they still permeated tenaciously. in all his actions. I have no way of distinguishing which part belongs to his stress reaction to the experimental scene and which part belongs to his inexplicable reaction to me driven by residual memories; I don’t know which part belongs to the Masked Era and which belongs to the Post-Masked Era. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I let out a sigh, and the mask bulged out. A stream of hot air surged upwards, overflowing from the sides of the mask, and a layer of wet mist formed in front of my eyes. I think the current VR technology is too realistic. In an era when it has become an antique and only a few examples still lie in museums, it is actually possible to recreate the feeling of wearing a face mask through sensors. Moist, sticky, almost suffocating, that legendary classical ambiguity, how exactly does it simulate it? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I can’t go with you. It would be best for us to go our separate ways. &amp;rdquo;I heard myself say softly but firmly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It&#39;s like a quarrel that lasted for a hundred or two hundred years. The past and the past are irrelevant, but the emotions are all connected. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qiao Yisi didn&#39;t care to answer my words, she clenched her fist and smashed it on her thigh. The car stumbled one after another, and finally stalled completely. The navigation showed that our coordinates were less than 500 meters away from the intersection of the expressway out of the city, and we were unable to move due to the traffic flowing in front, back, left and right. I looked out from the passenger seat. To the right of us, there was a driver yelling at his cell phone, then pressing it down, lowering his head, and burying his face in his broad palms. Then he got out of the car and walked back and forth in the gaps between cars, borrowing fires from others to smoke, and after chatting with each other for a few words, he became more and more excited. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;He should have been here several times. Knowing that there was little hope, I wanted to try my luck again. &amp;rdquo;Qiao Yisi said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;At least, there is someone waiting for him outside. Someone deserves this. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You are still like this, you like to make up stories. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You are still like this, unable to understand the story. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ten minutes later, a drone hovering on the roof of the car got closer and closer, issuing instructions. Qiao Yisi pressed the button to open the sunroof, and the remote sensing physical sign detection system collected our data in ten seconds. After another ten seconds, the drone turned on a red light and my ID number was announced. The machine repeated over and over again: &quot;One or more of your physical signs are not up to standard and you are not eligible for passage.&quot; Please go to the hospital to check by yourself. Thank you for your cooperation. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The light is green on the other side of Qiao Yisi. He reacted quickly and held my hand that was about to open the door. &quot;Don&#39;t be stupid,&quot; he said, &quot;Can I let you go to the hospital alone?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You still have time to get out. I deserve it, who allowed me to be willful? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He snorted, as if he wanted to sneer at it, but I could see that his shoulders and arms were stiff. The new strain has just spread in local areas, virologists around the world have only limited samples, and there is no consensus on many issues. One can imagine Qiao Yisi&#39;s nervousness. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Just the same old thing. Delay, divert, and control the number of spillovers. You may have been picked at random. &amp;rdquo;He was comforting me, but his tone was more like comforting himself. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The vehicles on both sides seemed to be frightened by the red light and gasped. They all used their driving skills to turn at incredible angles and actually made way for a narrow road, allowing Qiao Yisi to fall out. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There was a rustle in the back seat, and the cat turned over in the transparent bag. She obviously had a good dream. She raised her flesh pads and stretched out her claws to hook the ventilation holes on the bag. She grunted and was reluctant to open her eyes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;三&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The testing point at the entrance of the hospital was chaotic group. The originally designed closed-loop system was deformed by the flow of people from time to time and branched into two or three tributaries. There are always people who line up in the wrong line, or who suddenly faint when their legs give out while standing in line, causing a burst of exclamations. There were not enough staff wearing medical protective equipment. Two robots trying to guide the flow of people in accordance with operating regulations were slapped several times by more than a dozen angry hands and finally collided. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My heart was beating hard and I was retching. The sound field in the hospital is too realistic, with countless sounds bouncing and flapping on the eardrums at the same time. It was like I was sealed in a glass bubble, surrounded by invisible solids. It’s also semi-immersive mode after all, I guess. It’s true that half of me—maybe more than half of me—is already a believer in virtual environments. I am getting more and more into the character, and those abstract symptoms that once appeared in historical materials seem to be fulfilled in me. Dry cough, body heat and cold, chest tightness and shortness of breath. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My sense of reality is weakening at a steady pace, and the only connection between me and the outside world is a kite string that is about to be broken, wrapped around my wrist. I subconsciously wanted to hold on to it. I have indeed never seen these pre-modern hospitals - in real life I rarely even need to go to the hospital. I live in a world where telemedicine has long been mainstream. Even if a minor surgery is required, within an hour a sterile tent can be set up in your living room. This is just enough time for a medical surgical robot to arrive with a large set of instruments and prepare for surgery. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hospitals during the mask rule, especially those at the center of the epidemic storm, were really oppressive. I glanced at Qiao Yisi. Even though he was wearing a mask, I could still clearly see that his face was turning pale from the edge of the mask. He was even more flustered than me because he didn&#39;t have the kite string in his hand. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We all wear plastic gloves. He was afraid that I would be scattered by the crowd, so he held my hand. In the heat of the room, my gloves and his were almost sticking together. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You still have time to leave now. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Stop making trouble. We still have time to quarrel, it doesn&#39;t have to be now. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Now I know for sure that this is a storyline that works for us. I don&#39;t have to think hard at all and can just follow along. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;How do you know we still have time? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Then what else do you want? All places to apply for certificates are now closed. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As expected. In this story line, our relationship only needs a divorce procedure to end. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When the robot inserted the probe into my nasal cavity, the soreness and numbness seemed to reach my tear ducts. The inspector sitting aside hardly even raised his eyelids, and motioned to me, with blurred eyes, to quickly follow the team on the right. Only those patients who fainted in the queue or were obviously out of breath while clutching their chests were likely to be carried on the stretcher on the left side and sent to the intensive care unit. But stretchers are also queuing up. I glanced over and saw that the two stretchers that had been carried into the glass door on the left an hour ago were still lying in the same position. There are no more new hospital beds available. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The whole city is busy. But most of the energy is consumed on various assembly lines. People are transported from one level to another, and then, like being stuffed into a revolving door, they turn around and are sent back. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Ms. Qi Nanyan, within three hours, your test results will appear on your mobile phone, and your data will enter the CDC monitoring network. We will take countermeasures according to the priority of the situation. Please go home and wait. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is no medicine, there are people to verify vaccination records, precautions for home isolation and self-healing of mild illness were repeatedly broadcast, among which the word &quot;believe&quot; appeared most frequently. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I followed Qiao Yisi numbly, got in the car, got out of the car, and visited three supermarkets in succession, each one more deserted than the last. We soon realized that looking at the shelves was in vain. Only on the open space next to the shelves could we pick up a few potatoes and two bags of instant noodles (one of which had a tear in it) that had rolled off the shelves during the scramble. ) and a small package of cat food with a buy three, get two free label. Qiao Yisi scanned the code at the automatic checkout counter, but the machine had no response. She didn&#39;t know who had unplugged it. I waved my hand at Qiao Yisi who was in a daze, urging him to leave quickly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Don’t be stupid. I&#39;ll settle the money with them later. &quot;Although I also know that in the Masked Era, the sense of time becomes erratic - when you talk about the future, especially &quot;after the disaster,&quot; you never know how long it will be.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My test results arrived at the same time as the city’s hibernation announcement. &amp;ldquo;Negative. This does not mean that your risk is over, as the incubation period can range from three to 30 days. Please observe your physical signs closely and consciously maintain social distance from others. &amp;rdquo;Just when Qiao Yisi finished reading this sentence word for word, we happened to walk to the door of Room 101. His face was quickly scanned by the camera, and the door opened with a sound. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is the home of Joyce and me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The lights are turned on one by one, and the furniture seems to emerge one by one from the depths of memory. The dark green matte leather sofa and the pumpkin-colored wooden carved fruit plate are obviously second-hand goods that Joyce picked up from an antique store; all the lead-gray bookshelves look like they have been washed twice by cold water or moonlight, and those minimalist lines are deliberately cold. , I should have chosen them all. One or two hundred years later, our tastes are still completely different. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The cat returned to its familiar residence and suddenly lost its sleepiness. She quickly found the darkest corner of the living room, her pure black fur gently disappearing into the shadows, her yellow-green cat eyes getting wider and wider, shining with a faint light. But she didn&#39;t seem to be interested in us. She just stared at the patio outside the floor-to-ceiling windows of the living room. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Corona, don’t run around. &amp;rdquo;I heard Joyce calling the cat’s name. Coronavirus is a well-known global epidemic before the Masked Era. Although its scale and intensity are smaller than a series of viruses during the Masked Era, it is generally considered to be a warning preview of the Masked Era. It&#39;s more my style to give a cat such an ironic name. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kona ignored Qiao Yisi’s warning and still approached the floor-to-ceiling window step by step. I walked over and pushed it gently with my hand, and the floor-to-ceiling window opened along the slide rails. Connor jumped out and without hesitation found the familiar small hole at the root of the patio wall. She curled up and got out, blending into the dusk outside the wall. Like a piece of dark chocolate dropped into endless milk tea. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What are you doing? Cats don’t understand, and neither do you? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I turned my back to Qiao Yisi, not wanting him to see the first smile on my face since I entered this experiment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Four&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In virtual experiments, the measurement of time It&#39;s a wonderful thing. I will never understand how ten minutes in real life can be expanded and contracted at will in the virtual space - it can be squashed into one second, or stretched into a month or ten years, and not only do you take it for granted, And it&#39;s not as chaotic as in the dream. You feel the passage of time precisely. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When did the kite string disappear? In other words, when did I start not realizing that I had a cable in my hand? I have no idea. I seem to fall asleep easily in my virtual home. When I vaguely saw the reflection of reality in my dream for the first time, and when I dreamed about the present during the Masked Era, I may have already crossed that dividing line, and have been wandering between semi-immersion mode and full-immersion mode ever since. in the gap between. All the memories about the outside world are broken into strands of gossamer, floating in my subconscious, and will not emerge until the critical moment. I have to declare that for all the narratives from that time on, I have lost my reliable footing and no longer have the same stable and complete memory as I did before. The text you read below mainly relies on the chaotic tracing after the experiment, the splicing of fragments, and even fiction. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Of course there are benefits to this. The two time and space no longer collided, and my body and heart accepted the reality of a hundred or two hundred years ago: I was locked in the same house with my husband, who was about to divorce. The farthest distance we could go was the lobby on the first floor. There, we wore face masks (with goggle lenses embedded in the masks), exchanged glances with our neighbors, and received rationed daily necessities stacked by drones at our doorsteps. The supply of supplies has not been cut off, but the varieties and portions are getting smaller and smaller. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I had no further symptoms worth recording. I might have a slight fever in the afternoon, but it seemed to only add a little change to my body feel and complexion. After observing my health data for three consecutive days, Qiao Yisi also lost interest. &quot;Well,&quot; he said, &quot;psychologically induced sympathetic and parasympathetic imbalance. In the past two years, such &quot;false mental positives&quot; have been very common. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;There is really nothing you can’t explain. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He didn’t intend to refute my sarcasm, but just used a little force to bury his body deeper into the dark green sofa, making a dent in the leather. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At first, everything was self-explanatory. We each occupied a bedroom in a tacit agreement, staggered the time to go to the living room, kitchen, bathroom and patio, and moved all sharp and fragile things to places where we could not easily grab them. Projection TVs on the walls scrolled with updates on the epidemic, from the city to neighboring provinces and around the world. Most of the time, we set the sound on mute, no one was interested in watching it seriously, but no one wanted to turn it off. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;偶尔，当乔易思在落地窗边的书桌上跟国外的公司总部连线开视频会议时，我透过厨房的玻璃滑门远远地看他的背影。上半身西装领带，下半身条纹睡裤和棉拖鞋。我熟悉这样的背影&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;我们在现实中结婚的那几年，他打的也是一份跟历史专业没什么关系的工。这些会议显然没什么要紧，多半只是为了给老板提供世界还在运转的错觉。乔易思不时抬起头冲着屏幕露出标准格式的微笑（美颜镜头足以将他那颗痣淡化到近乎消失），然后垂下目光，悄悄看一眼台式机的摄像头拍不到的左侧。他是左撇子，单手就能在笔记本上打游戏通关。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我记得他的左手。记得食指和无名指微妙的触感，记得它滑过我的后颈时那种刻意的停顿。我的呼吸也跟着停下半拍，一拍，一拍半。他的右手就没有这么邪性。他只会用他厚实的右掌轻轻按住我的肩。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无论如何，在一个ＶＲ游戏里看一个人打游戏（尽管蒙面纪时代的游戏实在很低级），总是一件诡异的事，哪怕我当时并没有清晰地意识到这一点。我的太阳穴微微悸动，我的身体的某些部分，隐约觉得堕入了无限循环的套娃，害怕卡在哪一层里出不去。可是当时我告诉自己，我不喜欢看乔易思打游戏，仅仅因为他曾经在现实世界的联机游戏里，跟别的女人聊得忘乎所以。那是我们吵架的经典话题。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;所有曾经吵到想同归于尽的夫妻，都知道沉默的价值&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;何况你根本不知道这样被关在一起还要过多久。我在厨房里烧汤，留在锅里的正好够他盛一碗；他煎鸡蛋，多撂一个在盘子里，搁在灶台上。我在汤里留着惟一的那块带着软骨的肉排，而他撂下的蛋一定是蛋白刚好只焦了一层卷边、蛋黄凝结了三分之一的那种。我猜，以他的厨艺水平，为了煎一个火候合适的，他自己得吃掉两个煎废的。我们不需要说话，就可以把越来越少的配给食品安排妥帖。我把房子里所有的库存食品写在纸上，贴在冰箱表面。他默默地跟着我在上面打勾。我们之间就好像心照不宣地捧着一只松松垮垮的箱子，但凡有一头倾斜，里面说不定就会有条蛇钻出来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沉默在第三天打破，因为猫粮快要耗尽，而配给食品里并没有宠物的份。我顺手拿起一把漏勺在不锈钢锅沿上蹭出不太悦耳的声响。在乔易思从厨房门前经过的一刹那，我重重地叹口气。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;明天，只够明天了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;什么？ &amp;rdquo;他果然停下来，&amp;ldquo;不是还有那么多没打勾的？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我只轻轻提了句寇娜，他便回过神来，随即去开冰箱门，想翻翻冷冻室里有没有鸡胸或者三文鱼碎肉，可以照着网上的方子做。他手里在忙活，嘴里也没闲着：&amp;ldquo;我知道你在想什么。不行，真的不行。你不看新闻的吗？太危险了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;寇娜本来就会常常出去遛个弯，她找得到回家的路。人家就是这么长大的。她可不懂什么叫隔离。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;可是我们一向不让她晚上出门。我们一向会在傍晚，在猫洞的这一头洒上她喜欢的猫薄荷，把她勾引回来，然后堵上那个洞。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;夜晚，是猫科动物捕食的最佳时刻。 &amp;rdquo;我学着动物纪录片的口吻，捏着嗓子朗诵。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我的眼睛一定隔着面罩上的护目镜片闪着令人气恼的光，因为乔易思突然把面罩往下一拽，露出鼻孔哧哧地呼着粗气。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你，有没有必要，故意听不懂我的话？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我知道他在说什么。我知道如今有不少人正在把无处安放的怒火，往动物身上扔。病毒的中间宿主的候选名单，正在被越拉越长。人们的视线，渐渐从亚洲的蝙蝠和美洲的鹿转向了全世界所有的家庭宠物。虽然从这些动物身上检测到病毒并不能证明它们会传染给人类，但是那些私刑诱捕宠物的激进组织早就不是什么新事物。他们给一只泰迪或者布偶实施人道毁灭的时候，会录制视频。他们在镜头前出示检测报告，点上香薰烛。他们会穿好白色的简易防护装备。你看不见他们的脸。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我不信他们抓得住寇娜，&amp;rdquo;我冷冷地说，&amp;ldquo;她的智商比他们高多了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你简直&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;不可理喻。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你才不可理喻。我们已经把日子过成这样了，你还想关住一只猫？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我的话对乔易思并没有什么作用。最终，他之所以妥协，是因为寇娜不喜欢吃他做的东西。傍晚，她用爪子拨弄那一坨他花了两个小时鼓捣出的白色肉泥，瞳孔先是放大一圈，又缩成一条竖线，几乎要抱着猫盆睡着了。我忍不住，扑哧一声笑出来，喷湿了大半个面罩。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;夜渐深。乔易思终于打开落地窗。寇娜难以置信地在猫洞周围转了两圈，发现我们完全没有阻拦的意思，这才欢喜地呜咽了一声，钻出去。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我给她戴了GPS项圈，&amp;rdquo;乔易思喃喃地说，&amp;ldquo;项圈上有针孔摄像头。如果碰到什么事情&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;她不会有什么事，你放心，&amp;rdquo;我说。当我发现我的声音和口吻一下子柔软了很多时，自己也吓了一跳。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;五&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;寇娜是只特别的猫，特别到没有什么现成的宠物养育指南能罩得住她。乔易思说那是因为八个月前我从空调外机上捡到她开始，就在跟指南对着干。那一小团黑影蜷缩在那里，身体随着外机的运转而微微震动。她并不因为有人用一条毯子把她裹起来挪进屋子里，喂两口牛奶，让她的眼睛发亮，就成天跟你黏在一起。她喜欢寻找跟她的毛色相近的暗黑角落躲起来，她相信观察要比被观察更安全。似乎从一进门开始，寇娜就自觉维持着对人类最低限度的依赖。除了有一次尿湿了地毯，她的发情期似乎过得并不艰难。她一定能听见窗外野猫凄厉的叫声，但只要我们在家，她就保持着高贵的沉默。面对这样一只猫，你不可能想到给她做什么绝育手术或者修剪猫爪。墙根上始终留着几道抓痕，但你就是看不到她是什么时候挠的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一连好几天，我们都在清早的天井里，看到精疲力尽的寇娜在一小块半黄半绿的草地上睡觉。阳光照在她毛茸茸的耳朵上，乌亮乌亮，色彩饱和度高到几乎要溢出画面。再细细打扫战场，还能在她的爪子边找到几撮沾着血迹的赭黄鸟毛，甚至，一截灰色的鼠类的尾巴。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自从寇娜每天晚上出门之后，我和乔易思都不约而同地早起。我们的时间表，似乎突然间就有了一大块交集。天井里那个小而隐蔽的猫洞，成了这闷罐子一般的房子通往外界的惟一的气孔。不止是寇娜，我们也需要从那里透一口气。寇娜GPS项圈上的夜视红外摄像头会把视频传到乔易思的电脑上。每天早上，乔易思就把视频投影到客厅里的墙上，我们轮流拉着进度条，看看寇娜昨晚经历了什么。那些由寇娜的下巴、下垂的几根胡须以及地面框出来的画面有一种莫名其妙的吸引力。我们挪不开视线，傻乎乎地跟着她从汽车底盘下钻出去，小区的冬青树篱渐渐在眼前清晰，继而又模糊起来。 GPS显示，她的活动范围远远超出我们的想象，一口气就跑到了一公里之外的公园里。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;捕食反而不如想象中好看，因为动作太快了。摄像头跟着她的身体剧烈摇晃，跟着她一跃而起，跳到超过她身长七倍的高度。画面上闪过一团接一团的虚影。镜头几乎捕捉不到猎物，配上撕咬扑腾的声音，你会觉得寇娜是在跟自己战斗。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;画面上显示凌晨一点。一团漆黑中寇娜的步子缓下来，喉咙里发出我们熟悉的咕噜咕噜的声音。突然，镜头一个激灵，抖了两抖之后稳稳地聚焦在前方树丛里的两点微光上。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;嗯？ &amp;rdquo;乔易思也跟着一个激灵。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从微光闪烁的那个方向，传来一个清晰而响亮的长音。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;这是&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;猫。另一只猫，&amp;rdquo;我说，&amp;ldquo;雄性。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你怎么知道？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;直觉。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乔易思一时语塞。我们就这样默默地看着寇娜在画面中一动不动地与对面的公猫对峙。寇娜显然是侵入了对方的领地。能在公园的中央草坪里立下山头的，我想，应该是一只强壮的公猫。红外线下，他灰色的轮廓在镜头里渐渐清晰，看起来确实比寇娜大一圈。在对峙中，动物的首要原则是不把后背暴露给对方，所以这样的对峙常常会持续很久。乔易思一直等到镜头对面的猫先转过身去，才松了一口气。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我们的寇娜，&amp;rdquo;他几乎笑出声来，&amp;ldquo;并不是一只普通的猫。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我想你说反了吧。也许这恰恰说明寇娜也是一只普通的猫，像所有普通的猫那样具有对异性放电的本能。这并不是奇迹，只是故事换了一种类型而已。可我没说出口。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此后几天的进程证实了我的猜测。寇娜每天半夜里的坐标都会定格在公园里的大草坪上。武打片果然变成了言情剧，只不过，他们的互相试探缓慢而耐心，好像拿得准这一场恋爱可以谈上一百年。他们不用理会这个世界已经乱成了什么样，不用担心被那些从四面八方涌来的亢奋的话题日复一日地消耗，淹没。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预防接种，特效药，还是精准隔离？城市的自我修复还有多少潜力可挖？虚拟现实经济是否迎来划时代机遇？面罩熔喷布为何面临淘汰？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;淘汰？前一阵不是还抢得天翻地覆吗？有两个国家还差点打起来。 &amp;rdquo;我随口问道。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;纳米。打个比方，熔喷布是用粗线编细网，纳米是细线编细网。所以，不管是透气性还是过滤性，纳米的优势都很明显。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;照这情形，面罩迟早有一天要长在脸上。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;没准儿&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;材料往极限发展，配合人体基因的突变，也许再过一百年，两百年&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乔易思的语调像是在梦游。已经有很久没看到他这样漫不经心了。真是难得，这一刻，他居然发觉天底下有比拯救世界更重要的事。他几乎把整张脸都贴到了墙上，好像以为这样就能把那只勾搭寇娜的猫看清楚。我说大半夜的红外拍成这样已经很不错了，也许我们得靠想象。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;想象初秋深夜被露水打湿的草地，想象一只猫与另一只猫的目光与气味紧贴着地面彼此缠结。寇娜的每次温驯的静止，每次伴随着低频声的颤抖，都好像有什么事情正在发生或者即将发生。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;其实我们不可能确凿地知道，&amp;rdquo;乔易思摇摇头，往后一仰，歪躺在沙发上。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;为什么？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;因为摄像头装在项圈上，差不多在喉咙口的位置。你不可能看见她的后颈被他的牙轻轻咬住&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;你说那只愣头愣脑的家伙，能不能把力度控制得刚刚好？我担心寇娜受伤。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;为什么非得是脖子？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;因为这是猫交配的标准姿势。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;哦。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;同理，从那个位置，你也很难判断她在什么时候弯曲前爪，贴地匍匐，给他一个信号，告诉他我准备好了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;哦。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你不担心？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;不担心。我养的猫，没那么好追。她慢热。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;跟你一样慢？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;晚了。当我说出这句话的时候，就知道晚了。我的背正对着他，我们之间的距离刚好够他的胳膊舒服地绕过来环抱住我的肩。我的头脑还在抵抗，可我身体表皮的每一个神经末梢，都在等待触摸、碰撞和揉搓。接着，在仿佛只有十分钟、却又好像长达一个世纪的时间里，天花板上他选的贝壳吊灯，茶几下面我挑的米色地毯，交替着、旋转着出现在我的视野里。我努力半睁着眼睛，不想让自己晕过去。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我只记得一件事。我们最后脱下的，是面罩。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;六&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虚拟学术实验（蒙面纪）抽样对话实录。实验内身份&amp;mdash;夫妻，场景&amp;mdash;封闭室内。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;1. 第九天（场景内时间，与现实世界并无关联。以下同）&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行了&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;沙发&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;给我一条毯子。要命，寇娜什么时候来的？她在看我们。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没事，她在看投影。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;视频一直开着？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根本就没关过。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;你猜，寇娜知不知道投影上那个，就是她自己？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不好说。我想至少一定能认出那小子。你低头看看寇娜的脖子，贴着项圈那一道，毛都给他咬秃了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她有什么办法？她也没地儿可逃啊。天塌下来，总算有另一只猫，一起扛着。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我知道你在想什么。咱们这种人，就只适合在天塌下来的时候守在一起，是不是？回头天又支棱起来，咱就接茬吵架，接茬离婚。我说，齐南雁，衣服还没穿好呢，你可不可以不要这么扫兴？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那就不说这个了。我问你，那天，你为什么不出城？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我为什么要出城？孤魂野鬼，就算逃出去了，又有什么意思？你记不记得电视上那哥们，在两座城市之间的高速公路上来回跑，哪头都不收留他。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我现在觉得，你没走成，还是比走了，要好一点。也许是好很多。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哦。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2. 第十三天&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那些人又在物资配给群里撒传单。我们正在分压缩饼干呢，突然就有带动画的标语落下来。怼着脸问你：要猫权，还是人权？你想象不出他们有多能扯。从剑齿虎开始，把猫科动物跟灵长类的世仇整个捋一遍。蝙蝠和鹿什么的，那都离咱们太远，他们瞧不上。只有猫&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;带着家族使命忍辱负重，潜伏在千家万户&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;你还别说，那套说辞全须全尾的，还挺像那么回事。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;你忍一忍，当他们不存在。我是忍不下去，早就退了那个群。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;可是退了这个，还能到哪里去？现在有哪个群不在吵架？有多少道理在天上飞？你飞你的我飞我的，哪跟哪都不挨着。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人类是一盘散沙，需要一个共同的敌人。病毒那玩意儿，他们看不见摸不着的，怎么打？猫不大不小，伸手可及，最合适。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;别他们他们的。人类不是他们，是我们。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;好吧&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;我们。我猜，我们人类的如意算盘，就是天上掉下一头奶牛，一个挤奶工&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;必须是女的，长得顺眼，凯特&amp;middot;温斯莱特那种型号的。这样一来，那个叫詹纳的英国人就能多看她两眼，有兴趣多听她说两句家常话。聊着聊着，就把牛痘的秘密给聊出来了。我们人类，跟传染病斗了上千年，也就只有这一场，堪称完胜。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;可是，如果没有奶牛没有温斯莱特怎么办？病毒就跟你软磨着硬泡着，你一巴掌下去拍不死它，它换件马甲从后门溜出去，在地球上绕一圈，一个月就转回来。问题在于，你不可能同时把世界上每一道门都关死。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从历史的角度看&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;又是历史的角度。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了历史，我们手里还有什么？我在打一个游戏，罗马帝国兴衰史。千算万算，没有把鼠疫和天花&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;那会儿叫什么盖伦瘟疫&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;给算进去，哗啦一下积分就清零了。我去找书看，那年头是实打实地清零，人口一清就是几百万。你猜起因是什么？不过就是罗马人打了胜仗，从别人城里卷走一大堆战利品，病毒跟着金银珠宝一起回了家。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;可怜的&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;我们人类。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;可是你们人类很快就学会了使用它。也就隔了几百年吧，有一支军队攻打一座城，围城围了一半，自己倒快要被鼠疫清零了。你猜怎么着，他们想了一招，把自己人的尸体绑在弓弩上，愣是一箭一箭射进城里&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;天哪，这算生物武器？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最早的生物武器。效果很显著。结局？当然是他妈的反败为胜。这法子后来屡试不爽，征服异族最快的办法，就是带着先进的武器和陌生的病毒一块去。团灭，干脆得很。你们&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;我们&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;还是说咱们人类吧，总会胜利的。两军对垒，打到最后，耗到你全军覆没，我这里哪怕只剩一个人，也是我赢了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是现在&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;可不好说。人口流动速度那么快，谁围住谁，谁活到最后，真还不好说呢。整个世界，难道，不是连在一起的吗？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;道理是这个道理，但是&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;他们&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;我是说咱们&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;要是都懂这个道理&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（做了一杯咖啡的时间）&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;竟然还有豆子&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;你囤了多少？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没多少。最后几粒曼特宁豆子都在里面了，剩下的都是速溶，还能撑个把月。明天开始定个量吧，一天不能超过一杯，下礼拜两天不能超过一杯。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;你就没想过，也许我们都活不过囤的这些东西？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没想过。想也没用。从文学的角度看&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;好吧终于轮到了文学。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;怎么说呢，小说家的态度其实很不一样。笛福，就是写鲁滨孙的那个人，他更像个记者&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;好吧他本来就是个记者。他的空间感不错，如果让他用写《瘟疫年纪事》的方法来写我们现在的生活，我想他对我们本人的兴趣也许还不如对我们的房子更大。他会先画一张城市地图，精确记下每栋房子的位置。只有他，会在我们天井的猫洞上做一个标记。他会强调隔离的必要性，同时又对我们充满遥远的、抽象的同情。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;所以这位福先生，经历过伦敦的鼠疫大暴发？那不还是得回到历史的角度看嘛，我记得那是十七世纪。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;伦敦瘟疫时他只有五岁。小说家都是骗子。他扮演了一个当年在伦敦满大街蹓跶，亲眼目击全过程的幸存者。他说十万人被一扫而光，而我还活着。我简直可以想象他说这话时的表情。像电影里的超级英雄，浑身长满了塑料的那种。他写得很好。每一个字都像是亲眼所见的那样生动。从此，他伪造的这份回忆录，本身就成了历史的一部分，成了灾难叙事的样本。比如加缪。加先生写《鼠疫》里的大场面，基本上就没跳出过福先生的框架。 &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;你是说，加缪是抄的？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那可不能这么说。加缪在笛福的灾难片框架里加了个西西弗斯式的救灾小分队，格局就不一样了。人性顿时就有了光辉的一面。不过，我觉得吧，加缪和笛福要是穿越时空狭路相逢，可能会话不投机。加缪会觉得笛福太粗糙太功利，笛福呢，会觉得加缪太装。加缪说：&amp;ldquo;也许有那么一天，为了教训人类，鼠疫还会唤醒老鼠，并让它们死于一座幸福的城市&amp;rdquo;。你猜，笛福听了会是什么表情？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;猜不出。不过我倒是挺想看他们掐一架的。从科学的角度看，瘟疫也不是一点好处都没有。据说黑死病幸存者有一定程度的基因突变，人类也许一直都在被病毒推动着进化&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;从历史的角度看，瘟疫还成全了宗教&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这样说的话，从文学的角度看，瘟疫成全了爱情。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;好吧，连我都看过。 《霍乱时期的爱情》？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我不太喜欢那本书&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;也许是因为以前太喜欢了。在马尔克斯的世界里，霍乱只是爱情的背景板。那两个人，在乱世中相识，又在乱世中分离。只有这样长久的分离才能延长爱情的保质期。让他来写我们的故事，你那天就应该逃出城去，而我被拦在闸门里，然后我们用半个世纪互相思念。我们的爱情因此而不朽。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;所以你也承认我们是爱情？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哈，我那是，引用，不对，借代。总而言之，那是马尔克斯在说话，不是我。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从你们文学的角度&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;我听到的都不是好词儿。小偷，骗子，至少也是装腔作势。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;照这个逻辑，那还有教唆犯。我是说《十日谈》。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就是那本教人寻欢作乐的？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;岂止寻欢作乐？那是狂欢。在瘟疫蔓延的时候狂欢。你知道吗，我这几天就把这本书的第一章来来回回看了三遍。薄伽丘那种没心没肺的写法，居然把我看出了一脸眼泪。你想啊，佛罗伦萨城里瘟疫横行，前面写了好几页尸横遍野，说连骨肉至亲都因为惊恐而彼此隔绝，形同陌路。突然就看他一个掉头，冒出一群俊男美女，集合起来出城去。城外也是莫名其妙，平白无故就有座伊甸园在等着他们。台布是雪白的，玻璃酒杯像银子般闪着光，到处点缀着金雀枝的花朵。他们什么也不用做，只要把故事一个接一个地讲下去，就够了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;薄伽丘写垮了呗&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;小说家反正也不用负什么责任。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;可他为什么要往那个方向垮？你猜，那是真实发生的，还是一个梦，一种濒死时的幻觉，难以言喻的颅内高潮？你说这些好看的、无忧无虑的、把悲剧演成喜剧的男男女女，是人，还是鬼？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;你看你，又想多了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;你别盯着我看。最好的故事，背后都有死亡的影子在晃悠。一定有。相信我，末世感&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;也就是我们知道人一定会死这件事&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;是所有文学艺术的基础。这种感觉越是逼近，作品也就越迷人。比如预期寿命还不到现代人一半的古代人&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;（停顿。沉默。摘掉面罩，嘴被嘴软软地堵上的声音。）&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;3.第二十一天&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;你的那些群，吵到第几轮了？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;让我看一眼。如果从薄伽丘的角度看，今天最滑稽的事情是反对接种的那些家伙嚷嚷着要戴上他们从来不肯戴的面罩。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为什么？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因为接种的人数已经超过了没有接种的。他们说，需要警惕那些家伙把已经变性的蛋白质传递到没有受过污染的肌体上&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;太他妈逗了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;让他们戴吧。面罩总有一天会长在脸上，真的。他们最好现在就适应起来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有意思，我怎么觉得你不像开玩笑啊。跟个未卜先知的女巫似的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不开玩笑。面罩材料不是在一轮一轮的进化嘛，我想，等到它越来越薄，薄到你渐渐感觉不到它的存在&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就像在屏幕上贴膜那样？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高分子。能透气能出汗，柔软，贴合，还能接收生物电信号，比如血压心电图什么的。时不时给你拉个警报。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个好像已经在研究了。电子柔性皮肤。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那就好办了嘛。再往前进一小步，贴个能杀灭或者过滤病毒的膜，一生下来就给你从头到脚都贴上，每隔十年换一身。再往鼻腔口腔里植入个隐形滤网什么的，病毒不就可以给团灭了？面罩不就可以扔了？嗯&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;可以留两个好看的进博物馆。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;你这哪里是一小步？要解决的问题太多了。怎么才能既保持呼吸又过滤病毒？什么材料才能持久贴合，不是随便洗个澡就能洗掉的？就算这些问题全部解决了，我猜有不少人的皮肤和口鼻都会对这类玩意过敏，有人穿件羊毛衫都会满头满脸的发疹子。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科学家会去想办法。材料会越做越好，人体也会越来越适应。当年扛过黑死病的基因应该也不仅仅是运气好。挺得过病毒、贴得上膜的人才更容易活下来，才配活下来。一两代以后，就该来点基因突变了吧？到那时候，早期人体对贴膜的排异和过敏反应基本消失，只有少数倒霉蛋还会过敏。他们会说，这叫返祖。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这算科幻小说？天下的事情，给你们搞文学的人一说，都跟闹着玩似的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;应该说，这世界上的事情越来越像闹着玩儿。如果不像薄伽丘那样喝着酒讲着笑话打发时间，你说日子怎么过？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;要是真有那么一天，要是人人都贴着膜，我&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;嗯，我是说我们&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;像这样，伸出手来，摸到的究竟是人，还是膜？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;别趁机&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;是膜。所以未来的人类就是安全的。绝对安全。想亲谁都不用先出示电子健康证。你的皮肤、黏膜，任何器官，全都不是直接接触。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;可是，有一点危险感，难道不会让整个过程&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;更刺激？亲一张皮，跟亲一个你觉得哪怕亲下去明天就会死但是今天也非亲不可的人，差别可太大了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;让我想想&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;那时候贴着膜的人可以玩复古VR游戏，躺进睡眠舱，回到危险的蒙面纪。最先进的传感器和脑机接口，会说服他这是真实的皮肤接触，他会忘记自己贴着膜。他甚至完全不知道世界上有滤毒膜存在。是的他可以。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他可以什么？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;可以亲那个就算明天会死，但是今天也非亲不可的人。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（十五分钟。渐渐模糊的话语直至高低起伏的单音节。喘息。呼吸。）&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我觉得&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;从来没有这么好过。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;真的？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;真的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那就好。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我还在想&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;如果这两个时代都有个入口，像电影里那样的闪着光的旋转门。你可以挑一个进去，你怎么选？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;困了。哪两个？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在，还有贴着膜的未来？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;女人话真多&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;那你在哪个时代？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哈，也许，我两个都在？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哦。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;喂，醒醒，醒醒。要睡到床上去睡。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;4.第二十八天&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;听着，齐南雁，咱们都冷静冷静。你这样嚷，我一个字都听不见。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;你就是不想听见。你总是这样。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;你这是为了吵架而吵架，这是情绪，不是事实。我们每次吵架都会忘了到底为了什么吵。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;因为我受够了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对，你受够了。全城都受够了。典型的幽闭恐惧症状。这很正常，但你不能靠折磨我来求得心理平衡。我也快要崩溃了，你和寇娜都不太对劲。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;寇娜怎么了？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;烦躁，懒得动，不爱理人。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她本来就不爱理人。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;昨天傍晚在外面转悠一圈，不到半夜就回来了。找了个没用的纸箱子，蜷在里面猛睡。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那她够不够吃的？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;够的吧。就算她懒得抓个老鼠什么的，她的男朋友，公园里那位，也不舍得饿着她。你不觉得她整个身体都圆了一圈？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我懂了。家里还有牛奶吗？哄她好歹吃一点。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;昨天配给品里总算有一盒新鲜牛奶。你什么意思？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;寇娜怀孕了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;啊&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;我们的寇娜，真不是一只普通的猫。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;你又说反了吧。这恰恰说明寇娜也是一只普通的猫，像所有普通的猫那样具有生育的本能。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这个乱糟糟的世界，维持本能是需要勇气的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;5.第三十天&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;什么？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我觉得有事情要发生。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;什么？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;手机上收到他们的警告。让我管好我的猫。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不用理。他们天天发。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但是&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;寇娜早上没回来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;什么？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我看你一直睡得很沉，不敢叫醒你。我以为只要再等一个钟头，寇娜就会回来。可是没有。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;睁不开眼睛。齐南雁，别过来。别碰我。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;怎么回事？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我想我是在发烧。不用测，肯定超过三十九度。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;你是说&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我想，是的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;怎么可能？我们哪里都没有去，哪来的感染源。我不信，我要打电话给医院。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;你等等，让我先想想。可是我头疼得厉害，我困。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;醒醒。别睡着。求你了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（大声抽泣。远处传来的凄厉的猫叫声。）&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;初步评估&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;1.&amp;nbsp;在以上截取的五段对话中，可以看到大量蒙面纪时期的关键词，词频分布均匀，充满当时的日常生活气息，作为样本极具代表性。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;2.&amp;nbsp;受试者在实验场景中的人设和社会关系，最大程度上延续其在现实中的本来面目，包括名字和身份。实践证明，这样能让实验场景中的故事线进展更顺利。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;3.&amp;nbsp;从第三段中可以看出全沉浸模式与半沉浸模式的差异。两个时空的冲突，让处于半沉浸模式的受试者饱受困扰。她的&amp;ldquo;预言&amp;rdquo;之所以与如今的现实有高度相似性，甚至随口说出了&amp;ldquo;蒙面纪&amp;rdquo;这个专用名词，显然是受到了现实的干扰，尽管她似乎浑然不觉。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;4. 由于不明原因，实验出现卡顿，继而宕机，第五段被迫中断。受试者未完成预定程序即被动退出实验，特此标注。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;七&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;实验故障事后访谈。编号019。调查人员代号C。实验志愿者代号V。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：在你陷入类昏厥状态之前，你记得最后看到的是什么？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：雪白的台布，闪着银光的玻璃酒杯，金雀枝花朵。男人，女人，一个接一个地讲故事。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：这已经在类昏厥状态之中了，你的意识已经模糊。紧跟着你就醒过来，回到现实中。当时你所在的虚拟实验遇到了故障，VR处于卡顿状态，什么情节也没有记录下来。你的大脑中出现一定程度的信息奔逸，都是正常。我要问的，是在此之前，你在虚拟现实里的那条故事线，发生了什么？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：让我想想，使劲想想。他病了，症状凶猛。他说他应该是中招了。我想给医院打电话，他说这样不行。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：为什么不行？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：因为&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;寇娜不见了。我们的猫被那些人定位，追踪，他们说家猫才是真正的中间宿主，他们一直在搜集更多的证据。如果我们马上去报告新增病例，你们猜他们会对寇娜怎样？寇娜快要生了，一窝小猫，不知道会有几只黑，几只灰，几只黑灰相间，我&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：抱歉，请平复一下情绪。你们紊乱的体征指标很可能是导致本次实验报警、卡顿、提前退出的原因。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：我们？乔易思好吗？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：你是说你的实验拍档吗？他很好。但是全沉浸模式苏醒的时间更长，他的脑机接口毕竟是深度植入&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;尽管是极微创。他应该还在睡梦中。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：我记得，当时乔易思嘴里还含含糊糊说了几句，我想我听懂了。他说我也会有嫌疑，因为我在一个月前出城时体温异常但再没有出现别的症状，人们会认为我是传说中的超长期无症状传播者&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;据说我这样的人，血清很有研究价值，弄不好会被抢购。也就是说，在上报之前，我和寇娜都要做好被关起来当成试验品的思想准备。现在人们已经失控了，他说，谁知道他们会干出什么来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：那你当时怎么判断？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：我能怎么判断？我觉得我成了一只快要爆裂的气球。是的，有那么一瞬间，我好像突然想起了外面&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;呃，我是说，想起了一百多年以后的&amp;ldquo;现在&amp;rdquo;，你懂我意思吗？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：明白。半沉浸模式的时空冲突。请说得再详细一点。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：我知道蒙面纪之后的研究结果表明，这事跟猫没什么根本性的关系。没有什么动物能替人背上这口锅。我当时不知道哪来的底气，但我很清楚这一点。我甚至想去找那些组织，我以为我能说服他们，当时乔易思已经说不出话来，可他拼命挥手拦住我。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：他是对的。蒙面纪的很多失控事件，都是因为一个人以为能说服一群人。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：我记得的最后一件事，就是我们在僵持。从僵持到出现雪白的台布之间，是一片空白。那种感觉，就好像手术台上的全麻你懂吗？时间就那么凭空不见了，此前与此后毫无空隙地咬合在一起。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：好吧，了解。看来这个实验的细节还有很多可改进之处，谢谢你的全程参与。你还有什么问题吗？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：我&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;我想知道为什么会有这个实验。除了学术研究以外到底还有什么意义。我以为我会进入一场曲折的冒险，我以为我会发现一个阴谋，或者见证一个发明，等到一个足以拯救世界的奇迹。我以为我会扮演一个角色，比如在某个抢救中心跟死神抢时间的医生，最后自己染上了病毒，绑在呼吸机上无助地望着惨白的天花板。然而没有，什么都没有。我只是又演了一遍我自己，傻乎乎地跑到一百多年前隔离了一个月。在漫长而琐碎的日日夜夜里渐渐失去时间感。我对一切都无能为力，就好像被白白偷走了一生。最后连结局都被偷走了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：但是你的投入程度，丝毫不亚于一场真正的冒险。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：我还是想知道为什么？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：这个实验可能有一定的实用价值。比如可以为你提供写作材料，再比如，也许能治疗心理疾病。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：真的？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：这么说吧，齐南雁女士。有一类人，也许你见过，他们深深地陷在后蒙面纪综合症里无法自拔。尤其是具有相关惨痛家族记忆的人，对那段历史深感好奇的人，以及有专业研究背景的人，诸如此类。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：我想我见过这类人。比如，历史修复师。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：他们无处倾诉，但总是被噩梦惊醒。他们相信即便是最新版本的滤毒膜也无法阻挡病毒的变异，我们终有一天会被进化到X代的超级病毒攻破防线&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;而那时，我们的肌体甚至不具备与我们的祖先相当的抵抗力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：我懂。因为他们读完了传染病与人类缠斗了几千年的历史，他们知道病毒与人类的任何和平共处的时间都是短暂的，短得像一场初恋。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：呃&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;你形容得很准确。是那么个意思。你身边是不是有过这样的人？这种创伤渗透到他们的日常生活，伤害他们的心理状态，也影响他们与别人的关系。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：当然有。而且我知道这种影响会很严重，很持久&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：你在想什么？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：我跟他说，看着我的眼睛，我们真的不考虑生个孩子？他说，为什么要让这世界多一个潜在的受害者？在这个乱糟糟的世界里，维持本能是需要勇气的。我知道他偷偷地加了一道防护&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;说真的，他还不如一只猫勇敢。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：什么？我听不懂你在说什么？感觉像是两辈子的事。你还是需要休息。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：没什么。是两辈子的事。有点串。你们这个虚拟实验里出现的宠物，我是说那只黑猫，有原型吗？它做得那么逼真，是不是用到了&amp;ldquo;真猫捕捉&amp;rdquo;的动画特技？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：让我查一查。还真有。一只被收容进实验室的流浪猫。年纪不小，快要退役了。你看，我把这只猫的DNA谱系资料调出来，她居然还有隐性的蓝金渐层基因。你看，往前推几十代，她的生活在前蒙面纪时代的祖先叫作&amp;ldquo;奶茶&amp;rdquo;，长得多好看啊。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：我能不能收养她？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：抱歉，这个我真不知道。回头你跟公关处再打听打听。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：好的，谢谢。再耽误你两分钟可以吗？我想知道，这样的治疗，让饱受后蒙面纪综合症的病人亲身经历那段历史，真的会有用吗？难道不会让他们更恐惧吗？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：你知道，实验刚刚开始，对疗效的评估还需要时间。何况，就算有了第一批数据，那也一定是保密的。我只能说，有风险，但值得尝试。除了恐惧，齐南雁女士，我相信你在这个实验里也感受到了别的东西。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：好吧。我没有问题了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：再次感谢你的参与。对了，有件事也许你有兴趣知道&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;刚才，一分三十秒以前，你的拍档，乔易思先生&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;他醒了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;责任编辑：舟自横&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文选载自《钟山》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FoIosTASxA6efZbi0eCt3jwjHN6Z&quot; alt=&quot;黄昱宁&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;黄昱宁 &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@黄昱宁&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;上海译文出版社副总编辑。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;关注&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;相关推荐&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/3465&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;海外关系&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 黄昱宁&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6144)&quot;>;点击可下载ONE一个app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 07:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4044]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4187]]><description>&lt;div>;2 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FrM27gw-3p9j3uzg_l428qsqXsu9&quot; alt=&quot;首页图&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4044&lt;/span>;摄影| Heino Schliep&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nov. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;在没有人与人交接的场合，我充满了生命的欢悦。 &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 07:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>