<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE · one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[读很多书可以改变人生，是不是一个骗局？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3991]]><description> &lt;div>;28 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Wild Wolf Asks&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>;Read Many books can change lives, is this a scam? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Xiwheat Answer&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FlN2jF6fXy14QIL5pPwzP9tno0Sa&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FlN2jF6fXy14QIL5pPwzP9tno0Sa&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;This topic is very old and interesting. I would like to talk about it from another perspective. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Recently, a police station specialist has been stationed in the community group. Every week, he lists various scam cases in the group. Liu was accidentally defrauded of tens of thousands for making friends, and Wang was defrauded of hundreds of thousands for health products. , Zhang Moumou was defrauded of millions of dollars in investment. In short, it was all money, and the most valuable things were inadvertently taken away. Every time I talk about this with my friends, I always have the thought that these data may also be made up, carefully created and well-intentioned scam data to prevent us from being deceived. &lt;strong>;Yes, the scam theory is deeply ingrained&lt;/strong>;. The more intense the propaganda, the closer the truth will be to us, followed closely by fear and anxiety. Once the theory of being deceived is formed, we will unconsciously put ourselves in a state of fear and attempt to change the status quo, like a drowning person trying to catch a stick. Reachable straw. Even reading is not immune. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A few years ago, there was news that someone organized a spiritual growth reading club, claiming that they could gain positive energy through reading and learning, thereby significantly reversing the status quo and changing their lives. The prerequisite was to pay the membership fee and become a member. , buy the corresponding courses and cheats, of course, it may be more exaggerated. As a result, a large number of students were deceived, and the small treasury they had saved so hard was wiped out. &lt;strong>;The drowning people could not get to the shore and became drowned people&lt;/strong>;. And they firmly believe that reading can change their destiny. If they move a few chairs over, put the book on their knees and open it, and read it for a few afternoons, they can turn their fortunes around, become famous in one fell swoop, and make a fortune. And I am very sure that they will not have the patience to take a closer look at what type of book the medium-thick book on their knees is, what the title is, and who the author is. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I wrote the novel two years ago. Before that, I didn’t read any books or feel bored. Outside of work, I was filled with low-level entertainment, such as playing games, watching videos, playing cards, and bragging. One day, I was standing in a classroom full of students, being stared at by them, and suddenly I was speechless. There was a four-letter word that I couldn&#39;t remember, and I couldn&#39;t say it out. The wind blew in from the window, and I felt like I was standing in a quagmire. , between repetitions, the lack of mud gradually submerged the feet and the knees. After returning home, I started reading, on paper and electronically, subscribing to periodicals and buying magazines. Later I read a sentence from Wang Xiaobo&#39;s &quot;The Silent Majority&quot;, &lt;strong>;&quot;If a person needs to get happiness from his thoughts, then his first desire is to learn.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The benefits of reading are concentration and thinking, which makes it easier for me to immerse myself in my own world, break away from the complicated world, and try to get in touch with other people’s thoughts. , or even enter a certain era to feel the weight of history and feel the emotions and joys of the characters. It’s just a feeling, nothing more.&lt;strong>;Don’t try to get the Golden House and Yan Ruyu from the book, it’s still a scam. &lt;/strong>;Reading Borges, Bolaño, Calvino, Vonnegut, McEwan and other big names will not make you live in a villa or drive a Mercedes-Benz. I remember a cartoon that explained the meaning of reading very well. With the book under your feet, you can see beyond the wall, into the distance, into the clouds, and into the universe. People have not changed, but their height has changed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Our&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Our&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Life&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Real&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong >;How many&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;s&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;dramatic&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; changes are needed&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; ? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the era of self-media, explosion has become a key word. The great changes in life have come in many unexplained ways. I have been paying attention to GIAO a while ago, selling apples in the village on a tricycle, and his family is bare. After I shot a short video in the woods and uploaded it, the gears of fate began to turn. Until now, I drive two luxury cars, own two houses, and still live in the woods, transforming myself into a life mentor Zhan Yapeng. &lt;strong>;Those who go to the theater are always visitors, those who buy tickets are always the audience. The only ones who change their lives are those adventurers who are willing to step on the stage.&lt;/strong>; As a general public, we need to calm down and put aside changes. In the back of your mind, stack up your own books one after another, immerse yourself in your own &quot;scam&quot;, and &quot;deceive&quot; yourself with all your heart. Everything will fall into place, and you will be another person who reaches the pinnacle of life and changes his life. When it appears, you can comment calmly, the world is full of chaos, and all sentient beings are concerned, it can be you or me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To borrow a quote from Ursula LeGuin,&lt;strong>;&amp;ldquo;As a man’s true power grows and his knowledge expands, the path he takes becomes narrower and narrower: until Finally he stopped choosing and just did exactly what he had to do. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Reading will only make us narrow down, find our own &quot;scam&quot;, and be willing to &quot;be deceived&quot; without any doubts. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Mei Butan onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the call for papers information, please see @ONE Studio pinned on Weibo. The official WeChat account of the editorial department: oneapp2020. Regularly publish Q&amp;A collections, give away books and peripheral gifts, readers are welcome to add. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FlR5Z0EII4KoZAiklg49yN -v3fdm&quot; alt=&quot;西 wheat&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;西 wheat&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@西 wheat typing&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt; div style=&quot;&quot;>;One ​​for writing. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3991)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/ div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[真心游戏]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6181]]><description>&lt;div>;28 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;文／Boli&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data -author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fii-67vcHvLNxvfCzw19i8lVloLm&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fii-67vcHvLNxvfCzw19i8lVloLm&quot;>; &lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Not every love song has a happy ending. With a hand in hand, a kiss, a hug, and a goodbye, we climbed up along the sweet line, and then in a lost moment, we fell heavily into the unknown. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the ninth month of working in Beijing, Zhang Ruipeng suddenly called me. He spoke in his hometown dialect and said that he had seen it in &quot;If You Are the One&quot; I became prettier and mellower, and asked me why I didn’t hold hands with that outrageous returnee financial man in the end. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If he hadn’t called me, I would have almost forgotten about him. I had just come out of the company bathroom. I looked around subconsciously and saw no one I knew. I quickly switched my language system in my mind, then lowered my voice and used the dialect at home: I am three pounds fatter for photogenic purposes. I am not fat. It was captured by the camera. As for the shows, they are all acting, and they cost 2,000 yuan a show. They can earn some pocket money after work, but they are not dedicated to dating on TV. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Ruipeng and I separated the summer before last, when I started my junior year of school. On the last night before going back to school, I video-recorded with him in the bedroom and tried sex phone for the first time, that kind of separation. , very sad sex phone. After sweating profusely, Zhang Ruipeng lay flat on the bed, panting slightly with unprecedented tenderness and affection, and said to me for the first time, &quot;How about being my wife?&quot; His rare vulnerability, inadvertently revealed due to separation, strengthened my expression, and I solemnly said with a certain dedication: When I graduate, I will marry you, wait for me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I was in high school, my mother took me to tell my fortune under the bridge in front of my house. It was originally about my studies and whether I could get into a good university. , I will meet the first person who treats me sincerely and wants to marry me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said: What will happen to us in the future? Will we get married? The fortune teller said: It depends on your fate, it&#39;s impossible to tell. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was 19 years old when I met Zhang Ruipeng, and I had doubts about whether he was the person who the fortune tellers said would treat me sincerely. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before I met Zhang Ruipeng, I often came out of the dormitory bathroom naked, wearing only a pair of briefs, and looked up and down in the full-length mirror posted in front of the dormitory door, admiring my body. , while feeling that it was such a pity and waste that when I was the youngest and most beautiful, there was no man to love me, appreciate me, and enjoy me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So when I met Zhang Ruipeng, I decided to live up to my time and dedicate my best youth to him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Ruipeng was 34 years old that year. The year after he returned to his hometown after failing to start a business in Beijing, he was already an older bachelor in the county. He majored in art, and it was difficult to find a job in a small county. If he went to teach in an art education institution, his salary would be pitiful. He went to take the exam to be an art teacher in our county, but there were only eight out of thousands of people. He didn&#39;t pass the exam in the first year, and he had no chance to take the exam again. 35 years old is the threshold. When I met him, he was preparing for the community worker exam. Community work in small counties pays very low wages, two to three thousand a month, and it is not difficult to pass the exam. So if he can pass the exam, he will work first. Make the transition and slowly look for another job. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking back now, I met him when he was at his lowest. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first time I asked him out, at night, on the overpass in my hometown, he was wearing an off-white hat with a low brim, a black T-shirt, and was tall and thin. As soon as he saw me, he said : So young, ninety years old? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I pursed my lips in embarrassment and said: Guess. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said: Ninety-seven? Ninety-eight? ...Ninety-six? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said: I am born in 2000, 2001. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was our first offline date, and he seemed a little sad that day. The sadness started from the moment he learned my age, and spread to the entire summer we were together. After that, he kept recalling to me the past events of his college days and his drifting to Beijing after graduation. Those days in Beijing were probably when he was most energetic. He opened an art tutoring agency in Haidian with his friends and earned a lot of money a month. After work in the evening, he would go to the basketball court near the university town to play basketball. He often met some high-spirited people. Some college students were cheating and playing dirty, and then the two groups started fighting. He said that he was a good fighter, but he was measured and would not cause trouble or end up in the hospital, but he could let the other party know that he was not someone to be trifled with. I used to fight a lot, but now I can’t do it. It’s so stupid. Speaking of emotional places, light a cigarette. I stood next to him and listened to him talk in an unhurried tone, as if I was a carrier for him to recall his youth. Being close to me was like returning to youth. Until later, he put out his third cigarette and asked me if he could pull it off. Take my hand. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said yes, stretched out a hand, and he squeezed it gently. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On a summer night in early August, the wind was warm. His hands were big, very hot, rough and dry. Because he had been painting all the time, the middle finger joints had very hard calluses, and my hands It was small and wet, shyly wrapped in his hand. He held it lightly at first, then tightened it more and more. The whole process lasted for five seconds before he let go as if he was frustrated. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said: I haven’t held a girl’s hand in two or three years. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What happened after that was a matter of course. He walked me home, and we stood side by side, occasionally bumping our arms. On the way, we had to pass through a quiet small park, and on the sixth step of the park trail, he grabbed my arm, carried me to the edge of the bush, and started to kiss me forcefully. For the first time, I felt the heat and hunger of a single man in his thirties. Later, he put his left hand on my chest through my clothes and began to knead it. The other hand that was originally holding my waist gradually reached down. , reached my butt, and slowly tightened my fingers. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Ruipeng is different from the boys I dated before. He is mature, skilled, and at ease. I was a little panicked at first, but half a minute later I almost collapsed in his arms. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I met him in the study room during the summer vacation. The study room was opened by his friend. He occasionally helped look after the store and read books by the way. I was looking for a suitable study room to prepare for the postgraduate entrance examination. I couldn&#39;t study at home, as anyone who has gone to school knows. He was the one who received me on the day I applied for the monthly pass for the study room. He wears a beige hat, has a low voice, and looks good, like the table tennis star. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After that, every time I went to the study room, it became a kind of expectation and concern. I always wanted to see him more. There is something wrong with me. Whatever I do ends up being unprofessional. When you go to the water dispenser to get water, when you get up to go to the toilet, when you enter or exit the door of the study room... you always have to take a few glances with your peripheral vision, and then sit down in a one-man show of panic. It takes five to ten minutes to calm down. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the monthly card expired, I couldn’t renew it due to other reasons and stayed in the study room. The night I packed my books and went home, I finally plucked up the courage to add his WeChat account. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We talked about art on the first night. He said that he studied art and he was willing to discuss the art of painting with others. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The second night we talked about study and work. He said that he had worked in Beijing for seven years and just came back the year before last. (In our small county town in Shandong, &quot;working in Beijing&quot; is a very honorable thing.) I said that I just wanted to get a graduate degree in Beijing and work in Beijing in the future. He said that if you don’t understand anything in the future, you can ask him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the third night we talked about our first impressions, and he said that he vaguely remembered that I was wearing khaki, a dark khaki top, light khaki pants, and my hair was always messy (although I didn’t think so) . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the fourth night we talked about our hobbies. I said I like writing novels and photography. Can I make an appointment with you for a photo shoot some other time? I think you are pretty good-looking and would be suitable to be a model. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the fifth night we talked about our love life. He said that people of his age would be very lonely if they were not married. Brothers and friends around him were getting married one after another, especially during the New Year and holidays. Everyone had their own families. Spending time with their wives and children would no longer be the same as before. They went out to drink and dine with the same response. He also said that he had not been in love for two or three years, and was constantly being urged to get married by his family. He had been on countless blind dates, but nothing was suitable for him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said: So are you still in the relationship now? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said: Not much in the past six months or so. Because you&#39;re tired? Because there is no one to introduce me, all the relatives and friends around me can introduce me. Besides, I am too old, so the woman doesn’t like me either. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said: How could it be? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said: It’s like this, but you are young and you don’t understand. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said: I am quite curious about blind dates. Is blind date just about eating, watching movies and shopping? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said: Usually we eat first. After eating and chatting, if both parties feel that they are good together, they will watch a movie or something together. If they feel it is not suitable, they will go back to their respective homes. Everyone is very purposeful, so it’s okay. Meaning. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I continued to ask: Will you wear a suit on a blind date? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said: Usually not, only occasionally. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said: Do you know how to wear a tie? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said: No. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said: Do you know how to wear leather shoes? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said: If you are so curious, come and experience it next time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the sixth night we made an appointment to meet at the Tianqiao. His tongue was very powerful. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Friends commented: The young girl who came to our door was pretty, who wouldn’t want her? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I ignored her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My friend continued to make things difficult: I am almost thirty, old cows eat young grass, maybe I have a wife and children, so don’t let me fall into the trap of a mistress. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said: Get out. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Ruipeng later told me: If only we could have known each other through WeChat a month earlier, then we could have been together for two months during the summer vacation. After tasting these words, I felt that he was really hungry. Later he said: Alas, I wish I could have met ten years earlier. I think he is somewhat sincere. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He heard that I majored in Chinese and loved reading, so he cut two bookmarks for me out of white cardboard, with small paintings he drew on them. A black and white pencil drawing, the woods under the night sky, the stars seem to be sprinkled with white paint with a pen, and a colored pencil drawing, it is McDull with wings, flying in the sky holding a book, it is so cute, the painting After finishing, carefully seal it with transparent tape to prevent it from being scratched. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After I got the bookmark, I found it extremely valuable. I carefully tucked it into the copy of &quot;The Golden Age&quot; by Wang Xiaobo on my bedside, and would read it out from time to time to appreciate it. I always feel like Chen Qingyang in the book. I obviously didn&#39;t break the shoes, but mentally I am always in a state of urgency to prove that I didn&#39;t break the shoes. I am ready to refute others who say I broke the shoes anytime and anywhere. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later, I thought that this psychological feeling may come from the fact that we both tacitly understood each other and did not give each other a name. &quot;Brother in the study room&quot; was referred to as &quot;the man in the study room&quot;. Later, we did everything we were supposed to do, but when talking about him with my friends, I just stated the facts that happened between us without adding any secular meaning. Modification of status and relationships. Zhang Ruipeng went even further. As far as I know, he has never mentioned me to any of his friends (let alone relatives). I once asked why, and he said, it&#39;s very troublesome, and things will be very troublesome, so there&#39;s no need. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But I also feel that the relationship between me and him is perhaps the purest way of getting along between opposite sexes. We are together because we have a good impression of each other, but neither of us needs to be responsible for the other, and the other person will do whatever he wants at any time. I was preparing to leave—he went on a blind date and got married, and I went north to study for graduate school or work, and no one disturbed anyone after passing through this village. I think the future evolution direction of the way men and women get along is ours, which is healthy, environmentally friendly, degradable and sustainable. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But I am sure that I had deep feelings for him during those two months. I don’t know where that feeling came from and where it went, and I don’t know if it is considered love. Love is right for him. It&#39;s such a heavy word for me that I can&#39;t say it out loud. I wrote him many letters in the past two months. Sometimes we chatted until late at night. He was sleepy and wanted to go to bed. I couldn&#39;t bear to let him go, so I let him sleep with me on WeChat. I got up from the bed and went to the table. , turned on the warm yellow desk lamp, spread out the pen and paper, and wrote him a letter while listening to his breathing on the other end of the phone. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dear Ruipeng: &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A letter is like seeing you in person. I miss you very much. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;hellip; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I saw an article before, saying that for men in their thirties and forties... a youthful girl in her twenties only needs to be in the top 50% of women in appearance. She is already a beauty in their eyes. For older men, reaching the top 70% is enough. I don’t know what I mean to him. Sometimes when I hug him and make love, I often feel that he loves my young body more than me. He loves me because he sees the shadow of his youth in me. It&#39;s like I&#39;m young again. (Assuming there was love between us.) I have no intention of beautifying this relationship. When we watch movies, go to the supermarket, or go to the park together, he always walks behind melancholy, always looking melancholy and worried. , occasionally I turned around and held his hand, and he would approach me and whisper in my ear: Girl, will you go to the hotel with me? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I think of Faust in &quot;Faust&quot; when he signed a contract with the devil when he was most desperate. The first thing he asked for was not fame or fortune, but youth and the body of a young girl. Medieval Europe was no different from the here and now. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Compared to the young boy, I think he needs me more. So after he asked five or six times, we agreed to it on our fifth date. This limit makes me feel that I won&#39;t keep him waiting too long, and it won&#39;t make me appear too frivolous, even though I know it doesn&#39;t matter whether I am frivolous or not in his eyes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My first time was delivered in an hourly room for 40 yuan for two hours. There was not a lot of blood, and there was no pleasure. It was just huge pain and I wanted to curse (but I held it back). After everything was over, I lay sprawled on the bed and cried, not because of the pain, but because I thought that my youth had been dedicated to a middle-aged man I had only known for half a month, and I felt that this situation needed some tears to stir up emotion. , so I squeezed out a few tears. When he heard my deliberate sobs, his expression quickly changed from the great enjoyment to concern and panic. He got up and asked me: What&#39;s wrong? Is it too painful or is he afraid? I&#39;m sorry, I&#39;m really sorry. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I almost couldn’t hold back my laughter when I saw him being naked and serious. I felt like we were acting in a movie. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But it was spoken in a dialect, our Shandong dialect. People in the play thought it was a bit sensational, but outsiders didn&#39;t know whether they thought it was more funny. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I divide the time we spend together into two parts, one is the time inside the hotel, and the other is the time outside the hotel. When I was lying naked on the bed, Zhang Ruipeng always took the trouble to marvel at the firmness, tenderness, smoothness and perfect proportions of my body. He said that he used to draw human sculptures and was familiar with the structure of each bone and the direction of the muscles. Sometimes he would stand on the bed and look at me from a high place. After looking at the overall situation, he would sigh, &quot;My figure is really good!&quot; &amp;rdquo;(If in feminist terms, this is a kind of &quot;male bonding&quot; that appreciates women as objects to be enjoyed, I can only say I&#39;m sorry, I&#39;m very proud of it.) &lt; /p>;&lt;p>;But after several encounters, I discovered that I only enjoyed his appreciative gaze and greedy touch of my body. I was not interested in the sex itself, nor could I get pleasure from it. I suspected that I might be sexually disabled, but out of Due to Shan Shan&#39;s consideration, I still performed very hard in front of him. So from a psychological point of view, the time in the hotel is more like fulfilling an obligation to me, which is solid, false and empty. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And outside the hotel, for example, when hanging lazily on his arm like a doll pendant while walking in the park, when walking hand in hand in the bustling night market, leaning on his shoulder in the dark When we watch a movie in the cinema and kiss his ear from time to time and whisper &quot;honey&quot; in his ear... our time is stretching, flowing and natural. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But for Zhang Ruipeng, the situation is exactly the opposite. He only likes me the most when there is no one around, and only when there is no one around will he take the initiative to behave excessively intimately with me. When people come and go, he feels embarrassed even if I hold his arm. (Later, I belatedly realized that this was because I was afraid of being bumped into by acquaintances. After all, the small county is so big.) In his words - it was like committing a crime in public, it was unseemly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What is decency? I sometimes think that maybe if he were a little older, a little uglier, a little richer, and I, a little prettier, this would be appropriate. It sounds much more reasonable for a middle-aged divorced man to use money to buy an inexperienced young girl. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the fact is that I am not that beautiful, he is not that old, he is not ugly or even handsome, and he is not rich or even quite poor. Every time he took me out to eat, it was always at a cheap and affordable restaurant. No young people go to this place on a date. As soon as they enter, they see a short square table of oily wood (sometimes made of aluminum alloy), a small horse rack, and green beer bottles piled at the door. The proprietress wears a plaid tie that hasn&#39;t been washed in I don&#39;t know how many years. Apron, handed over a menu (sometimes there is no menu). At the next table, there are always middle-aged men with bare upper bodies and bulging beer bellies, making jokes while eating. Every time he came to pick me up for a date, he would ride his little electric donkey and wait for me not far from the gate of the community. When he saw me, he would smile and say, &quot;Honey, get in the car. If he treats me to dinner, it would be like movie tickets or KTV money.&quot; It’s me who comes, and vice versa. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I don’t know his specific financial situation, but it is speculated that he does not have much money. First of all, he has been unemployed for two years. Secondly, he has an older brother and an older sister. The older sister has been married out of town for many years. The older brother’s son has just entered kindergarten. Zhang Ruipeng was still living with his father at that time, in a mixed urban-rural area in our small county. In the house rented by the Ministry. I made several video calls with him. His bedroom was very small and the decoration was very simple, even shabby. His bed is very narrow, less than 1.3 meters by visual inspection. The pillow cover on the pillow is printed with a washed-out pink and yellow peony pattern. I only saw this style of pillow cover still used by my grandparents when the older generation got married. It is sometimes used as a dowry together with the four-piece bed set. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He emphasized to me that he was only renting here temporarily. Because it was a rented house, he did not take care of it. The new house was in XX community and was still a rough house that had not been decorated yet. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Poverty is a big problem. This is a profound truth that I have only realized in the past few years. But I was 19 years old at the time. When I saw the lonely look of him lying on an old peony pillow in the video, I felt so sad and sad when I thought of how high-spirited he was in Beijing before. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I asked him: What will I do after I go back to school? If you have a successful blind date, will you get married soon? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said: I don’t know, I’ll just let it go at my age. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said: You are so handsome, don’t you have any friends around you who like you? Will you fall in love again immediately after I leave? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He smiled: You treat me as a treasure, no one wants me in the blind date market. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said: Nonsense, you are so nice, you have a good temper, you are good at drawing, you are so talented, you are so handsome...He turned around and pulled me away. He pressed down and said: When I think about you being attacked by other boys in the future, I want to kill him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The word &quot;kill&quot; he said through gritted teeth was so strong that it was like a stone pressing on me. I almost believed it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One afternoon when he came back from watching a movie, he took me home on a battery car. I said: Don’t go home yet, I want to stay with you for a while longer. He said: I made an appointment with my father to go to the decoration market in the afternoon to pick out some suitable decoration materials. I said: What style do you want to decorate the house in? What color to paint the walls? He said: Just decorate it casually, just be simple and don’t do anything fancy. Anyway, when you have children, the walls will be covered with graffiti. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As soon as we finished speaking, neither of us said a word. I sat in the back seat of the electric car and looked at the back of his head. I really wanted to cry, I really wanted to cry. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the last night before going back to school, a few hours before the sex phone started, we had the last mutton hotpot at the Little Fly Restaurant, which cost him more than 220 yuan. His biggest expense since we got together. He drank several bottles of beer, but he was not drunk at all. I said: The next time we meet will be during the winter vacation at the earliest, or whether we can still meet at all. He said: Maybe when I miss you, I will buy a ticket and go to you. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was studying in university in Nanjing at that time, and it took more than three hours by high-speed rail. But I know he won&#39;t come to me, because we agreed from the beginning to enjoy life in time, not to think about the past or the future, and to enjoy this summer well. He knows that my attitude is similar to his. What&#39;s more, the high-speed rail ticket to and from Nanjing from my hometown costs 700 to 800 yuan, and hotels in Nanjing are not cheap. I don&#39;t think I am worth so much money in his heart. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I turned my head away and started wiping tears at the greasy walls of the restaurant. This time I really cried and I couldn’t hold it back. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At first, Zhang Ruipeng said kind words to comfort me, but later he only said, &quot;Stop crying. If you cry again, I will leave.&quot; When I heard this, I felt even more uncomfortable and cried even harder. , the shirtless big brothers eating around all looked this way. He probably felt embarrassed or ashamed, so he took out a pack of cigarettes from his pocket and went outside to smoke. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I cried for a while while facing the leftovers alone, asking for trouble, so I ran out and saw him smoking alone across the street without saying a word, so I joined him. , crying and asking him: Why can&#39;t we be together when we love each other? Why do we have to miss it? I hate separation, why should there be separation? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He blew out the smoke, glanced at me helplessly, and said earnestly: You are still young, life is like this, separation and reunion are common, you must learn to get used to it and be strong. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said: Fuck you. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What happened next was the sex phone at the beginning of the story, the sad sex phone at the time of parting. Parting can put a filter on many things, and the same goes for sex. So for the first time he said that he wanted to marry me, and for the first time I said that I wanted to marry him. But I regretted it the next day. I am only 19 years old. I still have a long way to go in life. There are endless possibilities in the future. I still have to go to Beijing to study and work. I have never tasted a cup of Starbucks in a skyscraper glass building in the CBD. What it feels like to rush to a meeting. I have never cried in a BMW. How could I be content with sitting in his electric car and laughing all my life? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It’s just that we didn’t meet each other in Beijing back then, and this shop disappeared after we passed this village. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As I expected, Zhang Ruipeng did not come to Nanjing to look for me until I graduated. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was shocked when I received a call from Zhang Ruipeng in Beijing a few days ago. I had almost forgotten him over the years, but when I heard his voice, I immediately recognized him. He asked me if I was studying or working in Beijing now. I said I didn&#39;t pass the postgraduate entrance examination and came to work directly. He then asked me how it felt to be on a blind date on TV. There were so many handsome male guests for you to choose from. I said it was all scripted. Who would hold hands and who would turn off the lights had been decided in advance, but it was also quite interesting. It was just like acting. Don&#39;t tell me, I do have some acting talent. He paused and said thoughtfully, this is true. He also asked me if I was still used to living in Beijing, if I had any acquaintances in Beijing, if I had made any new friends, if I was lonely, and if I needed help or anything to talk to, I could tell him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said: I am doing very well in Beijing, I adapt very well, my work goes very smoothly, I have many friends, I am not lonely at all, and there is nothing I need help with. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said: That’s good. The sound is a bit awkward. Asked again, have you talked about a boyfriend? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said: Just talk. I&#39;m from Beijing. I just graduated like me. I&#39;m a nice person. Let&#39;s see how we develop first. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said: Very good. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After a few words of greeting, he hung up the phone in displeasure. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I collapsed on the bed with a long sigh of relief. This matter should be considered completely over. From beginning to end, I never asked him if he was married. If he was married, it would be quite embarrassing. If he was not married, it would be even more embarrassing. But no matter judging from my answer or his reaction, I am very satisfied with our conversation. He should understand that a good horse will never turn back. Even in Beijing, I have always been alone and very lonely. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Nana&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For information about the call for submissions, please see the @ONE Studio pinned on Weibo. The official WeChat account of the editorial department: oneapp2020. Regularly publish Q&amp;A collections, give away books and peripheral gifts, readers are welcome to add. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FsqqQjkalKAkxokjzizkiNUfY8JT&quot; alt=&quot;Boli&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Boli &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@boli丁梅月&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Nothing to live in, but a heart to live in&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px ;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6175&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Later&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Chen Function&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href= &quot;/article/6174&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Apricot sweatshirt&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Article A or B&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr >; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6038&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Majia There are no tears in Baozi&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Boli&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align :center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6181)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div >; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot; _blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run &lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4070]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4214]]><description>&lt;div>;28 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fms6W_VvWHSg2XysWK82EldddBdM&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;VOL.4070&lt;/span>;Photography | Ryan Klaus&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;28&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nov. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;We can be different , but there is no need to apologize for your differences. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 28 Nov 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>