<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[失去一个人，会有哪些「戒断反应」？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3944]]><description> &lt;div>;16 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Qi Even Rice Question&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>;Lost What kind of &quot;withdrawal reactions&quot; does a person have? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; ONE Friendly Answers&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Foi12xtOAHWOHy5wbPIVIRYhjSLy&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Foi12xtOAHWOHy5wbPIVIRYhjSLy&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot; font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Withdrawal reaction refers to the special psychological or physical reaction symptoms caused by sudden cessation of certain drugs or reduction of dosage. The existence of some people turns out to be a good medicine in our lives. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Originally we agreed not to consider dating for the time being, but my childhood friend + best friend who is not getting married got engaged without my knowledge. . The premise is that we were still chatting about work every morning and night and sharing our daily routine, but suddenly it felt like the relationship between us had changed. Nowadays, I often miss people when I see things, and I feel emotional when I see things, and I shed tears at every turn~&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Wandou, 26 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first year after my grandma passed away, I came home for the New Year, and I was still looking forward to the scene of her standing on the corner of the street waiting for us to come home. But &quot;po&quot; came out smoothly, but there was no response. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Dandelion, 28 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Once The latest season of the variety show we were following was updated, and I subconsciously wanted to forward it. At that moment, I realized that we were no longer in a relationship that shared this, so you see how outrageous this was. If I want, I can forward it to other friends freely, but I cannot forward it to you who once turned from friends to lovers and then separated. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Vitasoy, 25 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I would flip through his company’s official account and not miss every article, maybe just to see his name. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;77, don’t panic, 24 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;At certain moments in life, when you see someone who looks very similar to him, you will think of a previous moment between you. However, he has left your life forever, and from then on, there is no one left in the world. Your dearest relative. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Jianghe Nacuo, 24 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I usually eat snail noodles with eggs, yuba, ham, and a cup of milk tea. I lost five pounds in three days and ten pounds in five days. I woke up three times every night and couldn&#39;t sleep again. I started crying when I looked at the ceiling, and I shed tears all along Changsha Line 2. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;A netizen, 20 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; I lost my relatives one after another (what does it count? my dear grandpa &amp; grandma). too difficult. It is in every sleepless night, every time I think about it, I cry uncontrollably; it is in a calm moment when I suddenly think of it, it will break down; it is the lingering pain. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Xiao Lu, 20, who often thinks forgetting is a good thing&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I went to another city for college. My grandma got a data package for my mobile phone card and learned how to use WeChat. When I posted in Moments, she would give me likes. She also used the data to make videos for me. They say it costs nothing to make video calls, but the data charges are obviously much more expensive than the phone charges. She would barely go back to stay for a week during the winter and summer vacations, and other family members only went back once in a while. She installed Wi-Fi at home for our short stay. In the eyes of the elderly, when the children grow up, it means losing them (crying). &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Feng Youjingjing, 25 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;My grandfather and I are relatives and good friends. He would count the days and look forward to my monthly break, wait for me to come home and pick me up early, give me all the good ones like a child, and then wait for me to say &quot;delicious&quot;. He even has the temper of a child. If he gets angry because of my &quot;disobedience&quot;, he will also kick me down. He left unexpectedly this year and went to another place. When I hear my father snoring, I think of my grandpa and can&#39;t sleep for a long time; when I see an old man being scolded on the road, I think of my old man and can&#39;t help but feel sad; every time I go back to my hometown during the holidays, I see the man who is full of our memories. There are places where I get choked up... In short, I can&#39;t see anything about him or anything that involves him, otherwise I will choke up and regret for a long time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Glass, 21 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; It&#39;s my puppy. It cries as soon as I leave the house. Every time I turn around after closing the door, it feels like a farewell. Later, I installed surveillance cameras in my home, and I would turn on them and chat a few words when I went to the toilet. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Awei, 29 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; I kept listening to some sad songs and unconsciously picked at my fingernails until they bled (this bad habit still exists today, more than ten years ago). &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;The miracle doctor who picked his nails, 40 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>; I chatted with Crush for many days. One day he suddenly became cold. I felt that I had lost him because I was unpredictable about my vague feelings. Then we never chatted again. I felt empty in my heart. I would watch and watch over and over again. In his chat history, he would fantasize about what would happen if this relationship ended, and he would fantasize about meeting him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Cute Dunton, 18 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I will think of him from time to time, the words I said to him, and his hugs. Although there was a turmoil in his heart, he seemed to be a fine adult on the outside. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Min Ran, 30 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Responsibility Editor: Nana onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This Q&amp;A is from the ONE Editorial Department WeChat Moments solicitation. To participate in the solicitation, add the Editorial Department WeChat: oneapp2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8 &quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Complex The cutest people in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3941&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What &quot;folk metaphysics&quot; have you seen? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3940&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What are the benefits of &quot;breaking away from others&quot;? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3944)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[夜奔]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6128]]><description> &lt;div>;16 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;文／语鹹&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fv_AetOa2-KZ4blHVxfndnlJq0f_&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fv_AetOa2-KZ4blHVxfndnlJq0f_&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Fan, light bulb, clock, ice cream, zoo, worth 80 million The lottery ticket, the father who opened a repair shop and Uncle Pang in the small shop, these people and things are slowly connected in memories, taking us back to our childhood in that sultry summer. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;01&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the summer of 1990, three major events happened in Nanfang County. The most severe rainstorm in 68 years destroyed the Hengjiang Bridge. On the night of the heavy rain, the largest lottery prize ever awarded in Nanfang County, 80 million, went unclaimed. The third and most important thing is that my dad is laid off. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Three days before the heavy rain, my father was laid off and lost his iron job. My mother was silent at first, staring blankly at my father like a stone statue, hoping that my father would make a joke as usual. But my dad didn’t laugh that time. My mother is a seamstress, and she has a tailor&#39;s intuition. She can tell at a glance whether a man is cheating on someone or is at odds with his mother-in-law, just like tailoring clothes. This is what my mother told me later. She was looking for her reading glasses, and I quickly handed them to her. She slowly put on her glasses, placed her hands flat on the sewing machine board, and looked forward, as if thinking about some details. A tractor pulling a car of chickens passed by, &quot;Kuda Kuda&quot;, and a big smell of chicken excrement hit our face. My mother said, it’s all fate, there’s no such thing as a bullshit solution. After my dad was laid off, all his dark blue work clothes were washed and hung to dry at the door. Buckets after buckets of water stained them black. Remove the threads, cut the long sleeves into short sleeves, disassemble the broken sleeves into rags, cut them into pieces and use them as mops, and use the larger ones as a welcome mat at the door of the toilet. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These work clothes that were no longer of any use soon came in handy. During the heavy rain that lasted for seven days and seven nights, the vegetable market where my family lived was flooded. The heavy rain kept pouring in. The sewer at the door was broken, and the water rose higher and higher. It had nowhere to go and invaded the home. The air in the room was as cold as an invisible dark cloud. The sound of rain became louder and louder, and no one noticed the lottery results on the TV. My mother was busy putting towels and rags on the window seams, and the water flowed along the towels into the basin below. The whole house was like a leaky valley, with constant echoes. Washbasin, footbath, vegetable basin, and so on. When it’s full, it’s poured into a large water tank. If it’s not full, it’s flushed down the toilet. All night long, my mother mopped the floor frantically, trying to sweep the water away. My dad covered all the valuable appliances in the house and moved them off the ground. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The water was so strong that my mother held the cloth in her tailor shop like the God of Wealth. My dad said that after giving birth to me, my mom didn’t hug me so hard. My grandfather had a good life. Ten days before the rainstorm, the Lord of Hell took him away. He stayed on the bed at home without saying a word, with his eyes closed and his hands flat on his chest. There was still a smile on his lips. This seems to be made up by my father, but I have no basis for it. After all, I have never met his old man. After all the planning, he lived to be seventy-eight and died. Grandpa&#39;s mysterious smile seemed to be mocking the heavy rain ten days later. He had already escaped and went to the paradise world. The coffin was lowered into the earth and buried on the mountain, with a panoramic view of the mountains. Unless there was a thunderstorm and a huge mudslide, the old man could rest easy and sleep for a long time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The electric switch was turned off, and it was dark inside and outside the house. Originally, there was only one river flowing under the bridge in Nanfang County, which was far away from my home. Now the whole county is flooded with unsold cabbages, tomatoes, large watermelons and floods. When my dad looked out with a flashlight to investigate the situation, he saw a basin-sized black thing floating on the water, with arms and legs, and realized it was a turtle. My dad hurried to the kitchen to take a look, and sure enough, the ingredients he bought at the vegetable market a few days ago had somehow escaped. The turtle swaggered away right under my dad&#39;s nose. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My dad told me while repairing the electric fan. I sat on the low wooden bench he assembled and ate watermelon. I bought this vertical electric fan a week before the rainstorm. It is a Camel brand. My dad brought it back from the supermarket happily. My mother scolded me for being a prodigal. We obviously have a desktop electric fan at home. It was my mother’s dowry. , green and blue, with Guanyin Bodhisattva painted on the stand. My mother fried pickles for three days to punish my father for his &quot;sins.&quot; Later, recalling the rainstorm, my mother joked that my father was holding the electric fan on the rooftop like he was holding another woman. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This electric fan is older than me. According to my father, I should call it Brother Sheng. I scoffed and continued to smear my face with watermelon rind. The watermelon water was sticky on my face, just like the summer in southern counties. Only the blades of the fan were whirring, and I stared at it, my vision blurring, as if it was trying to pull me back to that rainy night. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;02&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In my impression, my dad always sits behind the high counter, leaning on the table and tinkering with various electrical appliances. Sometimes it&#39;s an electric fan, or a TV, a landline phone, or a camera. His head is buried in a big tool box, and his hands never stop. His hands are big, different from other men, and his fingers are slender. More like a woman&#39;s hand than my mother&#39;s. My dad’s hands are very powerful, and there’s nothing that can’t be fixed in his hands. Except for that pocket watch that doesn&#39;t keep time. Dark gold, it looks heavy, but in my dad&#39;s hand it floats like a feather, which has lost its luster. Almost every night my dad was fixing the watch that was not keeping time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the summer vacation in elementary school, I got up at midnight one day. There was an orange light bulb on outside, and my dad was fixing the pocket watch with his head down. I walked over, leaned on the counter, and watched quietly as he replaced the rusty parts, installed new ones, and turned around with a screwdriver with a large needle tip. The sound echoed in the room and I couldn&#39;t get out. On the wall behind him, there are clocks of all sizes hanging, including a round clock with a plastic case, a square electronic watch, an iron alarm clock, a wooden clock with small balls swinging around, and an oversized floor clock that tells the time, leaning against the wall. Standing, every time on the hour, he spits out a colorful bird that spins and sings. It does not tell the time during the day, but strikes the time in the middle of the night. The singing voice of the colorful birds is as harsh as chalk scratched on a rusty blackboard. All the clocks have different times, ticking, and moving at different speeds. Some have completed a full circle, others have only made half a circle, and some have stayed still and have taken root. The short needle is like the tortoise in the tortoise and the hare race. It only moves a small space at a time, as if it will never end. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is also the most bizarre clock that runs backwards. At that time, I was hiding in bed watching Jin Yong at night. When I was thirsty, I got up and went to pour water. Suddenly I heard a rustling sound, and I thought in my mind that it might be some criminal thief. The shoes were in my hands, my feet felt cool on the ground, and I walked with my waist leaning on the wall. It wasn&#39;t until I recognized that the sound came from a clock that my heart dropped in my throat. In the dim light of the bathroom, I could vaguely see that the hands of this clock were moving backwards, very slowly, making a subtle &quot;click&quot; sound every time it moved. Feeling sleepy, I drank the water, went back to sleep, and forgot about it the next day. When I was young, I was surprised by everything and forgot everything quickly, including happiness and worries. But this dim sound became clearer and clearer until I became an adult. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the day, guests would take away their own clocks, repair them if they broke, and continue using them after they were repaired. When they were too broken to be repaired, they would be thrown into a smelly garbage dump. When my dad passes by, if he sees a clock that looks okay, he will pick it up, give it a wipe, remove the usable parts, wipe it clean, and store it respectfully in a large tool box. Some clocks have never been taken away. The clock that was turned upside down has always been placed on the top of the cabinet, with its hands covered with dust and motionless. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to my mother’s story, after my dad was laid off, he couldn’t just be idle and had to find something to do, so he opened a repair shop. Later, when I was born, my dad upgraded the repair shop. When I went to the repair shop, I grew up on this counter. My mother held the needle in one hand and put the end of the thread in her mouth with the other hand and inserted it into the needle. I asked, has my dad been able to fix things since he was a kid? My mother suddenly stopped and remembered something. The collapsed bridge was built by your father&#39;s original factory. She said this in a very calm tone, as if she was talking about today&#39;s vegetable prices. My dad’s original factory was the company where my dad worked before he was laid off. My dad is a bridge and tunnel engineer. During a routine inspection, he discovered that the bridge had some flood control problems. Before he could report it, the layoff notice came. Immediately afterwards, the bridge collapsed in the heavy rain. After the heavy rains, the large factory collapsed within a year. The house leaked and it rained all night. My mother recalled that when the bridge was first built, it looked like a shoddy project. It was built in two months. How could we not cut corners? After my dad was laid off, he still wanted to report the problems he discovered. He went to the factory several times and was turned away. I don’t know if the note left in the security room was seen. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is no trace of the collapsed bridge. It has been there since I can remember. Every time my dad took me across the bridge on his motorcycle, his back would stand straight and he wouldn&#39;t say anything. I didn&#39;t know what he was thinking, but I just felt that someone as big as my dad had something on his mind. I had just entered elementary school at that time, in 2003. My family has a phone booth. It’s blue and very nice. It’s right in front of my dad’s electrical repair shop. It looks like a soldier. My dad’s eyes are bright and he says it’s the God of Wealth. My mother answered, can I make 80 million? My father stopped talking, and he stopped talking when he was unhappy. When my mother saw this, she said it was good that our family members were in good health. After I entered high school, the Blue God of Wealth went bankrupt and everyone started using mobile phones, including my dad. The coins in my piggy bank will never see the light of day again. For a while, I was obsessed with making calls at phone booths. I would press a series of numbers blindly, and the phone would be answered by different people. Most of the people who answered the phone were old people, and some were children. But most of the time, there was no sound, but I was determined. I truly believed that the person who answered the phone was from the past or the future, and wrote down my imagination of the future in my diary. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I wanted to grow up so much that I wrote in my diary: In this way, I can have my own mobile phone, and I can send text messages to the boy next door who is the fairest and has the best grades and let him guess. Guess who I am. I can lie in bed every day, sleep until the sun basks on my butt, and read novels all day long. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;03&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the 2008 Olympic Games, Nanfang County opened its first zoo. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was a mess in my final exam. I had an English paper with a score of 78 in my schoolbag. I walked into my dad&#39;s repair shop with fear and wanted to get his autograph. My dad was repairing the neighbor&#39;s electric fan. When he saw me coming, he looked up and smiled at me. He put down the thing in his hand and happily waved the two pink tickets in his hand, saying he would take me to the zoo. I didn&#39;t take out the paper because I didn&#39;t want to ruin my dad&#39;s fun. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is actually nothing in the zoo, except for the horrifyingly expensive ice cream. It&#39;s strange. In my impression, summer in southern counties is always hot. Even after it rains, it only cools down for a while. There are no trash cans on the dusty streets, so there are trash cans, cardboard boxes and melon and banana peels everywhere. A boy with yellow hair on his head was smoking in front of the store. The store owner yelled, &quot;Go away and smoke.&quot; Huang Mao and I were shocked. Huang Mao swore a few curse words and walked away. The store owner is a bald, fat man with a face that looks a bit like the Tathagata Buddha in &quot;Journey to the West&quot;. I call him Uncle Pang. He is my dad’s only friend. He was laid off later than my dad. Every time he sees me, he gives me an orange-flavored lollipop and puts his hands on the glass counter, making a squeaking sound. With a strange squeaking sound, he would always smile and ask me how I was doing in the exam and if I wanted to sign the paper for my dad. I proudly said that I had learned my dad&#39;s signature and would not bother him anymore. He took the calculator and pressed blindly on it, &quot;Zero zero zero zero zero, return to zero.&quot; The mechanical female voice sounded even colder. I don’t know why, but Uncle Pang’s eyes looked a little lonely. I looked at his shiny scalp and envied him that he didn’t have to carry long hair that looked like a dirty rag. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Uncle Pang pressed the calculator with his fat hand for a while. He felt bored and asked me if the zoo was fun. I swallowed my saliva and said they were all delicious, chickens, ducks, pigs, cows, and rabbits. , frogs, and a three-month-old lamb bleating at me. Uncle Pang suddenly laughed, showing his yellow teeth from chewing betel nut every day, and said that you are too cruel, not like your father&#39;s daughter. I also laughed and said that I am better than my predecessor. Get a piece of crushed ice from the freezer at the door and ask my dad to pay. Uncle Pang said, your dad saved my life, let alone popsicles, if you want to eat dragon meat, Uncle Pang will get it for you. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The second half of the sentence is to coax the child, but the first half is true. My dad did save Uncle Pang’s life. In that long-lasting heavy rain, the entire southern county seemed to be plunged into the sea. The low-lying area was reduced to the bottom of the sea. Uncle Pang&#39;s legs were pinned under the fallen door. My dad used force to get him out, but he missed the time to go to the hospital. Uncle Pang&#39;s legs suffered sequelae. He walks with a limp, is not good-looking, has a bald head, and is lame. He has been a bachelor and opened a small shop to make a living. He said that he watched me born and grew up. On the day I was born, the sky was clear and the weather was great. What a mess. There is the word &quot;Qing&quot; in my name, and my parents hope that my future life will be sunny. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Uncle Pang often said to me, your dad is a good man, but he is unlucky. I don&#39;t understand what Uncle Pang means by &quot;bad luck.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I was in high school, my family moved out of the vegetable market and moved into a two-bedroom apartment in an elevator room. It was less than one kilometer away from the vegetable market, but it seemed like a new world. When we were moving, my dad borrowed a large tricycle from Uncle Pang and neatly stacked the wooden sofa, wooden table, wooden cabinets, and wooden stools on the car. Finally, he got into the car with his beloved electric fan and asked me to Sit back and hug &quot;my brother&quot; well. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The life that followed passed by like this tricycle that was about to fall apart. My dad and mom were bickering as usual. The most handsome boy in the class next door was recommended to Tsinghua University in his second year of high school. I was still swimming around in the middle, thinking I was free, but actually I didn&#39;t know where to go. My dad took me to the zoo. This was my second time going to the zoo, but my dad had been there many times. The pink ticket came in a small iron box. That morning I washed my hair very clean, and happily bought an &quot;exorbitantly expensive&quot; ice cream with my pocket money and took it inside. When I walked to the animal area, four or five meters away, I saw the boy who was being escorted and a beautiful girl together, laughing so hard at the peacock with its tail open. In the hot summer, the ice cream melted and dropped on my hand, which was cold. I took it in my mouth and threw away the stick. Tossing his hair again, Meteor strode out of the zoo. It took a while for my dad to realize that I was missing. When he came out, he saw me squatting under a tree at the entrance of the zoo. I hugged my knees and scolded my dad, but my heart felt empty. It&#39;s summer again, my hands are sticky, my hair is tangled, all stuck to the nape of my neck, it&#39;s sweltering, the sun is shining down, the road is scalding hot, and my eyes are filled with white flowers. My dad patted me and I held my knees to stand up, the world spinning. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After returning home, I cut my hair to ear level. It only takes five minutes to wash my hair. I get up at six o&#39;clock every day to memorize vocabulary words. My mother usually tells me not to stay up late reading novels, but now she tells me not to stay up too late studying. . When it was cold on the way to school in winter, my mother would put a hot boiled egg in my pocket. After the last exam of the college entrance examination, my dad stood waiting for me at the school gate and took me to KFC to celebrate. By then I was as tall as my dad. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We went to the zoo early the next morning. I sat on the back of my dad’s motorcycle, pulling on his clothes. He looked much older in the reflector. He suddenly said, you have grown up. I said &quot;hmm&quot;. My dad used to ride this lady&#39;s motorcycle to take me out for fun and back home. I was only four or five years old at that time. I stood on the front seat of a motorcycle, looking around, and sang the &quot;little conch horn, dripping, dripping&quot; that I learned in kindergarten. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The zoo has been expanded and is much larger than before. There are three more monkeys, five orangutans, and a dolphin. My dad took the most photos of it. My dad said dolphins are the smartest animals in the ocean. The dolphin was swimming around, and when it saw someone coming, it swam to the glass. The eyes were dark and the mouth curved upward into a line. I suddenly felt a little sad. I said to my dad, what’s the use of being smart? I’m still here. My dad put his hand on the glass and was so close that he didn&#39;t hear me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I grew up as I wished, becoming the first college student in our family and the second best student in Nanfang County. The red banner hung at the door of my mother’s tailor shop for a long time. I went to my father’s repair shop and my mother’s tailor shop. There are more and more people, all of whom are learning lessons for their children. My mother is so proud, her sewing machine makes a squeaking sound, and her mouth is like a cannon. My dad was happier, happier than I was. As soon as the admission notice arrived, he put down what he was doing, wiped his hands, took the admission notice, and read it out word for word, smiling from ear to ear. There are many people who come to my dad&#39;s repair shop to try to get some luck, but my dad doesn&#39;t talk when he repairs things, and the customers leave in disgust. I went to Beijing, the heart of the motherland, to go to university. My dad was even happier than I was. He verbally made a list for me. First go to Tiananmen Square to see the flag raising, and then go climb the Great Wall. This way you will be a good man. I said that even if I didn’t climb the Great Wall, I would still be a good man. My dad ignored me and continued, go to the Forbidden City and see how the emperor lives differently from us ordinary people. I said you can see it on your mobile phone. My dad said, that&#39;s different. My mother answered, &quot;That&#39;s because the feng shui is different.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The last item on this list is to go to the aquarium to see whales. Because there is no zoo in our county. I replied to my dad that there would be no whales in the aquarium. Whales are huge and are the largest creatures in the ocean. My dad sounded disappointed, and after chatting for a while, I said that I was going shopping with my classmates. The shopping malls here are open at night, and there is an air-conditioned movie theater with softer seats than the seats in our county theater. My dad said, please pay more attention to safety, and then said that he went to repair Uncle Pang&#39;s mobile phone. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I went to the aquarium. I didn’t see whales. I went to see dolphins, many dolphins. The entire pool was so big that I couldn&#39;t see the end, and dolphins swam right above my head. There are also turtles paddling slowly across the glass wall. I looked at it for a long time, and suddenly I remembered the backward clock I saw in the middle of the night when I was a child. Maybe for a moment, I felt something was broken. Later I took a lot of photos, developed them and sent them back. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later, I graduated and found a job in Beijing. I would go home every Spring Festival and National Day. Every day it keeps spinning like a top. I can’t remember how many times I’ve gotten off work late at night, and the night view outside the taxi window is still brightly lit. I suddenly remembered that a long time ago, at night in Nanfang County, the sun set, the birds returned to their nests, the whole street was dark, the vegetable market became quiet, and I wanted to go home for dinner. After eating, it was dark outside the window, quiet, and there was no sound at all. It seems like our house is the only thing left in this world. The news was playing on the TV, and the rice in the bowl seemed strange. I suddenly wondered, why am I here? My mother didn’t seem to hear, holding the bowl and waiting for the weather report. I looked at my dad blankly, and my dad also looked at me. He was almost finished eating and stopped holding the chopsticks in his hand. I don’t know why I asked this question. I just wanted to ask it, but I just couldn’t figure it out. I thought my dad would talk about a lot of truths from Chicken Soup for the Soul books like he usually does. But he didn&#39;t. He thought for a long, long time. In the silence, it seemed like there were only two of us left in the world, and even the rice bowl in my hand disappeared. This memory is no longer clear enough. I can’t remember how my dad answered me at that time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;04&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My mother said that when my grandfather left, she didn’t know about the news that my father was laid off. My dad is the breadwinner of the family, the only support for my grandparents. There has been no news from my uncle twenty years ago, and my second uncle is far away from home and has ignored my parents. My grandpa was gone, and my dad showed no expression at all. He contacted the funeral home to pick up people, cremate him, and go to the mountain alone with the urn. When I came back, my clothes were covered in mud. My dad said he fell because of the slippery road. On the night of the last rainstorm, my mother was already too tired to fall asleep when she suddenly heard a strange noise in the rainstorm, like a wounded animal. When she looked carefully and looked at the moonlight, she saw that my dad&#39;s eyes were as bright as an animal. Rat, I asked my mother why he was a rat, and my mother said that my father was born in the year of the rat. My dad just stared straight into the dark air, with water all over his face. His throat moved and he sniffed quietly, but my mother heard him. He was holding a pocket watch in his hand. She patted my dad on the back and said nothing. My dad was nine minutes away from seeing grandpa for the last time. He had just come out of his grandfather&#39;s house, and his grandfather was still fine. He was lying on the bed watching the Anti-Japanese War drama with his glasses on, squinting his eyes as usual. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The heavy rain came without warning after dinner. Grandma finished dinner at my house and was going to go back after reading the weather forecast. My grandma has bad ears. My mother heard the sound of rain immediately and quickly asked my dad to close the window. My grandma was still sitting in front of the TV watching the weather forecast and listening with her ears tilted, but in fact she couldn&#39;t hear clearly at all. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Damn weather forecasts are never accurate. The people at the Meteorological Bureau are just shit. Three days before the heavy rain, the first floor was flooded. My grandma hugged my grandpa’s portrait tightly. Nothing in life can be said with certainty, my grandma said. Grandma said that the fortune teller at the entrance of the village said that she would have a big hurdle at the age of eighty-six, and if she passed it, she would live to ninety-nine, but she passed away at eighty-seven. My dad said that the fortune teller was not accurate, so I asked, maybe the god who was in charge of my grandma’s lifespan died. My mother glared at me, &quot;Don&#39;t talk nonsense.&quot; I curled my lips, why won’t the gods die? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the beginning of this year, I received a phone call, but there was no sound on the other end. For a moment, after more than ten years, I thought I had finally received the call from the past in the phone booth, and I was afraid of missing any sound. After a while, a low voice came from over there. It was my dad. He said, your Uncle Pang is gone. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Uncle Pang passed away. He drove a tricycle across the bridge and collided with a cement truck. Uncle Pang flew more than ten meters away, and the blue slippers on his feet flew to the tree. My dad later poked the slipper off with a clothes hanger, washed it, and put it on Uncle Pang&#39;s fat feet. When Uncle Pang left, he was decent down to his toes. His black and smelly toenails and fingernails were trimmed spotlessly by my dad. He was chubby and even a little cute. My dad held a small farewell ceremony at the funeral home, attended by only three of our family members. Uncle Pang was surrounded in the middle. He had never been lying so upright. I stared at his scalp, and the more I looked at it, the less shiny it seemed. I wanted to tell him to put some oil on it, but unfortunately he couldn&#39;t hear it. Uncle Pang was very eccentric. He smoked, drank, chewed betel nut, and had yellow teeth. Nine out of ten sentences contained swear words, but he almost never said them in front of me. My favorite shoes are slippers, my favorite song is Teresa Teng and the calculator&#39;s &quot;For Alice&quot;, my best game is Tetris, and my worst one is Super Mario. I haven&#39;t told him before, but I actually like him very much. When I was eighteen years old, I had already stepped on the train to Beijing. Uncle Pang grabbed my hand and told me to come back often. His hands were very fat and rough, like linen, which made me feel a little uncomfortable. , I nodded and took my hand away. I remember that when I was a kid, I loved going to the small supermarket run by Uncle Pang. The high shelves were filled with colorful snacks, and I could touch them row by row. The crisp sound of the packaging bags was the most beautiful music I had ever heard. Uncle Pang said that when he gets old, he will let me take over his duties and eat whatever he wants. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My mother has always disliked Uncle Pang. He loves to swear and has never been to school. My mother stood far away from Uncle Pang and suddenly said, Uncle Pang, your life is worth it. My dad did save Uncle Pang’s life, but it wasn’t what my dad said. My mom said that the truth was that my dad was laid off from work and walked to the bridge in a heavy rain in a state of despair. His whole body hung by the railing. Young Uncle Pang was heartbroken. , standing on the bridge and wanting to jump into the river. My dad caught Uncle Pang in a critical situation. Drag him up. My dad only found out about winning the lottery by reading the newspaper, because the numbers were my dad&#39;s and mom&#39;s birthdays. I asked Uncle Pang why his leg was lame. My dad said it was because the road was slippery on a rainy day and he broke it. It was so embarrassing, so he said it was caused by the door. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My mother said next to me that the lottery ticket fell out of my father&#39;s pocket. If my father had grabbed it with his hands, maybe my family would have no worries about food and drink from now on. However, the last thing my dad grabbed was Uncle Pang&#39;s arm. The palm-sized lottery ticket was blown to nowhere by the wind. It probably sank into the lake, in the belly of the fruit fish and shrimp. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My dad later learned from the newspaper that the unclaimed 80 million yuan was used to build a zoo in the county seat, the first zoo in Nanfang County. In the past time, many things that I didn&#39;t understand have come to light. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My dad and I stood side by side. I was surprised to find that I was already a little taller than my dad. He became thin and swayed when the wind blew. There are weeds everywhere on the hillside. It&#39;s already the beginning of spring, but it&#39;s still as withered as ever. I remembered the question I had forgotten the answer to before, touched him lightly with my shoulder, and asked him if he still remembered that I asked you a question before. My dad said, remember. I said in surprise, I haven&#39;t said anything yet. My dad said, but I always remember, you asked, why am I here. I suddenly felt like I didn’t recognize my dad and he didn’t look like a different person. I didn&#39;t speak, and the long pause condensed and dissolved in the air. came the voice. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I don’t know. He said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Am I expecting something?我也不知道我在期待什么答案。两个人久久地站着。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;又下起了淅淅沥沥的小雨。他弯下腰把墓前的草拨了拨，我听到了秒针滴滴答答的声音，分针越走越快，时针也越走越快，恍惚间，我爸，年轻时的我爸从我面前冲了过去，身上全是泥水，他急切地要去一个地方。再一睁眼，他已经伏在桥上，紧紧地拉住了那个跳河的青年。他的脸庞上两道清亮的水印子，我看得比谁都真切。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;水从天上下来，水流在街道上，盖过路面，水缓慢地行走在无人的街道上，水里有无数个孤独的月亮，我依稀看到，远远的，黑漆漆的夜里，水面向天边去，一片陆地上的海洋，一只乌龟摆动着四肢，不知从何处来，慢悠悠地往看不见的水面的尽头游去。在夜色中游走了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;责任编辑：李嘉龙&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;征稿信息见@ONE一个工作室置顶微博。更多编辑部的有趣日常请关注小红书：ONE一个编辑部。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fu4uqjdn0_ML9IjFDX2dY9uIJCw4&quot; alt=&quot;言隹&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;言隹 &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;今天晚上吃啥？ &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;关注&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;相关推荐&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6121&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;学以无用&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 宫主冰&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6122&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;较量&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 伊朝南&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6124&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;我与父亲走过最远的地方&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ Look look&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6128)&quot;>;点击可下载ONE一个app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4027]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4167]]><description>&lt;div>;16 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgBzREfN-FlVC-YSj1BRkzJczaVg&quot; alt=&quot;首页图&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4027&lt;/span>;插画| Dozy Boy&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;16&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oct. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;我独自度过了太多的时光，沉默已成一种习惯。&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 16 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>