<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[你的消费是如何降级的？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3923]]><description> &lt;div>;25 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Question from ONE Editorial Department&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>; How has your consumption been downgraded? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; ONE Friendly Answers&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FjK6OiuUxBws_suzGKaA3MTAmnhk&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FjK6OiuUxBws_suzGKaA3MTAmnhk&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;There were a few good years when I wore 2000+ ecco. Now 2,000 yuan can buy five pairs of shoes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Dongdong (38 years old, confused person)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;Now that I have a job, I don’t have any living expenses to pay. In the past, I didn’t have to pay rent for living expenses of 2,500 yuan a month while studying in college. Now I have to pay various fees with a salary of 5,000 yuan a month, so my consumption has naturally degraded. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Zi Yige (24 years old, novice at publishing house)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br >;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After resigning, I switched from a cup of hand-brewed drink from the store every day to an 8-pack of hanging ears for 20 yuan. It was really hard to drink, but... poor. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Free cup (30 years old, can’t live without coffee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I went to Maldives for the National Day in 2019. During the epidemic, I kept thinking about Mauritius, and then I had salary cuts, layoffs, and illness. Today, I am going to sleep at home during the National Day, but I may not be able to sleep. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;LongJ (29 years old, unemployed youth)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;After owning a kitchen, my consumption has naturally been downgraded and my quality of life has been upgraded. From now on, I basically say goodbye to takeout, which is not only cheap but also very healthy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Meng An (29 years old, programmer)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;This is not a deliberate consumption downgrade, but after trying all the cosmetics, I know that the one that suits me is the best. An eyebrow pencil worth more than a dozen yuan is also very useful. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Chanjuan (33 years old, banker)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;Moving from Guangzhou to Foshan, commuting across cities in the Guangzhou-Foshan area only increased the work time by 20 minutes each way, and the monthly rent instantly dropped to 900 yuan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;The cat in the fan room (27 years old, part-time worker)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When shopping, I will ask about any items that may have trial sizes, and buy as little as possible. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Da Ben&#39;er (31 years old, sales)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;Keyboards, mice, headphones... I’m not willing to buy good electronic equipment anymore. In the past, I might have read reviews and compared brands, but now they are sorted by price, as long as they can bear to use them. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Superman can’t fly (29 years old, Internet worker)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br >;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I didn’t actively observe when the downgrade started, but big data noticed my changes - the word &quot;replacement&quot; began to appear frequently in the recommendations of my various apps. Pages, and searching for keywords like &quot;can be 10 times cheaper than usual!&quot; &quot;With content like this, I think the network actually remembered my downgrade and started to help me downgrade. Big data is much more aware than me.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Xu Haha (27 years old, administrative staff)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;Before ordering takeout, you must first search for red envelopes to receive the official account. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Cookie Doro (29 years old, investment bank employee)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When buying a book, you have to open the major shopping apps on your phone to compare which one has the lowest price on the Internet. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Detergent Kitten (21 years old, prospective graduate)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt; br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sleep more, go out less, eat less, and if you don’t see where you spend money, you won’t spend it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;jenin (25 years old, international student)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A certain group of takeaways have a &quot;Pulled Rice&quot; meal. The options are limited but the meal is much cheaper. They are all converted from retail to wholesale to offset sales, so that consumers can spend less money. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;abcd (26 years old, poor man who can’t cook)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong >;&lt;br>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I gritted my teeth and paid off the mortgage in advance. Now I am selling it. I will cancel all entertainment activities before selling. Even if I am lucky and sell at a reduced price, I will probably exchange it for US dollars or gold, leaving a few dollars. Ten thousand yuan to spare. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;crystal (35 years old, deserter)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After being laid off, I changed to a &quot;stable job&quot; with a salary cut in half. My son&#39;s tutor changed from a famous teacher who paid 800 per class to a new teacher who paid 300 per class. I hope he won&#39;t blame me in the future. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;801 Househusband (36 years old, a man)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Li Jialong onewenzhang@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For information on the call for papers, please see @ONE Studio’s top Weibo post. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8 &quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Complex The cutest people in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3896&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Where does our sense of poverty come from? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3696&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What happened to the young people who traveled around in poverty? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3923)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[放心，离婚比爱情容易]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6105]]><description> &lt;div>;25 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Jia Binbin&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data -author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fr1OZLWHy4YxnhObP1L4np--y4gc&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fr1OZLWHy4YxnhObP1L4np--y4gc &quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Two screenwriters who are good at handling various dramatic conflicts go together When I entered the marriage hall, I found that the problem of love was more difficult to deal with than imagined. After a long period of consumption, they got to know each other again during the divorce. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;1. About &amp;ldquo;Me Willing&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The most unexpected proposal was to participate in someone else&#39;s proposal and find out that the person being proposed to was himself - Li Xiang was on the high-speed train returning from a business trip, maybe It was the stretching scenery outside the window, or perhaps the fear of the unknown that excited him, and he felt that he had come up with a wonderful idea. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ice kept pulling the high heels out of the deck where they were stuck, and she was starting to get annoyed. When she walked in, the confetti collapsed and all her friends applauded, she thought: It&#39;s over. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The yacht has already sailed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Someone helped her take off her coat, someone put a garland on her, someone pushed her to the center, the music started, Li Xiang showed a successful smile, and took the microphone, she could no longer listen. to any sound. Li wanted to say something, and everyone laughed from time to time. She wandered in her thoughts: Was their discussion about marriage in the past six months such a big deviation? Why this, the worst possible time, in the most disgusting way for her? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is said in &quot;Big Fish&quot; that when you meet your true love, time will stop. This is definitely false. But when your partner proposes to you, your time is stretched like a ball of stitches. Ice could no longer hear the sound, but the faces of every friend present became extremely clear in her eyes - this long love was never just a matter of two people, but a relationship that included career lines and friendship lines. is a sitcom, now a reunion, many people and relationships are set on a marriage proposal. After the yacht stops, they will go their separate ways and leave the city. They will be separated, live and die without contact, and will face Some tough life decisions. Is this where the play is going to end? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She has withdrawn from work again, handling many script projects, and there are many love-hate separations in them. Both the screenwriter and the client will always ask repeatedly, &quot;This is the grasp of the relationship.&quot; What are hands? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At this moment she discovered it, she didn’t know it at all. Do relationships need a hand? Is marriage the catch? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It’s too late, it’s too late. The infinitely stretched time also has an expiration date, and it does not allow her to make a mind map, list the pros and cons one by one, and calculate the proportions. Li Xiang has already knelt down on one knee. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ice looked at his somewhat uneasy eyes - such an expression rarely appeared on his face. She recalled the countless separations and reunions over the years, with tears streaming down her face, and the most ferocious appearance of the two of them. The infinitely jumping memories finally stopped at the New Year&#39;s Eve of 2017. They had a big argument in the mall over trivial matters, and he suddenly stopped talking and dragged her out of the door while she was chattering endlessly. Fireworks exploded in the night sky. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;It’s midnight. &quot;He said, &quot;That&#39;s the most important thing. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She thought too much, and at this moment, she also dragged him into her own stagnant timeline and swinging world - there were only two of them, asking him a hundred thousand whys, but it was wrong. A quarrel will last forever. But no, she couldn&#39;t say &quot;I have no confidence&quot; at this moment, and let the yacht sail towards destruction in embarrassment and disappointment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The eyes of my friends have changed from excitement to encouragement. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ice held out her hand and said, &quot;That&#39;s okay.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Maybe this sitcom has been renewed, and other main characters who have left halfway cheered. She was grateful that the cheers were loud enough, because the heckling drowned out an inappropriate voice:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;She didn&#39;t say I would. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It doesn’t matter, we don’t look at life with a magnifying glass. Kiss and let the yacht go on. Taking pictures, cheering, crying blessings and saying goodbye in the KTV, it’s nothing more than this. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ice ordered the song &quot;Tomorrow Will Be Better&quot; and managed to see other people hugging and crying. She sat in the corner and kept smoking. A friend came close to her and whispered, &quot;It doesn&#39;t matter, you can leave after we get married.&quot; &amp;rdquo;She wasn&#39;t worried about this. Through the swirling smoke, she looked at every friend on the field, including Li Xiang. The renewal button made a ding sound when pressed, and the avatars of the participants were frozen here, and then turned gray one by one. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ice wants to catch someone who will not become gray at this moment, or in other words, someone who will not become gray too soon. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In short, this eight-year love is always like this. Li Xiang&#39;s ideas are never brilliant and often painful for her, but they all work. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;2. About the beginning and the end&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Men remember &amp;ldquo; Women treasure the &quot;serious&quot; moments, at least they do. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Their acquaintance was not a meeting, but one story after another filled with nonsense, half-truths and half-false hearsay. When love arises from too many &quot;hearings&quot;, the unguarded one will easily become the loser. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was an inexplicable and mixed situation. Li Xiang, 29, aims to make a good postcard for his company, reflect the company&#39;s eagerness for talents, and introduce friends who are successful or unsuccessful to get to know each other. The 21-year-old Ice needs a big drink to get rid of the pain after a broken relationship, and the part-time job she has enough money and leisure to do is boring. She is thinking that her career should be on the right track. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As if out of a sense of social responsibility, they raised their glasses in unison and stood up, starting to circle and introduce each other - if they were having a wedding, this would probably be the same. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;A certain teacher is finally here. So-and-so has been waiting for you. I especially like your show... A project...&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After a few laps, the scene became familiar, with some drunken promises, flattery and laughter. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Xiang held the wine glass with a flushed face, still wearing a skillful smile, and sat alone in the last row. He watched people at several tables walking back and forth, and smiled in response from time to time. Voice. It seems to be sincerity that the most courageous drinker has the worst capacity for drinking. Ice came to confirm whether he was really drunk, and Li Xiang suddenly said, &quot;These are meaningless.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ice was a little surprised. After thinking about it, he said, &quot;Life is meaningless, otherwise why would you drink.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He sat up straight, as if he was not drunk at all, and said, &amp;ldquo;You will have connections when you get older. Fame and money, a project succeeds or fails, it comes and goes. Being worldly is just a joke, don&#39;t take it as your core skill. The skill is to take serious writing seriously when you are young enough. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She started to think about it, and he laughed loudly, showing his hungry side again, and said, &amp;ldquo;So, you should come to our company and work with me. I guarantee that you will be single within five years. Set the price for this number. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ice also laughed, thinking he looked like a fool engaging in a pyramid scheme. She drank her own drink and shot back, &quot;I can write this number even if I don&#39;t follow your path.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even though she said this, even though they didn&#39;t look at each other or clink glasses from beginning to end, the strange lights after the alcohol began to slow down, the pleasant laughter faded away, and there was no longer any contact between them. There are other voices. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If you jump to the perspective of a bystander, you have already noticed the risks of this relationship. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;First, if you want to have feelings, don’t work together. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Second, this battle for emotional dominance will last for a long time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Third, both fools take a cause of little significance as their top priority. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What they said that day came true. It’s not a good thing. They have to pursue or compromise to something they despise, and exchange repeated disillusionment for a pile of money, but still no one has written anything. They spent all their time on these things that they should fulfill their wedding vows. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the following year or two, all risk predictions were fully reflected in this relationship. They thought of many ways: for example, they no longer wrote a project together. , each looking for a way out but helping each other. After years of war, the emotional dominance may have been taken back by Ice, but she hates controlling and changing someone, and they both find that this kind of struggle is meaningless. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Xiang is always good at finding solutions: starting from the third year of their relationship, in order to reduce disputes and make work easier, they began to sleep in separate rooms. Later, for greater convenience, they ate separately and only communicated with each other before going to bed. Have a cigarette in the room and talk about projects. After that, she would just wave her hands tiredly and say, &quot;Don&#39;t ask.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They advise each other on their work and organize all the festive gatherings. Every day when I wake up, the living room is full of friends having meetings in front of the computer. I made a joke while making coffee and laughed and chatted for a while. When the coffee was almost finished, I wondered if this project would be bad. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When their careers got better, they also became busy. Being away from each other for a long time, everyone is busy with their own things in the video. She said, &quot;I have influenza A,&quot; and he said, &quot;I haven&#39;t finished posting the invoice.&quot; She said, &quot;I&#39;m going to have a showdown tomorrow, and I don&#39;t want to do this job anymore because I broke the contract.&quot; He said, &quot;The cat litter seems to be running out, please remember to buy it.&quot; She said, &quot;Please accompany me to Switzerland for euthanasia. I will die on my own, and you can accompany me.&quot; He said, &quot;Just go skiing in Switzerland.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It ended later than both of them expected. They won&#39;t admit it, but they know that &quot;this relationship will definitely be messed up&quot;, and they have thought about it many times. People who are as high-spirited as the sun will certainly not be swallowed by a black hole, but they will never understand the eternal depression, resistance and desire for destruction of a black hole. They are obsessed with the qualities they don&#39;t have and feel that the world composed of this is complete and rich. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Opposite qualities can make a relationship unique, but they cannot sustain a marriage. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When we were young, everyone underestimated the need for &quot;understanding&quot; in love. It doesn&#39;t matter whether you become famous or live a lifetime of worthlessness. A person&#39;s social status can change his life, but it cannot solve emptiness and loneliness. If there is no one to hold the balance for you, if there is no one who can hold your heart and everything about you in the palm of his hand, your life will be in vain. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Just like the yacht that made Ice want to jump into the Huangpu River. What you want is an apple, you love him, he loves you, but he is just a pear tree. This is fatal. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With different personalities and busy work, the straw that broke the camel&#39;s back was expected, like &quot;You never asked me to squeeze lemon juice into fried chicken&quot; I&#39;m just as ordinary. Her first reaction was to laugh and file for divorce. Then she immediately confirmed the project delivery date for the two of them and set a timetable for the divorce. Not too emotional, just a little complaining, why can&#39;t he just pretend to be himself a little, let life pass for a while, and then face it when he has time, wouldn&#39;t it be easier? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fortunately, I am used to sleeping in separate rooms, so I can finish my manuscripts behind closed doors. The coming and going of love is beyond anyone&#39;s control. She has already predicted the outcome and just hopes to reduce consumption when facing it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was unexpected that the situation got out of control-Ice came back early after dinner and wanted to review the divorce agreement. Li Xiang was not there, and the computer screen was on. She inevitably saw some things about him and him. In the chat records of friends about divorce, she was slapped with some big labels and described as a person who was far from who she thought she was. Divorce was a naive woman following the fashion. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All psychological construction is vulnerable compared to these misunderstandings and judgments. Eight years of hard work, whether beautiful or painful, have all turned out to be fake. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ice cannot accept it. She is indeed naive, otherwise, at nearly thirty years old, why would her desire for all emotions still be illusory things, such as deep understanding and knowing delivery. If everything you have experienced in eight years can&#39;t do this, then what have the past eight years been? What is left in the future besides desolation? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li wanted to defend himself and slap himself, but she fell to the ground, crying and convulsing. He took a knife, and she climbed out of the window--and finally relied on her friends to hug each other. , forcibly separated. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ice said something that he could not refute, &quot;When I get married, I don&#39;t want a wedding, a wedding ring, a wedding room, or a bride price, because I don&#39;t like it.&quot; I convinced my parents. They only made one request, just take good care of me and make me happy. You didn&#39;t do it. Now they want us to separate, and you can do this. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I don’t want my marriage to be like theirs, and neither do they. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That night when they applied the ice pack, they finally no longer had to be afraid of losing each other, nor were they afraid of the pain of tormenting each other. Because I feel no pain at all. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;3. About beauty and beauty afterward&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He looked at her My favorite movies and dramas always make me fall asleep without interest. He always criticized her for being hesitant and changing her orders from day to day. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She helped him with the scripts and would always criticize him vigorously, accusing him of being too slow in meetings and lacking emotion and details. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But they can argue and take a walk for several kilometers in the middle of the night; feel frustrated and think &quot;fuck, your metaphor is too accurate&quot;, and then laugh; and argue for themselves in front of their friends. Noun Definition: Noisy for three hours, while gathering depressed friends together to make soup and dishes to ensure that every festival is happy and joyful. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So, Ice kept asking Li Xiang a question for seven years, &quot;What do you like about me?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Xiang’s answer has not changed, “Except for the objective conditions, I like your kindness and innocence.” &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She has always been dissatisfied with this too old-fashioned answer. After the divorce, she understood. Because Li Xiang was already a sophisticated and harmonious person when they met, he liked that she was always an idealist within a secular framework, and understood that while she was high-spirited, she constantly wanted to be a deserter and a coward. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ice has been in Shanghai for ten years, but still refuses to take a physical examination and pay social security, refuses to buy a house or a car, hates the huge sense of ceremony, hates all social activities, and spends money. In treating friends to dinner and drinks and cathartic shopping. She seemed ready to run away at any moment, but she didn&#39;t want to leave Shanghai. The same goes for him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said, &quot;I can&#39;t get up if you don&#39;t hold me.&quot; &amp;rdquo;He came to coax her out of bed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said, &quot;I can&#39;t wake up even if I get up.&quot; &amp;rdquo;He made coffee and cooked food for her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said, &quot;I don&#39;t want to write it.&quot; &quot;He turned on the computer for her and said, &quot;I think it can be written like this.&quot; &amp;rdquo;Ice suddenly jumped up: &amp;ldquo;You must not write like that! &amp;rdquo;She pushed him out the door and finally sat down in front of the computer. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Did Li Xiang outside the door smile like he was succeeding? have no idea. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He always has a way to break out of her logical framework of going straight to hell, fooling the deserters into returning and turning them into elite soldiers and generals. This enabled her to complete one project after another that was “unable to be completed”. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ice never told Li Xiang what he liked about him. This is something that cannot be admitted in this relationship:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You always have a way to push me to do the right thing. You patiently coaxed me, letting me cry and collapse to do the things I didn&#39;t want to do. This is how I grew up and became strong. Otherwise...otherwise I don&#39;t know what to do in life. I don&#39;t want to do anything and I&#39;m not satisfied with anything, but I can&#39;t be idle without direction. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Marriage is different. The &quot;wonderful idea&quot; emerged from his mind, and she kept exposing all his deceptions and tricks. Things were different from the beginning - while he was pretending &quot;I&#39;m from your side&quot;, he was trying to completely coax her into secular discipline. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For example, sneaking into her room in the middle of the night and measuring her ring circumference with a steel ring. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For example, he has been planning to buy a house and a car, and promised to return the wall-climbing rose that was stolen many years ago and replenish the golden retriever. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For example, when it comes to bargaining for a wedding, she really doesn’t understand what the purpose of a wedding is. Out of all kinds of worldliness and responsibility to her parents, she drew a bottom line, organized a dinner party with strange relatives, said &quot;eat and drink well&quot; and ran away. He kept testing whether the bottom line could be lowered further, &quot;It&#39;s not a bad thing to collect money from members&quot;, &quot;In fact, cutting a PPT is quite commemorative&quot;, &quot;It will be easier if you have a master of ceremonies to control the rhythm.&quot; . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A huge dislocation occurred during an unexpected &quot;wedding photo&quot; session. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When his hometown was moving, his parents earnestly requested that they take a family photo - something she couldn&#39;t refuse. She was used to not disappointing people, especially the elderly. Ice had to think about his words and draw the bottom line. The more casual and ordinary the better, and taking wedding photos of the two of them would definitely not work. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Ice arrived late at the photo studio, the family of four all dressed up in Chinese wedding clothes, with their hair tied into a bun, hairpins inserted, and they began to choose suits and wedding dresses. She looked at Li Xiang for help. Li Xiang carefully selected from a row of hair gels and cut his hair. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The air conditioner in the fitting room was not warm enough, and she could not find the window where the wind was leaking. She was sleepy, hungry and cold. She looked at the white dress she had been forced to choose, which was the most unlike a wedding dress, and encouraged herself to go out and take a photo now. Would it be harder than jumping into the Huangpu River at that time? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She was so cold that her stomach ached and she kept taking deep breaths. Li Xiang, who finally got her hair done, called her name and came over. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ice opened the curtain and came forward. She expected him to say the same words as when she first fell in love, &quot;These are meaningless, let&#39;s go eat Haidilao.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But he is like the groom in all idol dramas, and even performs better. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There was an unreal but dazzling light in his eyes. He walked quickly and held her hand, &quot;You are so beautiful.&quot; It seems that while I am in love with you, I have fallen in love with you again. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her hands were very cold. He quickly hugged her and rubbed her hands. He quickly found the window that was not closed tightly and closed it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ice looked out the window, and the wind blew down the dead leaves. On the street, a group of children fired small cannons to scare a wild dog. The wild dog was so frightened that it jumped up and down and barked. They laughed so happily. Their parents twisted their eyebrows and said, &quot;Stop making trouble, maybe it&#39;s a mad dog and what to do if it gets bitten.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are no firecrackers here. Everyone is infinitely doting and tolerant of her, but why. Why did she feel like she was both a mad dog and a person being bitten? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the second day after the divorce application was submitted, Ice moved the cat to the house that had just been signed. Li Xiang packed his luggage and returned to his hometown to heal, facing the framed Family photos, a dressing room and a bathtub prepared for her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A month later, accompanied by their friends, they came to the marriage registration office again and signed countless words with countless fingerprints. The moment he got the certificate, the clerk loudly told his colleagues, &quot;The last couple is finished.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The lights in the entire registration area were quickly turned off one by one. The clerks left work faster than them with their bags under their arms. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After walking out of the door, Ice and Li Xiang smoked a cigarette together. She gave him a few instructions and he closed the car door for her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Ice and Li wanted to get a certificate, they had a six-hour negotiation and reached an agreement. It was not a vow or restriction in the name of love, nor did it involve any material things, but a divorce. It must be easy to get together and part ways. This agreement was more detailed than the divorce agreement written a year and a half later, such as how to divide the cat, how to deal with friends, how to deal with work matters, what to do after the divorce, and what to do after the divorce and each has a partner. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even if expected and unexpected things happen, they are still trying to defend the agreement they made when they got married, which is even more difficult than defending their marriage. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li wanted to escape and return to Shanghai, wandering around, but had to come back because of the smooth progress of the script. He wrote and attended meetings like a zombie. After socializing and drinking, his memory was repeatedly awakened by the streets he had walked on. . He found that he had an emotional disorder, as if he had become an idiot and only wanted to laugh, without tears. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ice became an alcoholic again. In the first month, she always cried when she was drunk, but later she always laughed when she was drunk. Projects that were not going well and could not be scrapped were revived. The insomnia and anxiety have improved. Every day when I wake up, there is cat poop at the door of the bedroom - the aunt said, &quot;Cats are more difficult to adapt to than humans.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They called, once or twice, only when they were awake. For the staff transfer at work, and for those friends who are still worrying. Recommend some new projects to each other, talk about their respective work progress, and confirm that each other is doing well. It is still easy to start arguing while talking, and then start arguing and laughing again. So Ice proposed not to contact her for half a year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pull the timeline back to when we fell in love. Ice complained that Li Xiang never expressed love, and begged him to write something to him, not necessarily a love letter, but something sincere, even a few lines. Li Xiang always refused. He had written novels for all the girls he had interacted with, but he didn&#39;t want to write them for her. He said, &quot;This is something you can only write when the relationship is over, not when you are in love.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the divorce, she received a letter from Li Xiang--in the early morning after getting drunk. The letter is very long, with many typos and incorrect sentences. The structure is confusing and there is no theme. She could only use her drunkenness to conclude by herself, &quot;I love you, but I can&#39;t do it well, I&#39;m sorry.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At that moment she remembered something. She also tried to write a love letter to him when she was newly married. She rummaged through the computer folders one by one, opened them, and found that she had only written half of it. Apparently she couldn&#39;t write anymore due to countless self-tortures, and she couldn&#39;t write any more. Because it doesn&#39;t look like a love letter at all, more like a premeditated defeat plan. I don’t know what I lost to. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The present letter answers the old letter. She created a new document and placed the two letters in it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She seemed to have forgiven those chat records, because when a relationship ends, people always need something to finalize their relationship, even if it is false or wrong. So she saved two poems in the file, one of which they had all read: &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;em>;&amp;ldquo;That night in the motel room,&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;&lt;em>;In those early morning hours,&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;em>;he opened the curtains. See the clouds gathering&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;em>;covering the moon. He leaned against the glass, &lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;em>;closer. The cold air rushed in and placed its hand on his heart. &lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;em>;I loved you, he thought. &lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;em>;Love you well. &lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;em>;Before I stop loving you. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Zhou Ziheng&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For information on the call for papers, see @ONE Studio’s pinned Weibo. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/Fq5uVbK51WDOTcw0w0hLsNxMdR42&quot; alt=&quot;Jia Binbin&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Jia Binbin&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@二 BinAh Erbin&lt;/span >; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Young author and screenwriter. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/article/1228&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Killing the lovers of time&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Jia Binbin&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr >; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6105)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt; /div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt; a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx. best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4006]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4141]]><description>&lt;div>;25 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FtP_XfxZzPIM72zSAyvLX4Ozalbz&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;VOL.4006&lt;/span>;Photography | Gracia Dharma&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;25&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sep. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Sometimes, I feel like I have been living between two alarm clocks my whole life, the first alarm clock in the morning, and the second alarm clock 5 minutes later. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 25 Sep 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>