<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[昨天晚上，你有什么突然出现的感悟？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3968]]><description> &lt;div>;6 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Question from ONE Editorial Department&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>; Did you have any sudden realizations last night? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; ONE Friendly Answers&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmpZkW2_jR_qeJkrwBrdJsmBFYsw&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmpZkW2_jR_qeJkrwBrdJsmBFYsw&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot; font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;When the busy day is over, in the quiet At night, many ideas always flash through our minds, and golden sentences, jokes, and short stories emerge in endlessly. Have you recorded these inspirations? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My best friends are all married. Why do I suddenly feel a little lonely? What changes do I feel? . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Zhuli, 26 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I heard foreigners chatting before going to bed, and I realized that even if you don’t learn English systematically, if you want to communicate on a daily basis, you must first accumulate vocabulary. Although the environment for learning a language is important, memorizing vocabulary is also essential. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Pan, 29 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; I suddenly wanted to go see the sea, so I set out today and am on my way now. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Ono, 19 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; I feel that I am still young, but suddenly I realize that I have graduated four or five years ago, I am already 26, and I have accomplished nothing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;YIXUN, 26 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Recently, before I go to bed, I fantasize about hiking a snow-capped mountain in April next year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;gerry, 25 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; I thought about the future a long, long time ago, not knowing where I would be and what kind of life I would live, and I fell asleep thinking about it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Xixi, 16 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Yesterday, I attended a friend&#39;s wedding for the first time, which was actually quite touching for me. I had always thought that it would be okay to marry late or not at all, but in the atmosphere of that ceremony, I have to admit that I want to get married, and I want to be with The person I like has three meals a year with the two of us. At night I was thinking that my thinking may have been restricted before. In fact, a blind date may not be without love. Being able to meet each other is also fate. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Hunt, 23 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I went to bed early yesterday and forgot what I was thinking about. It’s hard to find a job recently. How can I find a job? I’m a college student who has graduated for several months. I’m crying~&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color : rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Wait for a persimmon, 23 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was hospitalized with a fracture, and now I can’t sleep every day OK, I can’t eat it. I had never had any serious illness in the past ten years or so, and I didn&#39;t feel much about having a healthy body. Every day since I was hospitalized, I hope that I will get better soon, and I secretly make up my mind every day that after I get better, I must live a good life and change my previous attitude towards life. I have surgery tomorrow, I hope I can recover quickly (ง&amp;nbsp;&amp;bull;̀_&amp;bull;́)งGood luck. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Counting sleeping sheep, 19 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The road to school that used to feel long and endless is actually not that long. I don’t know whether it’s because I walk faster, or because my perception of time is slow, or both. When I was walking on this road before, I felt like I couldn&#39;t see the end at a glance, and it would take me a long time to get home. But now it seems that I can get there in just thirty minutes, which is just the time it takes to listen to a few songs. At that time, even if I was sitting on an electric car, I could get there. Later, I can also imagine a story about saving the world. The older I get, the slower my perception of time becomes, and many days pass by without even realizing it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Tong Lu, 22 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&amp;ldquo;The further you travel, the more you see, and the more people you meet, the more you will realize that in this life, there are only a few people who you really care about and who care about you at the same time. These few people are your entire world. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Chen Qucheng, 32 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>; Recently I was reading Shi Tiesheng&#39;s &quot;The Temple of Earth and Me&quot;. There is a sentence in it: &quot;In the immersive light that fills the garden, it is easier for a person to see time and see his own figure.&quot; Being alone makes me more visible. Own. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Eat a big bite of strawberry cake, 28 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;While riding after work in the morning and evening while waiting for the traffic light to change, next to me was an old man riding an old-fashioned third-floor bicycle. The bicycle was full of neatly packed cardboard boxes. When I was sleeping, the figures of my parents flashed through my mind, and I suddenly cheered up and told myself, &quot;Qiaoqiao, come on!&quot; You must also work hard for your parents who have worked so hard for you! The outside world is so chaotic and you can still live a comfortable life, isn&#39;t that a big profit! &amp;rdquo;Yes! It is inevitable that there will be a lot of confusion and sadness in life, but we cannot be immersed in sadness, we must discover the warmth and beauty we have. Magnify the happiness and magnify it, shrink the troubles again and again, and know that you earn it by living! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Qiaoqiao, 24 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;If I can&#39;t sleep at night, I will think of me in the parallel world who has endless sleep, and all my sleep has been stolen by him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;The sea breeze of Dongji Island, 30 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;(Looking at the drunken roommate) If you want love, you just want it. If you don’t want it, it doesn’t mean you really don’t want it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;(・(ェ)・), 27 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;Don’t put emotional value on anything. Being happy is more important than anything else. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Seven fish, 23 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The moon is the brightness of my hometown. When I can&#39;t see the moon in a foreign land, I always think of that summer vacation. The yard in my hometown was bright at night, and the moonlight filtered through the windows, making the summer heat less uncomfortable. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Twelve, 26 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;There is no thinking in my life, it is all feeling. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Dadai, 22 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >; Seize every opportunity and be brave. Love boldly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;another, 25 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;What were you thinking about before going to bed last night? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Li Jialong onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This issue of Q&amp;A comes from the WeChat Moments of ONE Editorial Department. Please participate in the collection and add Editorial WeChat: oneapp2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8 &quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Complex The cutest people in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3962&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What are your recommended winter items? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3968)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[再见箐箐]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6152]]><description>&lt;div>;6 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Cheng Huizi&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FoUscy35kpPtdjViLIXJvUzk5oED&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FoUscy35kpPtdjViLIXJvUzk5oED&quot;>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Puberty is like a strong wind, blowing two girls to different paths. One is a romantic and special &quot;bad boy&quot;, and the other is a reserved and ordinary &quot;stupid kid&quot;. But friendship is like spider silk, connecting, connecting and wrapping them together. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is a big Paulownia tree behind the bicycle shed downstairs in my house. Because the carport is blocking it, I can&#39;t see how thick it is, but it is definitely thicker than several adults can hold it together. It has long grown past the height of the carport, and its branches are luxuriant. In summer, it crosses the carport and casts a deep shadow downstairs. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the short carport as the boundary, after the carport it is no longer the scope of the family area, but the countryside. We live in this place where urban and rural areas meet. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Logically speaking, the Paulownia tree should not belong to us. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In autumn, the paulownia trees have been blooming all summer and the flowers have fallen one after another. Many of them have fallen on the open space downstairs of my house. They are neither purple nor white, and they look very rough. They really can’t be said to be pretty. But it attracted a group of children to pick it up because there was residual honey at the roots of the flowers. The children picked up the flowers and tore them apart. They put their noses in and carefully stuck out their tongues to lick them. When they felt the sweetness, they excitedly picked up the flowers. Leave it behind and look for the next one. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qingqing was among the children, holding an armful of paulownia flowers, and shouted to me standing far away: &quot;Come on, there is honey in the flowers!&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I stood motionless, holding on to my clothes and refusing to come forward. I didn’t know what kind of reason to give, so I had to smile at her awkwardly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I don’t know why, but I don’t have any fondness for this paulownia tree with its lush branches stretching out from afar. I always feel that the countryside on that side is as old as tree trunks and full of devastation and evil. Every morning there are always people from the village pushing breakfast carts selling breakfast downstairs. Most of them are fried dough sticks and oil tea in a big pot. There are many people buying them. My mother asked me if I wanted to eat them. Said: &quot;No.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I don’t even like the paulownia tree. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But I can’t say it because I don’t want to be thought of as being aloof or pretending to be aloof. But actually I am afraid. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So I had to stand there, saying nothing, and smiling at Qingqing with the corners of my mouth raised. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qingqing is the child of my door-to-door neighbor. She is the same age as me. We were both three years old when we moved here. As the old saying goes, we grow up young. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qingqing is a child who easily gets along with others. She is beautiful and outgoing, with a pointed chin, small but smart eyes, a sweet and soft speaking voice, and two small dimples on her cheeks when she smiles. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I like Qingqing very much, but I can’t fit into her vast circle of friends. At that time, I was not as gentle and smooth as I am now. I always used the little thorns on my body as a probe radar. I was dismissive of the class leaders who always bluffed and pretended to be powerful, and I was cold to the little girl who showed off her new skirt in a cooing voice. A cold glance. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My mother said that I don&#39;t know how to &quot;be a human being&quot; and &quot;turn corners&quot;, but I wear this on my shoulders as an honor and use it as the most independent sign. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So for a long time, I only had Qingqing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the first and second grades, we came home from school together, sang like childish singers together, and took the double hundred test together; when she was on duty, she would secretly leave the pieces of chalk in the blackboard slot and give them to me. We graffitied on the cement floor downstairs; after the Dragon Boat Festival, we washed the remaining rice dumpling leaves and wove them into simple little bracelets to wear on our wrists; during the Lantern Festival, we walked around the community with lanterns and sang &quot;Lantern Festival&quot; , Lantern Festival, put out the lanterns and go home to sleep.&quot; The last two lanterns touched together and burned. The firelight reflected our faces that were red from the cold. We sang and danced around the small fire until it turned into a handful of ashes with a gold edge. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Whether it was on the way home from school or downstairs in the community, there were always many classmates saying hello to her, and she would respond enthusiastically. I am particularly grateful that she had so many friends at that time, but chose not to leave. I. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One time on the way out of school, I suddenly saw a lot of people gathered in front of a small store, forming a big circle. People went to the center of the whirlpool to grab something. It turned out that the store had printed leaflets. If you create a small book to attract customers, free stuff will naturally attract people, no matter how cheap it is. I was inexplicably afraid of that huge crowd. I felt that my short figure was not enough to resist their crowding. As if I would be swallowed up by them if I didn&#39;t leave, I pulled Qingqing and started to move forward. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qingqing stopped and said: &quot;Let me go and see!&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Don&#39;t--I held her hand to prevent her from diving in, but before I finished speaking, she had already dived in. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But she left one hand outside, holding my hand tightly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was very scared at that moment, thinking what if Qingqing let go and fell in. I didn’t dare to get in to find her, so I pulled the hand tighter. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thank God, Qingqing got out of it after a while, with the trophy in her hand and a look of excitement on her face. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Here you go! &amp;rdquo;She gave me one, looking very proud of it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The cover of the book is full of colorful advertisements. When you open it, you will see that the dark yellow composition paper is rough to the touch, and it even feels like the trunk of the log used to make the paper. The emerald green grid printing is poor quality and blurry. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I didn’t like this book, but when I saw Qingqing’s excited face, I picked it up and raised my apples to look happy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is the first time I did something that went against my stubborn character, in order not to ruin Qing Qing’s happiness. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She kept talking along the way and seemed very happy: &quot;Oh, you don&#39;t know how many people there are. I squeezed hard, and a person behind me almost stepped off my shoes and my hair... It&#39;s all messed up. There were too many people in front of me, so I couldn&#39;t see the one who handed out notebooks, but a few books fell on the ground. They were probably squeezed out by the people in front of me, so I picked them up. It&#39;s okay, okay, look, it&#39;s not dirty. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I put the notebook on the side of my school bag and retracted my hands into my sleeves. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When we arrived at the door of our house, the doors of both families were already open. Both parents took our schoolbags and asked, &quot;How was school today?&quot; Wash your hands and eat. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qingqing raised the notebook in her hand as if showing off: &amp;ldquo;We saw it on the way to school! Someone sent it, it’s free! There were so many people grabbing it. She pulled me outside and I squeezed in to get it with great difficulty! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Unite and collaborate! Okay, I just don’t need to buy you a laptop. ” Qingqing’s father touched her hair and pushed her in to eat. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So the parents of the two families exchanged a few words and closed the door. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the dinner table, my mother asked me how Qingqing squeezed in. I told the truth. My mother added a spoonful of soup to my bowl and said:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You and Qingqing, it’s good to unite and cooperate, but next time something like this happens, don’t go. You are so young, what if you are crowded? Don’t ignore safety just for a few notebooks. Your parents will buy you whatever notebooks you want. . &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qingqing’s father was the backbone of the factory and later became my father’s leader. Her mother was a nurse in the factory-affiliated hospital and later became the head nurse of the internal medicine department. In that era when children used their parents&#39; official positions to show off and compare with their classmates, Qingqing never showed any arrogance or complacency in front of me, and I never regarded her as a child led by her father. She had low self-esteem or deep self-esteem. What else. We are who we are, we are friends, we are, well. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qingqing’s parents became very busy after being promoted and rarely paid attention to her. Several times, Qingqing came home from school and knocked on the door, but no one answered, so she stayed at my house for dinner as a matter of course. , and then do homework with me. It wasn&#39;t until it was time to go to bed at night that her parents came back and took her back from my house. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I am very happy to be with Qingqing and look forward to her parents working overtime a few more times. Qingqing has no complaints about her parents’ busyness and neglect of her. She is happy every time she comes to my house. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later, when I was in third grade, my parents enrolled me in a Mathematical Olympiad English class on the other side of the city—it was said that the teachers there were excellent. The Mathematical Olympiad is a lingering nightmare for me, and the teacher in that class assigned so many exercises that my time for kicking sandbags and jumping grids was squeezed out little by little, turning it into a dense and meaningless calculation book. number. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I told Qingqing to come to class with me. She shook her head: &quot;My parents said I don&#39;t need to go.&quot; &amp;rdquo;She is still playing carefree with her friends downstairs. I am envious, but there is nothing I can do about it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I was entangled with complicated and boring Mathematical Olympiad questions such as &quot;Tree Planting Problem&quot;, &quot;Chasing Problem&quot; and &quot;Cow Eating Grass Problem&quot;, I could often hear my friends downstairs shouting: Her voice was mostly that of a boy. They shouted in a long voice that was already showing signs of changing their voice: &quot;Qing---&quot; &amp;ldquo;Come down right now&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Our time together is getting less and less. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After graduating from elementary school, I was admitted to G Middle School, and Qingqing was promoted to the children&#39;s middle school at home step by step. I go to school on the other side of the city, and I come home very late after studying at school every day. The lights in Qingqing&#39;s house have long been turned off. During the holidays, G Middle School will always try every possible means to make excuses and spend more than half of the holidays making up lessons. I was in the dark and fighting with my weak mathematics, physics and chemistry. I almost never had the chance to see Qingqing again. Even if I did, it would only be a quick glance and a scribbled hello. From time to time, I could only hear a few words about her from my parents at the dinner table:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Qingqing has grown taller again. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Qingqing is getting more and more beautiful. So much like her mother. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;She seems to have studied liberal arts as well? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I heard that there is a boy waiting for her at the school gate every day holding flowers. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I started to interject curiously and couldn’t help but want to know Qingqing’s gossip, but I was frightened by my parents’ earnest yet slightly harsh tone:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo ;Do your homework. Don&#39;t worry blindly, your task now is to study, don&#39;t worry about other people&#39;s affairs. Don’t you have an exam next week? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qingqing is no one else. I wanted to say it, but I didn’t dare. I knew it was not easy for me to go to school across the district. Not to mention the high tuition, and having to be picked up and dropped off by my father every day, it was really hard. I knew I was not qualified to refute anything, so I had to bury my head in my rice bowl. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Youth whizzed by like a draft, blowing the time we spent playing Ludo in the small room to the edge of memory, blowing Qingqing and I in different directions, farther and farther away. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Goodbye Qingqing, I mean, seeing Qingqing seriously again was already the summer vacation after we finished the college entrance examination. I ended my six years of inter-district schooling and was admitted to university to prepare to go south. But Qingqing, in the attached middle school where the admission rate was less than 30%, in the words of adults, was completely &quot;degenerate&quot;... ;&amp;mdash;Only passed three exams from a local private school&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;became the denominator of the 30%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The summer in the north is so pure, the sky dims, like a heavy curtain shaking off dust, and the residual heat of the scorching sun still covers the body like a suede blanket. There are already big flowers on the paulownia tree downstairs, occasionally swaying in the hot and dry evening breeze. When I saw Qingqing, she was no longer what I remembered. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She is indeed more beautiful, but not what I imagined. She had double eyelid surgery and opened the canthus of her eyes, making her eyes larger than when she was a child. He is 1.7 meters tall and very thin. Her hair was dyed ginger and permed into big waves that hung down to her waist. Brown eyeshadow, flaming red lips, eyelashes that look like spider legs, cat-eye green contact lenses that are huge and hollow, three or four very punk black earrings on her left ear, and slanted bangs in front of her face. Covered one eye. She called my name:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Long time no see! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I am no longer the little girl with a sharp personality. I have smoothed most of the edges and corners of my body during my chaotic and grand youth, and I have learned to act normal when I see people I don’t like. Speak softly and tactfully. I suppressed the huge shock in my heart, controlled my expression, and said hypocritically and joyfully:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Qingqing! you&#39;re so beautiful! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She smiled, showing her neat white teeth, which made her lips even redder. I remembered that there was a time when she was wearing braces when I was little, and we laughed at her as &quot;the girl with steel teeth.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Let’s go shopping together. We all grew up in this city, until we reached the age of eighteen. I am ashamed to say that I was a desk-bound nerd and a road nut. I knew nothing about the entire city’s transportation planning. The only routes I knew were From home to school and several regular tutoring classes. Qingqing, on the other hand, has become very familiar with the traffic pattern here during her six years in middle school. She knows all the streets and alleys in the city. I followed her blankly, taking the bus and subway, and after many twists and turns, I arrived at a small underground shopping mall. . She was clearly a regular customer here, and she hurriedly introduced to me as if she was following her own family: which store&#39;s nail polish fades easily, which store has the cheapest double eyelid stickers, which store makes the best high-quality imitations, and which store has earrings? The rhinestones are easy to fall off, how to choose contact lenses, how to apply false eyelashes, how to use a curling iron... She wore exaggerated sunglasses, black fishnet stockings, and a brown turtleneck shirt. Tie it into a hasty knot at the navel. The limbs are as slender as a praying mantis. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I have been a good student for twelve years, living an honest life according to the school rules, and not daring to go beyond the limits. When I took off my school uniform and sneakers, I felt awkward walking down the street wearing a pair of platform sandals, as if I was afraid that others would see me. I have never been exposed to what Qingqing is talking about - I have long been accustomed to wearing a bare face, and I can no longer take off my glasses. There is no air conditioning in the underground mall, and my chest feels hot and stuffy, but I still act cooperative on the surface. I should tell her when the time is right, that&#39;s it, this high simulation can be made to look like the real one. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Actually, I don’t even know what I’m talking about. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qingqing quickly bought a bunch of cheap trinkets and a high imitation bag. Seeing me standing next to her empty-handed, she felt a little embarrassed and asked me: &quot;What do you want to buy? Follow me.&quot; Tell me, I&#39;ll take you there, you can&#39;t just accompany me. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I hesitated for a moment and didn’t know what to say. I turned around and saw that the wall of a small shop next to me was covered with rhinestone-encrusted hairpins, so I walked over and picked out a cherry-shaped one. The boss came over to help me bargain. The boss was a fat man in his forties. He was not very familiar with the items in the store. At first glance, he looked at the stalls for others. Qingqing brushed her hair and pushed her sunglasses over her head. He said in a good voice: &quot;Uncle, you look so kind, why don&#39;t you make it cheaper?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The man couldn&#39;t resist and waved his hand: &quot;Forget it, the little girl has such a sweet mouth, I sold it to you at a loss.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I paid and took the hairpin. The light spots on it made my eyes hurt in the ample light in the store. I stuffed the hairpin into my pocket, with the smell of metal still lingering on my hands. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was nearly nine o&#39;clock in the city, and nightlife had just begun. The city center was brightly lit, as if it were daytime, and huge neon advertisements hung above our heads. There was a lot of traffic and people coming and going around, but it was enough for us to hear each other. Sound. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We did not hold hands like we did when we were children, nor did we link arms like the little sisters on the street. We walked separately, with a subtle distance between our shoulders. We chatted for a while, and she suddenly turned her head and asked me with a smile:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Do you have a boyfriend?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I shook my head in embarrassment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Never been in love? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I nodded embarrassedly and admitted. Without puppy love, there will be lifelong regret. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I&#39;m just telling you,&#39; she said with a clear look, &amp;ldquo;I&#39;m just telling you why you bought such a cherry hairpin. It should be bought by a boy for his girlfriend. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Why? Can’t girls buy it? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Because cherry means cherry, which sounds very close to cherish. If a boy buys it for you, it means that he likes you and cherishes you very much. &amp;rdquo;Remembering the plot of such an idol drama, she smiled like a cunning little fox. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A sad joy surged through my heart, as if I finally discovered that Qingqing and I still retain some slightly shameful hobbies in common, like a thin and transparent shoulder strap. Connecting the two of us. During this day&#39;s wandering, I felt ashamed countless times that I had gone too far, but I did not lose her, which made me happy and full of gratitude. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I remember when you were a child, you said you wanted to marry a doctor in the future? &quot;She had that naughty smile on her lips, &quot;Do you remember? You also wrote it with chalk on the wall of the carport. I also wrote it, but what I wrote was to marry the president of the country. &amp;rdquo;Qingqing seemed very shy when talking about her childish thoughts. I saw a small vortex on her side. The red light on the road next to us came on, and the vehicles stopped one by one beside us, with a string of red lights on the rear of the car. &quot;I remember that we couldn&#39;t write the word &quot;marry&quot; at that time, and we still had to write it in pinyin. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I stared into her eyes, looking into her pure black pupils through her colored contact lenses, and said solemnly: &quot;Yes, I remember.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We were walking on the road home--it used to be muddy and clear, but now it is flat and turbid. Qingqing was wearing high heels and was one shoulder taller than me. She suddenly turned to talk to me. The surroundings were very quiet. Her voice was like a pool of water: &quot;When you go to college, you must fall in love.&quot; Although it may not be very good, you can&#39;t stop trying it just because it&#39;s not good. &amp;rdquo;She sounded like my sister, but she was actually a few months younger than me. &quot;I&#39;m afraid that you will be too scared to try it after seeing my tattoo today. In fact, it&#39;s really nothing. It was very painful when I was broken up, but you see, I&#39;m fine now.&quot; &amp;rdquo;Under the streetlight, her makeup was a bit messy, and pimples were exposed under her foundation. &amp;ldquo;You will definitely meet someone who treats you well in the end, likes you and cherishes you. When the time comes, you can ask him to buy a cherry hair card for you. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was a little stunned. Qingqing’s astringent tone was intertwined with the sultry summer air, like a beautiful glass candy wrapper wrapping the scrawled past. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I took out the cherry hairpin from my pocket and handed it to her: &quot;I&#39;ll give it to you.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She looked surprised: &amp;ldquo;Why send it to me? This is a gift from a boy to a girl. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I don’t wear hairpins, my hair is too slippery to get stuck in.” The small cherry hairpin is like a piece of fruit candy. When the street light shines on it, it shines in my sweaty palms. , &quot;Besides, can&#39;t I give it to you? I cherish you very much.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her nails were dyed black and were a little faded, &quot;Thank you.&quot; &amp;rdquo;She took it with a smile, and I looked at her deeply. Her dimples were so obvious. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Hey Qingqing,&amp;rdquo; I watched her put the hairpin on her head, very seriously, &amp;ldquo;I found that it actually matches your hair color very well. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Nana&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For information about the call for papers, please see the @ONE Studio pinned on Weibo. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FslYZuaFJjFILh_P5BuPz84SRPAs&quot; alt=&quot;Cheng Huizi&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Cheng Huizi&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@that yingchu yunxiao road &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&quot;Pretend to be loyal to your ideals.&quot;&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP. openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style= &quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6113&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;The Burden of Reunion&lt;/div >; &lt;div>;Text/Cheng Huizi&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6150&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Mingfang&#39;s retreat&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Ma Chenwei&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt; /tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Read&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6151&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Welcome home&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Chi Lin&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style= &quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6152)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div >; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4048]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4190]]><description>&lt;div>;6 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FsUMsdZZhDgCIC_sxcuypP4W5WT9&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;VOL.4048&lt;/span>;Photography | Katy Pritchett&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;6&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nov. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Any answer We may not be able to withstand further questioning, so we have no choice but to continue asking questions and keep ourselves in a broader, vast, boundless loss. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 06 Nov 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>