<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[独处时你都在做什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3990]]><description> &lt;div>;25 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Question from ONE Editorial Department&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>; What do you do when you are alone? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; xianganswer&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original- src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fp1jHDDHjeNKMSJKzW5S287I8OLI&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fp1jHDDHjeNKMSJKzW5S287I8OLI&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;I look down when I am alone Looking at the still water; or standing on the edge of the cliff, looking at the deep valley... Why do you ask the question &quot;What do you do when you are alone?&quot; Is it because being alone is really fun and makes people want to share their fun things, or is it just to see if others find these hours so unbearable? Anyway, now that the question is asked, it proves important enough. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;I learned 10,000 ways to spend my time alone very early. I even feel that my own world has invaded the world around me. Even if I am surrounded by people, it does not affect me. Keep yourself company. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One thing I have loved doing since I was a child is to throw the ball against the wall of the entrance hall at home, wait for the ball to bounce back, and then throw it back again, and the cycle continues. Back and forth. When I was not in elementary school, this was how I spent my time at home. I used to create a lot of characters in my head and then painstakingly draw them in notebooks, even though everyone looked similar. The game of throwing a ball against the wall can be played for a long time. The repeated movements of the hands are like a barrier, and the stories of those characters can thus unfold and spread safely in another dimension. I will also quietly speak out about them. the words said. When I learned how to play poker, I would sit on the wooden floor and deal cards to an imaginary opponent, then deal them to myself, manipulating the game without an audience. At night, the time between lying on the bed and covering up the quilt until falling asleep is especially precious. As early as when I was washing, I had already prepared in my mind the world I was going to imagine later - at that time, I yearned for a series of transformations. The buses that pass by are equipped with bunk beds, so friends can stay in them. When the bus is driving, you can see the most wonderful scenery from both the upper and lower decks. I would picture every detail of this car in my mind. Where did it park at night? Until falling asleep. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later, I finally had more free time, and I couldn’t help but feel that it was so much fun to be alone. After school at noon, you can cherish your pocket money and go out to search for today&#39;s lunch. It seems that being able to decide your own daily food gives you the power to make whatever changes you want. You can also take the bus home by yourself. After putting on the headphones, you just pray that the bus will slow down and slow down, hoping that it will never stop. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If you are lucky enough to have a small room of your own at a certain stage, you can decorate it according to your own preferences like me, and you will be more in the mood to prepare breakfast for yourself in the dim room. Watch movies under the lights, or connect to speakers to play Masayoshi Takanaka&#39;s 2008 live video. If you are busy going back and forth during the day for some reason, in the vacuum after cleaning up at night, you will not feel that everything is difficult to pass away. You will only want to sit in the dark for a while, and sit for a while again, hoping that this time will last forever. I won&#39;t leave you either. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;However, not all the time I get along with myself so smoothly. Even if I have a lot of ways to play with myself, I still can’t cope with all the time alone, not to mention that this kind of time is far more than We imagine more. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Have you also experienced that Sunday afternoon? When you wake up alone from the bed, the world around you slowly returns to its original shape. At this time, you are so naked and frightened. The feeling of loss gradually develops into a slight tingling. You are like a person with a stomachache who is eager for something. A hot water bottle. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Maybe it is to avoid this physiological condition from attacking unexpectedly, sometimes, I prefer to appear in the crowd. I would walk to the street and sit by the flower bed in the square and read a book, or sit in McDonald&#39;s and watch the passers-by and see what they are carrying in their pockets. What are they doing for dinner tonight? Gradually, my personal world invades the outside world. When watching live performances or on a crowded subway, the sounds of my world will unexpectedly cover up the sounds of the outside world, just like a train entering a tunnel and only the outside world can be heard. Buzzing. It wasn&#39;t until someone pushed me behind me, or the noisy door of the subway car opened in front of me in protest, that the world pulled me back and reconnected with me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sometimes being completely alone seems very weird. One Sunday afternoon in elementary school, I heard a group of senior children laughing and playing downstairs by the window of my study room. This was rarely the case. I leaned against the window and tried my best to poke my head out. I could only see through the layers of leaves. See their cheerful clothes flashing by. In the past, my grandfather always bought endless pens, notebooks, and erasers and stored them in the bookcase. Even now, there are still many unopened. Every time I open the bookcase, I am amazed at how rich it is. I also opened the bookcase that day and did something incredible: I took out a new box of erasers, opened the wrapping paper, and started throwing them downstairs one by one. The rubber is very light, passing through the branches and hitting the leaves lightly, making a slight sound. After probably throwing away a whole box, some of the older kids made a confused sound. They seemed to be following the sound and the trajectory of the dropped eraser, but because of the lush foliage above our heads, we couldn&#39;t see each other clearly. For a long time, I just leaned against the window and threw erasers downstairs, until the last box of erasers was used up. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Once, on a rainy afternoon, not far from the afternoon class time, I was walking outside in the rain. When I returned to the classroom, my classmates were surprised. Looking at me wet, why am I caught in the rain? Even now I can&#39;t explain it. Whether it&#39;s throwing a rubber downstairs or getting yourself wet, is it because you feel annoyed? Or is it a spontaneous resistance? I still can&#39;t explain it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I am alone, I feel like my emotions are flowing, and I also feel that I am facing the still water, looking down at myself in the mirror; I feel like a person standing on the top of a mountain, with his back to the screen. , looking at the sea of ​​fog, or the deep valley. I have to lament that time alone is so elusive and intriguing, surprising, scary, restless, and hard to let go of. We should ask, &quot;What do you do when you are alone?&quot; ” instead of “What should I do when I’m alone?” &amp;rdquo;Whether we fill our time with a hundred things or do nothing, there will never be an answer to being alone, and &lt;strong>;there will never be an end to being alone. In the following time, we can only continue to try to be better to ourselves. . &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Li Jialong onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see @ONE Studio’s pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. The official WeChat account of the editorial department: oneapp2020. Regularly publish Q&amp;A collections, give away books and peripheral gifts, readers are welcome to add. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FsJ4zRKtgiPcZPX7NH9nY4eUAlFU &quot; alt=&quot;xiang&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;xiang &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Boring xiang Occasionally write some short words&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td >; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt;/td >; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3986&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Can love really be your safe haven? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3987&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Where are you and how are you doing lately? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3990)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 06:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[偷手表的人（上）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6176]]><description> &lt;div>;25 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Hu Jingyu&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data -author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FlX0nG8-SJG2-CM-sPHSokD9lnuy&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FlX0nG8 -SJG2-CM-sPHSokD9lnuy&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;It was originally an ordinary drinking party In the game, I met a girl who existed in my hazy memory, and witnessed the naked transaction between the three of them. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I must have seen this girl somewhere. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She got out of the Maserati in Huangpu, her brows were furrowed and her rosy eyes were raised high, looking very powerful. Huang Pu, my most distinguished customer, was getting off the car from the other side. Shan Guangzong ran over and opened the door for him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Good evening, Mr. Huang, Shan Guangzong and I shouted in unison, bowing ninety degrees at the same time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Normally, Huang Pu would smile at us or pat us on the shoulder, but today he had no time to talk to us. The girl was staring at him, pouting and saying she didn&#39;t want to go in. Huang Pu went over to hold hands, once, twice, but failed. Don&#39;t be like this, baby, Huang Pu said. But I didn&#39;t know there were others, the girl said. Huang Pu put his head over her and coaxed her in a low voice. Shan Guangzong and I both took a step back. No need to guess, it’s still the same: buy a bag tomorrow, go skiing the day after tomorrow, the baby is the best and the baby is the most beautiful. Shan Guangzong winked at me and whispered, &quot;Baby is fourteen. I&#39;ll poke him with my elbow to remind him not to talk nonsense.&quot; Huang Pu had many girlfriends, and each one of them was called Baobao. Shan Guangzong added numbers to them. From Baby One to Baby Fourteen, it only took less than half a year. I asked Shan Guangzong, couldn&#39;t Huangpu be called by another name? Shan Guangzong glanced at me and said, &quot;I don&#39;t understand. This is to prevent the secret from being revealed.&quot; Shan Guangzong&#39;s explanation is well-founded and very convincing to me. With the speed at which Huang Pu changes people, it is not easy to remember every girl&#39;s name. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But I must have seen this girl somewhere. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I have been coming to the club for more than six months, and I have met a lot of beautiful girls. For a long time, I was confused. They all seemed to look the same. Shan Guangzong said this is because plastic surgery is so popular, coupled with the popular clothing in online stores. Some time ago, they liked to wear half-cut tops, exposing their waists and navels. Recently, they are obsessed with yoga pants that are extremely close-fitting, and their socks must be pulled up to above the ankles. &quot;Mid-level specialty, fresh thighs.&quot; ”Shan Guangzong made up a jingle. This sentence offended the waitresses, and they united to hold a meeting to criticize him. I had bad eyesight and quick legs, so I pretended to be on the phone and wanted to run out. The new lobby manager Han Xiaoxue stepped forward to stop me and said Yu Yang, don’t hide. I walked around behind her and covered my phone, saying shush, don’t make trouble. The counselor urged me to hand in a social practice report, and Han Xiaoxue turned around. He said, &quot;Go away.&quot; I quickly said yes, ran all the way to the toilet, and hid until the criticism was over. Afterwards, Shan Guangzong blamed me for being too dishonest, and I felt quite embarrassed. In order to atone for my sins, I had to work as an errand boy for him and go to the 711 supermarket at the foot of the mountain to buy cigarettes and potato chips. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The clubhouse is called Banshan and is located on the mountainside. The mountain is Wanfo Mountain in the south of the city, and it is very popular. Worship Buddha in front of the mountain and eat behind the mountain. We go during the day to worship Buddha and come at night to eat. We can&#39;t meet each other at the same time. The routes we take are also different. Those who worship Buddha climb up the stone steps in front of the mountain and enter the temple to burn incense. Those who eat eat drive up from the road behind the mountain. , eat, drink and get drunk. In addition, there are several wild roads on the mountain, which are deserted and sparsely populated, so unfamiliar people dare not take them without permission. In addition to the clubhouse, there is also a five-star hotel behind the mountain, which is located on the top of the mountain and is called Dingjian. When a guest drinks too much, the waiter will take him to the hotel in a shuttle bus, and then go back to Gan Gou Yu&#39;s office to receive a hundred yuan. Gan Gou is our boss. He has business cooperation with Dingjian’s boss and has a good relationship. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While waiting for Huang Pu, Shan Guangzong began to study the relationship between Qian Gouyu and Han Xiaoxue, mainly focusing on whether they had sex. Han Xiaoxue has been studying this problem since he came to Mid-Levels three months ago. The research method mainly relies on observation, plus a little imagination. When he was in a good mood, he said that Han Xiaoxue was not like that kind of person. When he was in a bad mood, he said that women were just like her mother. Shan Guangzong was in a good or bad mood today and spoke more objectively. Shan Guangzong said, have you seen Yu Yang? I said, what did you see? Shan Guangzong clicked his tongue and said, it&#39;s time for general cleaning. At ten o&#39;clock in the morning, all the waiters gathered in the lobby, took roll calls, sang songs, did general cleaning, and praised Han Xiaoxue for his good glass cleaning as he passed by the lobby. Oh, I said, it doesn’t look like it. Shan Guangzong took a breath, let it out for a long time, hummed twice, and said, judging from Han Xiaoxue&#39;s attitude, it really didn&#39;t look like it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was absent-minded. While talking to him, I looked towards Huang Pu. Mainly look at the girl. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She wears a high ponytail, with a pearl hairpin on the side of her hair. She has a slender neck, a thin back, and her breasts have the outline of a girl, with small ups and downs. The setting sun covered the side of her face, and she could see the soft down on it. My brain was spinning, trying to pull out the clue from my memory that would just fit her outline, but I couldn&#39;t. Her head was always turned to one side, her expression could not be seen, and her arms were folded in front of her chest, as if she was still angry, but also seemed to have some room. The autumn wind blew her green gauze skirt, exposing part of her thigh. I felt cold for her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Give her some face, baby. Huang Pu stretched out his arms to hug her. She pushed Huang Pu, each one becoming lighter than the other. Finally she said, okay, just go in, but don&#39;t drink. Huang Pu chuckled and said, whatever you want is fine, as long as you are happy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shan Guangzong went to park the car, Huang Pu held her in his arms and walked towards the hall, and I was responsible for leading the way. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The club is not big, with a total of eight halls, with different styles. Huang Pu is familiar with each one. The Roman hall that Shan Guangzong and I are responsible for is the one he orders most often. The Roman Room is a suite with a bar and a lounge. Before dinner, Huang Pu likes to use the semi-automatic coffee machine on the bar to make cappuccino. He can froth milk and latte art. I have seen him do this many times. After entering the room, I first removed the extra tableware, leaving only three sets. Then I walked into the bar, took out the Bitan Piaoxue stored in the locker, washed it, and put it into the bone china teapot. . Huang Pu has already started to draw flowers. His expression is very serious. He rolls up his sleeves and reveals his watch, which is quite new. I glanced at the logo, Rolex. The girl stood behind Huang Pu, folding her arms, looking up at the light for a while and looking down at the ground for a while. When the coffee was ready, Huang Pu brought it to her face and said, &quot;Try it.&quot; She took a sip and said calmly, &quot;It&#39;s okay.&quot; At that moment, I suddenly remembered: it was her. She was sitting in the row behind me in last year’s political theory class. The class was taken jointly by three departments, two semesters, and thirty class hours. If I remember correctly, she came once in total. That&#39;s right, that&#39;s her. She has a high ponytail, rosy eyes, and a frown on her face. She looks quite powerful. But now she didn&#39;t look so good. Huang Pu hugged and coaxed her and finally made her laugh. She laughed in a milky voice and bit her fingers, which looked a little awkward to me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shan Guangzong did not enter the house when he came back from parking the car. He only opened the door a crack and winked at me. I turned around and bowed to Huang Pu and said, Mr. Huang, I will go first. Huang Pu has a distinguished guest tonight, and asked us to greet him at the door: surnamed Kong, arriving at seven o&#39;clock, black Audi, last number three nines. After going downstairs, Shan Guangzong looked at his phone and said, &quot;Fuck, it&#39;s only half past six.&quot; The two of us made eye contact, and walked around behind an old locust tree outside the side door. Shan Guangzong took out a box of deflated Chinese soft drinks, which were left behind by the guests last night, and divided them among several waiters. There are three left. One person took one in his mouth and lit a fire. He was afraid that the wind would blow the smoke forward, so he spit it toward the ground. Shan Guangzong asked, did you see Huang Pu changing his watch? I said, I saw it, Rolex. Shan Guangzong said, OK, everyone knows Rolex. I said, of course, a crown. Shan Guangzong asked, do you know what model it is? I said, I don&#39;t know. Shan Guangzong started to look at me sideways. Ever since I first came to Banshan, he has always looked at me sideways. I know that he wants to use this stupid method to make me look like a country bumpkin. But I don&#39;t know him the same. A Mercedes-Benz business car drove into the yard, and seven or eight people in black suits got out. Wang Guanghui from the Persian Hall ran up to him and led them into the hall with a smile on his face. The cool autumn wind in the evening blew straight into people&#39;s collars. We hunched our shoulders and continued talking about the watch. Shan Guangzong asked me to guess the price. I said I was too lazy to guess, so just tell me. Shan Guangzong glanced at me again, spit at the root of the tree, and said, six hundred thousand. Shit, he said, how do you think they can make so much money? Who knows, I said, looking up at the sky. The sky is dim, and the sun has set at the junction of the sky and the mountains. Several pieces of sunset are stacked together, not so red anymore, and the edges are gray, like coals that are about to burn out in a furnace. Maybe it&#39;s fate, I said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My life is just average. I have never worn a watch. I didn’t use a mobile phone until high school. A relative in the city got it for me. Except for making phone calls and chatting on WeChat, it was stuck. Let alone a watch, I couldn’t even put on good clothes before going to college. When I was admitted to college, my family gave me 500 yuan, and I took it to the county town to buy a pair of Li-Ning clothes and a pair of Xtep sneakers. I bought them all at the cheapest price. In my sophomore year, I worked as a promoter in a supermarket and saved a lot of money. For a thousand yuan, I went to an outlet and bought two pairs of Nikes. There&#39;s nothing to show off. My college roommates wear AJ and coconut, and I can&#39;t talk to them. After coming to Mid-Levels, I got to know Shan Guangzong, Armani, Gucci, Louis Vuitton... there are many more. The names are too confusing to remember, so I can&#39;t remember them correctly. Shan Guangzong does not have a high degree of education, but he entered society early and has much more experience than me. He follows hundreds of accounts on Douyin, including test driving cars, tasting famous watches, and teaching you how to properly taste Burgundy red wine. Occasionally push it to me and say check it out, this is real life. In the video, the man is riding on a luxury yacht, surrounded by groups of beauties in bikinis. I don&#39;t feel anything. That kind of life is too far away from me. It doesn&#39;t seem real. Besides, who knows if it&#39;s staged. But Shan Guangzong is different. He not only believes that that is the real life, but also studies how to live that kind of life. Three years ago, he participated in the trainee draft and failed to pass the preliminary round. Why don&#39;t you try again? I asked him. Don’t you understand? Shan Guangzong said that drafting requires costs, and they are all the rich second generation who bring capital to join the group. It&#39;s 6:59, and many people are coming in one after another, but our distinguished guest is still nowhere to be seen. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What do you think Huang Pu does? Shan Guangzong asked me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I don’t know, I said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shit, Shan Guangzong said, you don’t know anything day by day, and you’re still a fucking college student. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fuck, I said, there are so many college students, who stipulates that college students must know everything. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shan Guangzong snorted and said yes, going to college is useless. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huang Pu didn’t go to college either. This is what he said personally. He didn&#39;t study well when he was a child, so he was sent to study abroad. There was no point in studying abroad. He had to go back to his country to earn money. Huang Pu is easy-going and would sometimes chat with us about the elementary school he went to, the girls he dated, and his ex who we broke up with married to Japan... He never mentioned making money, and we didn&#39;t ask. Gan Gou Yu specifically said during the meeting, just listen to what the guests say, don&#39;t ask questions, and don&#39;t talk too much. At Huang Pu’s dinner party, I have met real estate executives, financial elites, TV reporters, lawyers and doctors, as well as people from the entertainment industry, film makers and live broadcasters. If there is an unknown guest with an arrogant expression, we will I guess he is probably a high official. Female companionship is never-ending. Most of the time there is one, but sometimes there are two or three. Most of them have long hair, thin waists and soft expressions. The men talked, and they sat and listened, nodding or laughing, making the atmosphere stuffy. It was obvious that a few of them really liked Huang Pu, as shown by their willingness to help him with his drinking, and silently squatting on the ground to clean up his vomit when he was drunk. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Once Shan Guangzong asked me why I came here. I said I wanted to gain experience and get in touch with society in advance. I didn&#39;t tell the truth. I came to Mid-Levels because the wages here are the highest, McDonald&#39;s is 12.5 yuan an hour. I work as a promoter in a supermarket for 120 yuan a day and stand for nine hours. I come to Mid-Levels and work one afternoon a week, two full days. Including commission, I can get more than 2,000 yuan at the end of the month. I can buy an Apple computer in four months. After a year, by saving some money, I can save 20,000 yuan and buy a second-hand 310R. After I graduate from college, I will ride a BMW motorcycle, leave here, and find a serious job. I didn&#39;t say these words to Shan Guangzong, for fear that he would look at me again and say that the 310R is the cheapest BMW motorcycle. But at least it&#39;s a BMW. I also asked Shan Guangzong the same question, and his answer was a bit funny. He said that at the beginning, he was very innocent and just wanted to be with a rich woman. After a year, he discovered that being with a rich woman was not that easy, and the risks were very high. So he began to practice stealing wine, stealing wine from guests and from the club. At first, I only dared to steal a bottle of wine and taste it myself. Later, when I became bolder and my skills became more proficient, I stole half a bottle and exchanged the fake wine for the customer&#39;s real wine to sell. On the first night in Mid-Levels, I saw with my own eyes that he exchanged empty bottles for the guests’ Moutai. Before the guests left, he pulled me into the serving room, held the door with one hand, held the milky white porcelain bottle upside down with the other, and took out a small half glass of wine for me to taste. I was extremely scared at the time. I was afraid that the customers would find out about asking me to accompany the money, and I was also afraid that if they found out about it, they would file a lawsuit against me in school. Come on, Shan Guangzong said, who knows you? Besides, they are all drunk. Just in case you’re not drunk, I said. You believe me, Shan Guangzong said, they were so drunk that they couldn&#39;t distinguish between water and horse urine. They were so drunk that they couldn&#39;t even remember who they fucked with. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shan Guangzong has been stealing more and more boldly recently. Last week, a customer drank too much and went to the hospital. His car was left untouched at the club, so he drove it out overnight and replaced parts, earning more than 10,000 yuan. The money was split with Li Zhifei, who was in charge of the keys in the hall, and it has not been discovered yet. In the past two days, I often heard him say that people must live with great vigor. Thinking of this, my heart skipped a beat. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At a quarter past seven, the distinguished guest finally arrived, a black Audi with a tail number of three nines. As soon as the car door opened, a short and thin middle-aged man got out. He was in his forties, wearing a short windbreaker and a pair of glasses. He looked like an economics professor from our college. Shan Guangzong and I bowed ninety degrees and said good evening to Mr. Kong. Mr. Kong was very polite, nodded and said hello. I said Mr. Huang specifically told me that the car would be parked in the backyard for you, which is safe and convenient. Mr. Kong nodded again, put the key into my hand and said thank you. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The club originally had two parking attendants, but one of them resigned last week because he found it inconvenient to commute here. When I was too busy at night, Shan Guangzong took over. He had been working in the club for the longest time, and he had touched a lot of cars and was very familiar with it. While Qian Gouyu wasn&#39;t paying attention, Shan Guangzong also gave me a chance. I am very self-aware and would not touch a car that is too good for fear of making a fool of myself. The Audi is not bad. I have driven it a few times and I am not afraid. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Because I am a novice, I move very slowly. When I go out from the front yard, everyone else will do a U-turn, so I can only drive forward and circle around the small fountain at the door. Out. The car is an old model, very clean inside, and has a light woody aroma. I really like this feeling, driving through the neatly manicured trees in the yard, listening to the turn signals clicking in the car, like a clock ticking, one after another, the present moment leads to my future. . Now, I began to imagine that there was a girl in the car, with pure white skin and a black ponytail. I took her here to dine - a quiet and prosperous three-story villa halfway up the mountain, in the middle of a dense forest. She sat in the passenger seat and went to court. Looking outside, the cheeks are red and the eyes are shining. After dinner, we took a walk in the mountains, all the way up, and stayed at the top of the mountain - stop, it seems that it took me a long time to come out. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I parked the car and trotted back to the Roman Hall - to be precise, it was the serving room of the Roman Hall, with a small door alone so as not to disturb the guests. Shan Guangzong poured the white wine into a white porcelain pot with bamboo leaves, added three hot wine cups, and placed them together on a special ebony wood tray. Shan Guangzong asked me to take the wine out and went to pick up the four side dishes delivered from the window. He always bosses me around when it comes to work, as if I am his subordinate and have to listen to him in everything. He also lied to me and said we were the same age. In fact, he deliberately reported a false age. I peeked at his ID card. He was born in 2001 and is one year younger than me. He is only twenty-two this year. I glared at him, took the tray with one hand, and pushed the other door - the one connecting to the main hall - with the other hand. As soon as the door opened, a sweet fragrance rushed towards me. I guessed it was the smell of the girl. She sprayed a lot of perfume and stayed in one place for a long time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mr. Kong is sitting in the main seat, with Huang Pu on his right and the girl on his left. The two men put their heads very close to each other, chatting about blockchain, financing and the like. The girl put her arms on the table, holding the phone in her right hand, and swiping up and down with her left hand. Shan Guangzong also came out and put the four side dishes on the turntable one by one. I stood behind Huang Pu with the wine in hand and waited for him to finish speaking before asking, Mr. Huang, would you like to pour some wine? Huang Pu extended his hand and paid respect to Mr. Kong. I started to serve, with my back straight and my steps straight. I walked to Mr. Kong&#39;s side, turned around, held the tray with one hand, put down the cup with the other hand, picked up the wine bottle, and put the three-cent wine cup into the cup. Fill steadily. This set of movements was specially trained after coming to the club. It focuses on one belief: noble service. At first I couldn&#39;t get into the mood and I would laugh from time to time. But now I&#39;m fine and I feel quite confident. I poured the wine for Mr. Kong and served Huang Pu the same drink again. Then I turned behind the girl and looked at Huang Pu&#39;s eyes. I don’t want to drink—I heard her whisper. Huang Pu was still talking about blockchain with Mr. Kong, without looking at her or me. I put the wine cup in front of her, and when she didn&#39;t stop me, I put the spout up to it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is not surprising at all. According to my experience, Huangpu brings a lot of girls. Even at the beginning, they look embarrassed and say they can&#39;t, won&#39;t, or are unwell. Last month, Huang Pu brought a girl with baby hair, overalls, and a bit of a picky manner of speaking. Huang Pu said to drink some, but she waved her hand and said no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no. Huang Pu said just a little bit, and she said Boer Boer. Huang Pu said, pour it first and talk later. She said, Bo&#39;er, Bo&#39;er, really Bo&#39;er. When the banquet started, Huang Pu said that he had already poured all the wine, so he would just have a drink. On the second cup, Huang Pu said that odd numbers are unlucky and good things come in pairs. After three glasses of wine, her face turned red, her eyebrows and eyes drooped, and she stopped mentioning &quot;Boer Boer&quot;. Last month, Huang Pu brought a singer with a long face and short inches, who would not laugh no matter how funny he was. At first she said no several times, but Huang Pu pretended not to hear. Then she covered the mouth of the cup and prevented me from pouring the wine. Huang Pu stood up and said, I will pour it for you. The singer sneered and said don&#39;t do this. Which one did Huang Pu say? Pancakes and fruit are too much. She suddenly became very angry and slapped her hands on the table with a &quot;pop&quot; sound, which really shocked me. She stood up and walked out. She moved so quickly that the chair was overturned and a cup was broken. None of the guests present, including me and Shan Guangzong, spoke. We all held our breaths, waiting to see a good show, such as her slamming the door and running away, or Huang Pu chasing her and pulling her, and they might quarrel and say some wonderful national curses. But what happened next took everyone by surprise. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For a long time, I always thought of that scene before going to bed - what made that angry girl become docile in an instant? I thought over and over again, trying to use logic to sort out the story. It&#39;s too simple, so simple that it can only hold up half of the outline. The remaining half is hidden in the air, shapeless and smellless, like water waves in a deep well, wandering around and breaking when picked up. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Now I can only recount what happened dryly: She walked to the door and reached the handle. I can even imagine the sound of her slamming the door and leaving. At this moment, Huang Pu Call out her name, Deng Jiajia. His tone was stern, but not scolding. There was an element of kindness and persuasion in his sternness, like a father scolding a child who made a mistake. Deng Jiajia froze and stopped in place. After looking at him for a few seconds, she returned to the table and let out a long sigh. Huang Pu made a joke, and everyone dutifully contributed to the maximum amount of laughter. Things passed smoothly like this, as if it had never been intense before. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She finally drank two large glasses of red wine under his pressure, on the grounds of art and world peace. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shan Guangzong said that this is what women do. He said this as he picked out a piece of arctic clam from a sashimi platter with a pair of chopsticks. I asked him which one was this? Shan Guangzong put the Arctic clam into his mouth, chewed it, and said, he winked at her. I asked again, what does that wink mean? Shan Guangzong licked his teeth with his tongue and said, I don&#39;t know, but women can read. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A few dishes were served one after another, and Huang Pu stood up to make a toast. Huang Pu likes to use idioms every time he opens the show. The most frequent ones are &quot;Sansheng is lucky&quot; and &quot;Eternal Life&quot;: Sansheng is lucky to invite dear Mr. Kong, Sansheng is lucky to be on this starry night, Sansheng is lucky to gather with all friends - Before Huang Pu could talk about eternity, his words were cut off by Mr. Kong. Mr. Kong said Huang Pu, what are you doing? We don’t have to do this. Huang Pu chuckled and said that it was the first time for the eldest brother to appreciate the glory, and he got what he deserved. Mr. Kong said that he accepted it, and we can do whatever we want next. Mr. Kong glanced at the girl when he said this. She was holding the cup with one hand and holding her arm with the other. She was leaning on the edge of the table, rocking back and forth. Huang Pu said yes, then I&#39;m welcome. Big brother, little sister, let&#39;s drink to the reunion. Huang Pu stretched out his arm, and Mr. Kong also stretched out his arm. Huang Pu looked at the girl, and Mr. Kong looked at the girl. The girl saw the two men looking at her and smiling, and the corners of her pursed lips turned up. The three wine glasses collided in mid-air. Huang Pu drank, and so did Mr. Kong. The girl took a sip, and when Huang Pu said &quot;dry it, drink it, drink it, drink it, drink it, drink it, drink it, drink it, drink it.&quot; I filled everyone&#39;s wine cups again, and Huang Pu then took the cups. Three times in a row, they drank them all. I changed the wine cup and refilled the glass. When I walked to the girl, I heard her sigh softly. But neither man seemed to care. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huang Pu turned the turntable and gave way to Mr. Kong to eat the food. Mr. Kong is very knowledgeable about food. Every time he eats a dish, he will comment on the taste and then explain the ingredients and methods of the dish. Huang Pu said yes frequently, and sometimes followed up with a few sentences. They extend from the ingredients and methods to the regional flavor, and then from the regional flavor to the humanistic style. The girl listened at first and stretched out her hand from time to time to admire her manicure. Then she simply checked her phone and accidentally made noise, so she quickly turned down the volume. Several times I saw Huang Pu looking at her with raised eyebrows, as if he wanted to give her a hint, but the girl seemed to be deliberately refusing to look up at him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When the &quot;Pink Beauty&quot; was served, Huang Pu said, little sister, look at this. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the dinner started, Huang Pu stopped calling her baby. Maybe it was because she acted proud and lacked politeness, or maybe it was because Huang Pu found that even so, Mr. Kong still insisted on talking to her. Mr. Kong asked the girl what she called her? The girl said Wang Anqi. Mr. Kong said Anqi is a good name. Where are you from? The girl said she was from Shouchun. Mr. Kong said that I know Longevity Village. It is a good place. The three villages of Fortune, Luxu and Longevity have the same origin. The girl smiled and then checked her phone. Mr. Kong asked again after a while, what is An Qi’s profession? girl said student. Mr. Kong asked which school? The girl said it was at the foot of the mountain, the School of Finance and Economics. Mr. Kong said, School of Finance and Economics, I am good friends with Professor Li from your Law Department. The girl didn&#39;t answer. She kept her eyes on the screen and typed quickly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An Qi, put down the phone, Huang Pu said, his usually cheerful tone dialed back twice, with a hint of command. This is specially ordered for you, Huang Pu added. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She slowly raised her head, still holding the phone in her hand, and said, I don’t like desserts. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is different, Huang Pu said, if you don’t believe it, just look at it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shan Guangzong placed the tray in front of her, and mist spread on the table. The tray is hollow, with a layer of dry ice on the bottom. There is a crystal ice bowl on the tray. In the center of the bowl is a milky white cake, made in the shape of a girl, wearing a long trailing skirt. This dish draws inspiration from magic, with the final step left to the guest. It&#39;s very simple. You just need to pull the pink bow on the girl&#39;s waist. The bow is connected to the lace on the waist. The lace is filled with strawberry jam and gold powder. Pull and lift, the lace spreads out, and the bright red strawberry jam pours down from the waist. The white skirt Turns red, shimmering with gold. Whenever this happens, there will always be a burst of cheers from the table, and the ladies will scream, applaud, and take pictures with their mobile phones. The lively atmosphere helps to enhance feelings, and guests order &quot;Pink Beauty&quot; for this purpose. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Shan Guangzong pointed at the position of the bow and let her try it. She held her cheeks and held her mobile phone with one hand, as if she didn&#39;t hear it. La, Huangpu said. She glanced at him and said, &quot;It&#39;s stupid, I don&#39;t do it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I saw Huangpu&#39;s face sinking like a black iron for a moment. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Kong always look at the girl, look at Huangpu, and stand up. President Kong said that you eat first, and I go out to make a phone call. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;br>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Now that the single light has returned to the passing room, President Kong also went outside the door, and there were only three of us in the dining room. I know that I should leave as soon as possible, but the ghost made it a good way, but picked up the teapot and walked towards the bar. The lounge where the bar is located is connected with the dining room. There are screens in the middle, and no one can be seen, but you can hear the sound. Perhaps the distance is far away, Huangpu does not have me. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I walked into the bar, poured out the tea in the pot, unscrewed the water into the teapot, and wiped it with paper, and then took out another one stored in the yellow garden from the locker. Tea, Phoenix Shan Shan. Burn in water, wash tea, brew &amp; mdash; &amp; mdash; I slowly do these miscellaneous things, stay in the room for a long time until I hear them start to quarrel. The sound is not loud, but it is fierce. She seemed to be questioning something, &amp; nbsp; content could not be heard clearly, and the kettle buzzed in front of me. The sound of falling door soon came from behind, and then I heard that Huang Pu called me, and my tone was rushing. I trot over and saw that anger was dissipating on his face, and when he opened his mouth, he had recovered his ordinary tone. Huangpu asked me to go downstairs to find, while litting the hanger with my eyes with my eyes, there was a coat of him and President Kong, and a pink lady&#39;s leather bag. Huang Pu said she was not far away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Kong always came in, with a smile. From the beginning to the present, he has always been this expression, like Mona Lisa. President Kong sat in his chair, swept through his eyes towards the room, and said, why, his girlfriend is angry? Huang Pu smiled, saying where the girlfriend, sister, a little sister. The Phoenix Shan Shan, who had just poured him, smelled the tea incense, laughed, your boy, there are younger sisters everywhere. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After I came out, I gently stood on the door, and suddenly there was a laugh in the room. I didn&#39;t know what secret joke they said. The door of the Persian hall next to the Persian Hall was pushed away from it. The group of people wearing black suits had taken off their coats and turned into white blue shirts. They were giving around and patting their hands to catch duck games. . Shan Guangzong poked his head from the window of the rumor, squeezed my eyes at me, and asked, the girl ran away? She seems to be my classmate, I said. Shan Guangzong snorted and said, what do you want to save the beauty? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Heroes save beauty, I haven&#39;t thought about it. I am twenty -three years old, 1.77 meters tall, and weighing 55 kilograms. Except for a young body and a poor 3,500 deposits, I have nothing. And she, the huge CD sign of the pink leather bag was worth tens of thousands of dollars. How should I save her, what do she need me to save? But maybe I can take this opportunity to make a little friendship with her, such as telling her that we are college classmates. I know that she does not necessarily like this. Maybe she will be frightened, and she will go detoured immediately in school in the future. After that class, I never saw her again. I guess she was studying in the department of Western District. There are two campuses in our school. The eastern district is at the foot of this half of the mountain. The western district is in the city. It is an old school. There are only three departments, music, dance, and decoration design. I forgot which subjects were in that big lesson, but looking at her body, it was either music or dance. Of course, there is a possibility of one tenth of 10,000. She is just a social leisure person and so on. If so, I will not find a reason to add her WeChat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I thought about walking down the stairs. She didn&#39;t go far away, so she stood in the center of the hall, her arm was still holding, and looked up at the crystal lamp. The crystal lamp is very bright, hanging on the dome ceiling, with long tassels hanging down. The hall was shining brightly, and her face was white. I slowed down and thought about what to say in the first sentence, but she turned her head and opened her mouth first. Huangpu asked you to come to me? she asked. I nodded. Her gaze stopped on my face for a while, and returned to the lamp, saying, do you see it like a skirt? What? I said. Do you think it looks like a skirt? She said again. I glanced up at it, the light was too bright, and a white dot appeared immediately in front of me. It&#39;s a bit like it, I rubbing my eyes and said, &quot;Aren&#39;t you dazzling? She laughed, and her red lips were very big. Who can wear this skirt, she said. It must not be burned, I said. She then asked me if Huangpu often brought girls here? I answered it after a while, and it was not clear soon. The corner of her mouth twitched slightly, her eyes stared at my eyes, as if to pick out something from it. Go back, I turned my face and said, the hall was very cold. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I followed her back and forth into the room, and saw that the two men put their heads close again, like the financial economy at the beginning of the meal. Huangpu spreads two hands, and his expression was complaining. I listened a few words, about what leaders who had offended, causing the project to be criticized. Mr. Kong just smiled and did not express his opinions, but he had sideways a lot, indicating that he was listening seriously. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the girl entered the door, Kong always didn&#39;t hear so seriously, and moved her eyes to her from time to time. Now she has sat down, rubbing her shoulders with both hands, and the suffering of Huangpu has not finished complaining, and Kong always started talking to her. President Kong said back, is it cold outside? She smiled and said that it was very cold. She wanted to go out and breath, but froze half dead. &amp; ldquo; Pink Beauty &amp; rdquo; It was a bit collapsed. She took a small spoon and ate it. Tomorrow the frost fall, and put more clothes, Mr. Kong said. Huang Pu and Kong touched a cup and said that my sister is very good, but it is naughty and unable to stay idle. President Kong said that naughty is good, and naughty girls are interesting. She took the eyelids and sighed Huangpu, and she raised her eyebrows and said to President Kong. President Kong read countless people. Since I said that I am interesting, I must have a little potential. Don&#39;t stop at the potential, Huang Pu said. She immediately stood up from her seat and said to President Kong, that is, I have the opportunity to teach more, and I respect you alone. Now she was pouting and smiling, blinking her eyes, making a cute look. Compared with before, she changed her personal. President Kong said that you sit down first and drink it. Her eyes turned towards it, saying that standing and drinking is my respect, sitting down and drinking is your friendship. I first express my respect and we will deepen my friendship. Mr. Kong laughed. From entering the room, I saw his teeth for the first time, a row of Wuqing, with tea colors. I don&#39;t know if it was smoking or born. President Kong gave a thumbs up to An Qi, saying that An Qi I saw that you really have potential. She raised her head and dried the wine, and President Kong did it. Huang Pu said that I accompanied one, and he did it. After that, he laughed, and the atmosphere was a lot easier. They drank a cup like this, respectful and respectful each other, and spoke playful words, everyone was full of red face. A bottle of white wine quickly went down, and Huangpu added two more dishes, a cold pig ear, and an old vinegar peanut. Confucius was smoking, spitting a cigarette ring in the air, and round and big. For a while, she was too happy, and she laughed at the two men. After laughing for a while, she sat upright, shouting with a crisp voice, the waiter, come over. I walked to her, bent down and asked, what did the lady need? Listening to Coca -Cola, she said. When she spoke, her eyes didn&#39;t look at me at all, and one hand touched the rose gold tail ring on the other finger. Good lady, I turned around and felt my heart began to fall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;br>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;span style = &quot;color: rgb (128, 128, 128);&quot;>; &quot;Stealing Watch&quot; (below) will be updated tomorrow. &lt;/span>; &lt;/p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; Responsible editor: Li Jialong &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; See @ONE Studio on Weibo. Editor&#39;s official WeChat: OneApp2020. Regularly publish Q &amp; A collection, gift books and surrounding gifts, and readers are welcome to add. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/Fjs4axx83XNQjyxKn-6mnTvJUjaW&quot; alt=&quot;胡镜宇&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;胡镜宇&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;微博@胡镜宇&lt;/span >; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style = &quot;&quot;>; labyrinth and roads, spells and magic. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href = &quot;/article/6173&quot; data-ajax = &quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>; The mystery of the universe &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; text/Lu Yinyin &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/TD>; &lt;/tr>; tr>; &lt;td style = &quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>; Read &lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6174&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>; apricot Color sweaters &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; text/A or B &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;TABLE>; &lt;TD>; &lt;div style = &quot;text- Align: center; padding: 5px; &quot;OnClick =&quot; OneApp.opndetail (2,6176) &quot;>; Click to download one app &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/trble>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/&lt;/&lt;/div>; div>; &lt;p>; &amp; nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 06:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4067]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4212]]><description>&lt;div>; 25 nov. 2023 &amp; nbsp; &lt;/div>; &lt;div Role = &quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/fn_u5cib6k7wg18ya9s1froeopm7&quot; alt = &quot;Homepage Figure&quot; &quot; />; &lt;p >; &lt;span>; Vol.4067 &lt;/span>; Photography | Natalien Parham &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 25 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Nov. 2023 &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; This world in this world Many bad things are caught up when you find that you are weak. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 25 Nov 2023 06:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>