<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[30+的朋友，青春期时困扰你的问题解决了吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3985]]><description> &lt;div>;22 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Received, but asked&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p >; Friends who are over 30, have the problems that troubled you during adolescence been solved? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; ONE Friendly Answers&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FnkTGVScIQBfBGAVsVuD67GUME4F&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FnkTGVScIQBfBGAVsVuD67GUME4F&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot; font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Adolescence is the most special period. Each of us looks like we have nothing, but in fact we are infinitely rich, and yet we are always very timid because we are young. Now that I recall those troubles and sorrows, I have other thoughts in my mind. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I was at school, I was worried about not having time to go to the toilet after class. &lt;/strong>;Now when I go to work, I still worry about not having time to go to the toilet after class. I used to be too lazy to change my sanitary napkin because I would worry about leakage, but now I don’t worry about it anymore because the volume is not that big. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Aweiwei, 30 years old, student conflict mediator&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;I used to watch my parents quarreling every day, and I was worried that they would get divorced. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As adults, I have a greater understanding and understanding of intimate relationships, and realize that instead of facing each other in pain every day, it is better to choose another way of life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Shirley Zhou, 31 years old, graphic designer&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Panic about the future. &lt;/strong>;My parents and teachers kept instilling the idea that if I didn’t study well, I would only be able to move bricks, but I just couldn’t get into it. But I went out to work on my own and started a small business. Life was not very good, but I&#39;m doing okay. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;fff, 32 years old, foreign trader&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;When I was in junior high school, I lamented every day about&lt;strong>;when the endless school days would end. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I miss that time every day after work, maybe because people unconsciously embellish their memories. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;ozawa, 33 years old, construction site dog&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;&lt;strong>;Physiological changes. &lt;/strong>;I didn’t understand anything at that time, I thought I was going to mutate, and I didn’t dare to tell anyone. When I grow up and get exposed to more information, I realize, hey, isn’t it something that women have to experience? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Maple Land, 33 years old, freelance&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;When can I achieve financial freedom, have my own cats and dogs, and have my own small house? &lt;/strong>;I want to get out of the control of home and school as soon as possible. There is a clear answer to this question, and the answer is absolutely impossible. Houses in third-tier cities are seven to eight thousand one square meters. I can be considered self-sufficient in raising myself. I have no ability to raise cats and dogs. It’s like, with my financial situation, I will never get married and have children. At least now I am mentally free. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Strike, 34 years old, code character&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;The question that bothered me most during my adolescence was why adults sometimes didn’t tell the truth and always tried to please those they hated. &lt;/strong>;Now I am no longer troubled by this problem, not because this phenomenon has disappeared, but because I am older and have realized the helplessness and powerlessness in real life. I realize that survival is not easy. When people grow up and face this society alone and ask for a living from the society, they have to make some concessions. Of course, we need to be very clear about our principles. These concessions must not break the bottom line. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Xiao Taofeng, 34 years old, media practitioner&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;When I was in high school, I was worried about &lt;strong>;when I would earn enough millions, and then I would&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;do nothing&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; and sit back and live in vain&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Now it’s solved: After being laid off and being rejected for more than ten consecutive interviews, I no longer have these unrealistic fantasies. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Crazy Aduo, 35 years old, coder&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;My mother said &lt;strong>;There will be no future if you can’t get into college&lt;/strong>;. With the double affirmation from the school and my parents, I was half-convinced. I didn&#39;t pass the exam in life science, so I went to a college. But luckily I was okay at that time. I have sold household appliances, mobile phones, and now I am selling insurance and have a small position in an insurance company. Of course, if this is not possible now, the minimum threshold for our company must be a bachelor&#39;s degree in accounting. This problem has been solved now. It cannot be compared with making a lot of money, but I am satisfied. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Gon, 36 years old, insurance officer&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;&lt;strong>;Why do adults not abide by the principles of life taught by teachers? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When you grow up, you will understand that the world says one thing and does another. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Amuli, 36 years old, wage earner&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When I was 16 years old, I had acne on my face, sweating under my armpits, hemorrhoids, protruding lower abdomen, and long hair. I was thinking&lt;strong>;about how this body would look like in the future, thinking about how embarrassing it would be to have a hemorrhoidectomy, and thinking about what I would do if no man wanted me. &lt;/strong>;Now these problems have been solved. After I went to college, the acne marks disappeared; I don’t have a good figure, but I am healthy; hemorrhoids have no impact and are still with me; men are not that important, it doesn’t matter whether I have them or not. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My vision in adolescence was too narrow, and I mistakenly regarded a piece of ceiling as the entire roof. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Jiuhai, 37 years old, pharmacist&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The boy I&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;have a crush on&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;does&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;like&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;not&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;like&lt; /strong>;&lt;strong>;I. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Solved, solved long ago. Everyone I&#39;ve had a crush on is married. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Yi Chaonan, 41 years old, author&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt; p>;Editor in charge: Nana onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For information on soliciting papers, please see @ONE Studio pinned on Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8 &quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Complex The cutest people in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3984&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What was the last social method you used to quickly integrate into a new environment? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3982&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;At what point did you truly become an adult? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3981&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What worries does &quot;E-man&quot; have? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3985)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 06:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我们与恶的距离]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6172]]><description> &lt;div>;22 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Wu Zhongquan&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fpe9NbuaTmbU4xuMaRDbepNwsQVv&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fpe9NbuaTmbU4xuMaRDbepNwsQVv&quot;>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;How far is the distance between human heart and evil? One word, one thought, one blow, one change, and we may suddenly fall into an abyss with no end in sight. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He found me on Weibo, gave me his name, and asked me if I still remembered him? It took me a long time to remember that many years ago, I worked in a construction company, and the company&#39;s projects were everywhere. I was first in Hulunbuir, then went to Gansu, and then returned to Hulunbuir. Hulunbuir&#39;s project is to build infrastructure in a coal mine. It is deep in a prairie and cannot be seen all year round. Only the earth is changing color. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In that coal mine, many construction companies were working on construction, but there were not many people, and even fewer young people, so we, the few young people, could easily cross the company barrier and get off the job. Ban would get together to play cards and drink to pass the long nights with only the roar of the wind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was one of the young men. I didn’t have a deep impression of him. I just remembered that he had a round head, was short, had a southern accent, and was good at drinking. After he found me on Weibo, we re-established contact, but we didn&#39;t exchange a few words. I only knew that he was in Jiangxi, no longer engaged in engineering, and was in the medicinal wine business. When he learned that I was in Hangzhou, he said he would come and visit me if he had the opportunity. I thought it was a courtesy, so I said yes, yes, yes. But I didn’t expect that he would really come, but he didn’t come to see me specifically. He wanted to talk about some agency matters, so I was just dropping by. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I wanted to invite him to dinner, but he refused to do so. He insisted on inviting me, so I was pulled into a private room in a hotel. Over the hot dishes, there is an alienation that has not been seen for many years. Fortunately, we have all been in society for many years, and we have learned to be polite. When we have nothing to say, we can talk about what we have been doing over the years, and also talk about the past. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He still likes to drink. He brought some medicated wine with him. I took a few sips and it was quite strong. After a few glasses of wine, all that could be talked about was almost exhausted. Silence floated in the box from time to time. He might be afraid of this silence, so he suddenly stretched out his arms and said, &quot;You are a book writer. Let me tell you something.&quot; . After he finished speaking, he added, &quot;It&#39;s my own business.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I have seen this kind of thing a lot, and I have heard too many personal experiences that I thought were wonderful but were extremely boring. I was quite scared, but out of politeness, I had to say yes with a smile. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He took another sip of wine, and the time went back more than ten years ago, to the grasslands of Hulunbuir. Not long after I left, he failed to be retained by the company due to poor performance during the internship, so he left there. After that, he returned to his hometown in Jiangxi and continued to look for a job. I don’t know why. In short, he kept getting hired, went to work, and then left actively or passively. The longest job did not last more than half a year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His family&#39;s financial situation is not good. He was born in a rural area. His mother still has chronic diseases and takes medicine all the year round, so he cannot afford to change jobs so frequently. In other words, he cannot afford to wait for many years after he graduates. Give back to the family steadily. He also felt anxious about his predicament. The more anxious he became, the less able he was to work down to earth, and he only thought about making a lot of money quickly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The opportunity finally came. A classmate called him and told him that there was a good opportunity there and he could make money quickly. He hurried there without much thought, and even saw that the address was in Guangxi without much precaution, so he jumped directly into the pyramid scheme. Once the iron door was pulled, he couldn&#39;t get out. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All the money on my body was gently removed. I listened to inspiring pyramid courses every day. In the evening, my colleagues helped each other to wash their feet in a friendly way. In fact, I wanted to wash away the stubbornness in my mind and become a person who only cares about money. And the more civilized people deceive relatives and friends into joining the gang without any psychological barriers. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His mind was filled with anger towards the classmate who tricked him into joining the gang. He always wanted to find an opportunity to hammer him to death. This hammer was not an adjective, but he really wanted to hit him on the head. Hammer, but the classmate was quickly transferred to another den. He couldn&#39;t find an outlet for his anger, so he turned to holding his breath and trying to escape. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although the den was strictly managed, he still found the opportunity. He got into the trunk of a middle-level leader’s car. After the car drove out, he jumped out of the trunk and ran to the He was saved by the traffic policeman directing traffic on the roadside. But the pyramid scheme&#39;s nest was not taken away. When the police arrived, the building was already empty. They were so alert and cunning, and he was lucky to escape. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The police bought him a ticket and asked him to go back to his hometown. When he entered the station, he refunded the ticket and ran out. He did not dare to go home just like that. When he left home, he took away the fertilizer money that his father had borrowed. It was stolen and without fertilizer, the fields were ruined for a whole year. He couldn&#39;t face the fact that his family had become as barren as the land without fertilizer because of his mistakes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He wandered in the city until night, tired and hungry, so he went into a park, lay down on a bench to rest, and saw a woman wearing gold and silver, carrying a bag. Take a leisurely stroll in the park. He suddenly felt that this was a dangerous opportunity, and without much thought, he touched a red brick and followed it. There were not many people in the park, and the lighting was not good. The woman went straight into the woods, as if she was deliberately looking for an opening for him to strike, or there was a path home. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He looked around, gritted his teeth, and was about to rush up. The back of his head was the softest. If a brick hit him, he would definitely fall down. Then her gold and silver jewelry and the money in the bag, Enough for him to plug the holes in his home. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He rushed over at a trot, with the bricks raised high, but he didn&#39;t know what was going on. Maybe he was afraid, or maybe he was too soft-hearted. These emotions were all transmitted to his palms, and his hands became soft. He lost all his strength in an instant, and the brick slipped from his hand and fell to the ground, making a clanging sound. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When the woman heard this, she turned around and was startled for a moment. Then she realized what had happened and started running, yelling. He was also startled, and immediately ran in the other direction, faster and faster, and the more he ran, the more he dared not stop, until he lost any strength and collapsed on the ground. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He stopped talking about this. He knew that this was an important moment in the story, so he looked at me like he was waiting for a response. I couldn&#39;t break away from his story for a moment, and my mood stayed there. It took a few seconds before I recovered from the dark night and returned to this mellow moment of the banquet. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I came to my senses and said it was really risky. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I didn’t expect that this response was the same as his state of mind. He said yes, it was so dangerous. Every time I think about that moment over the years, I feel that it was so dangerous. My life was almost ruined. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said that night was the dividing point of his life. As soon as it dawned, he called home. His father scolded him on the other end of the phone. He cried. His father later Cried too. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He returned to his hometown again, as if running for his life. Whenever he found a job in the future, he would work hard. No matter what kind of work he was doing, he would not despise it or feel tired. Every little bit of salary he received would be a reward. I treasure every little bit of happiness. He found that after his mentality changed, the operation of everything in the world became smoother, and he went more and more smoothly, reaching such a good field now. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Faced with this ending, I felt happy for him from the bottom of my heart, but I was also at a loss for words. I forgot all the writing skills and gorgeous rhetoric I had accumulated over the years, and could only say, &quot;It&#39;s great, it&#39;s great.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A few years ago, I published a new book and went to a bookstore owned by a friend in the Northeast to do an event. My friend is also a writer, and her husband was a journalist before opening a bookstore, so he can also be a host. The questions asked during the event were quite unexpected, and I always had to think for a while before I could answer them. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the event, the couple took me to dinner, where they ate a large plate of chicken and drank Dawusu beer. We chatted during the meal, talking about new books, and what we wanted to write in the future. In those years, Northeastern literature had just begun to become popular, and suspense themes were also very popular. His husband knew that I was from Heilongjiang, so he said, why don’t you write about your hometown? I have thought about the story, but I don’t know what to write. He said that there was a famous serial murder case a few years ago, do you know? Raped and killed many children. I said I&#39;ve heard of it. He said that I interviewed the murderer back then. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was stunned. This was the first time I had ever met a murderer. I asked him how he felt, and I forgot his answer. It was probably just ordinary, with no special mentality. I asked him again, why did he kill people? He said it was quite complicated and the details were all written in the report, so he asked me to look for it online. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This topic ends here. I drank some wine that night and felt a little dizzy. The next day I returned to Beijing from Northeast China and went to Vietnam. After that, my life has been busy. , although this matter still comes to mind from time to time, it passes by in a flash, without occupying too much attention, and I have not read the report for a long time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then the epidemic came and I was quarantined at home in the Northeast. Although I was writing another novel, I still had a lot of free time, so I thought of that report again and looked it up online. It seems that my heart is getting more and more uncomfortable. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Around 2006, multiple murders of minors occurred in a small town in Northeast China. The police made every effort to investigate and arrest the suspects. The suspect was a middle-aged man who had just been released from prison, but he told a long story about the reason for his crime. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than ten years ago, when he was still a young man, he took over from his father and joined a state-owned factory. However, he soon encountered the restructuring of state-owned enterprises and was forced to be laid off. After that, he worked on his own, found some way out in life, and got a girlfriend. The two had sex, but the woman&#39;s family called the police. Only then did he discover that his girlfriend, who had always claimed that he was an adult, was not yet full. At the age of sixteen, he was convicted of rape and imprisoned. Naturally, he felt that he was wronged, but he was not wronged either. The law was there, but he didn&#39;t understand it well enough to violate it. However, a few years after he served his sentence, the law was changed, defining that after the age of 14, if there is confirmation of ignorance and consensual sex, it does not count as rape. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This change has improved him over the top. If the incident had happened a few years later, would he not have to go to jail? Do you no longer have to endure the pain of being bullied in prison these past few years? Why should the law be changed as soon as it is said to be changed? If it has been modified, does that mean it was wrong before? Then why should I bear the mistakes of others? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Once people have the idea of ​​&quot;why&quot;, it is dangerous. If there is an answer to this &quot;why&quot;, it would be fine, but if not, it will be a lifelong obsession. The worse things get in the future, the more you blame others. But who can he blame? So he blamed his girlfriend and society, and after he was released from prison, he began to take revenge crazily. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the murderer in this report was merged with the story of my friend, I had the illusion of parallel time and space. Every intersection when a person walks on the road is a forking point. As soon as it turns, two worlds are created. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So for life, every step, every choice, every decision is a test. In other words, life is inherently one trap after another, including mistakes, desires and temptations, choosing and being chosen, and so are love and friendship. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is too difficult for a person to go through this life smoothly without making any mistakes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition to the temptation of external factors, we must always guard against the resentment in our hearts and prevent it from turning into evil thoughts and spewing out. When our lives are going smoothly, we think that our evil thoughts are thousands of miles away, but if we are not careful, , it will turn into a brick in your hand, and if you smash it down, your life will be completely different. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My friend didn’t hit me, so I was afraid for many years. There was more luck in my fear. I was lucky that my hands were soft, and I made the right choice subconsciously. I will live a good life in the future, and the days will get better and better. The better you are, the more grateful you are for who you were. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The murderer in the report smashed the bricks down, but the resentment in his heart was not resolved, so he could only smash them down one after another until the last one hit his head. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A few years later, I adapted and wrote a book based on that report. When I went to the publishing house for a meeting, I found out that the editor was a fellow countryman of mine. What&#39;s even more coincidental is that I met the editor of another group and chatted with him, and he turned out to be a fellow editor. When she talked about the story of my book, she said that she knew the prototype of the story and was even half-experienced because she had also been to the Internet cafe in the story. After the murder occurred, she was extremely frightened. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At that moment I looked at her, and I felt a little dazed. Even though I had been with this story for several years, even if it was an interview report done by my friend, even if it happened in my hometown, I still It still feels like a very distant thing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But now, this half-experienced person is sitting in front of me, and I suddenly feel that it has crossed thousands of mountains and rivers of time and space and came to my side. I finally realized that in the lives of ordinary people, sin always follows us. This sin can be caused by others or our own. It is hidden deep in the body and among people without being visible. Then at a certain moment, I couldn&#39;t stand it anymore and suddenly rushed out and ruined everything. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking back at our ignorant childhood, indifferent adolescence and fearless youth, we must have had many dangerous moments and thoughts. If we avoid it, it will be daily life, but if we cannot avoid it, it will be disaster. In our long road ahead, we will still live between the time we have escaped and the time we have endured. All we can do is wait, waiting for fate&#39;s care or cunning to push us to the edge of one cold night after another. Test to test. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The rest of the time, sitting calmly with family members in the ordinary world, is God’s silent mercy, and we must treat it well. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FtZvjMZ12Wzt4JdbLJEC3AHbzzqs &quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FtZvjMZ12Wzt4JdbLJEC3AHbzzqs&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Li Jialong&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Wu Zhong The new book &quot;Silence on a Cold Night&quot; is released today. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FuesooEpr13-iy8Yt-6-tZtu9dZD&quot; alt=&quot;Wu Zhongquan&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Wu Zhongquan&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@ Wu Zhongquan&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Writer/Screenwriter&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2 , )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6158&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Starless at night&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Text/Wu Zhongquan&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/article/6142&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;People&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Wu Zhongquan&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Read&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6127&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>; I met a hundred million trees&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Wu Zhongquan&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6172)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt; /div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 06:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4064]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4208]]><description>&lt;div>;22 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpFloCe7QFoM_gBpobaZwN_HGQbH&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage picture&quot; />; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;VOL.4064&lt;/span>;Photography | Valter Zhara&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;22&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nov. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;People want Why is it so difficult to live neatly? Survival, life, outside, heart, everything needs to be ironed, and there are outlets everywhere. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 06:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>