<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[你有哪些奇葩的「生活定理」？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3939]]><description> &lt;div>;10 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; ONE Studio Question&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p >;What weird “life theorems” do you have? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; ONE Friendly Answers&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FvSFyi9TsHrH1fpz5Coi-Ck7JQL3&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FvSFyi9TsHrH1fpz5Coi-Ck7JQL3&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt; div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Living harmoniously with bad luck is a required course in this life. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bus I was waiting for never came, it was not the buses I was waiting for one after another. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@小小小乐&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; There&#39;s always a big unexpected expense when you&#39;re trying to save money. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@ mutual thoughts&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My dad Damn theorem: Other people’s children are good at everything, but your own children can’t do anything. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@西的月&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The more Express delivery that is not in a hurry will come faster, while express delivery that is more urgent will come slower. My succulents rotted on the road, and my persimmons (crispy persimmons) had turned into soft persimmons in my hands. I am now in the cold north, waiting for the long socks that have not arrived after four days of walking on the road. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@What just happened&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; When I own something, I realize that it is not as valuable as I originally imagined. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@小十一郎&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Don&#39;t get off work on time, just wait and catch fish, look for opportunities to be seen by the boss, and get promoted easily. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@白Robin Hood&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Find I searched all over the house to find it but couldn&#39;t find it. I stopped looking for it and it appeared on its own after a while (helpless). &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@Im_zp&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Except for banks Fixed deposit interest, my other investment and financial management methods will always lose money. I bought stocks with bonuses in the early years, and the stocks fell when I bought them. I bought a liquor and medical fund at the end of 2020 and made a little money at the beginning of 2021. However, starting from the second quarter of 21, the liquor and medical fund began to plummet. I bought gold not long ago this year, and gold also fell during the National Day holiday. But I believe this is only a temporary victory and gold will always be valuable. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@The threshold of the rooftop has been broken by me&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;When you think you are going to be late, you are not late; when you feel you will not be late, you are late for various reasons. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@ Shanghai Green Stuffed Vegetable Buns&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;Every time I ask for leave from work, I always have to call me with a lot of trouble. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@Thank you for the small animals surrendering to the table&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;This world is like this. The more you want it, the less you can get it. If you calm down, life will start to become more logical. So the more eager you are, the less urgent it is. Holding too tightly is often the beginning of screw up. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@Heaxyen&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Like to eat If you eat at a restaurant more than three times, the store will be closed down. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@昕唕婷婷婷婷&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; I am a small animal insulator. If you go to a relative&#39;s house to rub cats and dogs, either the dogs (which are free-range in the village) have gone out to play on their own, or the cats have been sent away to take a bath. My mother said there were newborn kittens in the park. When I went there, there was nothing there. The uncles around me said they had been captured and raised. But my parents always take pictures for me and say where they saw a kitten or a puppy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@万 beasts dislike&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Must Gotta have my boyfriend. Every time he went out, it seemed that the earth&#39;s gravity suddenly increased, and he wanted to poop. Is there any physicist who can study this? The older woman was grateful. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@Beidou is useless&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;We live in a shared house. When I get off work early, my roommate will also get off work early, so we have to share the kitchen together and wait in line to take a shower. But when I work overtime, my roommates will also get off work late, and we will share the kitchen together and wait in line to take a shower. The amazing thing is that all three roommates are like this. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@无privacyThe frog in the well&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; I have a strong appetite when I eat at home. I can add two portions of instant noodles to the takeout Malatang, and a handful of dried noodles when cooking instant noodles. I can eat 24 large dumplings made by my mother, and I can eat two packages of potato chips in a row... &quot;But it doesn&#39;t work when I go out to eat. I feel full after eating a few mouthfuls of meat in the hot pot. I feel full after eating three roast duck pancakes. I can&#39;t even eat half of the Kung Pao Chicken Rice Bowl.&quot; My belly is amazing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@It seems like I am the one who does not have weekend breaks&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Every time I queued, I always stood in the shortest line, but it turned out to be the slowest line. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@lingTsai&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor: Na Na onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For information about the call for submissions, please see the @ONE Studio pinned on Weibo. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8 &quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Complex The cutest people in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3626&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What truths do you know after paying the price for it? ​​​&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/ span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3936&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Why is it so difficult to &quot;reject&quot;? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3939)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[爱的发疯练习]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6123]]><description> &lt;div>;10 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Zhou Hongxiang&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data -author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FqP-hOXEQducMV8pYviLKwE8ublR&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FqP-hOXEQducMV8pYviLKwE8ublR&quot;>; &lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;We face the test questions on the examination paper, make mistakes again and again, and correct them. Finally get high scores. In the practice of love, every love process is a repeated review of the same question. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When James and I were sitting and drinking at the Hide &amp; Seek bar in Lido, he said: &amp;ldquo;Whenever everyone falls in love with someone , I feel that there is no other choice, and regard this fate as a uniqueness. This is the reason why most love affairs fall into anxiety. &amp;rdquo;This was originally like the opening of a movie, probably in the style of Woody Allen, with jazz music, talking about this kind of thing in the corner of a metropolitan area with people coming and going. But this has nothing to do with fiction. It actually happened around me. I said, &quot;Yes.&quot; &amp;rdquo;At that time, I had not grown up in love, so I was very sensible in evaluating other people&#39;s feelings. When you fall in love with someone, you don&#39;t want to treat them as the only one, unless you don&#39;t love them at all. James&#39; theory is that of course you can love him, but he is definitely not the only one for you, and don&#39;t plan the other person in your future as soon as you come. Love is an exercise, not a result, otherwise failure will happen at any time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is difficult for people like James to be regarded as people who have failed in love. He is a returnee from overseas, has an excellent background, and has a rich job. Although he is not particularly outstanding in appearance, he cannot be classified as ugly. After all, I have drunk foreign ink, have some taste, and can be friends, but when it comes to falling in love, I feel like a primary school student. According to the people around you, people like you should be masters in love and not be confused by a little girl. But James&#39; reason is very simple. I just treat my feelings sincerely, but most of the time this sincerity is not paid for. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;James is well-known in his small circle and lives in a very expensive community in Beijing. When love begins, he can attract all the people, regardless of appearance, status, or There is more or less the element of Muqiang in it. Many girls appreciate James&#39; excellence and classify him as a special boy who is not greasy and doesn&#39;t have too many bad intentions. Normal dating, holding hands, hugging, and kissing. Because of his slowness, it is always difficult to quickly promote a relationship. You always have to be sure that this person is someone you can date before you take action. In the long process of pulling , most of the girls will fall into an ambiguous love network, and begin to guess that James is probably a scumbag, and he should be more than two-way in the process of dating them. But scumbags are often more lovable, and then they have the idea of ​​​​female competition. As everyone knows, James is just not ready. He weighs too many things, but being tempted can happen in an instant. Sometimes friends around him advise, if you don’t Putting down your body to feel a relationship is like opening the yogurt and only licking the lid. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I think this has a lot to do with his long-lasting first love. In the first relationship, he always devoted himself wholeheartedly to it, which meant pouring everything into it and expecting it to blossom and bear fruit. Of course, the result was that he was dumped. James couldn&#39;t react afterwards, and the girl disappeared from his life. Then he went abroad to study hard and enrich himself. After returning to Beijing, he worked hard. Every time someone approached him, he would imagine many possibilities. Does this person really like him? Will it suddenly evaporate like the past relationship? So that pretended coldness was just a form of self-protection, and it turned out that if James opened this hole, he would be seriously scratched. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Every time James established a relationship, he would soon be met with indifference from the other party. More than once, he had to suspect that the girls who showed kindness to him were actually just for a game. When you asked James When it comes to how to deal with love relationships, I also worry about his immature way. James believes that love is when two people are in contact 24 hours a day. Even if the other person is working, studying or focusing on something, they should reply to his messages anytime and anywhere. If there is no reply for half an hour, he will He couldn&#39;t help but call the other party. Sometimes he found out during the chat that the other party skipped some of his sharing, and he started to ask why the other party didn&#39;t answer his questions directly. Sometimes James would plan a meeting a year later. When traveling, or when something in the future seems a bit too long-term to the other person, James will say, don’t you want to be with me? This kind of loss is a double demerit. The other party feels that James is too clingy, and clinginess seems cheap. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While the relationship was tense, James once called me and asked me to pick him up at the coffee shop. I asked him what was wrong, and he said he had been let go and lost contact with the other party. No matter how he called and sent messages, the other party did not reply. He even found some social platforms of the other party and let the other party know through private messages that he was looking for her. . I said, your way is really suffocating. Even I don’t want to go back after seeing it. James is confused, can&#39;t he explain it directly? I said, of course, but not replying is a way of making it clear. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His face, his voice, and his gestures are all very charming when there is no emotional anxiety, but when he is anxious, he becomes a very ordinary person. This is what makes him so charming. The main reason why romantic partners are disappointed. When I mentioned this to him, he said that if a person likes you, he should care about your anxieties. I said, no, only when a person loves you, will he care. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is easy for us to confuse liking with love. Liking is an easy thing because there is no need to bear too much pressure. Two people only need to be close and sweet. , but love is deep. When you reach a certain level of enough love, the other person will be willing to share your anxieties with you. Our worries about gains and losses in relationships often come from the inconsistent pace between us and the other person. When the other person is still enjoying the process of liking, you must not advance to the &quot;love&quot; stage in advance, and don&#39;t plan for the future. Don&#39;t care about gains and losses, don&#39;t be aggressive, don&#39;t be sticky, don&#39;t do anything, these will easily destroy the good things that happened in the first place. Like is to like a person&#39;s advantages, and love is to accept a person&#39;s shortcomings. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When James is at his most exaggerated, he will check the other party’s replies on social platforms to see if there is a possible third party. Regarding the other party’s indifference, he concludes that he may just be one of the ones she has screened out. one person. This idea is of course understandable, but the key point is that dating itself is a two-way choice, and you don&#39;t have to regard the other person as the only one. James said, isn&#39;t that a scumbag? It&#39;s normal to ride the horse at the beginning of a relationship. Before you confirm a relationship, you should have contacted more people and had more choices to ensure that the other person is the one you want. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After three or four relationships, even if everyone said that the next person was better, James had never met the so-called &quot;better person&quot; at all, but I always believed that moving forward It&#39;s not the right choice. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I used to think that letting go of the past was just three words - move forward. But I recently discovered that it is not. In fact, self-renewal is more important than moving forward. If you only carry your past self with you, no matter how far you go forward, you may encounter the same problems and the same knots as in the past, and you may even go back to where you started. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But to truly create a new world, you have to become a new self and truly renew yourself. Be aware of your own problems, the root knots that over and over again mess up your relationship. If a person always worries about gains and losses in relationships, he will only continue to &quot;go crazy&quot; in every relationship. Over time, it will be attributed to the fact that others do not love him and others are playing tricks on him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Of course James is excellent, but he has never made good use of his excellence in relationships. He has even forgotten that the fundamental reason why he attracts others is because of his sense of distance and his unfathomable heart. Once he is emotionally invested, it will be replaced by a kind of coercion, which will only scare more people away and make people who originally like him doubt. Is this the person I like? This is what he looked like. A good relationship must be based on emotional stability. If you are always suspicious in a relationship, it means that your self-confidence has never been established. No one likes people who are not confident. If you are not afraid that the other person will run away, the other person will. You won&#39;t run away. Once you are afraid, the thing you fear will definitely happen. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Of course you need to fall in love more. I have never denied this point of view. Falling in love is the fastest way to discover your own shortcomings, but you must admit and correct this shortcoming, otherwise falling in love will be an ineffective exercise. . In love, you must insist on yourself, but the part you insist on must be a matter of principle, not your own mistakes. Being too stubborn about mistakes in a relationship will only make every relationship awkward. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;James said that it is very interesting that every time those people are separated, they always get back in touch with him after a period of time, as if they are back to the state when they first met him. Flirting, ambiguity, joking, and saying some specious things, but it is difficult for him to be emotionally invested anymore. I said, this is not normal. Feelings are always fluid. There is no 100% breakup, just like there is no 100% forever. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Do you know why when we were in school, the exercises in the test papers always appeared repeatedly from time to time, and the gap between high scores and low scores was widened by these recurring questions. Those smart students People who have been fooled once will not be fooled a second time, and those stupid students will always lose points on the same proposition. The same is true for relationships. The process of falling in love multiple times is like reviewing the same question over and over again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;About a year later, when I saw James again, he already had a new girlfriend. What was very different from the past was that he became more relaxed in the whole relationship. Even if his girlfriend is at another dinner party, he will not rush to ask her when it will end unless she sends a message asking him to pick her up. This change actually surprised me. When we were sitting at the bar and finishing the glass of wine, James said: &quot;It seems that it is really difficult to admit that you are excellent, but once you admit it, you will no longer panic others.&quot; &#39;s left. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;How many people have low self-esteem in relationships because they always think that the partner they get is beyond their expectations. But in fact, everyone is just an ordinary person. If you don’t know yourself Where is your excellence, and how can others fall in love with your excellence? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In love, of course we are all crazy. Otherwise, if everyone is sober, there will be no taste of love. But after all, love does not exist to make us crazy, but to make us more sober. of. After trying it again and again, the final result is that you got this exercise right and finally no longer lost points in the exam. But from another perspective, because you have practiced enough, you finally remembered this question. the correct answer. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Li Jialong&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see the @ONE studio pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FnG6mnVK6opY4g75Tw-7h415dwbd&quot; alt=&quot;zhouhongxiang&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;zhou hongxiang&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@zhouhongxiang&lt;/span>; &lt; /div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Young writer, representative works &quot;Famous Fair&quot; and &quot;They Are Burning&quot;&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot; OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6095&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Memory is often in vain&lt;/ div>; &lt;div>;Text/Zhou Hongxiang&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6079&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Breakup is a galloping return&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Written by Zhou Hongxiang&lt;/div>; &lt;/a >; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6123)&quot; >;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get More RSS: &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href =&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4021]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4160]]><description>&lt;div>;10 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FlN0ILBhLWzqzBM6BZ4rVGYBID9G&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;VOL.4021&lt;/span>;Photography | Annie Spratt&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;10&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oct. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Sad people Sad people, people facing difficulties in life, and people who are about to be depressed may not look strange from the outside, but there may be some cracks in their hearts. It’s just that people don’t crack on the surface. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot; color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 10 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>