<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[东亚小孩，你也有「娱乐羞耻」吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3955]]><description> &lt;div>;27 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Have you eaten rice dumplings on Christmas?&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>;East Asian children, do you also have &quot;entertainment shame&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Pancake Orange Answer&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data- original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FnFTJzF11FlochGcPjaAZ0BRexza&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FnFTJzF11FlochGcPjaAZ0BRexza&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The weekend was over again in the blink of an eye Passed by, I slept for a day and didn&#39;t do any &quot;business&quot;. A strong sense of &quot;shame&quot; came to my heart, and I regretted that my day had been &quot;wasted&quot; again. I wonder if you have this strong sense of &quot;entertainment shame&quot;? It seems that only time spent on learning, improving oneself and creating value, these so-called &quot;business things&quot;, is correct. Otherwise, time is wasted. Purely pleasing yourself and loving yourself is a very &quot;shameful&quot; thing. ; thing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So, why do children from East Asian families have this sense of &quot;entertainment shame&quot;? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;1. People are products of the environment, and in East Asian cultural circles, &quot;diligence&quot; is regarded as A virtue&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The four East Asian countries, China, Japan and South Korea, are all in the Confucian cultural circle. Since ancient times, Confucians have regarded &quot;diligence&quot; as a moral standard. This concept It has deeply influenced generations of people, and even the ability to &quot;endure hardship&quot; has evolved into a virtue. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At home, I believe that every child in a Chinese family has heard their elders praise their children&#39;s &quot;hard-working&quot; spirit. Especially in rural areas, if a family marries a hard-working daughter-in-law, the pride of the mother-in-law can permeate the entire village. And this diligent daughter-in-law will also become someone else’s child in the eyes of the mothers in the whole village. Once their own daughter fails to do something well, she will be nagged and said: Look at how hard-working that daughter is. Look at yourself again, who dares to want you, and whose mother-in-law can stand a lazy daughter-in-law like you. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In school, those who seize all the time to study hard will always be loved and praised by teachers in various subjects. There are countless examples of hard study in the textbooks, such as Kuang Heng chiseling a wall to borrow light, Sun Jing&#39;s cantilevered beam with a sharp cone, Zu Ti hearing the chicken dance, etc. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After entering the society, the leader of my first job said something to me. She said: &quot;No one hates hard-working people.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Growing up in this cultural environment, even if the influence of Confucian culture gradually fades, the word &quot;diligence&quot; has been engraved in our genes, reminding us all the time that laziness is shameful. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2. Collectivist values ​​emphasize collective responsibility and contribution spirit. People do not live for themselves&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;Under collectivist values, individuals are often ignored, and we don’t seem to have learned how to love ourselves. &lt;strong>;We have been taught since childhood that we should be proud of our collective contribution. Our happiness and sense of accomplishment almost all come from the value we can provide to the collective; loving ourselves and living for ourselves is almost equated with selfishness. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I am a child born in a rural area. After working hard in the city for many years, I can barely get a foothold. I have also longed for the fact that through my own efforts, I can give my family a better life, but the truth of life is often cruel. My efforts can only make myself feel better, but cannot help my family at all. Therefore, my current state is very contradictory. I can neither win nor lie flat. On the one hand, I can’t help but stop wasting time and enjoy life by watching dramas or playing games after work. On the other hand, I can’t help but feel selfish and ashamed of these entertainments. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;3. Seeing the truth of culture clearly, but unable to break the confinement of culture on oneself&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>; Negative freedom refers to the freedom from external restrictions or obstacles, the freedom not to let others hinder me; positive freedom means being my own master, and my life and the decisions I make depend on myself. &lt;/strong>;The era we live in today has given us a lot of freedom. We have seen the limitations of the previous generation, and we have also seen the truth of culture. We understand that there can be many standards of happiness, and excellence and success are not the only standards. However, many people only enjoy &quot;negative freedom&quot; and cannot escape the restrictions placed on them by the values ​​of those around them. Few people have the courage to ignore the opinions of those around them, to pursue what they truly want, and to fully enjoy positive freedom. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;We are like being locked in an unlocked cage, desperately complaining about our pain and complaining about being trapped. The unlocked cell door was clearly right in front of him, but he never opened it. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Zhou Ziheng onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see @ONE Studio’s pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FqErzI2FNOMKZnFPem8cy5LaXQI1 &quot; alt=&quot;Pancake Orange&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Pancake Orange&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot; >;Read well, don’t ask for deep understanding&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td >; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt;/td >; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3949&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;How to develop a hobby into a side job? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3955)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[人啊人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6142]]><description> &lt;div>;27 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Wu Zhongquan&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FocjyRYn26MDLpGZYPbMmdlayJyw&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FocjyRYn26MDLpGZYPbMmdlayJyw&quot;>;&lt;/div >;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The ups and downs of one’s life experience, fate plays a trick on people. Ordinary people are powerless to reverse this unsolvable fate. Only by relying on each other can they live without distractions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Liu Xiaodong and I haven’t seen each other for several years. We are good friends. When we used to work together, we drank all day long. That’s how men are. When you drink too much, your feelings come out. Although the relationship has not been maintained much in recent years, it is fortunately strong and we don&#39;t feel strange when we meet again. We still go into a small shop and drink. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He has not looked older in the past few years. After a man reaches the age of thirty, time will hover on the body for a period of time, and then suddenly plummet towards aging. Fortunately, we are all still in this suspended state, waiting fearlessly for the weightlessness of time to arrive. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We drank from noon to dusk when his cell phone rang. It was a video showing his daughter’s face. The daughter was seven years old and had just entered elementary school. She asked when her father would be back? Behind her is half of her wife&#39;s face, saying drink less and don&#39;t drink too much. Liu Xiaodong said don&#39;t worry, you won&#39;t drink much. The phone was hung up neatly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I say call your wife and children together, and they will feel relieved if we eat together. He said no, and added that my wife is pregnant and has a severe reaction. She will vomit if she eats outside. I was quite surprised, why did I suddenly have a second child? He said it was nothing, she just wanted to get pregnant. I said it was fine, fine, but actually I had doubts in my heart. After he gave birth to his daughter, I saw how much he liked children, so I asked him if he wanted to have another child, and he said no. I asked why you are so determined? He doesn&#39;t say. Another mutual friend of ours said behind our back, why else? The marriage is unstable. They might divorce one day. Have you forgotten how they got together? I nodded, understanding. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before Liu Xiaodong was 27 or 28 years old, he dated several girlfriends, all with the intention of getting married, but none of them succeeded. In fact, he looks pretty good, and he works pretty well in our county, but he is too boring and doesn&#39;t like to talk. But the girlfriends he did have were all too hot-tempered. , leading to various endings. Some cuckolded him; some were wrestling practitioners and would throw him on the back when they got angry; and some who didn&#39;t like him would take him to a bar and find someone to beat him up. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When another friend of ours saw that this was not going to work, he introduced his current wife to him. She was working as a cashier in a supermarket at the time. She was quite shy and spoke softly. Once they met, they got along well, and Liu Xiaodong was able to talk more, and they quickly developed into a romantic relationship. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As soon as she falls in love, a girl’s desire for control comes out. She hopes that Liu Xiaodong will be obedient to her. Liu Xiaodong has a stubborn temper. It is okay for me to treat you well, but it is impossible to be obedient. The two of them frequently quarreled over trivial matters shrouded in &quot;obedience and obedience.&quot; Girls are also soft-spoken when quarreling, but they like to get physical. When they are in a hurry, they will reach out and scratch someone, until their face is bloody. Liu Xiaodong was annoyed by the tickling and couldn&#39;t bear it anymore, so he slapped her back, and the two often fought with each other. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I forgot some reason during that time. In my hometown, we had to have a drinking party every day. We would often send the two of them off properly after the night before, and they would come back the next day with the same face. There were bloodstains all over the face, and the other half of the face was swollen. Everyone looked worried, but they all asked, &quot;How can this be fixed?&quot; You can&#39;t scratch someone&#39;s face, right? No matter what, you can&#39;t slap me! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two of them just laughed, maybe feeling embarrassed, or maybe they didn’t care, and didn’t discuss the topic. Then they drank too much at the dinner, and started fighting again when they got back. The cycle went on and on, with Mobiu. It looks like a ring, and I don’t know what it is about. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Until one night in the middle of the night, the girl disappeared. Several of our friends were called out to help look for her. They said there had just been a fight on the street and she disappeared in the blink of an eye. So we shouted as hard as we could on the quiet streets of the county town, sweeping up street after street like a pack of wolves. Later, we called out the police, who thought we were drunk and causing trouble. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After learning the details, the police advised us not to look for her. We had seen this kind of thing a lot. The girl must have hidden it deliberately so that her boyfriend would not find her. She would be fine. But we persisted for a few more streets, and finally found the person in the green belt on the roadside. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Seeing that she couldn’t hide it anymore, she patted her clothes and got out, saying softly, I see you have been walking back and forth here several times. Liu Xiaodong was so angry that he said, &quot;Why don&#39;t you come out?&quot; Aren&#39;t you just torturing people? What would you do if something happened to you? When the girl saw that Liu Xiaodong was really anxious, she cried. She stepped forward and hugged him, saying that I just want to see you anxious and that you care about me! Then the two hugged and cried on the street. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The rest of us didn’t know if we should leave for a moment, so we just stood there and watched with gusto, thinking that this looked like true love, and we couldn’t separate even if we fight, so let’s get married happily. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Marriage is conditional. The girl proposed to buy a house in the county, and only her name would be written on the birth certificate. Liu Xiaodong&#39;s family agreed. His parents lived in the countryside and had worked hard for half their lives. They had also saved some money. The square footage of the house should not be too big. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The girl also proposed that in addition to the house, she also wanted 100,000 yuan to cross the river. The so-called cross-river money means that this money can only be given to her and is not used for her family. It can only be used when she encounters a river that she cannot cross in her own life. Liu Xiaodong&#39;s parents were anxious to get their son married, and considered the money to be a betrothal gift. Liu Xiaodong had saved tens of thousands of yuan from working over the years, and it would be enough for his parents to find relatives to chip in. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The girl made the last request, that all the land of Liu Xiaodong’s family should belong to her. This request was too much. All of Liu Xiaodong&#39;s parents&#39; livelihood depended on those lands. To remove them would be to strangle them and starve them to death. Naturally, a hundred people disagreed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liu Xiaodong was also furious, saying that there is no one like you, so why are you? The girl still whispered softly and told me that this was all justified. When my brother got married, the woman wanted my house to be empty. I secretly swore at that time that I would also make the man&#39;s house empty when I got married in the future. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This logic is simply illogical. Although it is illogical, people just insist on it. Liu Xiaodong came to drink with us and talked about his bitterness and grievances. His friends advised him not to get married if it didn&#39;t work out. If you were scratched and she was slapped, you wouldn&#39;t suffer any loss. Let&#39;s find another family. Liu Xiaodong felt that this was the only way to go. During this period of drinking, people sobered up and regained some sense. The two of them didn&#39;t have much feelings for each other. What&#39;s more, the feelings created during the fight were a bit Stockholm, and outsiders couldn&#39;t see it. I understand, I feel awkward and uncomfortable too. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He went to break up with the girl, and the girl agreed after hesitating. They didn&#39;t hit anyone again, and the two of them even ate a pot of bridge-crossing rice noodles together. After they left the door, as soon as the breeze blew, they separated calmly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liu Xiaodong waited for a few days, and his friends began to introduce people to him again. His family seemed to be vindictive, arranging blind dates for several people in a row, and they dared to do anything wrong. , just anxious to get him to get married. He looked at a few, and one of them was quite good. He wanted to try Virgo, have a meal and drink some wine to see his character and so on. But before he could drink it, his ex-girlfriend called and said she was pregnant. Liu Xiaodong was confused. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The girl was also confused. She was pregnant for the first time. She didn’t know what to do and there was no one at home to discuss it. Only then did we learn that her parents had been divorced for many years. Her mother was in Harbin, her father was in Qitaihe, her brother was in Mudanjiang, and she was in Jiamusi. The family of four was scattered in four cities in Heilongjiang, each busy with its own business. Life is hard to take into account. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liu Xiaodong made an appointment with her to meet at a Malatang shop to discuss what to do about the matter. He thought about abortion, but it passed by in a flash, thinking it was a sin. Girls don’t dare to try the path of single motherhood. It’s hard to support yourself these days. Having one more child is like pushing your life into a dead end. Then get married. I had planned to get married before. If I needed a reason to get married, this time it would be more sufficient. But the conditions have to be negotiated separately. Because the girl is pregnant, her negotiating weight is much less. Liu Xiaodong has become the master, condescending, and whether he agrees with the conditions or not becomes a charity. Fortunately, he was not a bad person. In the end, he agreed to put two people&#39;s names on the house and not give her any money to cross the river, but all the money received from the wedding went to her. As for the land issue that was discussed before, the girl didn&#39;t mention a word. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I went to Liu Xiaodong’s wedding. It was held in a pretty hotel in our county. I loved to follow the fashion when it came to weddings, so I made the wedding process look like the popular Legend of Zhen Huan in those years. When Liu Xiaodong knelt down to serve tea to his father-in-law and mother-in-law, he mouthed off the emperor&#39;s mother-in-law. I was so embarrassed that I went to the bathroom to avoid this part. When they came back, they were already taking family photos. The girl&#39;s father, mother and brother were standing behind them, all restrained and smiling. Outsiders couldn&#39;t tell that this was a loose family, nor would they know that there was a murderer in it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After Liu Xiaodong got married, I went to Beijing. My life became busy and I had no time to chat. Soon his child was born, a daughter. When I asked him how he felt, he said he couldn&#39;t tell. Anyway, he was not lazy at all the work and was full of energy. I asked him how his relationship with his wife is now? Still fighting? He choked for a long time and said I wouldn&#39;t fight back. I could understand clearly and could feel the pain, so I comforted him in a cliche manner, saying that he would be fine in two years, but that he would be unable to fight as he got older. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then the days passed slowly. I didn’t go back to my hometown for a year or two, and I didn’t pay much attention to Liu Xiaodong’s current situation. Then one morning, he suddenly called me and asked me to borrow money in a panic. I asked what happened? He was vague at first and said what the package land was for. Later, I saw that I didn’t believe it, so I opened up and said that his father-in-law had killed someone, but not now, but more than 20 years ago. Now that he was arrested, he wanted to spend money to find connections to smooth things over. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was surprised and curious, how did you kill them? He said that several people fought and beat people to death. He spent some money to smoothen the relationship and they were considered private. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I asked again, why is the case from more than 20 years ago being uncovered now? He said he didn&#39;t know, so he asked me if I had any money to lend him. I said yes, and do you want it now or when? He said he would wait for the letter. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While waiting for the news, I learned from other friends the reason why the case was uncovered. The child of the man who was beaten to death has always been brooding over the affair and worked hard for many years. Now he finally became a small leader in the public security system, so he dug up the case and re-investigated it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is a very inspiring revenge story. From the perspective of an ideal society, my emotions are more willing to be projected on his side. But on the other side was my friend, Huang Ama, whom he called me over and over again. I didn’t want him to have a bad ending, and I didn’t know how to expect this to go. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But things will eventually go one way. More than a month later, I still waited for the news. Liu Xiaodong called and said that the money was no longer needed. I knew what the result was. After all, it is not the same as it was back then. Relationships are not as easy to clear as sewer pipes. It is not easy to use money to atone for sins. Small money is not easy to use. As a result, his father-in-law and several other people were sentenced, with prison terms ranging from seven to fifteen years. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I asked Liu Xiaodong, how does your wife feel about this matter? He said that she went to have her fortune told during the Chinese New Year. People said that she would suffer disaster in the next few years and asked her to find out. She didn&#39;t believe it at first, but now she finally believes it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I thought to myself, why is this all about metaphysics? This is not a disaster, this is an incident that happened in public, and you reap what you sow. But if you think about it carefully, if people can attribute their own unsatisfactory experiences to metaphysics and destiny, it would be a relief, so I didn’t say more. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two years later, I moved from Beijing to Shanghai, and then from Shanghai to Hangzhou. I was so busy with work that I didn’t even go back to my hometown to celebrate the New Year. I occasionally spent time with Liu Xiaodong. We chatted once or twice on WeChat, and drank wine once or twice on video during the Chinese New Year, but we didn’t chat too deeply. It seemed that the days couldn’t stand the depth of chatting, and the superficial things just passed by. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then late one night, I suddenly received his call again. My heart skipped a beat. Nowadays, when people are looking for someone, they are accustomed to saying &quot;Are you there&quot; on WeChat first? It&#39;s so direct. The phone call was probably not a good thing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the other end of the phone, he spoke with a straight tongue. It sounded like he had drunk too much. There was a lot of noise in the background. It felt like he was in a barbecue restaurant, and it didn&#39;t look like he was drinking alone. I was half relieved and jokingly asked, &quot;What are you doing so late at night?&quot; Did you drink too much and miss me? He didn&#39;t answer the question and asked directly, &quot;Are you my good friend?&quot; I said yes. What&#39;s up? He said yes then do me a favor. What did I say about being busy? He said don’t you write a book? Do you know any media, newspapers, etc., please report it to me. What did I say about reporting? What do you have worth reporting? He said that my old mother-in-law was killed. Is this enough? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was confused, just as confused as the last time I heard that his father-in-law was a murderer. If you reflexively hope it&#39;s false, just stop talking nonsense. He said no, really, he was stabbed to death at his home in Harbin, and he has been dead for half a month. I said who stabbed him to death? He said he was stabbed to death by a man, and the police said it was a murder of love. Did I say that person caught him? He said he didn&#39;t catch it, so he wanted you to find the media, report it, and put some pressure on the police. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I say your logic is correct, but how do you know that the police are not handling the case carefully? Have the police revealed to you at what stage of the investigation it has reached? He said he had revealed the truth and found out that the murderer had committed suicide by jumping into the Songhua River. Although the body had not been recovered, he wanted to close the case just like that. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He felt that the police must have taken advantage of the other party and wanted to close the case quickly. Several people who were drinking together behind him echoed, &quot;Definitely, it&#39;s not such a coincidence, maybe the police let him go.&quot; &quot;Yes, expose it and let the police know that we have people.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;If that doesn’t work, let’s go to Harbin together tomorrow and have a sit-in in front of the Public Security Bureau. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They started chatting away, seeming to have forgotten that I was still waiting on the other end of the phone. I listened to their discussion for almost three to five minutes, and no one paid any attention to me. Just hung up the phone. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I barely slept that night. First, the impact of this incident was too great. I didn’t want to think about it, but I just couldn’t get around it. Second, I really started looking through my address book and looking for friends who were engaged in the news media industry in the Northeast. I actually found a few. After asking about them, I found that they had already changed careers. News was not easy to do, and now they are engaged in social work. The insignificant career was gone, so I had another little emotion. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Early the next morning, as soon as I fell asleep, Liu Xiaodong called again. This time, it was the voice of someone who had woken up but was hungover. He said sorry, I drank too much yesterday, so you don’t have to worry about that. What did I say? Not ready to be exposed? What did he say about the exposure? The police evidence was quite conclusive. It was just that some of my friends drank too much and started messing around. It was fine. My mother-in-law was cremated a few days ago. I sighed and said that everything has happened to you. He was quite helpless and said that who knows what happened, maybe it was his life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I thought of his wife’s fortune telling when his father-in-law was imprisoned two years ago. At that time, I thought it was a kind of self-comfort. But now, on that sleepy morning, I was actually willing to believe it. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What is fate? It is the sum of the probabilities of everything. It is very similar to playing mahjong. One thought can stagger the entire game. But there are only four people on the mahjong table, but there are thousands of people in the world. Every thought is a killing knife. Fa, in the light and shadow of this sword, we have nowhere to hide, we can only kill each other. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Time returned to the wine table at the beginning, and the topic returned to the topic of the second child. I said that your relationship with your wife is quite stable now. chant? Does she still like to scratch you? Liu Xiaodong sneered and said, why are you scratching? I don’t even want to quarrel with her now. Did I say personality evolved? Or is it that the old monk who has entered samadhi will not be surprised by the favor or humiliation? He said what&#39;s the fuss about? She&#39;s so pitiful. One night last year, I couldn&#39;t help but quarreled with her. She packed her bags and ran away from home. I didn&#39;t chase her. I just drank beer at home. Half an hour later, she came back with her suitcase. I said angrily: What are you doing here? She stood at the door and cried loudly, saying that I realized that I had nowhere to go, and I didn’t even have a single family member left! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liu Xiaodong took a sip of wine and said that I only realized this after she said it. From then on, I never had a fight with her again. Something didn&#39;t sound right to me, why didn&#39;t she have any family members left? Doesn’t he have a brother in Mudanjiang? It&#39;s the one where the woman wants the house empty when she gets married. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liu Xiaodong’s face darkened and he said that he was gone and that brother was gone too. A dark cloud suddenly swept over my heart, so I didn&#39;t rush to ask him what happened. Liu Xiaodong also took his time before speaking again, saying that he had been to Shanghai once last year. I said I was in Hangzhou, so close, why didn’t you go find me? He said how could he be in the mood? I was going to deal with her brother&#39;s funeral. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her brother has not made much money in Mudanjiang in the past few years. He and his wife have also divorced, and he still owes some foreign debts. He had a friend who was delivering food in Shanghai. He heard that it was quite profitable during the epidemic, so he joined his friend. I bought a battery car there and started working as a delivery boy. It was indeed quite profitable, earning more than 10,000 yuan a month. But within a few months, something happened. He and his friend shared a house. The friend&#39;s battery cart was being charged in the house, and a fire broke out in the middle of the night. All four people in the house, including him, were burned to death. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liu Xiaodong and his wife rushed to Shanghai after receiving the news. When they arrived at the hospital, he was still alive, with 90% of his body burned, and he was dying in one breath. The doctor talked to the two of them and said that the current situation was irreversible and that people would suffer if they were so close to each other. He could sign a consent form to give up treatment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;How can he sign this? Just now in the ward, his eyes could still recognize people, and he felt relieved to see his relatives. The two hugged each other and cried. How could such a tragic thing happen in this world? Why did such a tragic thing happen to them? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two of them did not sign, but they still left two days later. After finishing the funeral arrangements, they returned to their hometown with a box of ashes in their hands. All the compensation received was remitted to her brother&#39;s ex-wife. After all, she still had a child to raise, and that was also a bloodline. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After Liu Xiaodong said this, I didn’t say a word. I felt uncomfortable in my heart and my tears fell uncontrollably. When Liu Xiaodong saw me crying, he cried too. In the afternoon in that small northeastern county, the more we cried, the sadder we became. In the end, we didn’t seem to know who we were crying for. Those tears may also contain a lot of our own grievances. We have suppressed too many tragedies in our middle age. , released by the strength of wine, but also full of shyness, not daring to let anyone see it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Life is always like this, making people live but not crying. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That evening, when Liu Xiaodong and I left the small restaurant, we were sober from the wine. I wanted to rush to the next game, but he didn&#39;t go, saying that he would stay at home to take care of the children in the evening. I said, isn&#39;t your wife at home? He said today was the weekend and she was going to church with my mother. Liu Xiaodong’s mother has been a believer for many years. I know this, but when did her wife also believe in it? Liu Xiaodong said that he had just believed in it not long ago, so he went to church frequently. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He didn’t say anything more, hailed a taxi on the side of the road, and disappeared into the late summer dusk. I stood there and watched, imagining her wife praying devoutly. Maybe this is also a good destination for the soul. In the past few years, so many things have happened. I have long been helpless about my fate. I no longer believe in anything. I can only believe in God. I believe that there is a big hand that arranges and combines everything in the world. My luck and misfortune are all determined by it. If you can&#39;t control it, it&#39;s not your fault. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Perhaps she can also understand that everything has its time, and we will all say goodbye to all our loved ones in the end, but time is out of control, and it has accelerated for her in the past few years. I remembered that when she and Liu Xiaodong first got together, those days were full of farce. No one would be optimistic about their love and marriage, but the two of them stumbled to where they are now. What is love? Is it pure in nature? Or is it just the integration of various conditions. Beauty is a condition, material is a condition, timing is a condition, and so is sympathy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Until fate makes each other the only one to rely on, we will stop fighting, robbing, and making trouble. We will suppress our desires and tempers and live happily in the future. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The rest are just distractions in life. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Li Jialong&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see @ONE Studio’s pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FuesooEpr13-iy8Yt-6-tZtu9dZD&quot; alt=&quot;Wu Zhongquan&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Wu Zhongquan&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@ Wu Zhongquan&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Writer/Screenwriter&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2 , )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6127&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;I met 100 million trees&lt;/ div>; &lt;div>;Written by Wu Zhongquan&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td >; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6100&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;The swaying world&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Wu Zhongquan&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Read&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6085&quot; data-ajax= &quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Look there is light in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Wu Zhongquan&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6142)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4038]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4182]]><description>&lt;div>;27 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fg5-sEg0U8-_t9Eup4ACWMOKl0tH&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4038&lt;/span>;Photography | David Libeert&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;27&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oct. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p >;If life closes your door, then you open it again. This is the door. This is how doors are used. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>