<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[年轻人真的“变娇气”了吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3943]]><description> &lt;div>;14 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Fearless Questions&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt; p>;Are the older generations right? Have young people really become &quot;squeamish&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Rabbit grass answer&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpuIGM64xmGYMO4rPMQvNEYXaJJa&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpuIGM64xmGYMO4rPMQvNEYXaJJa&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;In the blood of our fathers, there is a cultural gene called &quot;enduring hardship&quot;. Take my parents as an example. They were born in the 1960s and experienced natural disasters when they were young. If there are many brothers and sisters in the family, eating meat may become a luxury. &lt;strong>;In those times of scarcity, they had to minimize their needs and desires in order to survive. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Because they have experienced hardship, they have become more tolerant. It is precisely because of this that they will look down upon young people who grew up in an era of material abundance. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I can understand the thinking and opinions of the older generation, but understanding does not mean that I have to accept everything they say. &lt;strong>;And their comment about young people &quot;becoming squeamish&quot; is more like a way to vent their anger at the difficult years they have experienced, a kind of secret jealousy&lt;/strong>;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ldquo;Why have I eaten it? Are you unwilling to endure the hardship? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Having said that, have today&#39;s young people really become &quot;squeamish&quot; as the older generation said? In fact, no, the &quot;squeamishness&quot; of young people is more like a helplessness in the face of the squeeze of life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;1. It’s not that young people have become more “squeamish”, but that the workplace environment has become worse&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;My parents were both workers when they were young. The factory was quite punctual when leaving work, and there were corresponding canteens and kindergarten facilities. In fact, they don&#39;t have much idea about working overtime. However, when I started working, 996 and 007 became commonplace, the work intensity became more and more intense, and the working hours became longer and longer. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sometimes they don’t understand why I work overtime all day long, because they have never experienced overtime work, and they don’t know how hard it is to be forced to work more than eight hours. Sometimes, if I occasionally complain, they will think that I am &quot;not dedicated enough.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The intensity of workplace work faced by contemporary young people is actually something that the older generation has never experienced. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2. The new generation of young people are more pursuing self-development and are unwilling to suppress their own nature&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What to say I think the biggest difference between the older generation and young people is their view of &quot;self&quot;. &lt;strong>;Young people are more concerned about freedom and hope to live a valuable life, while the older generation feels that food and clothing are enough. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the minds of the older generation, eating enough to fill their stomachs is enough, but young people always want more spiritual things. Sometimes the awareness gap between the two parties is caused by the times. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the reform and opening up, China has experienced rapid economic rise and rapid development. Young people who grew up in a period of material prosperity no longer regard &quot;food and clothing&quot; as their primary pursuit. They want to experience more. Interesting life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I often hear some older leaders in the company say that young people cannot endure hardships and are too squeamish. However, if you think about it, &lt;strong>;isn’t it the progress of the times that you are not willing to &quot;submit it&quot;? Why can&#39;t you just say &quot;no&quot;? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;3. There is no need to &quot;remember hardships&quot;, young people have become more selective&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In fact, compared to the older generation, today’s young people have more choices in life. Although young people always complain that their lives are too hard, in fact, compared to the previous generation, everyone I already have a lot more choices in life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;It is also material abundance that enables young people to choose better things instead of having to endure what they don’t like. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Whether a person will be &quot;squeamish&quot; sometimes depends on the living environment. As the saying goes, it is easy to go from frugality to luxury, but it is difficult to go from luxury to frugality. Young people who grow up in a good economic environment naturally have a broader vision and are less willing to treat themselves badly, so they have quality requirements and pursuits for life. It&#39;s all understandable. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So, don’t the older generation have any advantages worth learning from? Not really. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My impression from my interactions with my parents in the past few years is that they have more &lt;strong>;&amp;ldquo;blunt sensitivity&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>; than me. This is reflected in their ability to adapt to various environments and their ability to enjoy hardships. From a certain level, they are indeed less &quot;squeamish&quot; and have more wisdom in life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sometimes, I think that instead of arguing with the older generation about whether young people are &quot;squeamish&quot;, it is better to turn conflicts into friendship. We can take the older generation to experience the beautiful scenery, food or items they never experienced when they were young, and we young people can also learn their skills in daily life, such as cooking and housework. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In short, we don’t have to be ashamed of the word &quot;squeamish&quot;. Sometimes, &lt;strong>;being able to live a more dignified life is a gift of economic development to young people. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Zhou Ziheng onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see @ONE Studio’s pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmIxumvucSMThvBqzjla4dEmFbwL &quot; alt=&quot;Rabbit Grass&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Rabbit Grass&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@Rabbit Grass Tucao&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style =&quot;&quot;>;Retired copywriter, juggling writer. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Question and Answer&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/question/3922&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Life is not bad, but where does the pressure come from? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3943)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 06:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[胜利之夜]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6126]]><description>&lt;div>;14 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Zhao Chunxiang&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt; img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fmi7f59zbWLZrm4zIyFlgkcYng3d&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fmi7f59zbWLZrm4zIyFlgkcYng3d&quot;>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Highly stylized writing techniques, as violent and fanatical as &quot;Pulp Fiction&quot; , a filmmaker who commits crimes for the sake of the script, a story wrapped in a rich cult film temperament, and understands what madness is on the verge of suffocation. &lt;br>;Some of the content in this article is quite intense, please read it as appropriate. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of Hu Xiaojun’s thirty-second birthday, his boss from seven years ago came to visit the studio. He led his senior all the way from the elevator to his office and arranged him on a soft sofa, giving him tea, coffee and sparkling water of his choice. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;It is an honor for you to come and see me. &amp;rdquo;Hu Xiaojun sat back at his desk and spoke. But as soon as he finished speaking, he felt that he shouldn&#39;t sit so far away from his senior and look so superior, so he stood up and prepared to sit next to his senior. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Xuelin immediately made a parking gesture like a traffic policeman and said, &quot;You don&#39;t have to work!&quot; You just sit there. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;How can this be done? If you want to sit, you should sit here! &quot;Hu Xiaojun said, but his legs did not move any further. He hesitated in place, looking quite cramped. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Just sit there and relax! Sit down! ” Zhang Xuelin seemed unconcerned and generous. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hu Xiaojun remembered how Zhang Xuelin used to teach him a lesson behind the desk, slapping the desk and tearing up documents, blushing and trembling, always insulting himself as the most pitiable guy in the company. Now, only seven years have passed, and their bodies have been swapped. This makes him feel like he is still in a dream, which is extremely unnatural. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Xiaojun, I came to you this time because I must have something to ask for. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What the hell! &quot;Hu Xiaojun just sat down, then stood up excitedly and said, &quot;As long as I can help, I will do my best. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Xuelin took a sip of the sparkling water brought by the administrative girl and nodded to express his gratitude. As soon as the administrative girl closed the door, he said, &quot;I wrote a script.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Oh? &quot;Hu Xiaojun stood up with his senior, without any sign of neglect. Whether it was his pretended interest or the sense of smell that he should have as a practitioner, he focused on his emotions and asked, &quot;As a person in the industry, A senior script consultant who has not written a script for ten years and has been in seclusion for more than five years. Today he comes up with a script that will probably shock the whole world! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Xuelin didn&#39;t bother him. He turned around and rummaged in his briefcase for a while, took out a large pile of white paper and said, &quot;This is it.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hu Xiaojun stretched out his hand, but saw Zhang Xuelin stuffing the script back into his briefcase. He didn&#39;t know where to put his hands for a moment. I only heard Zhang Xuelin say, &quot;Stop reading.&quot; Between us, we are colleagues. In terms of judgment, if it’s not available, it can’t be photographed, and it’s hard for you to speak. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hu Xiaojun immediately felt relieved and marveled at the senior&#39;s meticulous thinking and broad mind. He just put down his hand and walked out of the desk, thinking about how to praise this, when he saw Zhang Xuelin zipping up his briefcase, walking towards him, showing a strange expression, and said to him, &quot;Look, I don&#39;t I let you see it, but you really didn’t bother to see it. Well, no one would be interested in a script I wrote! Everyone rejected me and thought I was just a bad producer who could only make plays but couldn&#39;t write scripts. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hu Xiaojun stared at Zhang Xuelin&#39;s face and saw that the face was illuminated by the overhead light. The grease from a sleepless night flowed across his cheekbones, and the bloodshot eyeballs revealed a faint musty look. texture. He was so frightened that he took half a step back and explained, &quot;You just said...&quot; Zhang Xuelin interrupted him and said, &quot;No need!&quot; You don&#39;t have to look. You can&#39;t fake interest. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hu Xiaojun suddenly felt that there was a little daughter-in-law in the heart of his senior who had not had her legs broken for three years. At the same time, he smelled a stinky smell and couldn&#39;t help but lower his head and pretend to be Rubbing his nose, he casually looked at Zhang Xuelin&#39;s shoes and socks from below. Only then did he realize that they were a pair of rotten shoes that were as thin as wontons. I&#39;m afraid that was the source of the stink. He quickly raised his head and heard Zhang Xuelin say, &quot;Introduce me to a producer. My request is that he has a strong and heartfelt desire for a truly excellent script.&quot; He was fed up with the torture of aesthetic famine in the boring and disgusting film market, and desperately needed the emergence of a great genius to save his dry soul. and! The most important thing is that he has enough connections to actually get the script off the ground and make it into a movie. Is there such a person around you? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Yes! &quot;Hu Xiaojun swallowed a gulp, suppressing the pungent stench and quickly added, &quot;Senior, you don&#39;t have to tell me about you! You still call me Xiao Hu, please don’t do this. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;No matter what the reason was, the first thing he thought of was Wang Hao, the famous man who broke a screenwriter&#39;s leg and was sentenced to one year in prison. Pure industry legend. Graduated from Repin Academy of Fine Arts, with extremely picky eyes. Rumor has it that Wang Hao is rich in resources, has an impulsive personality, and is lawless, all because he has a stepfather who is the CEO of a company listed on the Nasdaq media sector. He himself has no worries about food and clothing, and drives a Tesla top-end sedan. As a producer, he brought out two pioneering directors in the country and won many awards at Cannes. It was just released last year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Who is it? Do I recognize him? ” Zhang Xuelin said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You probably don’t know that you have been in seclusion for so many years, but he only emerged in the past two years. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Where is he now? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;In Beijing. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Does the character meet the conditions I mentioned? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Senior, among the people I know, he is the only one who can come close to what you said. &quot;Hu Xiaojun said, &quot;If it is 100% consistent with what you said, I have limited dealings with such a person, so I really can&#39;t think of it! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;In this way, you buy me a plane ticket and I will go find him. Return it to you later. &quot;Zhang Xuelin walked back to his seat, drank the sparkling water in one breath, then held his stomach and rubbed it for a while, and burped loudly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hu Xiaojun agreed wholeheartedly and started using his mobile phone to buy tickets for his seniors. Afterwards, he respectfully led his seniors to visit the company&#39;s new media area and material operation area. However, no matter where he went, Zhang Xuelin had a gloomy and melancholy expression on his face, looking at the workstation where short films were being made. The young people in the video look like American soldiers paying close attention to a group of refugees from Hiroshima. Finally, Hu Xiaojun and Zhang Xuelin broke up in front of the elevator. As soon as the elevator door closed, the smile on Hu Xiaojun&#39;s face immediately dissipated. He walked quickly to the office with a stern face, sniffed hard with his nose, and shouted, &quot; Xiao Zhang, hurry up, call Auntie over and clean the whole thing! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hu Xiaojun moved out of the office with his computer and sat at a temporary workstation, looking anxious. Until his aunt walked into the office carrying a set of cleaning tools, he did not forget to give instructions from behind. He said, &quot;Wipe the entire sofa and vacuum the carpet!&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the evening, Hu Xiaojun told his date about the matter and ended with &quot;Something big is going to happen in the motherland.&quot; The date was a college student with long hair and deep cleavage. The kid asked Hu Xiaojun, &quot;Is there going to be a good movie like &quot;Farewell My Concubine&quot;?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hu Xiaojun smiled and said, &amp;ldquo;Wrong. What&#39;s this called? It&#39;s called a tiger meeting an African lion, and two hundred and fifty have a good bite. &amp;rdquo;As he said this, the corners of his mouth turned up, and he broke off a toothpick with one hand. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The female college student could not understand what Hu Xiaojun was saying. She only thought that his profile looked like Matthew McConaughey, and he was full of riddles and very charming. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the evening of November 9, Zhang Xuelin rushed downstairs to Wang Hao’s house wearing the same set of clothes. Wang Hao hung up the phone with Hu Xiaojun impatiently, wore a set of pink pajamas, and went downstairs to greet him. The two shook hands downstairs. Seventeen minutes later, Wang Hao was so angry at the smell of Zhang Xuelin&#39;s feet that the two had a big fight. After another four minutes, Zhang Xuelin said, &quot;You are a sincere person, a person worthy of everyone&#39;s respect, and that screenwriter should not just have his leg broken, he should simply die.&quot; &quot;After that, he immediately set off to Wang Hao&#39;s bathroom, holding a basin, getting water to wash his feet. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At seven o&#39;clock in the evening, Wang Hao came into the room with a script. His long hair reached his shoulders, and his disheveled punk look made Zhang Xuelin extremely excited. Wang Hao asked him to wait at the door and not to follow him in. Zhang Xuelin took a last look at Wang Hao&#39;s bedroom through the crack in the door: stewardess uniform, Beatles album poster, pink tape, golf clubs, six-pointed star carpet, and a picture hanging on the wall. Row big whip. To him, all this outlines the typical demeanor of a super art master. At that time, he thanked his former outstanding subordinate Mr. Hu Xiaojun from the bottom of his heart, and turned around and returned to the living room with a pair of fragrant feet to start waiting. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Xuelin&#39;s eyes kept jumping between the clock, the TV, the fish tank, Wang Hao&#39;s bedroom door, and his own feet. Compared to the crazy furnishings in the bedroom, the living room was too plainly decorated, like a place specially used to receive nuns. He was so bored that, in fact, the seconds seemed like years and he had to start struggling back and forth on the sofa, sometimes leaning on his arms, sometimes on the cushions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At around nine o&#39;clock, he began to suspect that Wang Hao was asleep inside. Once this thought came up, it would uncontrollably torture him in every possible way, so he walked over and knocked on the door, and immediately listened. To the wild roar inside, &quot;Don&#39;t--make--any--any--sound.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Xuelin jumped back to the sofa like a child who got candy, feeling a hundred relieved. He murmured in a low voice, &quot;You can&#39;t find anything even if you wear iron shoes, and it takes no effort to get there.&quot; It&#39;s called fucking professional. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the two hours from nine to eleven, Zhang Xuelin switched more than fifty channels, watched the beginnings of more than a dozen new movies, and recited more than a dozen &quot; &quot;Garbage&quot;. Eventually, he began feeding the fish without consent, going to the kitchen, and eating yogurt and leftovers from the refrigerator. I even went to the floor-length mirror and looked in the mirror for twenty minutes. He posed in various ways in front of the mirror, but did not take pictures, simply admiring his own appearance. He felt that he looked almost the same as he did when he was twenty, except that he had a few more beards, a few pieces of hair missing, and his hairline moved back ten centimeters, making him close to baldness. No, he is actually completely bald, but bald people can generally tell that they are dense and prosperous from the few scattered fine hairs on their heads. He felt that his masculine charm had reached the peak of his life. At this time, &quot;What woman doesn&#39;t love?&quot; &quot;The praise he received was finally brought intact from Shanghai to Beijing. &quot;It&#39;s just that the movie hasn&#39;t been released yet, so it&#39;s hard for them to understand me.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Suddenly, the sound of the door lock turning came from the direction of the bedroom. Wang Hao frowned and glared at Zhang Xuelin. He walked to the water dispenser and drank a few glasses of water. He looked at the goldfish and then smiled slightly. He shook his head, pursed his lips, and sat back on the sofa. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Xuelin stared at Wang Hao&#39;s mouth. The moment Wang Hao&#39;s mouth moved a few microns, Zhang Xuelin pulled his vocal cords and shouted, &quot;Stop!&quot; Let me guess, you let me guess! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What are you shouting! Wang Hao&#39;s eyes widened and he cursed, &quot;Let&#39;s talk about things, don&#39;t be like a fucking lunatic!&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Just tell me directly! Polanski, Kubrick, are these two worthy of using my script? &quot;Zhang Xuelin&#39;s face was almost close to Wang Hao&#39;s face. He hooked one leg next to Wang Hao and kicked the other leg on the carpet. His whole body looked like a large shepherd dog crawling diagonally. Wang Hao wrinkled his eyebrows and was about to speak when another sound interrupted him, because Zhang Xuelin suddenly changed the question and shouted, &quot;No!&quot; Just say, OK! Still not good! ? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Hao turned his eyes to the sky, frustrated that his ears were irritated by the bombardment, turned to look at Zhang Xuelin, and almost collided with his lips, he quickly lay back and took a big shot He touched the sofa and said, &quot;Complete garbage!&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What! ? &quot;Zhang Xuelin stared into Wang Hao&#39;s eyes and said with a hot expression, &quot;Are you talking about the Chinese film industry? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What the hell is this movie industry? I said your script, your script! Complete rubbish! ”Wang Hao repeated. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Xuelin suddenly turned from fear to smile. His smile was like a three-year-old child, tilting his head, so cute. His teeth were all exposed, and his nose was wrinkled by the smile. He said in an extremely frightening and delicate tone, &quot;This is impossible!&quot; You must point out to me which sentence or line is rubbish... Even gods don&#39;t know why a forty-seven-year-old screenwriter suddenly uses a child&#39;s coquettish tone. say. This made Wang Hao feel uncomfortable and yelled, &quot;Writing a script is not shopping for groceries!&quot; What kind of rubbish words and lines did I tell you? The words are all Chinese characters, and there are no garbage sentences. The script is a great assembly. The article you assembled is garbage, and the whole article as a whole is pure garbage! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;How could that happen? Nothing eye-catching? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Hao lay down relaxedly, took a deep breath, and stared at the ceiling. &quot;The scene with a few kids on the side of the road is worth filming.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;That scene is not the point! Just a cutscene. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Except for this cutscene, everything else is garbage! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Xuelin stood up and walked towards the bedroom, muttering, &quot;Impossible, impossible. Did you print out other versions?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Hao stopped him from behind, &quot;Don&#39;t fucking enter my bedroom!&quot; ” He quickly put the cigarette case and lighter he had just picked up back on the table, got up and walked quickly towards the bedroom, rushing to the door of the bedroom in three steps at a time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Xuelin suddenly appeared at the door holding a golf club, laughed loudly, and swung it at Wang Hao more than twenty times. Wang Hao first felt that the world was spinning, and his skull was bubbling. Then he felt that his knuckles were cracked, and his eyes suddenly became dark. He was lying on the ground and what he saw was Zhang Xuelin&#39;s big foot stepping on his nose. Zhang Xuelin stepped on him, fixed his numb head, rounded the club in a golfing posture, and hit his temple hard. After a sound of turning off the TV and a moment of flash, Wang Hao completely lost consciousness. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Hao woke up at about two o&#39;clock in the morning. He was woken up by the fishy smell of the fish tank water that had been poured on him at an unknown time. After waking up, he felt that he could not speak for the first time. He looked down and saw Zhang Xuelin&#39;s socks and his own underwear stuffed in his mouth. The stench stimulated the saliva crazily, and the saliva was already flowing all over the floor. As for himself, he was tied to a chair, his feet were fixed to the legs of the stool with pink tape, his hands were handcuffed with sexy rubber handcuffs from behind, and his whole arm was wrapped with pink tape on the back of the chair, covering at least a few Ten circles, airtight. The pajamas on his upper body were stripped off, and the pajamas were now on Zhang Xuelin. Zhang Xuelin was shaving in the bathroom with his back to him, enjoying his own high-grade shaving foam. He tried to struggle twice, but was afraid to make a sound. His eyes were now as big as those of an ox, and except for his neck, there was no feeling anywhere. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He turned around and looked around. There was no sign of damage to the furniture, but the bedroom door was wide open. At a glance, he knew that a lot of things were missing inside. He quickly turned around and found these things on the coffee table on the right. From left to right, they were a stewardess hat, a big silicone stick, a fascial gun, three types of leather whips, a riding crop, and a small golf ball. ball. Wang Hao was startled by the neat arrangement of these things, and he shouted uncontrollably, which turned into a long &quot;woo&quot; through Zhang Xuelin&#39;s socks. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Xuelin turned his head and glanced at each other. The two looked at each other. One was as frightened as a refugee, and the other was as leisurely as a landlord. Mr. Landlord finished shaving slowly and leisurely. He picked up the small bottles on the bathroom counter one by one, twisted his fingers to check the ingredient list and product name. When he found the one he liked, he unscrewed the cap of the small bottle and applied it to his face. Afterwards, he came over with a scent all over his body and squatted in front of the stool where Wang Hao was tied. &quot;Oops,&quot; he said, looking in the direction of the coffee table. His eyes just drifted like this, and he heard Wang Hao let out another long &quot;woo&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Xuelin was calculating some logic in his mind like he was picking a general, his fingers were shaking back and forth on different things, and Wang Hao carefully observed all his details, including the plausive mantras in his lips. Read the words. He really didn&#39;t know what he should expect his fingers to land on. After a few seconds, his pupils dilated and he &quot;whimpered&quot; loudly and quickly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That&#39;s because Zhang Xuelin came over with the small golf ball, weighed it up and down in his hands, and said, &quot;This is not easy to handle. It was so difficult from the beginning.&quot; God&#39;s will is unpredictable...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Hao continued to make &quot;wuwu&quot; sounds from his mouth, which were long and short, as if he was talking. However, Zhang Xuelin didn&#39;t care, walked around behind Wang Hao, and made a louder and longer &quot;woo woo&quot; sound. Zhang Xuelin pulled off Wang Hao&#39;s pants, spent a full twenty minutes of effort, and listened to a full twenty minutes of heart-wrenching &quot;woo woo&quot; before he found a good place for the golf ball. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Xuelin washed his hands, turned back, and shook off the water on his hands. Wang Hao&#39;s nose opened into a big hole, and he breathed out and inhaled desperately. His hair was soaked with sweat. He was no different from a person who had just washed his hair. His curiosity drove him to look at Zhang Xuelin&#39;s face. Next steps. Zhang Xuelin once again muttered some inaudible words in front of the coffee table. He moved his fingers up and down, like a concert conductor, and stopped his fingers on the big silicone stick. Accompanied by a rough &quot;Woo&quot; , the finger miraculously moved the last square to the left, and finally stopped on the flight attendant&#39;s hat. Wang Hao quickly closed his eyes, as if he was relieved. When he opened them again, his eyes changed from panic to complete pleading. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Xuelin put a small blue square stewardess hat on Wang Hao&#39;s head, took a step back, looked at him for a while, and then laughed. This smile contained complete praise. Just when he was about to return to the coffee table, Wang Hao began to twist his body desperately, and made a new round of rapid &quot;Woo&quot; sounds from his mouth. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Xuelin said, &quot;What&#39;s the matter? Do you have something to say?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Woo! Woohoo! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;If you have something to say, what should you do if you have something to say? Will it make me unhappy? &quot;Zhang Xuelin stood there and said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Woo! Woohoo! Woohoo! Wuwu......&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What are you whining about? You can&#39;t even explain something clearly. &quot;Zhang Xuelin took the largest whip from the coffee table, stroking it in his hand, and walked over and said, &quot;You have to think about it. It&#39;s not that you are not allowed to speak. The key is that what you say must be As it relates to movies, put your own feelings aside. After all, we are all filmmakers. Your own feelings don&#39;t matter compared to the greatness of the film industry. right? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Hao nodded repeatedly, nodding wildly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Okay, then I believe you. You are an excellent filmmaker. I hope that the first words you say are carefully considered and do not make me angry. Have you considered? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Hao nodded again sincerely. After that, Zhang Xuelin reached out to Wang Hao&#39;s mouth, grabbed a corner of the sock, and pulled it all out. A piece of wet cloth fell to the ground. Wang Hao did not speak in a hurry, but moved his jaw first, making a rattling sound. When the whip was raised, he said categorically, &quot;Good movie.&quot; good movie. No! Great script, great script! This is a good script! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Oh? Good script? What did you write? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Written, written... , raised his arm, and with a &quot;pop&quot; sound, the skin exploded from Wang Hao&#39;s back. Wang Hao screamed in pain, but he was afraid that the scream would anger Zhang Xuelin, and then it turned into a whimper with gritted teeth. Anyone can hear the element of strong forbearance in it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Now, you need to use concise language to summarize the outline of the script. I&#39;ll check to see if you watched it carefully during those four hours, okay? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Yes, I can...script, script, good script... Another whip, with a mocking sentence, &quot;You can start now!&quot; What are you thinking! I asked you to speak, but you are hemming and hawing here. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;A deaf-mute mother with a daughter... Another whip struck, causing Wang Hao to twist his spine into a snake shape, groan and scream hoarsely for a while. Zhang Xuelin educated him expressionlessly, &quot;What kind of mother brings her daughter?&quot; Is this how to write an outline? As a professional producer, if there is a screenwriter who starts like this, can you finish reading his outline? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Hao started to cry. He felt like he was in so much pain that there was nothing he could do about it. And Zhang Xuelin raised his whip again and shouted, &quot;Can you!&quot; ? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;No, no...&quot; Wang Hao wailed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Yes! Then be professional! We are all filmmakers! With your ability, can&#39;t you summarize a script outline? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Hao seemed to be thinking desperately. The pain near his sphincter and the strange pleasure made his heart rate soar. He had never wanted to find a crack in the ground so much as at this moment. He forced himself to calm down and think about what the long story of more than six hundred pages was about. Several times before he spoke, he hesitated, fearing that he would be whipped if he didn&#39;t open his head properly. Finally, after five minutes, he worked hard to adjust his hoarse throat, swallowed, moistened his throat, and began to speak:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;The story took place in Guiyang, 2012. In 2006, a deaf-mute mother subscribed to a deaf-mute magazine all year round, called &quot;Voices of the Heart.&quot; &quot;Voice of the Heart&quot;, &quot;Voice of the Heart&quot; suddenly lost contact and ceased publication. It was less than two months since the last annual fee was paid. The deaf-mute mother&#39;s daughter Xia Chan, a high school student, noticed the way she lingered in front of the mailbox for a long time. The commonplace and disapproval of the elderly postman also made Xia Chan, who had a fierce personality, grit her teeth and decided to ride in the pickup truck of her friend&#39;s band and go north to Chongqing to find the magazine in person to ask for an explanation. And the reason why she is so sensitive to the deception of the magazine and has the courage to embark on an adventurous journey is precisely related to the same loss of contact that her father experienced back then... Zhang Xuelin applauded slowly. , said, &quot;Okay!&quot; Very good, that’s what it means. Did Xia Chan go alone? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;No, no, she went there with a girl who had a completely opposite personality to hers, Liu Shuchen, Liu Shuchen... This girl is a good girl, and she has supported a fierce and fierce personality. The conflicting personalities of the two sweet heroines and the tension of the drama...&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Don’t be so eloquent. Let’s be more sincere and simple and just talk about the script! How did they meet? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;When Liu Shuchen was buying sanitary napkins at Xia Chan’s store, there were several male classmates inside. Liu Shuchen was embarrassed to take them, so Xia Chan came over impatiently and took them in a black plastic bag. Wearing a sanitary napkin was doing her a favor. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What do you think of this design? &amp;rdquo;Zhang Xuelin moved his face closer. While his face was still flying towards Wang Hao&#39;s face, he heard Wang Hao yelling impatiently, &quot;Okay!&quot; good! good! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Hmm... &quot;Okay, let&#39;s talk about Xu Ye. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Xu Ye, Xu Ye... Xu Ye is one of the many boys in the town who has a crush on Xia Chan. He, he... he is a bit of a gangster, addicted to In the Internet cafe, Xia Chan ignored him at first. However, during the days when Xia Chan went to Chongqing to ask for her explanation, Xu Ye promised to help Xia Chan and kept an eye on the small shop, especially because there was a group of bastards nearby who liked to use sign language to insult deaf-mute mothers. Therefore, Xia Chan finally fell in love with him. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Fart! &quot;Zhang Xuelin stood up and whipped Wang Hao&#39;s half-exposed butt, &quot;You fell in love so easily? ! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Hao first gritted his teeth to endure the most painful force, and then began to gasp for air while saying, &quot;No, no... it&#39;s the train station scene at the end.&quot; The play! Xia Chan left Guiyang, and Xu Ye chased her to the train station for a long time. Because there was no sound outside in the train, Xu Ye was so anxious that she suddenly said &quot;I love you&quot; to her in sign language. Xia Chan realized that Xu Ye had secretly learned Sign Language. He was running with the train and using sign language. Xia Chan started to cry while holding on to the train window. At that moment, she really fell in love with him. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Very good! I read it carefully. It looks like I read it carefully! Good guy...&quot; Zhang Xuelin nodded and looked at the ceiling for a while. He seemed to be thinking about something in his head. Just as he was about to ask again, he saw a drop of blood dripping from under the stool. He walked around behind Wang Hao and leaned over. He took a look, shook his head, and then came back and said, &quot;Let me test you again with a more difficult test.&quot; Let’s talk about the ending. How did Xia Chan communicate with the deaf-mute magazine president? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;夏蝉和妈妈生活，会手语，她和杂志社长交流的时候，其他不懂手语的人，就在旁边看着。这时候非常好！电影看起来像默片一样！他们最终达成了一个协议，杂志社因为诸多原因确实是办不下去了，尤其是短视频时代，聋哑人都刷短视频了，订阅杂志的少了。但夏蝉说你这个杂志不能一走了之，其实，这里的一走了之，对应着夏蝉父亲的一走了之&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;啪&amp;rdquo;的一鞭子，王浩感觉自己快被抽死了，他忍着剧痛，听见张学霖教训道，&amp;ldquo;没让你分析我的创作意图，你就说剧情本身！与电影无关的那些狗屁词儿，少说！别说！ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;好&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;好&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;所以，&amp;rdquo;王浩大口喘着气，从痛苦中挣扎出来，继续说，&amp;ldquo;所以社长答应夏蝉，出一期告别期刊。这期告别期刊的封面大图，是夏蝉、刘书辰、采花大盗，和全体杂志聋哑工作人员们在山坡上的鞠躬合影。拍摄这张照片的是当地的花农，山坡上种满了花，把「那就好好告个别吧」这句核心台词和剧本立意，推向了高潮！ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张学霖皱着眉毛，留意王浩屁股正下方的血滴，说话间，又落下一两滴，他嘴里稍显怜悯地招呼道，&amp;ldquo;我就不问你采花大盗的事儿了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;采花大盗！采花大盗是女孩们给那个在公路上遇到的怪人起的外号！他神秘，富有魅力，在重庆和贵州的边境线往返，靠抢劫重庆的玫瑰花转卖给贵州的花店老板为生&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;从女孩的勇敢行动中，他也获得了温暖的力量，在影片结尾，决定亲自种一片玫瑰花田。对，他这个形象，应该找郭富城演！ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;放你妈的屁，郭富城都多大年纪了！ ? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我的意思是，形象！那种范儿！啊！ &amp;rdquo;王浩说着话，尖叫了一声，那是因为他突然感受到下身的撕裂。血滴的渗出加速了，王浩拼命想观察自己的身后，但他目前被绑出的怪异姿势使他难以办到，他哭得更悲切了，哀求着说，&amp;ldquo;可能破了！破了！要大出血了！我要死了，我要死了&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;要死了！ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张学霖对着王浩大扇了六七个耳光，一边扇，一边说道，&amp;ldquo;你怎么答应我的！怎么开始说和电影无关的话题了！ ?你是我这部片的制片人，我不可能让你因肛裂而死！那也太丢人了。连个高尔夫球你都夹不住，传出去遭人笑话！你放一百八十个心好了！我再问你最后一个问题好了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;好，您问，您尽管问，这个剧本已经刻在我的脑门上了！ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;别说这些俏皮话。保持你的专业性。 &amp;rdquo;张学霖想了一会儿，说道，&amp;ldquo;你为什么觉得那个过场戏反而是好的？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;全片都好，没有不好的地方&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;全片都好&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;我之所以觉得那个过场戏特别好，那是因为，因为&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;因为它体现了真正的自由和快乐。您想，从前，车子碾压水泊，溅得路人一身水，路人可是要生气的。而在那场戏里&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;乐队孩子们和两个女孩刚在贵州的田野里抓完鱼，玩完泥巴，浑身是泥，急需一大波冲洗。怎么办呢？观众都要嫌弃他们身上和脸上的泥巴了。这时候，高速路旁边雨后的大水坑，他们集体站成一排，用手势主动引导着路过的车往水泊上轧，前面几个车都不敢，或者不懂他们的意思。直到那辆前七后八的大卡车司机经过，和孩子们眼神对照，心领神会，方向盘一打，前轮后轮，两次碾压大水泊，巨大的水花把孩子们浑身淋透，那一幕，翻转了观众日常生活对水坑避之不及的印象，是个非常棒的设计！关键，大水花，大轮子，落汤鸡，洗掉满身的泥，拍起来也过瘾，画面上，构图上也容易出彩！ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张学霖从茶几上拿来烟盒，取出两支烟，一支给自己，一支温柔地塞进王浩的嘴唇间，他极为诚恳地弯腰给王浩点上烟，一边说，&amp;ldquo;你瞧，中国不缺艺术家，也不缺懂电影的人，只缺像你这样敢于面对真正优秀作品的纯粹的大师，大鉴赏家。不过，我的建议是，你以后还是把那些什么画面，构图，翻转之类的狗日的专业词汇给扔掉，那些和真正的电影没什么关系！ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王浩抽了两口烟，突然瞪大了眼睛，尼古丁让他的括约肌进一步松弛，这种松弛无法被神经抑制。他嘴里迅速地念叨着，&amp;ldquo;不行了&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;不行了&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;之后，整个房间进入了极致的宁静。两个男人可能心里都清楚这个&amp;ldquo;不行了&amp;rdquo;代表着什么，他们一站一座，纹丝不动，像一幅内容疯狂的后现代油画中的人。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;突然，一个红酒开瓶的&amp;ldquo;叭&amp;rdquo;的声音，杀破了这份宁静，紧接着是一个血淋淋的高尔夫球落地的声音。那个球带着极大的初始速度，直接撞击到鱼缸的底座上，回弹的时候，刚好正打正地从王浩凳子下面穿过，一直滚到了张学霖的脚边停下。张学霖抿了一口烟，从地上捡起那黏糊糊的高尔夫球，表情上看，就像看着一个宝贝。接着，他不由分说地把球塞进先前湿漉漉、黏糊糊的袜子和内裤里，再一边提鞭狂揍，一边扇巴掌，好说歹说，把袜子和内裤重新塞回了王浩的嘴。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;呜&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;呜呜&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;王浩的下巴肉眼可见地肿起来，很可能是脱臼了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;别搁这呜呜了，接下来我说的话，你还是需要回答，只不过只需要点头Yes摇头No。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;呜呜&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;王浩拼命地点头。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你知不知道点头代表Yes，摇头代表No？别搞半天你不知道这一点，弄得我会错了你的意思，把你给杀了，那可实在是太冤枉了。点头代表同意，摇头代表不同意，关于这一点，你同意不同意？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王浩大幅度地点头，鼻涕和眼泪疯狂从他的三窍涌出。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;好，&amp;rdquo;张学霖说，&amp;ldquo;第一，你不会报警。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王浩点头。 &amp;ldquo;呜呜&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;呜&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;第二，你会把《纯爱小说》尽你所能，动用你所有的关系，拍成电影。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王浩点头。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;第三&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;张学霖看了看王浩身后下面，血滴的流速越来越大，已经汇成小血泊，血泊里还有一些块状物，实在看起来恶心，他索性把目光从上面移开，想了一会儿说道，&amp;ldquo;第三个就是，你会用你自己的名字作为电影编剧署名。因为我对名利已经无所谓了，最好没有人认识我，我的生命是为电影服务的，而不是说电影是我人生的荣誉装饰物。所以，这部电影的所有名气，由你的名字来承受。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王浩刚要有所动作，张学霖就按住他的头说，&amp;ldquo;这个问题你想好了再回答！不是我在这跟你装屄，而是因为，这个世界上有好的评价，就有不好的评价。有能看懂的，就有看不懂的。如果看不懂，还乱骂我，以我的脾气，我会想法设法找到那个观众，给他杀了。这是我能做出来的事。所以，你的署名，用来承受所有的评价。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王浩闭着眼睛，深沉地点了点头。之后，张学霖嘟囔着，&amp;ldquo;事不过三，没有第四个要求了。 &amp;rdquo;他走向沙发，坐在那伸了个懒腰，突然大喊道，&amp;ldquo;你们家剪刀放哪儿了？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;呜！呜&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;呜呜呜&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;呜他妈个屄，问你剪刀放哪了，我要给你松绑呢，你在这里呜呜呜的。 &amp;rdquo;张学霖一边辱骂，一边在大大小小的抽屉里翻找，他从茶几抽屉里看到剪刀的同时，还看到了一部王浩的手机。他走到王浩面前，把剪刀放在地上，突然来了什么兴致，点亮手机，面部解锁失败。于是他把手机端正地怼向王浩的脸，王浩狰狞着脸上的肌肉，闭着眼睛，乱摇晃自己的头，嘴里不停发出&amp;ldquo;呜&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;呜&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张学霖摇着头，嘴里骂骂咧咧地，同时拿起剪刀走向王浩的身后，把剪刀头，对准了王浩身上流血的地方，侧着贴上去，大吼道，&amp;ldquo;非要我走极端吗！ &amp;rdquo;王浩突然感到身下突然贴上了什么尖锐又冰凉的东西，张学霖大声问，&amp;ldquo;是不是非要我费功夫！ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王浩疯狂地摇头，把头摇得幻影重重。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张学霖扔下剪刀，重新把手机对准王浩的脸，王浩一张绝望的脸，看见手机上的人脸图标朝着自己微笑了一下，一个优雅的旋转之后，解锁成功。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;彼时已经是凌晨三点十五分，解锁手机后，张学霖搬来一个凳子，和王浩并排坐着，同时翻看王浩的相册和隐私相册。两个人一起看&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;其中王浩是不得不看&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;看了足足半个小时，期间，张学霖不停调侃着说道，&amp;ldquo;你小子玩的真花呀。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;好家伙，长见识了，长见识了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;怪不得呢，你活该当个艺术家，这才是他妈艺术家该干的事。你瞧瞧。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张学霖嘴里不停地发出&amp;ldquo;啧啧&amp;rdquo;的赞叹声，遇到自己心仪的照片，还用双指搓着放大，笑着递给王浩看。直到隐私相册里最后一张相册翻看完毕，张学霖又打开多选模式，挑选了八千六百多张照片中称得上尖峰时刻的照片，用蓝牙发送到自己的手机上。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;没别的意思，单纯是respect。向你学习，向你致敬。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王浩于凌晨五点钟被张学霖解绑，彻底恢复自由。他的大出血已经浸透了睡裤，他虚弱地要求张学霖拨打急救中心的电话。同时，回屋把剧本拿上，走回客厅，怀抱着剧本，低头哭泣，原地等待。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;不至于，王浩。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王浩说，&amp;ldquo;没关系，应该的，我在医院可以继续看剧本。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这句话给张学霖带来的感动不亚于二十一年前大学的时候，他的同校学姐用手语对他说，&amp;ldquo;没关系，应该的，明天我就离开贵阳了，今天陪你睡一觉，神不知鬼不觉。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;救护车于五点二十分赶到小区楼下，闪烁着红蓝光辉，接走了浑身是血、鞭刑破损以及发紫的绑痕的王浩。王浩在五点二十一分的时候，让医护人员帮自己报警，他躺在担架上，眼睛发直，六百多页剧本散了一车，嘴里大叫道，&amp;ldquo;报警！报警！报警！报警！ &amp;rdquo;即便医生已经开始拨打报警电话，他的嘴巴还没停止，只不过降低了些声音，刻板地重复着，&amp;ldquo;报警&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;报警&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;警察&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;报警&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;救护车车厢乱成一锅粥，王浩挣脱了点滴的管线，一手捂着屁股，一手争抢医护人员的电话，大喊着，&amp;ldquo;报警&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;报警&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一路上，《纯爱小说》的剧本从救护车后门的缝隙里不停地露出。一页一页洒在地安门东大街上，反复被后车碾压，或被车轮掀起的旋风吹到路边。好奇的路人捡起来查看，只能看到零星的对话，不成章的碎片，随手扔进垃圾桶。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警车和救护车对向擦过，两个警察，一个持枪的便衣警，三人一起赶到王浩家里的时候，张学霖躺在沙发上，没盖被子，蜷缩着，握着拳头睡觉，像一个婴儿的姿势。他先是被关到看守所，于次年四月五日提审，判处有期徒刑十七年，转移至第三监狱。同年六月，王浩同母异父的妹妹李小萱，不得不从新加坡飞往北京，在宣武区精神病医院的文件上签字。那是因为王浩成天捏着一个臭烘烘的高尔夫球骚扰独行女性，下雨天时，还搬着凳子，在马路上找一个够深够大的水坑坐在旁边，不停地伸手招呼过往的车辆，看上去在找茬，脸上露出一种&amp;ldquo;喜欢您来&amp;rdquo;的怪异的笑容。 &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;责任编辑：舟自横&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;征稿信息见@ONE一个工作室置顶微博。更多编辑部的有趣日常请关注小红书：ONE一个编辑部。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FuVUfwTbUcPSXgyoJpTN72o46ZnA&quot; alt=&quot;赵纯想&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;赵纯想 &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;抖音、B站、微博：@赵纯想&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;小说作者。曾用笔名：凉炘。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;关注&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;相关推荐&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/944&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;兰州莎莎&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 赵纯想&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/1314&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;怀念少女骆菲池&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 赵纯想&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6127&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;我与一亿棵大树相逢&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 吴忠全&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6126)&quot;>;点击可下载ONE一个app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 06:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4025]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4166]]><description>&lt;div>;14 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgEl9proyZ2r2lrQ7gMHpi6IHkSn&quot; alt=&quot;首页图&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4025&lt;/span>;插画| Teddy Kang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;14&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oct. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;只有看星星的人才会被天空注视。&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 14 Oct 2023 06:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>