<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[你在哪里，最近过得怎么样？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3987]]><description> &lt;div>;23 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; ONE Studio Question&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p >;Where are you and how are you doing? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Zhu Deyong replied&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FrkI2BMqfK8foq86v59VFkfC6Vhl&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FrkI2BMqfK8foq86v59VFkfC6Vhl&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Nana onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Deyong&#39;s Q&amp;A column &quot;Me≠We&quot; is exclusively updated on the &quot;ONE&quot; APP. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmPuzv4rbuXt8DD2ZiWPWVY5GDQ3 &quot; alt=&quot;Zhu Deyong&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Zhu Deyong&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;Weibo@朱德yong&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style =&quot;&quot;>;Cartoonist. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Question and Answer&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/question/3979&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Have you become a useful adult to the world? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3972&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Where do you hide your dreams? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3964&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;How long do you think the shelf life of sincerity is? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3987)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[宇宙的玄机]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6173]]><description> &lt;div>;23 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Lu Yinyin&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data -author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fk3PN3nNXjR4spY8n7nQl51uiujp&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fk3PN3nNXjR4spY8n7nQl51uiujp&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Delicate, capturing the details of life and capturing the mystery of emotions. This is an unethical love affair that is beginning to break down and is destined to bear a heavy burden. When people make choices that exceed the rules, the price is inevitably inevitable. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He opened the door at two o&#39;clock in the middle of the night. With a click, the lock opened. She asked a little panicked in the study, who? He walked in and saw her playing a game. Watching continuously without using your brain is the easiest way to make yourself feel empty. She started filling out the U.S. visa form 160 at eight o&#39;clock. Because she was overdue twice, she only finished it intermittently at twelve o&#39;clock. Although there were still a lot of things waiting to be done, she didn&#39;t want to think about anything. She just wanted to click the left button of the mouse, connect the heads of three monkeys or three cats, make a meow sound and then disappear. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As soon as he entered the door, she turned off the game and could not relax like she was at home. He said why aren&#39;t you sleeping yet? She smiled and asked, why are you here? Every time after drinking, he always goes back to another home, the one where his wife and children live. He said I came to check if you slept on time. She smiled and turned off the computer again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When he went to take a shower, she ran to the kitchen, transferred the remaining porridge in the pot to a bowl, and put it in the refrigerator. The last time I used plastic wrap, I accidentally tore it in the middle, and then I couldn&#39;t get the two sides to be even and tear out a complete piece. So she could only put the lid on the bowl. The kitchen was really dirty when he was away, she thought. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The sound of water came from the bathroom. She knocked on the door and went in to brush her teeth. He is seen standing behind glass, water splashing on his exposed body. He spoke, using sentence patterns rarely used in ordinary times, &quot;I have a dream.&quot; She smiled as she brushed her teeth and asked him what it was. He said that he would build an audio-visual room specifically for listening to music. It turned out that I went to a friend&#39;s house for a drink at night and saw that their audio-visual room was very nice. The kid had a mental attack and wanted one too. She smiled at him with toothpaste in her mouth. Men are men, and building an audio-visual room also requires &quot;building.&quot; It&#39;s like starting from the foundation and building a house bit by bit. He said yes, his expression was very good, and he was so happy after drinking. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then she also took a shower and went to the bedroom together. I haven&#39;t been with him for many days. He held her tightly and his mouth tasted like alcohol. The wine tasted so strong, she said. Of course, he replied. My body felt hot. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That friend has a very interesting nickname, is divorced, and lives with his girlfriend. During the meal, we were talking about a movie we had watched a few years ago. A few people had a dispute. Instead of helping his girlfriend, his friend helped him. The girl became anxious. It reminded me of you then, he said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Because she is on her period these days, she always seems to lose her temper. Yesterday afternoon I was unhappy, so I opened the door and jumped out of the car. She didn&#39;t answer and asked who else was there. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Originally, his wife also wanted to go, he said, but then something happened and she stopped going, which made his friend’s girlfriend very happy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Are you hinting that she saw something, she asked. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yes, women have intuition. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As he talked, he almost fell asleep, but he kept holding his hands. She felt it for a moment, then turned to touch his. It&#39;s already very hard. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unfortunately, she said, not today. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Do you want to, he asked. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I want to, but I can’t. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said that’s fine, I thought you never wanted to. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;How could it be, she said in the darkness. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was almost four o&#39;clock when I fell asleep. She sensed him going to the living room to smoke a cigarette. I woke up once in the middle of the night and was snoring when I came back from using the bathroom. But strangely, as soon as she lay on the bed, he quickly flew the quilt over her, covering her just right. Then he put his arms around her and breathed next to her, smelling heavily of alcohol. She thought it was funny. He usually doesn&#39;t like to be touched when sleeping. He seems to be drunk. When he turns around, his arms are waving around. He must be drunk. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wake up at ten in the morning. She didn&#39;t know why, but she felt like she had been frowning these past few days, as if she was tired. Maybe it&#39;s because of the perm. There is no direct connection between these two things, but perming your hair will make people feel tired to some extent. In other words, it makes you age. She put the black sweater he had thrown into the basin a few days ago into the washing machine, as well as her socks and underwear, and then went to the kitchen to wash the dishes. He finished brushing his teeth and sat on the sofa. It seemed that he hadn&#39;t fully woken up yet. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The floor is really dirty. When she returned home after the Chinese New Year, she noticed that there were footprints in the dusty areas. His wife and children were away on a trip during those days, so he lived here alone and mopped the living room floor before she came back. But men do things, you know. She didn&#39;t say anything, but she was already happy that he was interested in cleaning. I have been very busy these days. I have to pick up the work I left off during the Chinese New Year, write two more summaries and prospects, and prepare for a US visa, so I just turn a blind eye to the dust. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It’s eleven o’clock when I finish washing the dishes. She asked him about his plans for today and he said he was going to work. She took out the porridge and prepared to heat it up before continuing to work on the information. You have to enter the company system to fill out a form, apply for a stamp on the salary certificate, call to make an appointment for an interview, and then check to see if there are any replies to yesterday&#39;s post asking questions. That&#39;s when he asked her if she wanted to go out to dinner. The opportunity to get along with him was hard to refuse. She hesitated but said yes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said she wanted to eat pizza. After moving to him for half a year, she had hardly eaten pizza or hot pot. With such a large portion, it would be strange for one person to order a whole table in a store. He thought that there was a Western restaurant that did good pizza, but it was near his home and he would meet many acquaintances. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I will take you to another restaurant. He said that there is very authentic Italian pizza there. Last time I invited a friend to dinner and drank wine, I spent two thousand yuan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She couldn’t quite hear what was being said behind her. I just feel like I&#39;m living in the dark. I went back to the university to attend a lecture a few days ago. The speaker made fun of the Mistress Village in Shenzhen in a sarcastic tone. There was a burst of laughter. Even the foreign students who could not understand Chinese smiled and tacitly understood it after whispering to each other. She laughed too, but she didn&#39;t know what she was laughing at. Everyone&#39;s situation is different, she said in her mind. Then she was surprised to find that, unknowingly, she had moved to the opposite side of most people. She never felt that she was like that. In fact, she had many reasons and excuses, but her heart didn&#39;t listen to them. What&#39;s even stranger is that she seems to have become numb, and these words cannot affect her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, a tear still fell. When she was changing clothes in the bedroom, she wiped her tears on the blue and yellow horizontal stripes of her sweater. He was very sensitive and looked into her eyes carefully when he passed by. She pretended it was nothing and put the sweater on her body. He didn&#39;t like her crying, she knew that, and nothing happened. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Just go to that Italian restaurant with expensive wine. He was driving and she was talking. For no reason, it was easy to think of it when sitting next to him. One time she came back from the airport and said she wanted to eat dark chocolate. He took out five pieces of dark chocolate from his backpack, different brands and flavors. He handed them over from the left at this angle and this posture. give her. One piece of it is still uneaten and placed in the refrigerator of the house she shared with her friend, and she has never gone back to live there since she met him. They were very happy that there was one less person fighting for the toilet in the morning. But also asked her, why don&#39;t you bring your boyfriend over to see her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There were not many people in the restaurant. On the left is a small bar, with a few rows of tables in the middle, and on the right is an open kitchen where the chef prepares what the guests order on the spot. After taking off their down jackets, they started looking at the menu. She wanted to eat Margherita pizza, fried cheese, and fried beef tenderloin with French fries. He warned her that the pan-fried beef tenderloin was a main dish and that she would not be able to eat it if it came on a large plate. Then switch to French fries and grilled chicken wings, she said. At this time, a father came to the left, bringing with him a little girl with flat eyes that looked like a Korean. She looked at her, remembering that she thought she was pregnant two days ago, and asked him what to do. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Born, he said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fortunately, it’s my period. Afterwards, she sent a text message asking him if he was afraid, and he said of course he was. But she was still grateful that he didn&#39;t say rudely to knock it off. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She touched her collar. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is a bow. She suddenly realized that when she was wiping her tears on her clothes in the bedroom, she had accidentally put her sweater on inside out. The bow should be at the back. Colleagues often joked when they passed her seat, quietly pulling the bow apart, making her angry, and then laughingly tying it up for her. She suddenly felt embarrassed, got up and went to the toilet. He asked later, what did you order, grilled chicken wings or pan-fried beef tenderloin? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Whatever, she dropped the sentence. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I saw myself flashing past in the mirror. I didn&#39;t dare to take a closer look. The hair scattered on my chest seemed to cover the collar. She walked into the cubicle, quickly took off her clothes, turned around and put them back on again. I took off my hat and straightened my hair. The static electricity was sucked into my cheeks one by one, and I couldn&#39;t get rid of it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Go out after using the toilet. When I washed my hands, I still didn&#39;t look at myself in the mirror. I only felt a blurry shadow, black and unclear. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When she returned to her seat, she felt something was wrong. The room seemed a little darker than before. The sunlight was turned away and the lights were not turned on yet. The boy drinking soup at the table on the right is now reclining on an empty seat playing with his mobile phone. He had already ordered food and was drinking water on the opposite side, because he was not allowed to drink alcohol while driving. Was it discovered or not? Can&#39;t tell by looking at it. She moved her chair and put her lips to the rim of the cup. He had a good temper these past two days, and she knew it in her heart. He tolerated her acting out and even bought salt and orange juice when he came to see her. But because of this incident, and perhaps fatigue, she became distracted. The girl at the next table was not good-looking at all, but she kept looking at her as she scooped up vegetables with a brightly colored plastic fork. He thought she liked it, and said that his children also had a way of doing it, but now that they have grown up, they no longer use it. She continued to look and saw the girl&#39;s father turning up the collar of his white T-shirt, like a farmer entrepreneur. Ironically, a TV series called &quot;Country Celebrities&quot; was playing on the TV on the wall of the restaurant. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She didn’t want to say anything until she finished eating. He ordered fried cheese, pan-fried beef tenderloin, and grilled chicken wings. When the fried beef tenderloin was served, she saw that it was indeed a full plate. I already told you, he said. She started to feel stomachache and couldn&#39;t eat anything. She knew she was annoying like this, just like how Salinger wrote about the girl in &quot;Franny and Zooey&quot; who was so unhappy eating a meal across from her boyfriend. She was very annoyed by this novel. She didn&#39;t expect that she would become her today. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But he was still very tolerant and said he could take it away if he couldn’t eat it. Then they packaged everything except the salad. She left the fried beef tenderloin untouched, and there were two pieces of pizza left. She also threw the remaining half stick of cheese into the plate of grilled chicken wings. He went to the balcony to smoke while she sat on her seat and slowly put her down jacket back on. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When checking out, he took his backpack and looked through his wallet for his credit card. She remembered that he would put a notebook in his bag. It was the same brand as the diary she had used for three years, but it was just a few circles larger. A few years ago, he had the habit of taking notes, writing some short sentences with no embellishments, but because the wording was accurate, she thought it was good. In the past few years, due to emotional problems, my life has been a bit chaotic, and I have gradually written less. But he said he would continue writing. The weather was nice the past two days. She had just returned from the Chinese New Year and was a little distant from him. She sat far away and listened to him read some words he wrote in November. It was the last days of autumn, and he was sitting in a room where he could see sunlight and fallen leaves. The leaves outside were spread like a carpet. She couldn&#39;t help but laugh and said she couldn&#39;t stand such clichés. Fallen leaves are like a carpet, without a sentence of beauty. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But now she has forgotten this, only remembering that he never let her read this book. She can understand that everyone has their own privacy. But for some reason, she suddenly wanted to draw a needle in his notebook. It was a long, slender, silver sewing needle with an extremely sharp bottom and a thin slit at the top. She asked him to take out the notebook, and he placed it in front of her while swiping the card. She didn&#39;t open it, just touched the cover and asked him if she could draw a picture on the last page. He said no, he would take the notebook back. She repeated it again and he ignored her. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They went downstairs to get the car. Along the way, she seemed to be possessed by an evil spirit and kept talking about painting. He asked why, and she said there were two reasons. One was that just like a dog peeing on his territory, she also wanted to draw something with her own flavor at the back of each of his notebooks. The second is that she has already thought about what she wants to draw. She didn&#39;t see that he was a little angry, or in other words, the evil thoughts that controlled her had no intention of letting her notice at this time. After getting in the car, she continued to complain, and he said, don&#39;t make one request after another, I will annoy you anymore. She asks what is one request after another. He said I was in a hurry to go to work, so I brought you here because you wanted to eat. I ordered all the dishes even though I knew you couldn&#39;t eat them, and now I have to draw in my notebook. At this time, she repeated her old trick and said that if you do this again, I will jump out of the car. He didn&#39;t react. She asked do you want me to go? He didn&#39;t answer. So she jumped. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He drove away. She crossed the green belt between the roadway and the sidewalk and sat on the edge of the street with her knees in her arms. Look around, don&#39;t know where it is. Send him a text message: I don’t know the way home, so I will sit here until dawn today. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He called her back and yelled at her, asking her what she wanted to do. She said she didn&#39;t know. He said he had to work and let her go home alone. She yelled back, is that my home? He came to pick her up very angry and sent her downstairs, letting her go up by herself. She disagrees. Then they went upstairs to argue. She took out all her things and said she wanted to move back in. He said yes and started to help her pack the boxes. She hit him with the power supply of her laptop. He said I don’t want to live the same life as before, please let me go to work. She said I didn’t deny you work. He said that I can&#39;t let you draw in my notebook. This is my notebook and you have to respect me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She knew he was right. But she didn&#39;t want to admit it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also said, very calmly and cruelly, just like warning her that there was a full plate of fried beef tenderloin and she would not be able to eat it, saying that this is what I want to tell you, not everything you propose. All requirements are met. You are an adult and should be responsible for your own actions. If you want to find someone to play angry games with you, I am not suitable. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She was a little confused, like an abandoned child, standing in the passage of time and space with her hands hanging down. Then he said slowly, &quot;What request did I make? Does eating count as a request?&quot; The real requests, like going on a trip with you, like ending your marriage, all the real requests I made were never met. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He didn&#39;t leave until almost four o&#39;clock. He was angry that she was taking up his time and said a lot of harsh words. She sat on the sofa, not knowing how to react. At around eight o&#39;clock, she sent him a text message and said she wanted to hear his voice. He never answered the phone where his wife and children were. She remembered that his cell phone rang before leaving today, and he picked up and called his wife by her nickname. She thought she was numb and this kind of thing wouldn&#39;t hurt her, but she remembered the words that came out of her mouth deeply. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The lamp his wife bought is placed in their living room. How many times did she want to pierce the white paper with scissors. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He reiterated in the text message that she is an adult and must adjust her emotions by herself. When she sent it again, he asked, &quot;Do you want to ruin everything tonight?&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The room was empty, and she was at a loss. She took out her diary and wrote in it: How can love remain pure despite being selfish and limited? Then I reflected on myself: work hard, live happily, fall in love sincerely, without thinking about tomorrow or the consequences. Don&#39;t belittle yourself. Feel His love. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then she crossed them all out. Lying on the sofa, watching the night shine through the window, there were trees but no one outside. Honey, she murmured to herself, I never wanted to destroy everything, and I didn&#39;t know what I was going to do. Maybe it was just my menstrual period, a little bit of hormonal changes that turned me into an unreasonable person. Plus, did you know that the secrets of the universe sometimes lie just in the bow of a sweater? &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Zhou Ziheng&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is selected from the author&#39;s novel collection &quot;Typhoon Days&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/Fna9-2xJKL1HlHFTQ5fJfooMo4p2&quot; alt=&quot;Lu Yinyin&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Lu Yinyin&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div >; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Young writer, he has won the &quot;United Literature&quot; Novel Newcomer Award. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/article/3670&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Typhoon Day&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Lu Yinyin&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr >; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Read&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6172&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;We are with The Distance of Evil&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Written by Wu Zhongquan&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text- align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6173)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/ div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4065]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4207]]><description>&lt;div>;23 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FuTzBp2mtdcVoXbfaEa5UiQjAVCb&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;VOL.4065&lt;/span>;Photography | Karsten Winegeart&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;23&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nov. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;The more I think about it, the more I don’t understand why I found nothing, my hands are full of calluses. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot; color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 23 Nov 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>