<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[“天生我才必有用”是不是一个骗局？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3996]]><description> &lt;div>;4 Dec. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Polanski’s driver asked&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt; p>;Is &quot;I am born to be useful&quot; a scam? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Wang Huicheng answered&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original- src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fh5DvAJA4LmKNvR_FHnzG4fCda3b&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fh5DvAJA4LmKNvR_FHnzG4fCda3b&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Fifteen years ago, I From a high school student to a college student. My parents are farmers and cannot provide guidance or help when filling out my application form and choosing a school. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Living in a small town, I longed to be away from my hometown and parents, so I relied on my romantic imagination to apply to a remote university, majoring in sociology. When I was less than twenty years old, I couldn&#39;t connect my major with employment. At that time, all I could think about was writing and wanting to be a writer sought after by thousands of people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The New Concept Essay Contest at that time successfully created a group of impressive young writers who had crazy fame and income. As for me, I was a talented person in the school for three years in high school. I published a short article about tofu cubes in the city evening newspaper. The reason why I chose sociology was because I believed the rumor that &quot;Chinese departments cannot produce writers.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Throughout college, my attitude towards my studies was very perfunctory. To be precise, it was dismissive. &lt;strong>;I spent almost four years in college reading and writing. I read a book every day and wrote a thousand words every night. I persisted in this life for about four years. At that time, I believed that &quot;I am born with talents that will be useful&quot; and firmly believed that I could make a living from writing. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Reality always slaps you in the mouth without explanation. After I started writing, I lived with depression and frustration almost every day. As I watched my friends’ novels being published in magazines one after another, I began to frequently dream about my novels being accepted by magazines. Dreams are the opposite of reality. In fact, my submissions have always been in vain, with no news at all. Until I graduated from college, I had only published a few novels. &lt;strong>;In other words, the dream of making a living from writing was shattered the moment I graduated. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The school was not good and my academic performance was not good. After I entered the society, I naturally ran into obstacles many times. Fortunately, society was in a stage of vigorous development at that time, so I was able to find a job in new media operations and advertising copywriting. The salary is very meager. After paying the rent, there is not even enough money for food. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I have been working as an advertising copywriter for about three years. Although it is related to words, it is fundamentally different from writing. Advertising copy is essentially a commodity, and it is necessary to eliminate individuality and create words that are easy to spread and efficient. I didn’t do well in this job because I didn’t understand the nature of advertising at that time. When I went to work every day, I was just like an emotionless typing machine, producing a large amount of incomprehensible copy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This stage is the most confusing period for me. There is no career direction. What makes me even more desperate is that the high housing prices are prohibitive. Writing has hit a bottleneck again, and I&#39;m vaguely aware that given my literary talent and level of effort, I definitely can&#39;t make a living from writing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Now, I have already left the advertising industry, and after going around in circles, I became a book editor. And my age has reached the precarious age of thirty-five. People who write at the same time have published many books and become eye-catching young writers. Professionally, you may also reach the middle level of the company. I only write literary reviews and continue to maintain my identity as a &quot;writer&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Will this persistence work for me? It looks like it, but it&#39;s not that big. Writing has brought me little fame and fortune. Maybe it will be helpful at work, but I still face many constraints in my specific publishing work. A work that I am optimistic about cannot be signed because the author is a newcomer or is famous. Frustration and depression still hang over me. &lt;strong>;But the biggest difference between me at this time and when I was twenty is that I can accept these setbacks and frustrations. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although there is a big gap with my expectations at the age of twenty, and I have not realized the ambition of &quot;I am born with talents, I will be useful&quot;, but I am still grateful. Those frustrating years. It was my almost stubborn persistence at that time that allowed me to enter the book industry instead of the advertising or new media industry that I did not want. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Therefore, for me, &quot;I am born with talents that will be useful&quot; is not a scam, but self-motivation. Or, to be more precise, it’s now, more than a decade later, that I truly understand what this statement means. &lt;strong>;It makes me realize more clearly what I want to do, what I can do, and what I can do. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And, most importantly, confirm your talents and abilities. &lt;strong>;Whether it’s a big talent but a small use, or a small talent that makes a big use, whatever suits you is “useful”. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Zhou Ziheng onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see @ONE Studio’s pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. The official WeChat account of the editorial department: oneapp2020. Regularly publish Q&amp;A collections, give away books and peripheral gifts, readers are welcome to add. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondents&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FjkoWIT -YyHhe1-ziZ892gIZJa2l&quot; alt=&quot;Wang Huicheng&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Wang Huicheng&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot; >;The young author has a mental age of 270 years old. @Huichengah&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Question and Answer&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3936&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Why is it so difficult to &quot;reject&quot;? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3996)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 06:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[冰湖的喜丧]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6184]]><description> &lt;div>;4 Dec. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;文／ Fan Qing&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FqlxTfP-0ExE3BR2aaFvOjp_CUz7&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FqlxTfP-0ExE3BR2aaFvOjp_CUz7&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;People in the power plant family home have their own stories. For children, the nearby glacial lake is a dangerous place that could burst at any time. When they grew up, Yan Huiwen discovered that the life she lived in was itself a frozen lake. The delicate and dense narrative outlines a sketch of the human world, describing all the fragmentary life, and writing down the treacherous human emotions to the core. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huiwen dreamed of the frozen lake again. She saw herself standing by the lake and wanted to call her back, but she couldn&#39;t make a sound no matter what. The ice began to melt, and she suddenly realized that she was dreaming, so there was no need to be afraid. Huiwen was woken up by the cold. She opened her eyes and let her thoughts dry out in the dark, cold night. They rode on a puff of exhaled water mist and turned into the wisp of white smoke on the cooling tower of the power plant. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The children in the courtyard of the power plant all like to play with Huiwen. Huiwen has a big TV at home and can also sing karaoke. There is a single-seater leather sofa next to the coffee table. Everyone is vying to sit on it. Huiwen always lets Zheng Yang sit first. Zheng Yang says that sitting on it is like being the general manager. When his father took him to the factory office, he was there. I&#39;ve seen similar ones. Sometimes everyone would gather in front of Tian Qiang&#39;s store and wait for his parents to get off work at the back door of the power plant. Tian Qiang secretly gave Huiwen a bag of snacks worth a few cents each. Huiwen took out all the snacks and shared them with everyone. If they didn&#39;t have enough, they would go to the store to buy more. Tian Qiang&#39;s mother always gave them more, including all the popular snacks. Eaten all over. Miaomiao is the youngest and a qualified follower. She follows what everyone else does. Her parents work three shifts, and she eats from hundreds of families. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huiwen’s father works as a salesperson in a furniture store, and her mother is an accountant in a factory. The family situation is pretty good, Huiwen is also smart and sensible, and everyone with children in the factory is willing to let their children play with Huiwen. Zheng Yang&#39;s father is an engineer in the factory. Zheng Yang is two years older than Hui Wen. He often leads the children in the courtyard to learn things - spinning pens, collecting cards, and playing yo-yo. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;This is &quot;sleep&quot;. You can always stay in place and spin wildly. If you don&#39;t stop when the time comes, you won&#39;t be able to do any tricks. If the rope rests, this one will Finished playing. ” Zheng Yang wound the rope back again and taught them how to play. Huiwen felt very proud. When she told her classmates, &quot;I have a friend,&quot; that friend could only be Zheng Yang. Zheng Yang first lent the ball to Huiwen to play with. She took it to show off to her grandfather: &quot;Grandpa, look, the yo-yo can travel a long way with one swing.&quot; Huiwen picked up the string, raised her arm suddenly, and finally got the ball back. Grandpa didn&#39;t know how to play, but he told Huiwen that those who can firmly hold the ball back in their hands in the end know how to use skill to see the timing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Occasionally, my mother took Huiwen to work in the factory. Huiwen was arranged to sit in front of the glass coffee table in the accounting room. There was a small plastic bench specially prepared for her. She often stepped on the stool. Lying on the window sill, I looked at the puffs of white smoke on the cooling tower. The pattern on it had been worn away. As long as you don&#39;t cry, make trouble, and don&#39;t look for your mother, you can ask your mother for a slightly more expensive reward if you behave a few times. She deliberately saved up a few times to be &quot;sensible&quot;, and she found the right moment when she and her mother passed the mall counter, and asked for a yo-yo as a birthday gift for Zheng Yang. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;There are small steel balls inside, which is so fun! &quot;Tian Qiang said. He hasn&#39;t played with it yet, but when he weighs it in his hand, he can tell that it&#39;s different from the ones in the store. As he spoke, he threw the ball into the air and quickly caught it. As soon as Zheng Yang unpacked it, Tian Qiang took it away. Unwilling to accept it, he jumped up and reached out to grab it. Tian Qiang immediately picked up the things in his arms and rushed out of the courtyard. A group of children ran out noisily and made a fuss to the lake. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The lake in the park is not big, lying between the power plant staff dormitories and family homes. They stood on the soil slope by the lake and looked in the direction Miao Miao pointed. The dead forest opposite had a bare area, revealing a section of iron railings surrounding the staff building. &quot;You can get in there. I&#39;ve seen people get out of it.&quot; &amp;rdquo;Miao Miao said. Use a knowledgeable tone. The surface of the lake was frozen, making it difficult to see clearly on a cloudy day. The large white area looked more like a worn cement floor. &quot;Do you dare to go down from here and go to the other side?&quot; &quot;Tian Qiang suddenly raised his voice and asked everyone. Several people remained silent for a moment, as if they had acquiesced that whoever holds the yo-yo has the final say. Huiwen hated Tian Qiang&#39;s appearance of being a villain, so she pursed her lips but did not argue with him, fearing that she would appear to be as petty as him in front of Zheng Yang. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Whoever dares is a bastard! Zheng Yang yelled, jumping off the slope in anger, and tentatively stepped on the broken ice on the edge of the lake with one foot. The sound was very fragile, but it penetrated into the soil sharply. Huiwen looked at the ice surface, squatted down and touched a small stone around the slope. Miaomiao thought she was about to go down, so she was so scared that she stepped back and grabbed Huiwen&#39;s arm. The stone was thrown out and made a muffled sound on the ice before sliding far away. Zheng Yang and Tian Qiang also found some stones and put them in their arms. They went down to the lake, took two steps forward, and threw the stones toward the center of the lake. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There won&#39;t even be a hole if a stone is hit. Zheng Yang boldly started skating on the ice, and Huiwen followed carefully after thinking about it. Miaomiao didn&#39;t dare, but didn&#39;t want to stay alone, so she followed Huiwen. Tian Qiang ran a few steps to pass Zheng Yang. The soles of his feet slipped and he slipped for a while, falling on his butt in the middle of the lake. Miaomiao couldn&#39;t care less about being afraid anymore and moved forward to see Tian Qiang making a fool of himself. Tian Qiang stumbled a few steps and finally stood up. Then, there was a short crisp sound from the soles of his feet. Everyone&#39;s laughter didn&#39;t stop suddenly, but slowly died down with the sound of rubber bands breaking one after another. In the end, even their breathing could not be heard. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The cracks began to spread around, dull and slow crawling towards the shore. Suddenly the ice beneath Tian Qiang&#39;s feet collapsed. Huiwen remembered the sound she made when stepping on the steel wire bed frame. It creaked and jumped, and finally one of the wires broke. Miaomiao screamed and turned and ran up the slope. Huiwen was so frightened that she couldn&#39;t move. She cried and called Zheng Yang&#39;s name. She felt as if she had stepped on the bottom line of the wire bed and could no longer bounce back. She closed her eyes tightly and huddled up inside her down jacket, waiting. Collapse. Zheng Yang reacted and ran to the opposite side like crazy, bypassing the ice hole in the center of the lake, avoiding the thin ice that might break, and stood at the foot of the dead forest. Tian Qiang was hanging on the edge of a slightly thick ice. Fortunately, he was only wearing a thin cotton vest, and he was still able to use his hands to scratch the ice. He screamed incoherently, his lips and face turned purple from the cold, and he couldn&#39;t get up or down. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huiwen was violently pulled back to the slope. When she opened her eyes, she found that it was Zheng Yang&#39;s father. Her mother ran over and hugged Huiwen. She was frightened and angry, and hit her hard on the back several times. Someone got out from the iron fence and ran along the lake shore with an empty sack and a thick hemp rope. The adults took some trouble to pick Tian Qiang up and dragged him uphill with the sack. Did the yo-yo fall into the lake? Huiwen looked at everything in front of her and felt that the question she suddenly thought of was particularly ridiculous. She reached out and caught a feather in the air. Mom patted the goose feathers out of her down jacket, as if to welcome Huiwen&#39;s chaotic days ahead. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When her parents divorced, Huiwen moved with her father to another city two hundred kilometers away from the power plant. On the day he left, my grandfather stood by the lake with Huiwen in his arms. He didn&#39;t say a few words, he just held her tightly. Huiwen looked up and saw the factory office building opposite, and saw the window she had once looked out of. She remembered that when she sneaked to the mall counter to watch the yo-yo, her mother and Zheng Yang&#39;s father, with Zheng Yang, were sitting at Baifu Burger Restaurant. Eat ice cream inside. Now Huiwen felt extremely disgusted, but towards whom or what, she couldn&#39;t tell. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My mother comes to see her once a month or two, bringing some food and clothing, and talking about the same things. Your Uncle Zheng even went down to the ice lake to save you. My mother said it twice, and she married Zheng Gong six months later. Huiwen wanted to go back and take a look, but her father wouldn&#39;t let her. He pressed the cigarette butt on the coffee table, crushed it, and said, &quot;What are you looking at?&quot; See those bitches changing their faces? I scolded your mother before, but now I&#39;m rushing to drink funeral wine again. &amp;rdquo;Huiwen also wanted to ask if Zheng Yang drank wedding wine or funeral wine. Ask Tian Qiang if he burned his head after falling into the lake. Where is the yo-yo? Ask Miaomiao... I don&#39;t know what to ask. I only looked at the person who fell into the lake, and never thought of Miaomiao again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;QQ became popular when Huiwen was in high school, and somehow she was added to the group of elementary school classmates at the power plant in her computer class. Everyone changed their nicknames to their real names, and she searched for them. Zheng Yang was also in the group, and she never spoke again. The small speaker on the screen coughed twice, and Tian Qiang sent a friend request. Huiwen saw that his QQ level was quite high, and Tian Qiang said, I go to Internet cafes every day, and I can register for you. The bell rang in the corridor, and Huiwen hurriedly got off the line. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After graduating from high school, Huiwen’s grandfather passed away and she returned to the power plant. Tian Qiang&#39;s mother recognized Huiwen and forced her to go to the store to chat. The small shop turned into a large supermarket in the factory. Dried radish and vegetarian beef are still sold, but now Huiwen is holding a few pieces of coin chocolate in her hand, which Tian Qiang&#39;s mother would not be willing to give in the past. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Tell your aunt what university you got admitted to. &amp;rdquo; she asked. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I still study accounting. &quot;After Huiwen finished speaking, she felt a little embarrassed. She originally didn&#39;t want to mention the third-rate university she was admitted to, but she said something else sincerely: She didn&#39;t want to study accounting like her mother. But there was no choice. No matter what the circumstances, this matter seemed to have been waiting for her at this juncture a long time ago. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;College students have great potential no matter what they do. &quot;After Tian Qiang&#39;s mother finished speaking, she took a bottle of drink from the refrigerator and gave it to Huiwen. Huiwen smiled dryly and did not answer her words. No matter how she sounded, she sounded like she was saying that she had no future. I don’t know whether it’s to make fun of herself, or to say that Huiwen’s mother has no future. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The five-story building in the family area feels older and shorter. Those noisy children have been replaced by another group of noisy children, and the power plant has always accommodated their noisiness. Many people in the room were talking in low voices. Huiwen sat on the plastic bench on the balcony and stared at the cooling tower in a daze. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;The old man is not suffering, but is happy and mourning. You no longer have to run back and forth every day. &amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;Your son and daughter are all going to college, so all you have left to do is enjoy yourself. &quot;Several people gathered around Huiwen&#39;s mother to comfort her. Their low voices were like beeps that sounded far and near. Huiwen could not drive away her restlessness. The moment he calmed down, he felt that everything had nothing to do with him. No, it was the wasp that was sitting on my body, trying to insert its sting. Huiwen looked around and saw Zheng Yang. He still acted like the leader he had been when he was a child, but he was devoid of airs and very artificial. He struck up a conversation as soon as he entered the house and began to hug and hold hands with &quot;relatives&quot;, and he could talk to everyone about family affairs. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Yan Huiwen, you are my biological sister. ” Zheng Yang called Huiwen’s name, walked to the balcony and patted Huiwen’s shoulder. Huiwen stared at the small pimple on Zheng Yang&#39;s chin, not daring to look into his eyes. She was unable to clarify her feelings and could only stare at the pimple that was about to come out. From a young girl&#39;s point of view, having a crush on a handsome college student was a completely normal thing in her physical and psychological development. &amp;ldquo;Don&#39;t call me sister. &amp;rdquo;Huiwen ran away after saying that. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A group of people went out from the main entrance of the family courtyard, passed through the power plant gate and back door, circled around the power plant lake, and then returned to the family courtyard. Huiwen had her head wrapped in white cloth and her body covered in linen clothes. The sun was covering her head, making her breathless with heat. &amp;ldquo;You remember, that&#39;s where I fell. Tian Qiang caught up and pointed to the lake to show Huiwen. Huiwen raised her head and looked at Tian Qiang with squinted eyes. &quot;Hey, why are you so high all of a sudden?&quot; When you fall into the lake, you will be about the same height as me. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hui Wen had described the lake countless times in her mind, so there was no point in pointing it out. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Do you have access to QQ? ” Tian Qiang asked. Huiwen glared at him angrily and didn&#39;t want to speak. He was really tanned, but he looked stronger than Zheng Yang&#39;s fair face... Huiwen&#39;s heart thumped, she fanned her clothes a few times, and didn&#39;t think about it any more. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huiwen lives at her grandfather&#39;s house. Her previous home is rented out, and she is not willing to go to the city with her mother for a new house, which is Zheng Yang&#39;s house. The night before she left, Huiwen packed away some books. She passed away, and the remaining treasures were not known to be called treasures. Huiwen was reluctant to throw it away, and Tian Qiang happened to come over. Huiwen asked him to take it home and keep it temporarily. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Three generations of our family combined have probably never read so many books. After Tian Qiang finished speaking, he put down the dried chicken goods that his mother had brought for Huiwen, and went downstairs with the box. Huiwen sounded a little ashamed. Her grandfather was a mechanic and a scholar. When she was a child, her grandfather taught Huiwen about force and reaction, how to hold a pen and how to move. When she grew up, her grandfather only kept telling her on the phone, &quot;Just do it well.&quot; But Huiwen couldn&#39;t study well and didn&#39;t know what to do. Suddenly I wanted to listen to my grandpa&#39;s teachings, but I couldn&#39;t even make a call. The ripples of family misfortune hit the old man and turned into a sigh that was taken to his grave. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After putting the boxes away, they walked along the power plant lake to the supermarket to buy water. Huiwen had not paid attention to it during the day. Only then did she realize that a circle of stones and cement had been built around the lake. It&#39;s those high and low slopes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Where’s Miaomiao, why didn’t I see her in the family home? &amp;rdquo;Huiwen asked Tian Qiang. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;She no longer lives in this courtyard, and she has not been admitted to high school. I am still in a technical school, and she and her parents are selling cold skin in Xiagang Street. Tian Qiang paused for a moment and then said, &quot;Now she works as a front desk clerk at the Metropolis Hotel, and her salary is much higher than mine.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What are you doing? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Just do small jobs, wash cars, repair cars. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tian Qiang kicked the stones on the ground into the lake. Huiwen felt that she was not as good as Tian Qiang. If her family could not afford the tuition for three books, she would not be able to work as a receptionist or a small worker. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Then Zheng Yang is the best. ” Huiwen said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;He doesn’t hang out with us. The red banner he wore when he took the college entrance examination was hung at the entrance of the courtyard for several months in the past two years. He looked so good that the little girl liked him. All good things happen to him. Tian Qiang said, spitting out the tasteless chewing gum on the ground. Thinking of something, he took out the yo-yo from his pants pocket and handed it to Huiwen. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Ah, I remember, I thought they all fell into the lake. Huiwen was surprised, holding the yo-yo with both hands, and even felt that this was the only happy thing recently. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From QQ to Renren, Huiwen kept in touch with Tian Qiang after going to college. There were traces of his pursuit under every update, but compared with Without the convenience of being near the water, Huiwen fell in love like a wave. Eating and watching movies, holding hands ambiguously, staying in a hotel room, and breaking up after graduation. San guided meal friends asked Huiwen, what is the feeling of this relationship without illness? Hui Wen said, it is like being stuffed with a sack, and she is confused. The love scene was finally over, and when she came to the arena of society, Huiwen first found a start-up company to work as a cashier, but it soon closed down, and then applied for a clerkship. Qian Shaoqian had to pay the rent every month and still had to ask her boss. Dad wanted living expenses, so he simply went home. Lao Yan had been working as a salesperson for so many years, but could not make any high-level connections. He asked Huiwen if she wanted to work as a front desk in a big company. If she worked well, she would be able to make a career. Huiwen thought about it and agreed, but the job was not that good. Something happened. She can learn how to dress up, but she can&#39;t handle socializing. She is not a smooth sailing person without strong winds and waves. She doesn&#39;t know what she wants. She thinks she&#39;s noble when she&#39;s happy, but she&#39;s arrogant when something happens. She&#39;s even less knowledgeable about people. Got it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You go work as a cashier first, try your luck to pass the accountant exam, get some qualifications, and then you will be able to move up. &quot;Huiwen&#39;s mother said that there was a suitable iron rice bowl in her hometown, so it was better to go back to her hometown and buy a house for Huiwen. Tian Qiang said that his car wash shop had opened and asked him to go back and have a look. He also said that Zheng Yang was getting married and it would definitely be a big event. Huiwen said that she should go back and take a look first. Lao Yan transferred some money to Huiwen without saying anything to persuade her to keep her. After Huiwen went to college, her father remarried. She would go back to her old home, her new home, or someone else’s home, no matter what, just go back and see her grandpa. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My mother took Huiwen to the curtain market. Huiwen chose the color she liked. After the new house was finished, it felt like her own home. At work, I sometimes go to the tax bureau for a day, and I have a lot of time to hang out in the afternoon. There is also a canteen in the workplace, so I don’t have to worry about what to eat and who to eat with. Whenever a popular movie was released, Tian Qiang would ask Huiwen to watch it, talk about his childhood, and hang around this small place. When Huiwen decided to stay, it seemed to Tian Qiang that she had tacitly agreed to fall in love with him. Huiwen felt that life had entered a gentle ocean for a while. She went back to the family yard of the power plant and moved the books that had been placed at Tian Qiang&#39;s house. She saw the white smoke from the cooling tower reflected in the power plant lake. The smoke was scattered whether in the sky or in the water. The misty things were nowhere to be found in the sky, and the phantoms in the water were all gone. Grandpa said, &quot;Okay, just be okay.&quot; Huiwen decided to let go of all the previous unpleasantness. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She sat at the main table at Zheng Yang&#39;s wedding. Huiwen could only nod and smile in front of all the relatives. She couldn&#39;t say a single word about homely things. She was really out of place sitting upright with a cup in hand. Mother and Zheng Gong walked around the banquet hall with full enthusiasm, appearing very familiar with everyone they knew or didn&#39;t know, and making timely jokes. When the main people finally sat back at the main table, her mother asked Huiwen to toast the bride&#39;s parents and thank them. Huiwen went over to toast and thanked them. Only then did she realize that her job was thanks to them. She put down her wine glass and lowered her head to tear the barbs on her fingers. It wasn&#39;t really a big deal, but the more she pulled, the more painful it became. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Your sister is quite beautiful, why don’t you introduce her to some decent men, Tian Qiang is really cheap. &amp;rdquo;The bride did not shy away from Huiwen, and some words just came to her ears. She sent a WeChat message to Tian Qiang and asked him when he would leave. Tian Qiang said anytime. Huiwen walked out of the box and looked at the tables in the hall. Tian Qiang stood up, grabbed a few packs of cigarettes and put them in his arms. He pointed at the door and asked Huiwen to go out first. Huiwen saw an eye-catching person sitting on the table from a distance. He was wearing a tight-fitting miniskirt, fluffy sandals on his feet, and his white calves. The woman also stared in Huiwen&#39;s direction. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Is that Miaomiao? &quot;Sitting in the car, Huiwen asked Tian Qiang. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;That’s right. Tian Qiang responded to Huiwen with a smile, took a sharp breath and blew out the last smoke from his nose, threw the cigarette butt out of the car window, and then said, &quot;She followed a big boss to Guangdong for a few years, and he gave me She sent back tens of thousands of dollars. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;The mistress? &amp;rdquo;Huiwen asked. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;How can we talk about it? Just give me this little money, even the little four and little five can’t afford it. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tian Qiang bought a second-hand car for Huiwen to use for commuting. Within half a month of driving, two nails were stuck in the tires. Tian Qiang asked Huiwen to stop taking alleyways to the car wash shop. Huiwen complained casually. It was really wicked. The car repair shop on the roadside must have deliberately scattered the nails. Tian Qiang did not agree, and Huiwen suddenly understood that Bad De had come to her door, and she never set foot in the car wash shop again. After a while, Tian Qiang took the initiative and said that he couldn&#39;t always do this kind of business. He wanted to get some money for Huiwen&#39;s house loan, start a second-hand car business, and earn some money to marry Huiwen. Huiwen didn&#39;t want to have any conflicts of interest with Tian Qiang, but he had never asked Huiwen for anything before, so he should help her if she was in trouble. After much deliberation, I decided to get my mother&#39;s permission first. After all, I didn&#39;t buy this house by myself. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huiwen’s mother treated Huiwen as if she were a guest, and she was as kind and kind as a child meeting a guest for the first time. &quot;It&#39;s not that mom doesn&#39;t agree with you, it&#39;s just that I really can&#39;t get it out for the time being. I&#39;m keeping it all in futures. When you get married, I will give you double it.&quot; &amp;rdquo;Huiwen learned that her mother had already used the house to take out a loan. She went back and told Tian Qiang, who said, &quot;Your mother is smarter than you.&quot; ” Huiwen listened to her quarrel, and the two quarreled for a few days and had a cold war for several days. Tian Qiang&#39;s mother came to the work to find Huiwen, and forced Huiwen to go to the mall to buy her a jade bracelet worth tens of thousands of pieces. The scene was really embarrassing, so Huiwen accepted it first and planned to return it to Tian Qiang later. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Someone set off fireworks at the Ice Lake. The children in the family home make a lot of noise and send messages to each other. The first person to know is the most remarkable person. Huiwen and the children who dared not go into the lake stood in a row along the lake. The children looked up at the sky. Huiwen saw Tian Qiang holding a cigarette butt and lighting fireworks in the middle of the lake. This person, as long as he was not born with evil, would be a good person and a bad person at one time or another. Huiwen felt that no matter how he lived, he would be the same no matter who he lived with. Huiwen&#39;s mother said that Huiwen was stubborn and could go on a blind date even if they were in love. After several attempts, Huiwen didn&#39;t appreciate it, so she just ignored it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huiwen and Tian Qiang received their marriage certificates. When they heard that the family home of the power plant was going to be demolished, Tian Qiang&#39;s mother urged the two of them to get the certificate first, saying that they would wait until the new house could be used as a wedding room, and then they would take care of things, or if Huiwen had a child, she would take care of things at any time. Huiwen&#39;s mother looked down on Tian Qiang&#39;s family and had no contact with Tian Qiang&#39;s mother, but their styles were surprisingly similar. They both said &quot;we&#39;ll wait until we get things done.&quot; On one side, the jade bracelet was treated as a low-level offer, and other matters would be discussed later; While saying that the two of them are temporarily living in Huiwen&#39;s house, they will talk about dowry matters later. Huiwen doesn&#39;t think money is important, and &quot;doing things&quot; may not be important either, but it can&#39;t be said to be important. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After half a year, Huiwen and Tian Qiang are going to &quot;do things&quot;. The wedding was held at the hotel that Zheng Yang had hosted before, and it was larger in size. The word &quot;demolished&quot; on the wall of the family courtyard never came. It was not Huiwen who had it, but Zheng Gong who had been promoted. If you get promoted, you won&#39;t have a banquet to keep it low-key, but your daughter&#39;s wedding will have to be a grand affair. Zheng Gong changed into Zheng Bureau. Visitors first drew their names on the gift register with a golden pen. When the etiquette lady next to them bowed, they placed the gift money on the silver tray she held. The etiquette lady took the plate to the back of the sign-in desk, pushed open the door of the storage room, and poured the contents on the plate into the sack. Huiwen moved her feet to make room, and she was changing clothes inside. The wedding dress was too tight, so the bridesmaid loosened it, and Huiwen wanted to stay warm in it for a while. She slumped down on the chair, letting herself huddle in the pile of clothes, staring at the sack of things in a daze, and suddenly remembered how she was unable to move forward or retreat on the frozen lake when she was a child. Someone knocked on the door outside, and Huiwen came back to her senses with a start. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The storage room is not big. Except for the corner where Huiwen is sitting, there are some sundries stacked up in other places and there is no space for people to fit in. Miao Miao came in and closed the door and squatted down leaning on the back of the door. I was so crowded that my long down jacket was out of breath, and the smell of cigarette smoke was everywhere. Huiwen straightened up slightly and lifted the hem of her skirt, waiting for Miao Miao to speak. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You are so lucky. &amp;rdquo;Miao Miao said. As she spoke, she began to cry, her thin body shaking in the fat down jacket, as if it was about to fall from the collar at any time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Stop crying now, you just want to say that you and Tian Qiang are getting along, right? &amp;rdquo;Huiwen was not sure before saying this, but after saying this, she felt that she was quite smart. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Miao Miao was surprised. She wiped her tears and looked up at Huiwen and said, &quot;You know everything.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hui Wen didn’t say anything. She couldn’t say what she wanted to know about this “everyone knows”. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After calming down for a while, Miao Miao said to Huiwen again: &quot;Then you still have to hold a wedding.&quot; &quot;He turned to look at the sack of gift money that was half a man&#39;s height beside him, and sneered, &quot;That&#39;s what we have to do. This will make more money than I can make in my entire life.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huiwen&#39;s eyes stopped on Miaomiao&#39;s feet. She was still wearing those plush slippers. Huiwen asked: &quot;Is it okay when Zheng Yang gets married?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Miao Miao thought for a while and asked Huiwen: &quot;When did your QQ get the sun?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Huiwen changed into her dress and came out of the storage room, the entrance to the banquet hall was already bustling. Miaomiao and Tian Qiang were pulling at each other, and Huiwen could see clearly that Miaomiao&#39;s long white down jacket was stained with blood. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Stop making noise! ” Huiwen shouted. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tian Qiang took Miaomiao to the hospital, but did not keep the child. There was no groom in the wedding ceremony. Director Zheng took the microphone and said a few words, and the banquet ended hastily. However, the rumors caused by this banquet burned in the small place for several months. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Bureau was investigated. Zheng Bureau’s collapse also implicated Zheng Yang’s wife’s family. Her mother was anxious and running around trying to recover some losses. Huiwen also lost her job. , not because he was a related household, but because he was inundated with crazy gossip, and even his employer wanted to avoid suspicion. Some say Huiwen forced someone to death, while others say she is the third party, as virtuous as her mother. Huiwen wondered if the people who said these words were the same people who drank wedding wine and congratulated her. She thought of her father and called him to exchange a few words. She wanted to talk about her divorce but didn&#39;t know where to start. Her father finally spoke after hesitating and asked if her aunt&#39;s brother wanted to study abroad and could he borrow some money. Huiwen hung up the phone and couldn&#39;t help crying. First, she cried about her own difficulties, and secondly, she cried about her father&#39;s difficulties. He never told Huiwen about his difficulties. This time, he lowered his head and her daughter was helpless. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huiwen dug out the suitcase she had used several years ago from the top of the cabinet, and randomly picked up a few coats and put them in it. Her residence was also sealed. The broken wheel on one side of the box rattled and screamed on the sidewalk, dragging it to the concrete floor, and turned into a continuous piercing roar. Huiwen stopped by the lake, stepped into the ice lake, staggered a few steps along the slope, and walked on the ice. The courage to take this step is very delicate. She is afraid of death and afraid of living, but she cannot let herself stop and cannot accept her timidity. She took off her coat and walked toward the center of the lake, feeling herself falling apart as she faced the shattered past beneath her feet. With a muffled sound, they died together. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huiwen fell into the icy lake. The instant coldness penetrated every inch of her body like countless ice blades, forcing her to instinctively look for a way to survive. The floating water under the ice hits the ice, cracks extend outward from the bottom, and the previously strong ice surface becomes soft and fragile. Huiwen stepped on the bottom of the lake and waded through the water, which was more than half a person&#39;s height, and moved slowly to the shore. Her limbs were so stiff from the cold that she could barely sit down. She glanced at the suitcase beside her and suddenly laughed, laughing that she had brought clothes with her. Play with water. Huiwen wrapped her coat around her body and found something in the middle of the box. She opened the zipper and found a yo-yo. She held it tightly in her hand and threw it into the middle of the lake. It&#39;s joy and mourning. She thought of what her grandpa said, just be good, be good. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later the glacial lake disappeared because Power Plant Lake never froze again. What Huiwen can be sure of in her memory is the coldness of the ice lake, its cracks, and the deep and long relief it once gave her. &lt;/p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; Responsible editor: Zhou Ziheng &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; See @ONE Studio on Weibo. Editor&#39;s official WeChat: OneApp2020. Regularly publish Q &amp; A collection, gift books and surrounding gifts, and readers are welcome to add. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Author &lt;/p>; &lt;hr style = &quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style = &quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src = &quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/fvfy2wx6c0ypgpjbvtpgwads4wn &quot;alt =&quot; Fan Qing &quot;>; &lt;/TD>; &lt;div>; Fan Qing &lt;span style =&quot; font-siZe: 10px &quot;>; &amp; nbsp; span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style = &quot;&quot;>; Non-full-day production of dreams &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width = &quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!- &lt;span Onclick = &quot;OneApp.opndetail ) &quot;>; Follow &lt;/span>; ->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>; Related recommendation &lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style =&quot; width: 40px: 40px &quot;>; &lt;span>; Read &lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/5988&quot; data-ajax=&quot;False&quot;>; /Water Fan Sixteen &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;TABLE>; &lt;TD>; &lt;div style = &quot;text-align: center; padding: 5px;&quot; &quot; Onclick = &quot;OneApp.Opendetail (2,6184)&quot;>; Click to download one app &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &amp; nbsp; &lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 06:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4076]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4220]]><description>&lt;div>; 4 DEC. 2023 &amp; Nbsp; &lt;/DIV>; &lt;DIV ROLE = &quot;Main&quot;>; &lt;DIV>; &lt;IMG SRC = &quot;Http://image.wufazhuce.com/fki6zzrped-rcu- V_urh8acik0-&quot; Alt = &quot;Homepage Figure &quot;/&lt;p>; &lt;span>; Vol.4076 &lt;/span>; Photography | Laura Meinhardt &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 4 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Dec. 2023 &lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; I am a person who lives lonely, and loneliness is like food and water. If you don&#39;t be alone for a day, I will become weak. I am not proud of loneliness, but I live in this way. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &amp; nbsp; &lt;/p>; &lt;br>; &lt;hr>; &lt;div>; Get more RSS: &lt;br>; &lt;a href = &quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style = &quot;style =&quot; Color: Orange &quot;target =&quot; _blank &quot;>; https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;cone&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.run &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 04 Dec 2023 06:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>