<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[今日中秋，你有什么心事？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3930]]><description> &lt;div>;29 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Question from ONE Editorial Department&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>; Things often go wrong as you wish, but you can always tell people the same thing. Today is the Mid-Autumn Festival. As a young man in a foreign land, do you have any worries that no one can tell you? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; ONE Friendly Answers&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt; img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fo_z7G3dWInjPEJ9IzRU1HrS_72z&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fo_z7G3dWInjPEJ9IzRU1HrS_72z&quot;>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Coco&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot; false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FtahtQa0QSgwA10aHTxcM3E9Jyy9&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FtahtQa0QSgwA10aHTxcM3E9Jyy9 &quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Ponyo on the Cliff&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgijUdYRGzXadjv2mNC7AhQN4mp-&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image .wufazhuce.com/FgijUdYRGzXadjv2mNC7AhQN4mp-&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Cinema Paradiso&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;br>; &lt;/p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fhtql15t5zw_7hCEXf2ZSqXKnN4Z&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/Fhtql15t5zw_7hCEXf2ZSqXKnN4Z&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Hidden Life&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>; &lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Ft1x9648ra6Dy5fr7-XLaNOS8thv&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Ft1x9648ra6Dy5fr7-XLaNOS8thv&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Falling Leaves Return to Their Roots&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align : center;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fl1FXVSQ9quOIVI6dQNPSCuRKXLL&quot; data-source =&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fl1FXVSQ9quOIVI6dQNPSCuRKXLL&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;Lian Lian Feng Chen&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text -align: center;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fo9PdHjkoIOYmd9JZ75SMF-2z9nI &quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fo9PdHjkoIOYmd9JZ75SMF-2z9nI&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&quot;The Thief of Time&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unsatisfactory things often happen, but Talk to people the same way. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Today is the Mid-Autumn Festival. As a young man in a foreign land, do you have any worries that no one can tell you? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;ONE editorial department wishes you the best Happy Mid-Autumn Festival. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Li Jialong onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see @ONE Studio’s pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8 &quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Complex The cutest people in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3688&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Valentine&#39;s Day Tree Hole | What I Can&#39;t Say to Him&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/ div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Question and Answer&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question /3743&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Paradise Tree Cave｜I miss you (with two poems)&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td >; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3930)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[团聚的负累]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6113]]><description> &lt;div>;29 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Cheng Huizi&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fhr9nQr787AztA-8PGoMP2sp1oA-&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fhr9nQr787AztA-8PGoMP2sp1oA -&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The purpose of festivals is to make people happy. As long as you want, you can spend the originally lively festival in a lonely way. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In &quot;A Dream of Red Mansions&quot;, it is written that Xiangling studied poetry. When the stone was opened, she got eight lines of chanting the moon in her dream, and she wrote the last line Tao: Chang&#39;e should ask herself why she doesn&#39;t want to be reunited forever. Later, people said that the poem hinted at Xiangling&#39;s fate, and they were infinitely saddened by her fate scattered like floating duckweeds. &quot;Eternal reunion&quot; is like an ultimate ideal. Everyone lives happily together, clinking bowls and glasses, drinking and talking, and the long night seems fulfilling and romantic. We have been told and educated since childhood: That is the Chinese tradition, that is the most beautiful moment, we should look forward to it and rejoice for it. On the contrary, if we cannot be reunited, if the wanderer is miserable outside, with his shadow in front of his knees and the lamp beside him, and if his relatives are lost at home, he should still talk about the traveler. The moon is missing, the trees are sparse, the silence is broken, and the wish for reunion is frustrated. It is a regret that cannot be made up for. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Body and aesthetics can be shaped, and so can emotions naturally. The popular summer movie &quot;Barbie&quot; has this opening: Barbie wakes up full of energy and starts a day of exquisite and elegant life. Day after day, even the arc of the smile at the corner of her mouth does not change, until one day, Barbie looks like I was dancing happily with my little sisters as usual, and suddenly a thought came to me - by the way, have you ever thought about dying? (Have you ever thought about death?) The flashing lights went out and the music stopped. Barbie&#39;s smile froze on her face. Everyone looked at her in surprise, as if she had revealed some shocking secret. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I must admit that although the dilemmas we faced were different, at that moment Barbie and I had a resonance. In many moments of toasting together, the glass collided with the glass, and the crisp sound was like some kind of key, opening the floodgate of fear and darkness in my heart, and countless inappropriate thoughts emerged from my mind, even if it was just a flash. And passed. Like everyone else, I said blessings, Happy New Year, all the best, good health, happiness and peace. It was like there was a spring in my mouth, and I could only repeat these words mechanically. What I&#39;m most afraid of is that someone will ask me to &quot;say a few words&quot; at this time. I can&#39;t refuse, I can only shirk it. This has been the case since I first remembered it. They said that I was &quot;coy&quot;, &quot;not generous&quot;, &quot;can&#39;t let go&quot;, &quot;can&#39;t stand on the stage&quot;, and &quot;how will I be a leader in the future&quot;? They were all right and I couldn&#39;t disagree. Someone will come out to help. I am introverted and my child is still young. Sit down first. I will do more exercise next time. They patted my shoulders and pinched my ears, and finally I was able to sit down amid the touching and pinching. I felt a little grateful, mixed with resentment—why? Why should there be a next time? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Reunion means expressing care for each other, hugging each other, and eating steaming meals as a family, but it also means that they will intentionally or unintentionally inquire about your life between chewing on the upper and lower teeth. , such as whether you plan to get married, how much you can earn in a month, and where you want to buy a house in the future. I can prevaricate, but I have to reply, at least without showing impatience, because these are done out of love and care, never malicious. After drinking and drinking, someone will mention &quot;thinking about the past&quot; that has been mentioned countless times, thinking about how much hardship they suffered in those days, or how simple the people were, how blue the sky was, and how much food they had back then. It&#39;s just a pound, and it won&#39;t be adulterated with water. I have listened to that bitter and sweet song countless times, and I know they are nostalgic, a flood of emotions without any reason, and even worthy of sympathy. But later on, the overflowing emotions overwhelmed me and required me to show an attitude of &quot;consideration&quot; and &quot;understanding&quot;. It was not easy for them back then, and they had to put in a lot of hard work to get there. Today, these words are hanging on the table, waiting for someone to pick them up and add the second half of the sentence. Don&#39;t worry, you don&#39;t have to worry about it now. I will take care of you in the future - they are not true. The younger generation should be responsible for the rest of their lives. They just want to hear that sentence and feel at ease after hearing it-but I am the one who cannot say that sentence. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My mother said that if I don’t have a sweet mouth, I won’t get into trouble. When I get older, I just want to hear a few nice words. So what’s wrong with you? As my mother said, I have really made no progress at all over the years. This is probably a natural aptitude, and &quot;exercise&quot; does not work. That kind of mixed feeling of anger, anxiety, fatigue and sympathy made people uneasy. After the meal, the thought of leaving the table came up repeatedly, but was suppressed by the remaining reason. I often get stomachaches after such dinner parties. When my mother asked about it, I just said that I had a bad stomach and ate something unclean outside. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Of course I know they only have rough kindness towards me. Love is true love, and caring is true caring. After I went to college, I could only go home during the holidays throughout the year, and there were not many opportunities to meet. Naturally, they wanted to hear what I had to say, but I couldn&#39;t do it. And I treat them the same way. For daily purchases, daily conversations, and taking care of them when they are sick, I am willing to give without water of affection and will never be stingy. Love and care are real, but they are just a ritual of reunion. The imagination and expectation given to the act of reunion make me tired and scared. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For a while, I doubted whether I was born &quot;cold-blooded&quot; and thought I was a weirdo, at least different from most people. Others&#39; wish for &quot;eternal reunion&quot; seems to me to be a burden, even a terrible curse. I can&#39;t imagine a life together forever. That, like eternal loneliness, means the ultimate challenge to the psychological bottom line. It is said that in Japan, children no longer live with their parents when they reach adulthood and have little contact with them. Sometimes they do not see each other once throughout the year and only send each other New Year&#39;s cards. After thinking about it, I&#39;m afraid I can&#39;t accept this kind of life. Being so alienated makes me feel guilty and uneasy, and I can&#39;t bear to be like this. To use a vulgar saying, being neither affectionate nor unfeeling enough is the biggest burden of being a fence-sitter. and dilemma. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The sense of ritual is like a thread that fills up the usual relaxed life. As soon as the bow string is loosened, the tense self is shot into the round table, and then slowly consumed by changing cups and cups, and with friends , this is true with my family, basically gatherings of more than four people will make me feel stressed. I am willing to go shopping with my mother, go for a walk with my father, go to my grandparents’ house after dinner, and chat with them about the recent weather. As long as there is no reunion ceremony, these are not big problems. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Yiwei wrote a novel &quot;I Really Don&#39;t Want to Come&quot; in his early years, which told a similar story. Luo Qingqing, who is 17 or 18 years old, has just been admitted to college. During the Chinese New Year, she returned to her grandmother&#39;s rented house to fulfill her obligation to reunite. She had to face old family traditions, complicated interpersonal relationships, and a low economic self-esteem. She felt sorry for her mother&#39;s hard work and understood her grandmother&#39;s obsession. Faced with her aunt&#39;s family&#39;s efforts to show off their face, she just saw through it without saying anything. Her grandmother asked her to kneel in front of the memorial tablet of the deceased, thank her for blessings, and pray for peace. This was very different from the modern education she had received, but even though her heart was in turmoil, she still obeyed her orders obediently. Such a subtle story, written in the capillaries, moved me. People are full of confusion and inconsistencies in the ethical structure of private life. I understood that I was not alone. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The imagination of reunion is not limited to Chinese people. This is probably a common obsession at home and abroad in ancient and modern times. Italian director Tornatore, in addition to the well-known &quot;Time and Space Trilogy&quot;, he also made a relatively unpopular movie, &quot;Family Journey&quot;. The old father walked out of the house, traveled around the European continent, visited his adult children, and planned a reunion dinner. In his imagination, the children have successful careers and live happy lives. In order to satisfy their father&#39;s imagination, the children have decorated their unsatisfactory lives into perfection. After the journey, everyone is exhausted. For the imaginary utopia of happiness, everyone paid a price, and the final reunion dinner was built on layers of lies, like a dangerous building. The fantasy of the father&#39;s dream and the cruelty of reality can be established at the same time and contrasted with each other, and people are chewing on it. No one can deny that an anticipated reunion places a heavy physical and mental burden on everyone. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My mother said to me, you young people are just living &quot;alone&quot; and staring at computers and mobile phones every day. How can you regard going home as a burden? Your family is looking forward to your return. . This kind of modern anxiety is difficult to explain. The popularity of the Internet is certainly an important cause, but I think there may be other reasons. I have to admit that being alone is the most comfortable way of life for me. There was once a &quot;loneliness level chart&quot; that became popular on the Internet. Except that no one has ever had surgery, I have experienced everything else. It has long been common to eat, go shopping, drink coffee, and watch movies alone. Without anyone around you, you can eat and watch movies according to your own wishes. You don’t have to be afraid to hang out in shops and compare them in front of your friends. When bargaining, you don’t have to worry about other people’s time and rush to complete tasks. Time and life are in your own fingers. It’s up to you to hold on tight or squander it. After several studies, I also gained experience in moving alone. I packed the boxes and sorted them into categories. Several square boxes were placed in front of me, and I felt refreshed. Even when traveling with my partner or friends, I often think of going out for a walk while everyone is resting, seeing unfamiliar cities and streets, taking a subway ride I have never taken before, and exploring the surrounding area alone. The novelty of the world is really fascinating - it&#39;s not that I am stingy about sharing. In my opinion, sharing and experiencing alone are two different things. They are not a fish-and-bear&#39;s relationship. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kafka once wrote in his diary, My name is Kafka, which is Hebrew and means cave bird. As the name suggests, the cave bird is a bird that lives in its own cave for a long time. This image was often used as a metaphor for Kafka himself and became Kafka&#39;s expression of self-understanding and his imagination of his ideal life state. He also has a novella &quot;The Burrow&quot;, in which he writes about a mole who always hides underground. Alone, he devotes himself to building a burrow for many years and guards his castle in fear. &quot;A mole that I should always worry about.&quot; Something, something I should always be prepared for: someone is coming. &amp;rdquo;This story made me laugh endlessly. Although it does not pursue an extreme personal life like a mole, a cave bird, or Kafka, the Kafka-style lifestyle is indeed becoming more and more popular. I told my friends that if Kafka was still alive, we would definitely smile knowingly because of the stories he wrote. My friend said, how is it possible? Kafka wanted to run away when he saw people, how could he be willing to meet people? You still want to smile at him, which shows that you are not Kafka enough. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When the time of reunion comes, I still long for a relatively relaxed state: if I go home, we can meet each other in daily life, and dinner and alcohol are not necessary; if we can’t go home, we can go our separate ways. Spend this ordinary day in each other&#39;s place, because the status of family in our hearts will not change just because of an absent reunion. It&#39;s not that who comes back, life is good, but who doesn&#39;t come back, life is boring. Parasitizing the joy of life on others is dangerous and cruel to both parties. People live together for a long time, and it is enough to know that each other is living well, so why bother to obsess over an unnecessary ceremony. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I am busy with my studies and have not been home for a long time. One afternoon when the weather was nice, I ordered coffee and cake for afternoon tea. Thinking that my mother likes sweets, I ordered another takeaway to be delivered to my house. I didn&#39;t order her coffee, but replaced it with hot chocolate, because I was afraid she wouldn&#39;t be able to sleep at night. When my mother received the takeaway, she complained that I spent money indiscriminately, and then asked me, what are you doing? I took a photo of the coffee and cake and sent it to her. After a while, she also sent a photo of an empty cup and some wrapping paper. All finished! My stomach is so full! She added several exclamation points and a smiley face. I asked her, is it delicious? She replied, &quot;It&#39;s delicious.&quot; I said, as long as it tastes good. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That day was just an ordinary day. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Nana&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For information about the call for papers, please see the @ONE Studio pinned on Weibo. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FslYZuaFJjFILh_P5BuPz84SRPAs&quot; alt=&quot;Cheng Huizi&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Cheng Huizi&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@that yingchu yunxiao road &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&quot;Pretend to be loyal to your ideals.&quot;&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP. openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style= &quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/5981&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Evening Breeze&lt;/div>; &lt; div>;Text/Cheng Huizi&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td >; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6107&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Ferry&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Yu Bing&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6113)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/ div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4010]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4146]]><description>&lt;div>;29 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fn6Z8KcM55NeCd2wwc0hwvRb-rec&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4010&lt;/span>;Illustration | Teddy Kang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;29&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sep. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Life It should be dedicated completely.&lt;br />;As much as you keep for yourself,&lt;br />;there will be as much sorrow as possible. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 29 Sep 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>