<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[一周的心情｜本周小记精选]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3935]]><description> &lt;div>;1 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Question from ONE Editorial Department&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>; It&#39;s been a week, how are you? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; ONE Friendly Answer&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1 ;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The holiday is finally here, how are you ONE friends? Listen, there is a new echo in the tree hole. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com /FiUWX96mI_wrAG71cBEtsa3CKc-M&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FiUWX96mI_wrAG71cBEtsa3CKc-M&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data -original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FrgVS_y7IYLt0rsYNrQTPfk20MAV&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FrgVS_y7IYLt0rsYNrQTPfk20MAV&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false &quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Ft8bV7ggPC54QyTJtMj6CrcpvuZ8&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Ft8bV7ggPC54QyTJtMj6CrcpvuZ8&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FoD1m7TPy0FlPfKn6srej-D9AAWw&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src= &quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FoD1m7TPy0FlPfKn6srej-D9AAWw&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce .com/Fmp4XC41BPDBcGV6lK14-hDPtwuX&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fmp4XC41BPDBcGV6lK14-hDPtwuX&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot; &quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FlUhw298XYXwNq88Dw1hxXgSQCWO&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FlUhw298XYXwNq88Dw1hxXgSQCWO&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable= &quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fi4IjACX40hQJmtFZnIqzSlsrCav&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/ Fi4IjACX40hQJmtFZnIqzSlsrCav&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FrJIIZDKvtnLNIF73-EcC8iXQ820&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FrJIIZDKvtnLNIF73-EcC8iXQ820&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image .wufazhuce.com/FiJOaeid3riiLN4UNobHerO0J036&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FiJOaeid3riiLN4UNobHerO0J036&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data -original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FjuUKpYIFXJdTj8DDp8z92bCEwDW&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FjuUKpYIFXJdTj8DDp8z92bCEwDW&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false &quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpuanaiNjf_RAQ2JWP0Dc3ZtrFEB&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpuanaiNjf_RAQ2JWP0Dc3ZtrFEB&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FtkHzKks1aSoZGZyrLOJv9Yu_ktj&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http ://image.wufazhuce.com/FtkHzKks1aSoZGZyrLOJv9Yu_ktj&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FiCUOjjXsNNYv4Hlz6BqtN5puvnL &quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FiCUOjjXsNNYv4Hlz6BqtN5puvnL&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot; http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fta39i9hOCWG9GG751BAIB0Qnu24&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fta39i9hOCWG9GG751BAIB0Qnu24&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data- author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fo79FIqUpvMAWcpfbLufzGu8JFyA&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fo79FIqUpvMAWcpfbLufzGu8JFyA&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt; div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fnll_Vb_uG3vZ3f6x3H125JGRBCF&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce .com/Fnll_Vb_uG3vZ3f6x3H125JGRBCF&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FtLzzDvZVJsx2WHcaxi4B_3vnSeA&quot; data-source=&quot; &quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FtLzzDvZVJsx2WHcaxi4B_3vnSeA&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Zhou Ziheng onewenti@ wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Click &quot;that pen&quot; below the date stamp on the homepage to leave your life moments and your unexplainable feelings in the tree hole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8 &quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Complex The cutest people in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3921&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;My mood of the week | Selected notes of the week&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, 3935)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[蝉蜕时]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6114]]><description> &lt;div>;1 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;文／水法综合&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FtgzEvKzwl7FO5AWPwVjCShgL6Di&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FtgzEvKzwl7FO5AWPwVjCShgL6Di&quot;>;&lt; /div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;When love changes quietly over a long period of time, lovers often realize it later. of. When Wei Jie wondered whether her boyfriend Li Youcheng was proposing or had cheated on her, some things were already doomed. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There were no pedestrians on the road, and the hot sunshine seemed to shine on our faces. We had nowhere to hide, so we had to face it. With strong enthusiasm, he raised his head, gave all his courage, and walked in stride in response to the scorching wind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At this moment, I didn’t dare to have any emotions, and I concentrated on feeling the large beads of sweat secretly appearing everywhere on my body. They were clinging to my thin shirt in groups, and they were sweating from the inside. came out. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wei Jie took my hand and stopped suddenly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You don’t think Li Youcheng would really stick with others and do all sorts of things, right? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;No, the hotel has air conditioning, which is more comfortable than what we have now. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wei Jie nodded and we continued walking forward. No matter what I say, she keeps going. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We were sitting in the lobby of the Park Hyatt Hotel, arranging our appearance in front of the glass window. Wei Jie&#39;s makeup was extremely strong, but half of her false eyelashes fell off. She held up a mirror that was no bigger than a palm and teased her eyes. We are not here to stay in a hotel, nor are we here to go on a blind date. We are here to catch an adulterer. We didn&#39;t have any plans except to park the car in a shopping mall not far away. We were like two tourists who were driven here by the heat wave. We sat down in a big way, but we didn&#39;t want others to see through our embarrassment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My imagination of this kind of scene is limited to all kinds of bloody scenes in movies and TV dramas. Are we going to rush in and beat up Li Youcheng? So how do we get in? Or call the police? What to say to the police? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Based on my understanding of myself and Wei Jie, I can’t even imagine what we would do. Wei Jie seemed to be imagining calmly. The heat subsides and we are gracefully waiting for some kind of judgment or some kind of disaster to come. All we can do is close our eyes and pray that the moment in front of us disappears or is interrupted. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Finally, Wei Jie stood up with her bag under her arms. It seemed that she had escaped the stagnant time in front of her. I followed her and thought about my role - to be her minion. When she accused me, I would scold me harshly. When she was angry, I would point and hit her wherever she went. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The staff at the front desk were smart and alert, with their heads raised far away and smiling politely at the uninvited guests like us. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Hello, I would like to extend my stay. &amp;rdquo;Wei Jie is polite and peaceful. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Hello, madam. Who made the reservation? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Li Youcheng. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Okay madam, I will help you check that the room has been checked in today. How many more days do you need to extend your stay? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;One day first. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Okay madam, could you please show me your ID? I’ll help you handle it here. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;My ID card? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;No, madam, you need the ID of the person who made the reservation. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was just about to step forward to negotiate and argue my case. Isn’t this the time when I need to use strong arguments? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Understood, thank you. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After Wei Jie finished speaking, she turned around and stopped me, dragging me by the waist and leaving the front desk. I was like the dominatrix who was dictating things from behind and preparing to cause trouble. I was kicked out of the hotel by her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Separated by a glass door, the inside and outside of the door are far apart. The sun is still waiting for us, as if it is only for two people to go to work today. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As soon as we left the shelter of the building, we were stared at by the light of a searchlight. The light held up our bodies and pushed us forward, and the back of our necks that it brushed felt hot. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There were more and more people on the road, cicadas were chirping everywhere, and it was so noisy that we couldn’t hear each other’s voices. We all stepped into the tree-lined path at the same time. The light sent a few strands of his henchmen to track the woman fleeing among the trees. Two tall shadows cast a fight on the sidewalk tiles, and we gestured with our hands and feet under the backlight and laughed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When we declare to the world &quot;we are in love&quot; with excitement, it is like a &quot;boiling competition&quot; has officially started. Look at this love. How long can a pot of muddy water boil? Wei Jie officially met Li Youcheng, even on a hot summer day, it seemed that the water was already boiling even without the addition of love. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At that time, Wei Jie wanted to lose weight and went to the playground to run laps every night. I don’t know from which day, Li Youcheng and her secretly competed with each other. The two of them tacitly agreed that whoever stopped first would be lose. One day Li Youcheng didn&#39;t go. He suffered from heatstroke because he turned on a small stove for himself during the day to practice. Wei Jie sat on the edge of the hospital bed and laughed at him, saying it was the first time she saw a person who didn&#39;t even bet anything and still wanted to win so much. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Now that I think about it, there was a lot of competition in their love. For so many years, even if they had a quarrel and a cold war, no one would break up first. The same goes for reconciliation. The person who is forced to speak first by circumstances is the one who bows his head. If someone is planning a surprise, the most respectful thing to do is to ignore it, wait for the surprise to come, and express your true feelings and emotions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Wei Jie returned home from overseas after half a month, she found fresh tulips on display at home. I asked Li Youcheng and he said it was a gift from a colleague and the project was negotiated. The wardrobe was sorted with seasonal clothes, and I also found the sunglasses I thought I had lost when I went on a trip a few years ago. Li Youcheng didn&#39;t say much. He was neither cold nor enthusiastic. Until Wei Jie accidentally found out about booking a hotel, this emotion was naturally understood as a prelude to a surprise. The pot of their love has indeed been tepid for too long. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Proposal? I thought you two would suddenly decide to get married one day, maybe even without a wedding. &amp;rdquo;I&#39;m a little surprised. Wei Jie told me that she thought Li Youcheng was going to propose to her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Maybe there will be such a day, but I think it will come later. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We sat face to face in a booth in the book bar. It was like a boring day in the past, when I picked up a few books and chatted about irrelevant topics. It was in such an empty and confused gap that Wei Jie suddenly mentioned this matter. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past few days after she came back, she accidentally saw a message reminder on Li Youcheng&#39;s smart bracelet - a notification about the successful hotel reservation. The hotel is not cheap for one night, but after checking it was a suite. She recalled Li Youcheng&#39;s recent &quot;suspicious changes&quot; in detail, and blamed herself for being petty, feeling that she lacked care for her lover. Just as he was about to reflect, he smiled wryly, lowered his eyebrows and began to lament, how to maintain the dignity of the other party and politely decline the proposal. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wei Jie has always been resolute and resolute. She is a girlfriend who never &quot;chases&quot;, a roommate who never &quot;finds&quot; a job, and a partner who never &quot;breaks down&quot; an appointment. The only thing about getting married has been three years and three years. This is their eighth year. Wei Jie runs an outdoor camp with her father and has been traveling frequently between Anji and Hangzhou in the past two years; Li Youcheng works as a project curator and is a frequent visitor to Shanghai and Beijing. The two of them had a tacit understanding and lived their lives as usual when they were together and when they were not together. The most intense conflict was a dispute and a two-month cold war caused by the assumptions between the two during the chat: If they were married, would they still live like this? A camp has just started and entered the status quo, and the relationship network of a project has been established. Then let’s live like this, live it first. Living a life has brought us to today, and we still live like this. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;June 28? Six plus two makes eight? &amp;rdquo;Wei Jie is studying why the hotel is scheduled for this day. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Sixty-two! ” (meaning fool in Hangzhou dialect) I laughed at her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She threw the books she was reading randomly on the table, and there were so many things going on, as if the proposal was already finalized. Afterwards, I realized that the finger that had been scratched felt a dull pain, but I could no longer find out which page was causing the trouble. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I don’t want to answer her questions precisely because I understand her. Answering &quot;Why not get married&quot; is as difficult a question as answering &quot;Why not get married&quot;. Except for those who need marriage to solve their immediate troubles, I, a person who does not marry for troubles, can&#39;t think of any benefits worth mentioning. If I solved any trouble, it was the trouble of &quot;I have to get married&quot;. I realized that I would get married eventually. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wei Jie may also have this understanding. Even if she is reluctant, she will still fantasize about the scene of being proposed to, of course, it is only a one-on-one scene. She said that this ceremony was the highest level of recognition for being a life partner, but she didn&#39;t want a prize, she just wanted to respond: You are interested. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Our chat ranged from story samples of married young people around us to entertainment gossips of married celebrities, and even family manuscripts including myself. There are various signs that this ceremony is more like a memorial ceremony for love. From then on, &quot;private matters&quot; became &quot;official matters,&quot; and it was so scary that even the frequency of having sex had to be calculated carefully. Speaking of which, I am pleased with Wei Jie&#39;s persistence. She is more sure than I am about whether she wants it now or not now. And I like to add a sentence at the end, but don’t want it now? What to do next? So I got married. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We decided to go out and take a breather. Go for it! She said this with a few exclamation points behind it, as if there was a scourge outside. She walked in front with her head held high and without hesitation, raised her hands above her head, pushed open the transparent curtain at the entrance of the mall, stepped out, turned around and stood respectfully to one side, and opened a page of curtains for me. I stared into her eyes and walked out slowly, and I said, Miss, thank you. She nodded and smiled, she could just call her Mrs. Li. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I actually had tears in my eyes. I think of the cold war they had over assumptions a few years ago. Wei Jie said, if marriage is a compromise, then love is a funeral. Who wants to go to the funeral? Afterwards, no one mentioned the marriage again. I think this change in identity, if not because of love, is because of fear of not being loved. Love that lasts for many years will also become shrewd. There was nothing at the funeral. I don’t know whether the cooked love was the calm soup base in the pot or the mixed ingredients. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is a ground fountain in the center of the square. A naughty child stepped on the eye of the fountain with his foot. The water column spread out and pounced on the passers-by. Wei Jie and I screamed and ran away in the distance. We ran into the blazing midday sun, holding a parasol together and scolding the child who just didn&#39;t know the importance of it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During those few days, this matter was on my mind, but Wei Jie didn’t mention it again, and I couldn’t ask about it. Li Youcheng is always more mature than Wei Jie, I think he will plan well. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wei Jie did not receive any hint the night before. She sent me a message and asked me to take leave the next day to accompany her to find out. I think love is really harmful. Going from one extreme to another can only allow us to understand ourselves more deeply, but not the other person. The overlap of time is just a trap. It is the biggest cover-up of love. As long as the crudest technical changes are used, lovers&#39; confidence in each other can fall apart overnight. The pot of love can be filled with bricks and mortar, and it can also be filled with oil and vinegar. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Youcheng went to work as usual in the morning. Wei Jie gave him another morning. She arranged herself to be very busy with her grooming and grooming, and assigned me to keep an eye on her mobile phone. There would be no movement. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wei Jie drove the car and forgot who started the car. We chatted for a long time about Li Youcheng - Li Youcheng from university, Li Youcheng from graduation, and Li Youcheng from work. The car stopped in front of the traffic light and braked when the yellow light flashed. The front of the car was pressed against the zebra crossing and we stared at the countdown time. The unfinished conversation just now seemed to be swallowed up by the stopped cars chasing after me. No one was talking anymore. I had to move forward as soon as the count ended. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The sunlight inevitably streamed in through the cab window, so intense that it seemed to separate Wei Jie into light and dark halves, and also broke the silence in the car - she clicked the button Music was played. It was an extremely noisy scene, and before the prelude was over, she quickly turned it off again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We didn’t find the elevator, so we had to walk out of the underground garage of the shopping mall. When we reached the road, we remembered that no one had taken an umbrella, and we were too lazy to turn back. We just dodged left and right in vain under the bright sun. . Who would know all this? In the year of graduation, Wei Jie moved to Li Youcheng&#39;s house with her suitcase that was about to break. I was carrying her large and small bags. I was also walking in such a boring and long summer, so I didn&#39;t have to free a hand. Block out sunlight. In just a few years, the sun becomes mature and cannot be despised. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For the first time, Wei Jie showed her distrust of Li Youcheng. I don’t know if it was because of her age or other reasons. She said &quot;I want to see who is outside him&quot;, which is a declarative sentence. , instead of &quot;Did he cheat?&quot; &amp;rdquo;Such a question. I think this distrust is more about questioning myself. I have to face up to my feelings in a panic and clean up the mess made over the years. If it&#39;s a proposal, I&#39;ll agree; if it&#39;s cheating, I&#39;ll fight against it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I want to tell Wei Jie that this is just a self-righteous desperation. But I can&#39;t say it, what a private experience love is. Because of this, we are more willing to pass the blame and retain our own justice for love. I can only support all her decisions and allow her to briefly become an irrational woman. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We finally entered the revolving door of the Park Hyatt Hotel. After a short pause and negotiation, I was kicked out by her. I don’t know if I staged the moment of losing her mind on her behalf. She found another answer different from “promise” and “crusade”. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That is, say goodbye peacefully. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When the car drove out of the underground garage, the sky darkened, and the skyline stretched between two tall buildings. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;That piece doesn’t look like a huge glass. &amp;rdquo;I gestured with my hand to the bottom of the cup on the skyline and the boundary of the cup body created by two tall buildings. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Like. When we walked out there, it still contained watermelon juice. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;But it’s all finished now. &amp;rdquo;We said this together and laughed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We were also little people flying across the skyline just now. After getting on the elevated road, the view becomes wider, and I always feel that everything that made people confused before gradually becomes transparent. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The car drove downhill in a secret deceleration. I woke up from the feeling of being in the air, and it turned out to be a leisurely dusk sleep. Someone called my name under the smoky purple sky outside the window. I tidied my desk casually. The book that scratched my finger was a university book that was still brand new near the end of the semester. textbook. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One person holding an umbrella turned into two people soaking in the rain. That day, we didn’t have to wait for the rain to stop, we held hands and kept running, running from summer to last year’s summer. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The melody of the electric guitar suddenly rose unexpectedly, the light stick pointed in a random direction, and the two faces illuminated in the shadowy crowd sang to the wrong beat at the same time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There seems to be no trace, so why can there be traces when you look back? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Youcheng came back from get off work and sat on the sofa with Wei Jie, cutting the watermelon in half and not finishing each half. Proposal, cheating, sweetness, crusade, nothing happened. Night fell as scheduled, and the two of them actively retreated and transferred to each other along with the cicadas chirping outside the window, and so did the cicadas. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wei Jie and I stayed in the book bar, chatting about this endless accident, feeling that the cracks in our relationship had already appeared. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Perhaps one day, two people, in the same home, closed the door of their own room, and from the moment &quot;we&quot; became &quot;you&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is really a huge and laborious breakup trip. Through you, I reached the age of twenty-eight, a mixture of good and bad, love and hate. There will never be a more stable summer than this. As soon as I step into the grass, the long grass, caught in the chaos of war, intertwines with each other and resists, covering up the fact that the cicadas are crushed underfoot. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As we walked into the shade, children hurried past in the scorching sun. This social gathering is really not as good as someone who has let down whom, and it is worse than ending it hastily and indifferently. It is as peaceful as the past summers have been spent this way, as peaceful as if this summer has never come. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I&#39;m leaving. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was still the knowledge that had been blurted out countless times at the moment of farewell, but the door that was closed this time was closed forever. If all the pain of transformation can be forgotten, I think I will definitely remember that I once wanted to fly so much because I loved you. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Zhou Ziheng&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For information about the call for papers, please see @ONE Studio’s top Weibo post. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/Fpa85Q61gcB5Eb1XPgn_fOJEIdWG&quot; alt=&quot;Shui Fan Sixteen&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Shui Fan Sixteen&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@水面Sixteen&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Part-time production of Dream Home&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP. openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style= &quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Read&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6057&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Park the car at Sunrise Moon Between the Fall&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Shui Fan Shiliu&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading &lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6107&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Ferry&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Yu Bing&lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6114) &quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>; Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4012]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4154]]><description>&lt;div>;1 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FtsdAqwko3CDyZ9JzU39oPGNA6rB&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;VOL.4012&lt;/span>;Photography | Chuttersnap&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oct. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Travel is a journey along the way Follow the folds of the earth and enter a state of complete confusion. The biggest uncertainty is not arrival, but how to get there. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 01 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>