<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[一周的心情｜本周小记精选]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3961]]><description> &lt;div>;29 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Question from ONE Editorial Department&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>; It&#39;s been a week, how are you? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; ONE Friendly Answer&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1 ;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The weather is getting colder, remember to put on some clothes. On the weekend, listen, there is a new echo in the tree hole. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com /FkTX3aWtP8ThFXPxjI52nINWkbCH&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FkTX3aWtP8ThFXPxjI52nINWkbCH&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src =&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FrECpckzJhZ_HHG5OIMOBIzN4ApO&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FrECpckzJhZ_HHG5OIMOBIzN4ApO&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fu561nPzFUbDkJANryHKuj2DIaUO&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fu561nPzFUbDkJANryHKuj2DIaUO&quot;>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fmjr7w8Jac17Iuqf7tTxnoDHPspo&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image .wufazhuce.com/Fmjr7w8Jac17Iuqf7tTxnoDHPspo&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FqcebHjDIPW6LKFa2sorAFRQiynt&quot; data-source =&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FqcebHjDIPW6LKFa2sorAFRQiynt&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http:// image.wufazhuce.com/FtrCDMuQz3eemHfJYGApdZJ3Q9Ww&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FtrCDMuQz3eemHfJYGApdZJ3Q9Ww&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmWNB4-mdff8DRUOyrGIp3HHY4Fp&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmWNB4-mdff8DRUOyrGIp3HHY4Fp&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt; div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fh_jEo4s4t55TyVsEaa0ShEC7iiv&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce .com/Fh_jEo4s4t55TyVsEaa0ShEC7iiv&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fjs9gJB9OO5a85IBXgpF7ongY9MM&quot; data-source=&quot; &quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fjs9gJB9OO5a85IBXgpF7ongY9MM&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image. wufazhuce.com/Furt06W1ZhvtOrQxMZK9ZToga47N&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Furt06W1ZhvtOrQxMZK9ZToga47N&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data- original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmNt6S1f8btW0HyZXOX6SVeEdjRi&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmNt6S1f8btW0HyZXOX6SVeEdjRi&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot; >;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FvEWCoWI5nivlZF7GYXkzhp7HBJN&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FvEWCoWI5nivlZF7GYXkzhp7HBJN&quot;>; &lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FqpuWTMWOOiKA-psqWSsxAMeaE5E&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot; http://image.wufazhuce.com/FqpuWTMWOOiKA-psqWSsxAMeaE5E&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce. com/Ft_4aTuHGnFqp89S-j5iFp8CmDAO&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Ft_4aTuHGnFqp89S-j5iFp8CmDAO&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fql0OPLnFrffhPOdVUPHkAr6wdYH&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fql0OPLnFrffhPOdVUPHkAr6wdYH&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot; false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FoluYUCXVjDVYPTBYcQv2pFsSTyJ&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FoluYUCXVjDVYPTBYcQv2pFsSTyJ &quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpPpb7bgbwG-UGwz_tBvWrr-tq1B&quot; data-source=&quot; &quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpPpb7bgbwG-UGwz_tBvWrr-tq1B&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor: Zhou Zihengonewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Click on the &quot;pen&quot; under the date signature on the homepage to leave your life moments and your unexplainable feelings in the tree hole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8 &quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Complex The cutest people in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3953&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;My mood of the week | Selected notes of the week&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, 3961)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[今夜星光灿烂]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6145]]><description> &lt;div>;29 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Ren Shuoran&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FncMlOeFOwuYd9X3EKGyj9FvJLDZ&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FncMlOeFOwuYd9X3EKGyj9FvJLDZ&quot;>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The mysterious cat, the dying grandmother, the damp smell of the village in the city. In this high-end apartment, Tang Ying alone connected all the riddles in the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Tang Ying came back from outside and stood in front of door 1801 to press the password. He hesitated whether to open the umbrella to the corridor or take it into the house. There was a light rain outside, and the water droplets shone brightly in the dim light of the corridor. The community is a high-end community in Zhucheng, with a swimming pool. She doesn&#39;t know whether umbrellas can be placed in the corridors of high-end communities. Just as he was thinking about it, the door of 1802 opposite opened, and a middle-aged man with a head as smooth as a potato poked his head out. Seeing Tang Ying, he smiled, causing the nasolabial folds on his forehead and sides of his nose to slide down. Tang Ying nodded at him, entered the password, took the umbrella and entered the house. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tang Ying changed into slippers at the entrance. There was a little yellow duck on the slippers, which seemed to have been worn by another woman. She took a look, called &quot;Meow Meow... Meow Meow&quot;, found a plastic bag to put the umbrella in, and wiped away the water droplets dripping on the floor. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xiao Wu did not appear. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Xiang sent a message telling Tang Ying that there was a cat at home. &quot;Xiaowu is a new student, he doesn&#39;t feel safe, so be careful.&quot; &amp;rdquo;Sounds like a threat. The rain outside the window has subsided, the clouds are rolling, and the sun is shining through the thick clouds and falling on the carpet in the living room, casting a few rays of shadow. There were no cats, but the cat food Tang Ying had placed in the food bowl had become less and less in the past two days. This is also shown in the movie. The poor boy helps the girl who travels to Africa feed the cat every day, but the cat named Boil never appears. When the courier rang the doorbell, Tang Yingzheng saw the boy calling the cat at the girl&#39;s house. Tang Ying usually likes to read movies and novels, and it is always safe to spend a few hours experiencing other people&#39;s stories. When Xiao Wu didn&#39;t come out, Tang Ying gave up calling him and felt somewhat relieved. Cats belong to women, and the cat demons in movies are always women. When women face women, they always look at and compare them. This is what a blogger who teaches people about falling in love says. After putting away the cat food, Tang Ying lay on the carpet in the living room and heard &quot;You look so beautiful when you smile, like spring flowers&quot; playing in the community kindergarten outside the window. It turns out that kindergartens everywhere like to play this song. Tang Ying originally thought that only the kindergarten in the urban village where she rented would play it. She wonders whether the baby she gave birth to will look good when she smiles, she thought. Tang Ying is already thirty years old, reaching the upper limit of the optimal childbearing age widely circulated on social media. If there were no such &quot;limitations&quot; in life, Tang Ying would feel that his entire world and time would be as beautiful as a scroll. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Three days ago, Tang Ying moved into Zhang Xiang&#39;s house. Tang Ying and Zhang Xiang have only known each other for three days. Tang Ying had just resigned that day and got drunk at the bar, and so did Zhang Xiang. Zhang Xiang is the kind of elite who is easily recognized at a glance. He has a high degree of education and a high income. He looks like a dog. He wears a tie to work and goes to a bar for a drink after get off work. That night Tang Ying and Zhang Xiang returned home. When he woke up, Zhang Xiang received a call and said that the old man at home was dying, so he packed his things and returned to his hometown. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Xiang told her the password to the door, but did not mention how long it would take to return, nor how long she could stay. Within three days, Tang Ying went back to the rental house, took some clothes and daily necessities, and stayed at Zhang Xiang&#39;s house. He told her to feed the cat, and she acquiesced that she could move in. Tang Ying had never lived in such a big house. It was transparent from north to south. She could wake up to the sun in the morning. She lay on the carpet in the living room and felt the sun exploring her face. The phone vibrated, and Zhang Xiang&#39;s message came in. &amp;ldquo;Are you still at my house? Thank you for taking care of Xiaowu the past two days. Today, housekeeping sister Wang will come to clean the house. My grandma is not in good condition and I can&#39;t make it back for the time being. ”Across the screen, Tang Ying felt that Zhang Xiang had just cried. &amp;ldquo;No problem. Tang Ying replied to him, feeling a little indifferent after saying that, and then sent &quot;It will be fine.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Xiang’s call came in. Tang Ying panicked and pressed the answer button. My grandma is dying, and Zhang Xiang’s voice sounds haggard and frightened. Tang Ying sat up and asked, how old is grandma this year? Ninety, Zhang Xiang said, if he has to leave, it will be considered a happy funeral. Tang Ying said, mourning is mourning, no matter how happy you are, you and grandma have a deep relationship, right? Only the sound of wind came through the phone. Tang Ying wasn&#39;t sure if he was crying, so she didn&#39;t dare to say anything more. I am outside the ward now. Zhang Xiang said, I was raised by my grandmother. Everyone in the room, including my father, my uncles, uncles, aunts and uncles, all say that my mother is blessed, my children and grandchildren are filial, and I live to be ninety in one breath. They all thought it was normal for my grandma to just leave like this. They were using so-called blessings to cover up the fact that they wanted to give up rescuing my grandma, and then asked me to accept it. Tang Ying thought for a moment and said, it is a fact that grandma is not in good condition and cannot be concealed. It is also a fact that you are sad. Perhaps when family members say &quot;blessed&quot;, they also mean to finalize grandma&#39;s life and let her go well. &quot;Blessed&quot; is not a comment that everyone can make. At least grandma is kind to others and has a peaceful mind. Zhang Xiang was a little happy and said, yes, my grandma has always been a very kind person. She was born in the 1930s and has witnessed a lot of history in her life. My grandpa passed away early, and she took care of my dad and the others all by herself. I sent my child to college, and I almost never saw her having any conflicts with anyone. Tang Ying said that this is what Buddhism calls cause and effect. Grandma planted good causes and bore good fruits. I guess Grandma didn&#39;t suffer much even though she was in the hospital bed. Zhang Xiang said that the organ failure was not painful or itchy. Tang Ying said, this is a blessing that cannot be achieved in several lifetimes. It is a blessing. Zhang Xiang was a little happier, and his voice didn&#39;t sound so heavy. Thank you, Zhang Xiang said, I feel much better. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tang Ying hung up the phone, the sun shone into the living room, and the world suddenly became brighter. She stood up and went to the kitchen to get a glass of juice. The wall-breaking machine at Zhang Xiang&#39;s home is very smart, and there is a whole grid of oranges in the refrigerator. Tang Ying peeled the orange, threw it in, and found a glass in the cupboard. It’s great to have a big kitchen, Tang Ying sighed. A U-shaped kitchen is a must-have at home. The real estate advertisement was right. Tang Ying likes to cook, and her biggest dream is to have a big kitchen with a dishwasher like in American TV series, so that the two of them will not quarrel over who will wash the dishes after dinner. Tang Ying&#39;s parents had a quarrel over who washed the dishes. After filling the orange juice, he disassembled the used wall breaker and put it into the dishwasher. Tang Ying returned to the living room carpet with the orange juice and continued watching movies on the tablet. The sun became as sweet and sour as the orange juice in the cup, and Tang Ying felt that his whole body was melting into the orange. In the movie, the girl gets into the boy&#39;s truck with the rich man. Tang Ying&#39;s father had one of those trucks. When I was a child, my father drove a truck to carry goods with Tang Ying. He passed by the Lingxiao Mountain Scenic Area in his hometown at three o&#39;clock in the morning, and the dark woods and high and low mountains whizzed by outside the window. The sound of the door lock turning was heard, and someone opened the door and came in. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Who? ” Tang Ying shouted. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Is anyone here? &amp;rdquo;The voice of a middle-aged woman. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tang Ying stood up, walked to the center of the living room, and saw a woman wearing sleeves at the entrance holding the door to come in. The woman was carrying a small bucket, and a small stick stuck out of the small bucket. &quot;I am the housekeeper hired by Mr. Zhang. Just call me Sister Wang.&quot; The woman said as she took something out of the bucket. The word &quot;Mr. Zhang&quot; seemed to have passed over the tip of the woman&#39;s tongue, and it sounded strange. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tang Ying nodded, turned around and sat on the sofa. She has never hired housekeeping staff, but she has seen many people on social media saying that some housekeeping staff require sweeping robots and window cleaning robots at home. Sister Wang went to the kitchen in a familiar way, and Tang Ying heard the crisp clatter of dishes. There was a takeout box left by Tang Ying in the kitchen trash can. She heard Sister Wang tying knots and blowing open plastic bags. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The air in the room changed slightly because of these sounds. Tang Ying tried to be a master, then sat back on the carpet and pressed the movie button to continue playing. The boy started stalking the rich man. Sister Wang walked out of the kitchen, holding a rag in her hand, and began to wipe the dining table. Sister Wang said, you also like to watch Korean dramas. Tang Ying immediately pressed the pause button and said, Ah, yes. Sister Wang moved the vase on the table, wiped it, and put it down again. The porcelain vase made a &quot;dang&quot; sound on the slate table. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sister Wang went to the bathroom to wash the rag. While washing, she said, Xiao Wu may be constipated. You have to tell Mr. Zhang. Tang Ying said, ah, okay. She looked sideways at the cat litter box next to the sofa, but didn&#39;t see anything. Sister Wang came out, put the rag on the back of the dining table and chairs, and bent over to change the cat litter. Tang Ying could smell the sour smell of rag. She pursed her lips and refrained from saying anything. She stood up and picked out a book from the bookshelf. The book is &quot;Hot Copywriting&quot; which was very popular in the early years. Tang Ying used to work as an administrator in a company and also ran the company&#39;s official account. This book was once her desk book. The content was familiar, so Tang Ying flipped through it in a few clicks, then lowered his head to read the newly written preface at the back. Sister Wang cleaned up the bathroom and didn&#39;t talk to her again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tang Ying sent a message to Zhang Xiang: &quot;Sister Wang came to the house to do hygiene and said that Xiaowu was a little constipated.&quot; After a while, Zhang Xiang replied: &quot;It&#39;s okay. Just remember to let her mix some probiotics in the cat food.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tang Ying hesitated for a moment whether to say that he had never seen Xiao Wu before, but felt that saying this would seem unreasonable. Sister Wang operated the sweeping robot to sweep the floor. Tang Ying put his shoulders up and raised his feet, remembering the short video of a cat fighting with a sweeping robot on the Internet. Seeing her like this, Sister Wang also laughed and said, don&#39;t be so nervous. He also said, today is a working day, aren’t you going to work? Tang Ying said vaguely &quot;Hmm&quot;. The sweeping robot passed by, walked to the entrance, and made a sound of &quot;Cleaning successful.&quot; When Sister Wang entered the study, Tang Ying went to the bathroom to wash his hands with bare feet. He put the rag in the wash basin and soaked it in water. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In about half an hour, Sister Wang finished cleaning the bedroom and study, said goodbye and went out. Tang Ying stood up to see her off, but felt it was too grand, so he sat down again and resisted the idea of ​​going to the door to see her off. After Sister Wang left, Tang Ying went to the kitchen to get bread for lunch. When he passed by, he saw the rag still lying on the wash basin. She found a pair of rubber gloves in the kitchen cabinet. After putting them on, she wrung out the rag and threw it into the trash. She found a new towel in the cabinet and wiped the table again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is a water lily in the vase, with its head lowered and its petals curled. It looks like it is more than three days old. Zhang Xiang didn&#39;t look like a man who changed flowers according to the seasons, so Tang Ying didn&#39;t want to think too much about it. After wiping the table, Tang Ying wiped the kitchen countertop again. She opened the kitchen window for ventilation, and the roar of the cigarette machine from 1802 next door came, carrying the smell of chili, which must be stir-fried pork. No matter where you live, real life is always dull and not always mountains and seagulls. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tang Ying lives in a single room on the first floor of a village in the city. There are windows, but he can&#39;t see the sun, and he can often hear other people&#39;s secrets. One weekend, while Tang Ying was catching up on her sleep at home, she was woken up by an uncle who was hiding under the window and calling his mistress. The uncle said, don&#39;t worry, I have a house and I am the landlord. Tang Ying filled in the important information for him in his mind about the village in the city. It had no property rights, no community environment, power lines were scattered randomly, and it was full of fire hazards. It was a small Kowloon Walled City. The eldest sister standing under her window complained that the tenant burned out one of her electric kettles. The delivery boys in yellow and blue clothes used her window as a gathering point, chatting about the King of Glory and taking orders on the platform. Women disliked the poor and preferred the rich and the bride price for returning to their hometown to marry their wives. In addition, Tang Ying also heard a lot of knowledge from people chatting outside the window, for example, there is a type of people who can make money with their feces. In the spirit of simple curiosity, Tang Ying checked on the Internet and found that donating feces can earn 6,000 yuan a month. Six thousand yuan! Tang Ying&#39;s monthly salary is only about 5,000 yuan. She has the opportunity to make more money, but that is not the life Tang Ying wants. So year after year, Tang Ying spent a lot of time in the village in the city. Tang Ying&#39;s only resistance was to buy a dryer to ensure that her clothes would not have the smell of drying in the shade and be free of Candida albicans and Staphylococcus aureus. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At two o&#39;clock in the afternoon, Tang Ying was woken up by the phone ringing. For a moment, she was a little dazed. The sun was as white as dried bones. Tang Ying put on her clothes and turned on the phone. It was Zhang Xiang. She cleared her throat and said, Hello. Zhang Xiang&#39;s end sounded noisy and lively. can you hear me? Zhang Xiang said, we opened a mahjong room in the hotel to play mahjong. Tang Ying said, why are you playing mahjong? How is the old man doing? Zhang Xiang said, my family has not been together like this for a long time, but we are not allowed to play mahjong. Besides, I’m tired enough from work, so I need to relax. Tang Ying said, &quot;It&#39;s good. You are a family waiting for your grandma to be upset.&quot; As soon as the words came out, Tang Ying was a little surprised. When she heard that the other end of the phone was much quieter, she felt a little panicked. She didn&#39;t know what to say to compensate, but then she went on to say that the lives of everyone in your family have been interrupted by death and have stagnated here. All of you have only done one thing. The thing - wait for her to die. These words seemed to come out without Tang Ying&#39;s control. She suddenly felt a little desolate in her heart. Half a minute passed, and half minutes and half minutes passed. Thousands of half minutes were about to pass. Tang Ying felt that she was just the old lady lying in bed. Until she died at the age of ninety, future generations would sigh: &quot;She was so lucky.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Xiang said, we’ll talk about it later. After saying that, he put down the phone. Tang Ying woke up suddenly, sweating on his back. He looked at his phone again and saw that there was indeed a call from Zhang Xiang. The call lasted for thirty seconds. She felt that she couldn&#39;t finish saying so many words in thirty seconds, and those words only existed in her heart. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tang Ying was a little thirsty, so she got up and went to the dining table to pour water. She saw a pool of urine and two pieces of feces in the cat litter box, and the cat food was also missing. It seems that Xiaowu does exist and the constipation has been relieved. She actually forgot whether she had asked Sister Wang to put probiotics in cat food. No matter what, Xiaowu is healthy, which is something worth celebrating. Tang Ying sent a message to Zhang Xiang, asking for credit: &quot;Xiaowu&#39;s constipation is gone, you don&#39;t have to worry.&quot; &quot;After a long time, dusk fell, and Zhang Xiang replied: &quot;Received. My grandma died, just half an hour after I hung up the phone. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking out of the window, the sky in the distance seems to be burning, and the dark base has been revealed, blooming from below. Tang Ying sat on the carpet and melted into the darkness. &amp;ldquo;Who are you? Why are you here? &amp;rdquo;A woman&#39;s voice came from the air. Tang Ying stood up suddenly. There was no one in the room, and a figure jumped off the sofa lightly. Tang Ying was startled and realized it was Xiao Wu. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The computer screen suddenly lit up, and the man driving the Porsche said that boys are the only people girls trust in the world. only. Tang Ying has never encountered this word, but in fact it is used in many scenarios. For example, the only fate of human beings is death. In the darkest moments, people always feel hopeless and can only raise their hands. &quot;Xiaowu, are you there?&quot; &quot;Tang Ying said, &quot;Can you come out and talk to me? After waiting for a while, Tang Ying said again: &quot;Hello, grandma, my name is Tang Ying.&quot; &quot;For example, a ninety-year-old man was sitting opposite her. She skillfully introduced herself: &quot;I am the girlfriend of your grandson Zhang Xiang. Don’t worry, grandma, I will live a good life with Zhang Xiang. &amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;I will supervise him to eat conscientiously, quit smoking and drinking. &quot;Maybe there is a soul wandering around at such a moment, so Tang Ying thinks he needs to do something.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The last ray of light outside the window disappeared, and there was wind in the room. Tang Ying turned on her phone and sent a message to Zhang Xiang: &quot;Grandma just came to talk to me.&quot; &quot;Zhang Xiang&#39;s message was answered quickly: &quot;What did you say? &amp;rdquo;Tang Ying did not reply. She was very hungry and she only ate breakfast in the morning before picking up the express all day long. The express delivery was cat food that Zhang Xiang bought for Xiao Wu. He is very interested in Xiao Wu, and Xiao Wu should be a relic of one of his predecessors, or maybe his current one. Tang Ying saw Xiao Wu&#39;s adoption certificate in the bedroom drawer. The adopter was a girl named Tangtang. Tangtang, a name that sounds sweet. Tang Ying&#39;s former name was Tang Ying, and before that, Tang Ying&#39;s name was Xiaoying. There are many Xiaoyings in the school. For example, Zhang Xiang’s grandmother is named Lanying. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The family in the building opposite began to sit at the dining table to eat. Tang Ying felt very hungry, his internal organs were empty, and the room was filled with wind. Tang Ying picked up the phone with trembling hands, ordered barbecue, and asked the store to put more cumin and chili powder. Tang Ying once had a boyfriend. He hated her eating barbecue and criticized her for looking stupid when eating barbecue. After going back and forth, Tang Ying felt aggrieved and broke up. The rider quickly took the order. Tang Ying felt much calmer when he saw the minion riding the electric bike on the map moving inch by inch. Zhang Xiang&#39;s messages continued to come in, his voice seemed urgent, such as, &quot;Can you tell me what my grandma told you?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;I feel very sad now. &amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;I think your statement that we are all waiting for my grandma to die is really sober and hits the nail on the head. &amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;I feel now that our family members are really selfish. &quot;Tang Ying almost laughed when she saw it. What is this called? On social media, this is called &quot;late love is worthless&quot;. She looked at the minion on her phone, which was only ten meters away from her, and then rang the doorbell. The barbecue was wrapped in tin foil, and it was sizzling with oil. Tang Ying&#39;s hunger disappeared. She didn&#39;t open the new cat food she got in the morning. She picked the meat off the skewers one by one and poured it into Xiao Wu&#39;s food bowl. Tang Ying walked into the bedroom closet, opened the door and took out a skirt. She stared at the mirror on the cabinet door for a while, put the skirt in the closet, and after a while, closed the closet door. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Do you have time? Let’s talk. &amp;rdquo;Tang Ying sent a message to Zhang Xiang. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There was no movement on the phone, and Tang Ying laid herself down on the bed. The smell of meat skewers spreads into the bedroom, soon enters the closet, and then hides in every corner of the house. She waited for a long time and finally fell asleep. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At three o&#39;clock in the morning, Tang Ying was woken up by a phone call. I was at the wake and my phone was out of battery. Zhang Xiang said, I didn’t see your message. Tang Ying yawned and said, do you know grandma&#39;s name? Grandma&#39;s name is Lan Ying. Zhang Xiang said, yes, my grandmother’s name is Guo Lanying. I only found out in the afternoon. I always call her grandma. Tang Ying was a little proud, and then said, grandma never calls her children by their names, she always calls them eldest, second, and third. You are her second grandson. Zhang Xiang said, God, how do you know everything? Tang Ying ignored him and went on to say that Lan Ying had some conflicts with her sister-in-law Zhang Lao&#39;er&#39;s family before. The reason was that Zhang Lao&#39;er worked as a worker in the mine and the family conditions were good. She made pickles in the winter and couldn&#39;t eat them, so she took care of Lan Ying. The tree in front of Ying&#39;s house splashed. We all live together in a bungalow, and there is a pear tree in the yard. The pears that are produced in autumn are big and sweet, and they are all picked by the second family. Lan Ying&#39;s man left early, leaving three boys and one girl behind, asking for food when they opened their mouths. Lan Ying could only endure it and think about food for the children every day. Playing sports one after another, the only thing Lanying could do was to pay attention to the children&#39;s food. Zhang Laosan, Lao Zhang&#39;s younger brother, would sometimes scare Lanying secretly behind her back while she was cooking at home, and put his hand on her chest. No one saw her, so Lanying didn&#39;t dare to speak. Fortunately, Lan Ying&#39;s children kept up with their expectations and were admitted to college one after another after the movement. The life of Zhang Laoer&#39;s son is getting worse and worse. Lan Ying said nothing, but felt happy in her heart. Zhang Lao Er died when he was sixty-two years old, and Zhang Lao San died when he was sixty-five years old. Lan Ying felt that these were retributions. But she didn&#39;t say anything. Once something was revealed, her luck would be gone. Before leaving, Lanying was confused. What would she do with her life? Is she lucky? Earlier, in order to compete with Zhang Lao&#39;er&#39;s family, they could live a life without steaming steamed buns, so they held back their energy and raised their children so that their son could study. The youngest daughter also took a ride and studied. Later it was for enjoyment. What blessings are there to enjoy? The sons&#39; wives were all educated people. They didn&#39;t say anything, and they were not very happy to see her. Later, Lan Ying simply returned to her hometown. Lanying doesn&#39;t like to talk, which saves her image in the hearts of her daughters-in-law. In these years in her hometown, Lanying has had enough food and clothing, and she has a place to go to see a doctor. The grandchildren are also studying and working. Before leaving, I felt that the second grandson has not yet married, he must be thirty. When death is imminent, I am afraid but not afraid, just lonely. Am I considered blessed in this life? Dad, Mom, Lao Zhang, wait for me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tang Ying finished speaking in one breath, her mouth was dry. There was a thin sound of electricity and wind on the phone. She hung up the phone and went back to sleep. Tang Ying had a dream at night. She dreamed that she still lived in a bungalow in the green neighborhood of her hometown, living in the same courtyard with her grandma, grandpa, uncle, and brother-in-law. There was a performance in the afternoon, so Tang Ying went back to her house to change into a white skirt. As soon as she closed the door and took off her clothes to put on a white skirt, she heard her cousin leading several classmates into the courtyard. Tang Ying opened the curtains and peeked over. There were men and women, and the woman was hanging around the man&#39;s neck. She turned around and picked up the white skirt to put on. A gust of wind blew up and the house was blown up to the sky. Tang Ying stood naked in front of the strange man and woman, trembling all over. The boys whistled and the girls whispered. Tang Ying shook the white skirt on her hand, and those people and the whole house were wrapped in the skirt. Everyone in the Green Street saw the huge and naked Tang Ying and pointed at her. Shame, anger and anxiety surrounded her until she woke up. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The next day, Tang Ying returned to his home. The landlord sent a message saying that the air conditioner in the house next door was to be replaced and the wiring was routed from her house, and she was asked to go back and open the door. After not returning for four days, she suddenly felt that she couldn&#39;t live in a village in the city. As soon as she entered the house, there was a smell of drying textiles, like the &quot;subway smell&quot; mentioned in the movie. After Tang Ying opened the door, he didn&#39;t have time to wait for the workers to finish installing the air conditioner, and got into the subway line 3 as if he was sleepwalking. There were not many people in the subway at noon. She got off Line 3, bought rice balls at the convenience store at the exit, left the station, and walked another 800 meters to Zhang Xiang&#39;s community. Mengang was a young man. He looked at Tang Ying and then at her. Tang Ying said, I have just moved in for three days, and I live in the house at 1801 on the west side of the 18th floor, Unit 2, Building 9. The owner is Zhang Xiang. Yesterday, when I came out to pick up the express delivery, I was still let in. The young man pointed to her mobile phone and said, please call Mr. Zhang to confirm before I can let you in. After saying that, he saluted her. Tang Ying thought for a while, Zhang Xiang should be receiving relatives and friends from all walks of life today, and his mobile phone is usually on silent. It seems not &quot;sensible&quot; to make a call at this time. Uncle Zhang Xiang and his uncle are both quite prestigious figures in this city, and there should be quite a few people coming today. Tang Ying could only wait for Zhang Xiang to take the initiative to call her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tang Ying decided to take a walk along Shiguang Road and eat the rice balls he just bought at the convenience store. When ordering takeout yesterday, she had already checked the surrounding restaurants on her mobile phone, including Japanese food, pubs and coffee. The barbecue restaurant she ordered yesterday was five kilometers away. Tang Ying then remembered that there didn&#39;t seem to be any barbecue smell in the house. When he went out in the morning, the food bowl seemed to be clean. Tang Ying walked to the end of the road and walked back, practicing the conversation with Mengang in his mind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Hey, little brother, have you eaten? &amp;rdquo;It seems like this should be said at the beginning, but it seems deliberate. In the final analysis, Tang Ying and the young man in uniform serving that high-end community are the same type of people. She wasn&#39;t afraid that he would look at her in his mind, and she could look back at him. As long as he could let her in, she could do anything. After this idea seeped out from the bottom of his heart, Tang Ying was startled. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After thinking about it, Tang Ying decided to say it directly: &quot;I am really the girlfriend of the owner named Zhang Xiang in 1801, west of the 18th floor, Unit 2, Building 9. His grandmother passed away yesterday. We were attending a funeral and he entrusted me to come to his house to feed the cats. His family has a chubby kitten, short and cute. &quot;Thinking like this, she walked back to the main entrance of the community, only to find that the small door on the side was open. The young man watched Tang Ying enter the community from the side door and did not salute her again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tang Ying went up to the 18th floor, and his bald neighbor happened to be out. Tang Ying finally remembered that the animal he looked like turned out to be a sloth. He didn&#39;t smile at her today, &quot;angry sloth&quot;, Tang Ying judged in her heart. When entering the password, Tang Ying heard a soft cry, coming from 1802. She opened the door, stood for a moment, closed the door, and continued to lie down on the carpet in the living room. Stepping into Zhang Xiang&#39;s house, Tang Ying felt like she was playing the role of someone, maybe the mistress of the cosmetics in the bathroom, or the mistress of the long skirt in the bedroom closet, or maybe &quot;Tangtang&quot;, these three people also Probably a person. In the first thirty years of his life, Tang Ying has never been at the top of the pyramid, and has never had the opportunity to play other people. It will be tiring for a person to think of himself all the time. Tang Ying put on the long dress, used the cosmetics in the bathroom to put on full makeup, and called &quot;Meow Meow... Meow Meow&quot;. Her voice is sometimes high-pitched, sometimes charming, and sometimes melancholy. Tang Ying was immersed in the joy of role-playing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mistress of cosmetics may suddenly appear, the mistress of long skirts and &quot;Tangtang&quot; may appear. Tang Ying thought of the girl in the movie eating oranges. She cleaned Zhang Xiang&#39;s tea set, poured some tea leaves from his tea can, boiled water, and brewed the tea. She usually did not drink the first brew and had to throw it away. She imagined him sitting across from her, his eyes taking over her body. But she couldn&#39;t just imagine that he was sitting on the tea table in the living room and forget about reality. Such a large and bright house, complete with household appliances, a soft bed, warm sunshine and a cat that cannot be easily seen. Thinking of this, Tang Ying felt that she could automatically enter a hostess state, and her mouth began to secrete saliva. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tang Ying placed an order for fruits, vegetables and meat on his mobile phone. The grapes were dripping with water when they were delivered, and the bass&#39;s eyes were bright, obviously it had just died not long ago. Tang Ying made a steamed seabass, stir-fried vegetables, stewed beef with tomatoes, and washed the fruits. One meal took two hours to cook. Alone in the dining room as big as her bedroom in the urban village, Tang Ying served three dishes and one soup to the table, and took a bottle of wine and two goblets from the Duobao Pavilion in the living room. It wasn&#39;t completely dark outside yet, so Tang Ying turned on the restaurant lights. It&#39;s a pity that it&#39;s not winter, so I can&#39;t see the moisture on the window glass. When she was a child, Tang Ying&#39;s writing desk was next to the window. When the temperature dropped, she could draw stars on the window with her hand. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bungalow on Green Street also had a small flower pond in the middle, where grandparents would plant tomatoes and cucumbers. Tang Ying lived there until he was fourteen. When his parents were getting divorced, Tang Ying lived in an old house on Green Street. At that time, the bungalows on Green Street were gradually falling into disrepair, and the neighbors had moved out of Green Street and moved into commercial housing nearby. Every day she looks forward to her parents picking her up. On the way back to Green Street, there were always some men smiling at her. She was afraid and did not dare to tell the adults at home. After half a year of trepidation, she finally found a partner. The boy lived in the same row of bungalows as her. After attending evening self-study every day, Tang Ying would observe how quickly the boy packed his things. If he was faster, she would be faster, and if he was slower, she would be slower. As time passed, the boys also deliberately waited for her. It was fashionable to give apples as gifts on Christmas Eve in those years. Tang Ying wrapped the apples in colored paper and wrote a card to give them to him. Unexpectedly, her parents went back to Green Street to pack their things at noon, and they started arguing again and their things fell all over the floor. In the afternoon, Tang Ying did not go to class and packed her things at home. Mom took Tang Ying&#39;s hand and said that she would rather live with her mother who is a beggar than her father who is an official.于是那天唐影的苹果和卡片都没送出去，过年期末考完试，唐影跟母亲回了母亲的老家，从此和那男生分开。他应该是她唯一喜欢过的人。唯一。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张翔打来电话。 &amp;ldquo;影，你是怎么知道我奶奶那些事儿的？ &amp;rdquo;张翔问。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是张翔第一回唤她的名字，在床上也没有过。唐影多少有些高兴，回他：&amp;ldquo;奶奶在梦里告诉我的。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你还梦到了什么？我的意思是比方说奶奶有没有跟你说过我家是不是会出什么事儿？她老人家会保佑我们吗？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;今天奶奶追悼会，那个一手提拔起我伯伯的领导没来。这领导好久没出现过了，就刚刚我爸他们一起吃饭，说起我奶奶的一辈子，那些事儿跟你昨晚上同我讲的一模一样，分毫不差。这些天他们都没梦到过我奶奶，不是说人走后都会托梦给小辈吗？我们为什么都没有？你昨晚上说话的语气、声音都跟我奶奶特别像。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我今儿跟我爸他们说了这事，我说我有一朋友，昨晚上给我打过一电话，电话里把奶奶的一辈子描述了一遍。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你知道最绝的是什么吗？最绝的是你用我奶奶的口吻说&amp;lsquo;爹、妈、老张，你们等等我&amp;rsquo;，奶奶临走前真的说了这句话！我就在边上，听得真真切切。我和我爸他们一致认为我奶奶喜欢你，所以在梦里跟你讲这些。这些天我大伯一直很焦虑，追悼会是一个节点，我们全家都盼着那领导来。领导来，就说明事情还有转圜余地。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你能在梦里帮我们家问问我奶吗？你就问问她，我们家这次会挺过这个坎儿吗？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我代表我们家请求你，也谢谢你。如果你能帮我们家渡过这一劫，你让我做什么都可以，有任何要求都可以提。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我真心的。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;唐影突然恍惚起来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我尽量吧。 &amp;rdquo;唐影答。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;谢谢，真的谢谢，我们家也确实没办法了。 &amp;rdquo;张翔的声音听上去疲惫又沧桑。唐影在脑子里搜寻张翔的长相，发现他在她脑海中还不如隔壁的树懒男人鲜活。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;唐影把没吃完的鱼、青菜和番茄牛肉、水果盖上保鲜膜放入冰箱。那瓶红酒不错，她的妆还没有花。夜色暗下来，适合跳舞。唐影选了一首歌，连上蓝牙音箱。流畅的旋律淌出来，唐影忘掉张翔、梦以及葬礼，想象自己正在宴会中，边跳舞边喝酒。一个年轻英俊的男人邀请她。一曲未尽，沉稳儒雅的男人等着和她跳另一曲。她想象自己是仙度瑞拉，客厅落地窗上映着她曼妙的身姿。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外面星星很亮，像是那些年她画在窗户上的。今夜星光灿烂，她可以跳到十二点。 &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Li Jialong&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see @ONE Studio’s pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FseGjZddArgUjXOXLJIe51XP4GoA&quot; alt=&quot;任不然&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;任不然 &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;微博@任不然-呢&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;想成为一棵树。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;关注&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;相关推荐&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6108&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;凝视&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 任不然&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6138&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;平铺直叙与叙述诡计&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 李浩然&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6145)&quot;>;点击可下载ONE一个app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4040]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4181]]><description>&lt;div>;29 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FoDjjBM__pVyVAb7VvFG2YPlIQHk&quot; alt=&quot;首页图&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4040&lt;/span>;摄影| Karsten Winegeart&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;29&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oct. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;生活该走向何处？也许你还不知道答案，但你一定是答案的一部分。&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>