<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[你认为把「孤独」描写到极致的句子是？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3928]]><description> &lt;div>;2 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; The Avatar Driving a Tractor Asks&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p >;What sentence do you think describes &quot;loneliness&quot; to the extreme? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; ONE Friendly Answers&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FjweOraA9WB0QI99As226rPU8Prz&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FjweOraA9WB0QI99As226rPU8Prz&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot; font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&quot;Loneliness&quot; is a generalized word. Perhaps we should try to understand it before instinctively fearing it. Since it cannot be eliminated, you might as well learn how to coexist with loneliness. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is raining in Macondo. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;from García Márquez&#39;s &quot;One Hundred Years of Solitude&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@黄小久久久&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last night, the wine entered my throat and my heart was happy. Today, the wine is cold and the fragrance has faded, leaving nothing but desolation. It&#39;s strange, just one night apart, my heart is completely different! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;from Omar&amp;middot;Khayyam&#39;s &quot;Rubaiyat&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@香夏野&lt; /span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since I was 22 years old, my household registration has only been in my name. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@The name is a bit long&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; I am lonely and alone. I went for surgery on my broken knee alone. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@ a handful of children&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; I want to drink some wine to make my soul weightless so that it can be blown away by the wind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But when I think that I will be your passerby, &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I feel like I have become a passerby of the whole world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;No matter how strong the wind is, it bypasses my soul. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;from Xibei&#39;s &quot;Passengers&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@米花図书师&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A group of people gathered together to chat, and I was curious to participate. Me: What are you talking about? Others: Nothing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@Second Senior Brother Jiajia is gaining weight&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Pick up your phone and put it down several times a minute, but not a single red dot belongs to you. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@Can’t wait until it’s ready&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;The word &quot;solitude&quot; (solitude), taken apart, contains children, fruits, puppies, and butterflies. It is enough to support the entrance of an alley in a midsummer evening, full of human touch. Children, fruits, cats, dogs, and flying butterflies are certainly lively, but they have nothing to do with you. This is called loneliness. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;from Lin Yutang &quot;The Feast of Life&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@江left一叶 Zhou&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thousands of birds have disappeared, and thousands of people have disappeared. Boat PC World Weng, fishing alone trees and snow. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;from Liu Zongyuan&#39;s &quot;Snow on the River&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@无码地&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I think even though we are in the space age, humans can already take a spaceship The moon, but can never explore the inner universe of others. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;from the movie &quot;Big Buddha Plath&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@马马西伊多&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I stood in front of the waterfall, I felt very sad. I always felt that there should be two people standing here. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;from the movie &quot;Happy Together&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@this秋&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Toast a glass to the bright moon and look at each other as three people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;from Li Bai&#39;s &quot;One of the Four Songs for Drinking Alone Under the Moon&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@密志 Bangwu Tip&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We do not live on land, in fact we live in time. Fields, streets, rivers, and houses are our partners in time. Time moves us forward or backward, and changes our appearance. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;from Yu Hua&#39;s &quot;Shouting in the Drizzle&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@ Today Lang Bo&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Today youqing, Erxi plowed one acre, Jiazhen, Fengxia plowed seventy-eight acres, and Kugen plowed half an acre even when they were small. As for you, I won’t tell you how much you have plowed. If I tell you, you will think I am trying to shame you. Having said that, you are old, so you have to do your best to cultivate so many fields. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;from Yu Hua&#39;s &quot;Alive&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@Kuiyinmomo&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I held the receiver and raised my face, quickly looking around the phone booth. Where am I now? I don&#39;t know where this is, I&#39;m totally confused. Where is this? As far as the eye could see, there were countless men and women walking to who knows where, and I kept calling Midoriko from the middle of nowhere. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;from &quot;Norwegian Wood&quot; by Haruki Murakami&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@Ah, so my name is Guanzhou&lt;/p>; span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The orphans of Asia cry in the wind. No one wants to play an equal game with you. Everyone wants your beloved toy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;from Luo Dayou &quot;Orphans of Asia&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@西奇&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ancients have never been seen before, and the newcomers have never been seen since. Thinking about the long journey of heaven and earth, I shed tears with sadness. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;from Chen Ziang&#39;s &quot;Dengyouzhou Taiwan Song&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@SpeechlessVodka&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Which is more lonely: living in your own world and loving no one, or loving someone in your heart but never being able to get closer to love? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;from Paolo Giordano &quot;The Loneliness of Prime Numbers&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@signed pig &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I have more than 3,000 friends on WeChat, but I can’t find anyone who can chat with me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@Silent Yo-Yo&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I tried to disappear, but it turns out that no one cares about me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@海月星光&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &quot;Don&#39;t be stupid, Gerineldo,&quot; the code said. &quot;It&#39;s normal to rain in August.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;from Garcia&amp;middot;Marquez &quot;One Hundred Years of Solitude&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@submarine driver -Be careful in your words and actions&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Zhou Ziheng onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the call for papers, please see @ONE一job The room is pinned to the top of Weibo. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8 &quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Complex The cutest people in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3741&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;If you could describe death in one sentence, which sentence would you choose? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3932&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What is your comfort in a complicated life? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3928)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[看看]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6110]]><description> &lt;div>;2 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Wang Daye&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data -author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FurHY9dkOsv0F6XfLoluc4QidZxr&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FurHY9dkOsv0F6XfLoluc4QidZxr&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;One is a sweet new love whom he met not long ago, and the other is his old-fashioned wife who has been with him for many years. Lao Wang fell into made the most difficult decision. When facing a similar dilemma, you can first ask yourself what you want, and then ask yourself whether you are qualified to be in a decision-making position. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He learned about this software accidentally. During the class break, several young male teachers in the office were sitting around playing with their mobile phones. He had nothing to do and walked over with a water glass: there were two people playing games, and a man named Xiao Zhang was watching from the side, holding his mobile phone sideways and tapping the corner of the screen. He accidentally discovered the &quot;secret&quot;: countless women&#39;s faces were changing, just like changing faces in a Sichuan opera. He was very curious, smiled and patted Xiao Zhang on the shoulder, and asked if multiple blind dates are popular nowadays? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Multiple people going on a blind date? What&#39;s the meaning. &quot;Xiao Zhang was stunned for a moment, then understood what he meant, and quickly put his phone in his pocket. The other two young teachers stopped playing games and smiled evilly as if they had a &quot;tacit understanding&quot;:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Ouch, Mr. Zhang is probably playing &quot;see&quot; again. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;Look&amp;rsquo;? &quot;He said to himself while holding a glass of water. This was the first time he mentioned this sentence, but he didn&#39;t know what kind of changes this sentence would bring to his future life. Seeing his curiosity, one of the male teachers explained to him:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Teacher Wang, how do you say &quot;take a look&quot;?&quot; It&#39;s just a dating app. Log in with your mobile phone number, upload a few photos, and you can match and make friends with people of different age groups around the world. Of course that&#39;s what he said, but...&quot; When the male teacher said this, he looked at Xiao Zhang next to him with a wicked smile. But he didn&#39;t care about that. He focused entirely on the middle sentence: matching and making friends with people of different ages all over the world. He smiled while holding the tea cup and said, &quot;You young people don&#39;t know what nonsense you are thinking.&quot; I&#39;m going to class, you can continue chatting. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The school bell rings. This period is Chinese self-study. He sat on the podium, flipping through an ancient Greek drama book: Euripides&#39; &quot;Medea.&quot; But I didn&#39;t have the patience to read it. After flipping through two pages, I turned on my phone, thinking about what the male teacher just said. &quot;Match and make friends with people of different ages all over the world.&quot; He thought about this sentence and opened the app store unconsciously with his fingers: He heard his son say that this software comes with it and is specially used to download other software. . The time was 3:07 in the afternoon, and a boring class had just begun. He thought in his heart, why not search or download, just take a look. With this thought in mind, his finger had already opened the input box, and he wrote the word &quot;look&quot; with a slightly trembling hand. The next second, an orange-red software &quot;look&quot; appeared at the bottom. This must be it, he thought to himself. To verify, he clicked on the introduction page. Yes, the screenshot was exactly the same as Xiao Zhang&#39;s. He saw a download count on the right: more than 500 million. He was shocked that one-third of China&#39;s population of more than 1.4 billion was using this software. This situation gave him some peace of mind: more than 500 million times, one-third, excluding minors and the elderly, basically all Chinese people are using it, so one more person should be no problem. With this in mind, he clicked the download button and immediately turned off the screen and continued to read the book. In the last chapter, the angry Medea poisoned the princess and the king, killed her two sons, cut off her husband&#39;s heirs, and flew to Athens in a car. This is a sad story. He clasped the book and took out his mobile phone from his pocket: &quot;Look&quot; it has been downloaded. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He clicked to log in and entered his mobile phone number and verification code. He was extremely nervous during the whole process and glanced at the students below from time to time. The software opened, and what came into view was a long-legged girl wearing sunglasses and long hair. This made him breathless, and he swiped hurriedly to go back. As a result, a red heart briefly appeared on the screen, and then a photo of another scantily clad woman appeared again. In desperation, he quickly pressed the button to lock the screen. The water dispenser was on the right side. He coughed and took a drink. After drinking the water, he tried to relax and reopened &quot;Look&quot;. The woman was still standing on it, and he adjusted his glasses to study the function buttons on the interface: swiping right should mean he likes it, and swiping left seems to mean he doesn&#39;t like it. Set it at the top. After entering, there is a blank avatar, with location, age and range below. He compared it to the software he is most familiar with, &quot;WeChat&quot;, and felt that the blank avatar should be used to allow users to insert photos. He tried adding a photo of the West Lake that was exactly the same as the WeChat avatar: it was taken when he and his wife went to Hangzhou many years ago. The system prompts that it cannot be recognized. It is not a human face. He understood that the avatar must use a human face. He stroked his beard and thought for a while, then inserted an ID photo of the labor rhythm last month. The prompt passed. He looked at his photo and felt a sudden panic in his heart. He felt that he was being interrogated, and the dozens of students below him were the judges. It happened that a student came up to ask a question at this time. He hurriedly put his cell phone in his pocket, and the trial was temporarily over. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He spent the whole afternoon in a daze. During get out of class time, I swiped a total of seventy or eighty times, and when I swiped again, the system prompted a fee. He dejectedly thought that his chance to use this software was completely over, but after so many swipes, there was no match, which made him unwilling. When I returned home with a depressed mood, my wife had already prepared dinner and my son was playing games in the bedroom. Dinner was rice porridge with side dishes, stir-fried beans and eggplant stewed in oil. Everything tasted like formalin. My wife works in a local tertiary hospital in the Department of Obstetrics and Gynecology. Her hand holding the kitchen knife is as sharp as a scalpel. The braised eggplant was cut into the same strips, and he suddenly had no desire to eat it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I won’t eat anymore. I’m going to take a shower. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Eat more, my son and I can’t finish it. &amp;rdquo;The wife responded holding her rice bowl. He didn&#39;t reply, took off his shirt irritably, picked up a towel and headed to the bathroom. The water was just right, and the bathroom heater produced warm light. Just as he was enjoying the tranquility of the moment, he suddenly remembered that his phone was still outside, so he hurriedly turned off the nozzle and went out wet with a towel. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I asked you to pay attention to your image. My son and I are still eating! &amp;rdquo;The wife shouted angrily when she saw him like this. He knew he was in the wrong but couldn&#39;t defend himself. He touched the phone and returned to the bedroom dejectedly. The house has three bedrooms and one living room. He and his wife slept in separate rooms three years ago. His wife couldn&#39;t stand his snoring, and he couldn&#39;t stand his wife&#39;s medical rigor. He and his wife both fell in love for the first time. The two families were well matched and they got married according to the decree. On the first night of his wedding, he was as nervous as he is now, anticipating what his first night would be like. Under the dim light, he could no longer hold back and rushed towards his wife in a hurry. But when he took off his clothes and treated her naked, he couldn&#39;t find any clue. What made him even more confused was that his wife stood up coldly, sat upright on the bed and explained medical knowledge to him: what is the labia, where is the hymen, and how to distinguish the urethra and vagina. That night, he sat on the bed and listened to his wife&#39;s explanation, and he could no longer feel any excitement in his heart. Now he was lying on the bed, holding the phone and feeling a warmth in his lower body. He felt that he was young again. So he opened his phone and what he saw was a message at the top: Congratulations, you have a new match. He was overjoyed and hurriedly entered to &quot;take a look&quot;. Sure enough, he became friends with a woman who looked pretty and had a backpack on her shoulders. But he was not very happy. This was not a woman, it was clearly a girl. The age at the bottom was written eighteen, which was similar to his son. He suddenly felt guilty. He wanted to give up this first opportunity, but he didn&#39;t know how to do it. He lay in bed and thought for a long time, and finally decided that since they were matched, it was fate, so even if he refused, it would be better to talk about it. So he opened the chat box, thought about it and typed &quot;Hello&quot;, followed by a smiley face. As soon as the message was sent, before the other party could reply, the system prompt appeared: The other party has been unpaired with you. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is how the good mood of the whole day ends. He put down his cell phone irritably, feeling sleepy, covering his head with the quilt and falling asleep. That night he had a dream in which Medea came to assassinate him with a scalpel. When he woke up the next day, he found that he was covered in sweat and looked exhausted. He got up and washed his face. It was the weekend, his son was playing games in the living room, and his wife had already gone to the hospital for a shift. He saw his son holding a handle and moving it left and right in front of the TV. On the screen was a moving car. He told his son to stop playing and he wanted to watch TV. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Dad, search for what you want to see on your phone. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;It’s inconvenient, dad just wants to watch TV for a while. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Okay, wait until I finish this fight. &amp;rdquo;The son said. He had no choice but to sit on the sofa and wait for his son to finish playing the game. If the wife is at home, she will definitely yell at her son. He feels that his son&#39;s appearance has attracted the discordant fire between the couple, so he feels sorry for his son and respects his son&#39;s hobbies, even games. He turned on his phone and thought that he had not uninstalled it yet and &quot;take a look&quot;, but unexpectedly found that he could still swipe right: He understood that this software has a fixed number of opportunities every day. He was very excited and decided to study the software in detail. By the time his son finished playing the game, he had mastered the software&#39;s rules and decided to change the age and range of matches. The advantages of doing this are, first, you can match friends with similar ages, and second, you can reduce the number of people around you meeting each other. Because just a second ago, he found a photo of Teacher Li in the office. She and her husband divorced three years ago and are still unmarried. As soon as I finished doing this, my son came over unexpectedly. He quickly stuffed his cell phone into his pocket, and his son threw the remote control to him, then went back to the room without saying anything more. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also forgot how many friends he had swiped right throughout the morning. Maybe it was because the fresh energy of the first time had passed, and he suddenly felt very depressed, feeling that everything was like a scam. Just when he was frustrated, Datura appeared: a woman in a bohemian dress, with a blue sea behind her. He looked at the photo and felt suddenly panicked. To be cautious, he did not swipe right, but clicked on the avatar first to check out her other photos. It was a middle-aged woman about the same age as him. Some of them showed her drawing, and one of them was in the library, looking down at Calvino&#39;s &quot;The Non-Existent Knight&quot;. The hair falls down on the shoulders, and the crow&#39;s feet are as gentle as autumn waves. He loved this photo so much that he unconsciously double-clicked his knuckles to take a screenshot of the photo. The next step was to make a decision. He would undoubtedly swipe right, but he was not sure whether the other party would be matched with him. He could feel his heart beating and his hands shaking. He told himself that it was nothing, he was just making a friend, and besides, this friend might not even know him personally. With this idea in mind, he made up his mind, but due to nervousness, he mistakenly slid Datura to the left:&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot; >;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Huh? ! &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Doubts and regrets came out of his mouth almost at the same time. The son shouted in the back room: &quot;What&#39;s wrong, Dad?&quot; &quot;He hurriedly said: &quot;It&#39;s okay, it&#39;s okay, I&#39;m watching the game. &quot;The son looked at me and said, &quot;Keep your voice down, I&#39;m just doing a question.&quot; While he answered &quot;Okay&quot;, he stared at another unfamiliar face, feeling that everything was destroyed by him. What a beautiful woman, he had the same hobbies as her, but he missed her due to a mistake. His sensitive brain filled with literature even began to think about the future course of his life: he will once again &quot;live&quot; in his current family, enduring the taste of his wife&#39;s formalin and her dull life that does not understand romance. He will raise his son until he gets married and has children, and then drags his aging body to annihilate his life. And all of this was caused by his mistaken left slide. Just when he was feeling sad and regretful, he suddenly discovered a spin button on the left side of the software. This button seemed to have a lot of mystery. With the mentality of giving it a try, he clicked it. At this time, the system will prompt you to pay two yuan to get a chance to regret it. In an instant, he was conquered by this opportunity of conscience, and felt that the life he wanted was back. He had no time to take into account the pros and cons. After paying the fee happily, the Datura appeared again. At this time, he no longer hesitated and felt that he was someone who had experienced God&#39;s inspiration. After decisively swiping right, the system prompts congratulations on becoming friends. For a moment, he felt everything come back. At this time, Messi on the TV was dribbling left and right, breaking through Varane and shooting towards the Real Madrid goal. Courtois failed to intercept and the ball went in. He feels that he is the chosen one just like Messi. He calmed down his excitement and immediately sent the message:&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Hello, Bu Radha dream. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Brada Dream is a character in &quot;The Non-Existent Knight&quot;, a beautiful and chic female knight. He thought that if the other party had read this book, he would definitely know about Brada Dream and the shadow knight Ajlulfo. Bradam loves Agilulfo deeply, so she will probably reply to herself &quot;Hello, Agilulfo.&quot; Just as he was thinking endlessly, the other party sent a message:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Datura sent a question, which also made him have questions. What does it mean? He thought carefully in his mind and felt that the other party might have forgotten the plot in the book because of the long time. It doesn&#39;t matter, he can give a hint:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;The characters in &quot;The Non-Existent Knight&quot; were discovered by chance after seeing photos in your circle of friends (coffee). &amp;rdquo;He carefully planned his language. In order to make the other party understand, he even added the title of the book, explained how he discovered it, and added a cup of strong coffee at the end of the text. But after posting it, he felt a little regretful: &quot;Look&quot;, are the photos he posted called Moments? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Oh, that’s it. Sorry, I just started reading that book. &amp;rdquo;&amp;nbsp;Datura replied. He exhaled a short breath in his heart. Books, like people, are the first time they meet. He spoke to her for more than an hour during the second half of Barcelona&#39;s game against Real Madrid. This is the first time since he got married that he has chatted with the opposite sex for such a long time. Waiting until his wife came home from get off work at noon, he sat at the back of the dining table and reluctantly sent her a goodbye and a smile. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What are you doing there without eating? &amp;rdquo;My wife asked, chewing on garlic cloves. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Nothing, just something in the class. ” He answered nonchalantly, feeling the smell of garlic rush into his nose. Datura will definitely not do this. In the morning they talked about Calvino, postmodern literature and performance art in postmodern art. He agreed with Datura&#39;s understanding of performance art. She said that performance art does not mean deviant. Performance art is a broad decentralized movement of civilian art, and everyone&#39;s life is a performance art. Datura said that she was teaching at an art college, and told him that she was performing several performance art performances with her students: including pushing a car for one kilometer, slapping herself a hundred times in a busy city, and watching the reactions of passers-by, etc. wait. He could still understand pushing a car for one kilometer because he vaguely remembered that there seemed to be an artist in Belgium who had done something similar: pushing an ice cube under the scorching sun until it died. But he didn’t understand the downtown slap. He asked Datura what the meaning of this performance art was, and Datura told him that the work “Downtown Slap” was to test people’s reactions and see whether anyone would care in the public eye. These acts of self-harm. Now he understood. This was a selfless act, a cold yet noble quality. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After eating, he felt in a good mood and volunteered to help his wife wash the dishes. The wife was washing the steamer on the side, and started to complain about the trivial matters in the hospital: it was nothing more than human relations and doctor-patient disputes. He couldn&#39;t get a word out, and couldn&#39;t help but sigh in his heart, why did he marry his wife in the first place? At that time, he had ideals, was passionate, paid attention to current affairs, was informal, righteous, and longed to become a great writer. But these ideals of his were quietly and continuously worn away as age changed and setbacks emerged. Fortunately, he now met Datura through the Internet. He suddenly felt grateful for this era: in the distant past, people communicated through letters, and the circle was small and boring. Now, with the rapid development of the Internet, everyone at home can recognize him. He is proud to have a friend like a performance artist. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For several days, his communication with Datura was extremely perfect. The two added each other on WeChat and chatted more and more frequently. He feels that he is not old, and he can still master some jokes from college. Gradually, he felt a temperature rising between the two of them, and he understood that this temperature was ambiguity. But he is not the kind of man who &quot;poaches&quot;. He insinuates himself into Datura&#39;s life, and Datura tells him that he already has a family. When he saw such information, he was a little sad, but at the same time he was a little lucky. But then Datura added:&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;But I am not happy. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In an instant, everything turned around. He understood that this was a middle-aged woman complaining to him. She told him that her husband was a real estate agent and how boring he was on weekdays. He only knew about money, interests and luxury. He expressed his understanding to her and responded that she was also experiencing such a life: her wife was a doctor, who made a living with scalpels, and treated herself indifferently, mechanically and irritably. Family life is the bond between him and her, and it is also the breakthrough in the progress of their relationship. He became accustomed to complaining about his wife to Datura every day, and in turn, Datura would complain about her husband to him. But he didn&#39;t understand Datura much. On the contrary, in his eyes, Datura&#39;s husband was actually quite capable. Sometimes he and she would comfort each other. Datura told him that his wife was honest after all and was not as carefree as David. She hated men who were duplicitous. David was the name Datura gave her husband. She said her husband&#39;s original name was Niu Guisheng. He responded to Datura, expressing his understanding of her mood. In fact, whenever such words appear, he only feels inferior in his heart. Apart from his name and some literary qualities, he always felt that he was not as good as David and not worthy of Datura. Slowly, he began to change his hairstyle, adjust his clothes, and modify his image intentionally or unintentionally. His son praised his change and said that the Andy Lau back then was back. However, my wife disagreed. She said that it was unnecessary to do this at such a young age. He was very angry and shouted: &quot;It&#39;s not for you to see.&quot; &quot;After saying that, I felt a little guilty, and changed my clothes again the next day. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later he reluctantly bought a suit, went to the park and asked his son to help him, took some selfies and sent them to WeChat Moments. The son smiled and asked: &quot;Dad, you didn&#39;t do anything behind my mother&#39;s back, right?&quot; ” He immediately panicked, thinking that his son had discovered his deeds, and hurriedly said: “No, no, no, no, the school will hold a teacher-student meeting in a few days, and dad is going to be on stage.” The son said: &quot;Oh, Dad, you are fine, but I am in trouble.&quot; ” He was stunned and asked: “What?” The son said: &quot;Dad, I have encountered a problem in love. Can you help me solve it?&quot; &quot;He said: &quot;You have a conflict with Sissi again? &amp;rdquo;Sissi is his son’s girlfriend. As far as he knows, they have been dating for three years. His son trusted him and told him that he had a girlfriend, but he did not tell his wife. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;It’s not a conflict, it’s just that I met a new girl online now, and I like her. How should I put it, I feel happier with her than with Sissi. As the son spoke, he took out his mobile phone and showed him the software that he was no longer familiar with. He suddenly felt a little cold in his hands and feet, and his son turned into Datura. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Dad, what do you think I should do? Sissi and I have been dating for three years, and she is going to Beijing to take the art exam soon. With my poor grades, Beijing won’t even dare to think about it. Dad, do you think I should break up? &amp;rdquo;The son patted his shoulder with his hand, but at this moment, his mind was extremely confused and he had no clue. He forced himself to calm down: This is his son&#39;s business and has nothing to do with him. He thought for a while and told his son: &quot;The most important thing about love is responsibility. This girl Sissi is very good. You must know how to cherish her.&quot; Of course, regarding this kind of issue, Dad feels that the final choice still lies with you. After saying this, he felt extremely awkward all over. Fortunately, his son just sighed and said, &quot;Okay, I&#39;ll think about it again.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The son is thinking, and so is he. Ever since his son told him this, he always felt that his communication with Datura had become restricted. Every time he uttered a word, he always felt like his wife was standing behind him, watching him. After all, the son is still young, so it can only be regarded as a breakup, or at most cheating. But it&#39;s different for me. What I&#39;m facing is cheating, and I need to bear many unknown consequences. But sometimes he would laugh at or comfort himself: It&#39;s the 21st century, the world is developing rapidly, why am I still so old-fashioned? The software is just sitting there, and more than 500 million people can&#39;t help but be tempted, why do you pretend to be a saint? Play and &quot;see&quot; by yourself, maybe your wife... Thinking of this, an evil thought sprouted in his mind: his wife&#39;s mobile phone does not have a password all year round. When his wife wasn&#39;t paying attention, he secretly picked up the phone and rummaged through it. He didn&#39;t know whether to be disappointed or lucky to find that his wife&#39;s phone was extremely clean and there was nothing unusual about it. After doing this, he suddenly felt disgusted with himself: his wife was not a bad person. Although they had been together for so many years, although they were not suitable, her wife had not done anything to feel sorry for him. But just like his son, Datura was there, and he couldn&#39;t stop the thoughts that were about to come to him. Datura lives in Hainan, and he lives in Xi&#39;an, one in the north and the other in the south. At first he thought that the distance of time and space would make the relationship between the two more controllable. But he slowly discovered that distance was not only an obstacle, but also an extension of desire. After all, he is a family man, and if he continues, he is afraid that the outcome will be out of control. When it comes to love, he is powerless and decisive. Moreover, his situation is no longer just love, but family love, father&#39;s love and life choices. Thinking of this, he suddenly began to suffer from insomnia: after saying good night to Datura every night, he always stayed awake for a long time, with many emotions flooding in his heart. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On those days when he was extremely anxious, Datura suddenly sent him a WeChat message, which was a voice message. Datura used a 60-second speech to cry out about how David had domestically abused her that day and called her a loser who couldn&#39;t have children. Datura is a non-marriage person, and her union with David has reached her limit. She does not want to cross another life between them. She was determined to divorce David. She would not have to worry about child custody, and her property would be divided equally, so she could get out easily. He listened carefully to the voice three times and understood that it was an olive branch extended to him by a middle-aged lady who was about to be divorced. Yes, lady. He had evil thoughts that were beyond love. He didn&#39;t think he would be like this, but he still thought about it. He thought for a long time and finally replied: Datura, please calm down first. Domestic violence is certainly unforgivable, but divorce is not a trivial matter after all. We will discuss it later. When the message was delivered, he suddenly admired himself for cleverly placing himself in a favorable position. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the following days, he continued to comfort Datura, and Datura kept talking about divorce and meeting. To be honest, he was not ready to meet Datura, partly because of the distance and partly because of time. He couldn&#39;t carry his wife behind his back and spend at least a day meeting Datura in Hainan, so the best way was to let Datura come to him. But as a man, he felt that there was no way to say such words. They have already made the decision to divorce for me. Don’t I even have the determination to meet them? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In this way, ideas began to brew in his mind. What he didn’t know was that it only took less than three months from the beginning to now. On October 1st, the National Day, he made up his mind to give Datura a surprise and bought a direct flight ticket to Hainan. He had already thought of the reasons. My wife and son are staying at home, and I have to go to Hainan to meet old friends. I haven&#39;t written for several years, so I took the opportunity to accumulate some materials. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That day was the morning of the first day of National Day.妻子手拿遥控器表示没有异议，就在这时，儿子猫着腰偷偷向他招手。他有点纳闷，跟着儿子回到卧室。儿子坐下，转了下电竞椅，告诉他自己想通了，决定继续跟茜茜好下去：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;爸，我后来想了想，觉得你说得挺对，茜茜真的挺好，我不该辜负人家。还有我觉得吧，网恋毕竟太玄，咋可能有现实靠谱。 &amp;rdquo;儿子的每一句话此刻都直插他的心扉。回到自己卧室，离登机还有两小时，他思虑良久，打开微信，在输入框手写出了以下一行文字：&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Datura，我觉得我们之间的关系还是太过于殊离，没有办法继续下去。 &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;可当他刚一写完，正准备发送，变卦再次出现。妻子在客厅喊：&amp;ldquo;怎么还不收拾东西走啊，不怕误了飞机？ &amp;rdquo;他烦躁地喊：&amp;ldquo;马上就走！ &amp;rdquo;接着赌气似的删掉刚才的信息，写出几个大字：&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Datura，我马上坐飞机去找你。 &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;他拉起行李箱，砰的一声关门，几乎是顶着怒气走的，可他都不清楚自己为什么要生这么大气。十月的天空因为人流原因还夹杂着闷热，路上Datura发来微信：&amp;ldquo;你真的确定吗？ ? ? &amp;rdquo;后面还跟着三个疑问和一个睁大了眼的黄脸。他坐在去往机场的出租车上，平复心情告诉Datura这是真的，他要去海南找她了，他决定了，不管与她的结局会如何，还是想去见见，去看看。他几乎是怀着无比激动颤抖的心情在回复：&amp;ldquo;是的，漂洋过海，与你相见。 &amp;rdquo;他插上耳机，打开李宗盛那首名曲《漂洋过海来看你》。侧身望向窗外，梧桐林立，它们在飞快地倒驰中，化为了海的模样。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《漂洋过海》播了三遍，出租车到达机场时，焦虑的他终于等来了Datura的信息：&amp;ldquo;真的吗，太好了，我现在正在市区做行为表演，马上回去做下准备。 &amp;rdquo;他迅速回复道：&amp;ldquo;好的，不用怎么准备，忙完再回。对了，还是那个闹市耳光的作品吗？注意安全。 &amp;rdquo;很快Datura发来语音，讲：&amp;ldquo;不是的，是另一个作品，也是今年最后一个，有关现代人的交流，名字叫《社交异化》。不跟你说了，我马上回去，旅途顺利喔。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他拖着行李箱，拿着手机站在偌大的咸阳国际机场。这次出行他选择了那身洋气的西装，行李箱内除了必备的出行用品，还带了一本精装版的《不存在的骑士》。正如Datura所言，一场美好的旅行即将开始，他在心里告诫自己，事已至此，已然没有退路。儿子马上就要高考，十八岁后他的人生将由他自己来决定。与妻子二十年来的生活也该结束了，彼此虽然坎坷，不过也算夫妻一场。离登记还有不到三十分钟，儿子发来一条微信：&amp;ldquo;预祝老爸旅行快乐。 &amp;rdquo;后头加了一个咧嘴笑的黄脸。他看到这句话，内心突然一阵伤感，一滴眼泪不争气的地掉了下来。他擦擦眼泪，回复儿子：&amp;ldquo;好的，爸爸不在的时候照顾好妈妈。 &amp;rdquo;气氛突然有些悲凉，机场播报航班马上起飞，他告诫自己不能这样，长舒口气，调出Datura的头像，准备告诉她自己马上登机。然而就在这时，异样的事情发生了：他的消息发送不出去，首部有一个鲜红的感叹号。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他慌了，再次尝试，依旧打不通。刹那间，不祥的预感在他脑海蒸腾。他飞快点击那个好久不用的&amp;ldquo;看看&amp;rdquo;，给Datura发送信息，屏幕上却显示：对方已和您解除匹配。此时他感觉天旋地转，周遭一切迅即倒流，他懵倒在了地上。而就在这时，微信传来一条新的信息，是妻子发来的：&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;老公路上注意安全，到海南时记得跟我讲。 &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;责任编辑：讷讷&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文选载于《当代小说》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmwJcW9jjsMB93_TzuLuND4NNzRH&quot; alt=&quot;王大烨&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;王大烨 &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@王大烨啊&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;青年作者&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;关注&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;相关推荐&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6029&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;巴掌&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 王大烨&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6107&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;渡船&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 语冰&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6110)&quot;>;点击可下载ONE一个app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4013]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4148]]><description>&lt;div>;2 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FnKIEKr14Gesewpv9n6u4R5Ra9W8&quot; alt=&quot;首页图&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4013&lt;/span>;摄影| Kate Williams&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oct. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;他不是不想多明白些，但是每每在该用脑子的时候，他用了感情。&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>