<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4046]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4179]]><description>&lt;div>;4 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FprGz-WM8hY1ryCYzW5dgRNuybLg&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4046&lt;/span>;Photography | Devin Avery&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;4&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nov. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Again A big fish tank is not as big as the ocean. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 04 Nov 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[生育率降低，未来的年轻人会更累还是更轻松？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3965]]><description> &lt;div>;3 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Wild Wolf Asks&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>;Fertility As the rate decreases, will young people in the future be more tired or relaxed? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Ni Renda&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FoCN7mLCSQc5vhYFe5_LpIvZ08Y9&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FoCN7mLCSQc5vhYFe5_LpIvZ08Y9&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;I was chatting with a restaurant owner recently, and he vomited a lot of bitterness to me. It&#39;s not that business is hard to do, it&#39;s that the employees are too difficult to deal with. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;If you have made any work mistakes in the past, you will definitely be fined. Now let alone fines, I don’t even dare to criticize too harshly. Last time, a boy who was working as a cook didn&#39;t clean the countertops clean enough. I told him a few words and he gave up the job! The boss frowned and said, &quot;You don&#39;t know how difficult it is to recruit people now... Once you recruit people, you still have to provide for them... The young people today are really much more difficult to take care of than we were back then.&quot; ! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I smiled, but thought to myself: &quot;Today&#39;s young people can finally take a breath.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Data show that China’s fertility rate has continued to decline rapidly in recent years. Because we have learned from the past - Japan, which is aging and having a low birthrate, has experienced economic stagnation in the past 30 years. The development path of Western countries with declining fertility rates is also similar. But China has not yet reached the stage of a developed country. What should we do if we are faced with population decline? Public opinion generally expressed concern. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the fertility rate decreases, will young people in the future be more tired or relaxed? This issue cannot be viewed simply. On the surface, if the low fertility rate leads to a reduction in the labor force and stagnant economic scale, young people will definitely be more tired. It&#39;s not that simple. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What exactly causes the pain and fatigue of young people today? In the 2022 Global Work Stress Report issued by Gallup, East Asia, including Japan and South Korea, significantly exceeds the world average. It can be seen that not just because a country is rich, it will make it easier for young people. The pain suffered by young people in East Asia is actually mainly caused by a competitive and oppressive culture. If this culture does not change, even if China becomes as wealthy as Europe, young people will still suffer. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So what will the reduction in fertility rate bring to young people? I think there are two main aspects. First of all, more resources per capita will definitely lead to an easier life experience. Long holidays will no longer be so crowded, there will be more and more green spaces and open places, and buses and subways will no longer be so crowded, which will make life much more comfortable. This feeling is very obvious in Europe. Even in less developed Eastern Europe, because there are fewer people, it still feels very open and the living environment is very comfortable. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another point is more important: young people looking for jobs will be increasingly &quot;cherished&quot; and &quot;loved&quot; by their bosses, the culture of oppression will be restrained, and overtime work will be reduced. Some people may think that this is inconsistent with reality. After all, everyone knows how difficult it is to find a job this year. But in fact, the hard-to-find jobs are white-collar jobs. Blue-collar and so-called low-level jobs are not hard to find. On the contrary, it is the small bosses who are worried about not being able to recruit people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The reduction in the fertility rate is likely to bring about the Buddhism and relaxation of most ordinary young people, but the competition among the elite group of young people will remain as fierce as ever. This will be a healthier social structure: most ordinary people live ordinary lives, and only a handful of elites live their lives. This is also the secret to the high happiness levels of Europeans and South Americans. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So the decline in the fertility rate is an opportunity for Chinese society to bid farewell to the painful &quot;national test&quot; and move towards a more reasonable social state. Most young people are going to have an easier life, and I think that&#39;s a good thing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, there is also a premise, that is, under the premise of population reduction, the economy can maintain long-term slow development without obvious decline. Another premise is that although population reduction will cause economic scale to stagnate, economic quality can improve. In this way, although the population decreases, the total social wealth created remains unchanged or increases, and everyone will have an easier time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the key point remains what was said earlier: the society’s culture of oppression must change as the fertility rate decreases. I hope so! &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Mei Butan onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the call for papers information, please see @ONE Studio pinned on Weibo. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FktxSzhjP3p -PlOXM0sG3bvuHhMU&quot; alt=&quot;Ni Ren&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Ni Ren&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;小红书@木濐&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;A cross-border writer currently living in Spain. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Question and Answer&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/question/3964&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;How long do you think the shelf life of sincerity is? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3963&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What’s so good about birds? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3965)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 07:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[如此失业三十年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6149]]><description> &lt;div>;3 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Palace Master Bing&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt; img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FsPJqTbzFryUj8OyVSaco_O-LuDf&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FsPJqTbzFryUj8OyVSaco_O-LuDf &quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;This is a child abandoned by the times. After decades of aging, my uncle has not had the chance to grow up, so the rest of his life is spent in old age. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the Lantern Festival, I accompanied my mother and grandma to watch the lantern festival in the ancient town. In an alley we met a man selling slingshots. Grandma was as surprised as if she had discovered a new world: buy one and buy one for Xiaojun. He likes to play with slingshots the most. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xiaojun is my uncle. He is sixty years old and has been a full-time son for more than thirty years. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before becoming a full-time son, my uncle was a top student who graduated from Harbin Institute of Technology. He was a man of both talent and beauty. Of course, this is the uncle in grandma&#39;s eyes. In the eyes of my aunt, my uncle&#39;s top students refer to high-level idiots who don&#39;t know how to make a living. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although my uncle joined a large state-owned factory not long after graduation, he was born at the wrong time. Before he even received his first month’s salary, he was laid off from his job. It&#39;s disgusting for a proud man to turn into a dog. If he hadn&#39;t met his aunt before graduation, I&#39;m afraid his life would have changed directly from a laid-off worker to a full-time son. The existence of his aunt gave him two more identities, one was a husband who was doing nothing, and the other was a father who didn&#39;t do anything. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Of course, like all families with serious conflicts between mother-in-law and daughter-in-law, grandma was strongly opposed to the marriage of uncle and aunt at first. During the summer vacation of my uncle&#39;s junior year, he brought his aunt back to Daqing for the first time. In the eyes of my uncle, he brought back a young, beautiful, hard-working and capable daughter-in-law, but in the eyes of my grandma, he brought back a woman with no education, no employer, and no parents. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For such a person with unknown origins to want to marry his uncle who graduated from a prestigious school and whose father&#39;s generation was an official is like a rat who wants to eat Tang Monk&#39;s flesh. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But my uncle didn’t give up. He didn’t think he was Tang Monk, let alone that his sweetheart was a rat spirit. To put it bluntly, even if the rat spirit wants to eat Tang Monk&#39;s meat, there&#39;s nothing wrong with it. Grandma&#39;s isolation only kept them apart for one summer vacation. After school started, they returned to Harbin, and their uncle and aunt got back together again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is said that college campuses are a paradise for love, but my uncle is not interested in the girls in the school. He has witnessed various cold wars between his grandmother and grandfather, two senior intellectuals, since he was a child. He cannot aspire to be evenly matched. For love, he does not need to work hand in hand. He feels that love should be complementary. When he is tired, he hopes that the person can know the cold and the hot and ask for help, instead of whipping up the horse and telling him to go ahead, victory is ahead. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My aunt is such a very considerate woman, at least in the beginning. They met at a dumpling restaurant near Harbin Institute of Technology. My aunt was working in the store at the time, and she also had many jobs including cleaning, cashiering, and cleaning. Because of her beauty, she was known as Dumpling Xishi. In addition to my uncle, there were many men who came to eat dumplings because of my aunt&#39;s good looks, but my aunt only fell in love with my uncle, a fair young man who wore glasses and studied civil engineering. My aunt enthusiastically added vinegar, garlic sauce, and spicy oil to my uncle&#39;s dumplings, and even told my uncle that , my aunt’s father also works in civil engineering. Many years later, my uncle learned that the civil engineering work his father-in-law did was completely different from what he understood. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In short, the relationship was very sweet at the beginning. Grandma had been cooking for my uncle for twenty years, but she could not keep his stomach. However, my aunt only knew my uncle for one winter and made him forget about food and tea. . But the sweet time is always short-lived. Nowadays, the various behaviors of my aunt can easily be associated with one word - &quot;fishing for girls&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My aunt also knows very well that people like my uncle will definitely return to Daqing after graduation. His family will arrange a job for him, and he will live a stable life under the shadow of his parents. As for her, if she cannot be recognized by her future parents-in-law, she will have no choice but to stay in Harbin, continue to sell dumplings for others, be taken advantage of by strange men, and eventually marry a greasy restaurant boss, and that is not what she wants. Life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So even if she is regarded as an ambitious girl, she still has to give it a try and join a rich family when she succeeds. This will save her at least twenty years of hard work. More importantly, she really liked her gentle uncle at that time, and she really thought that her uncle would have a great future. So as soon as her uncle graduated, she became pregnant with his child without hesitation. She felt that even if her future mother-in-law disliked her, she would not disown her grandson. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When it came to getting married, my grandma started doing pre-marital investigations. It would have been better not to do the pre-marital investigation, but the investigation almost sent her to the hospital. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It turns out that my aunt’s home is in a village in Jinzhou, Liaoning. Her mother died early but she was not an orphan. There is also her father and younger brother at home, but neither of them has been home for a long time. The younger brother said that he worked in the kiln to dig. The coal is gone. As for my father, he was arrested for committing crimes three years ago. Grandma asked the villagers what the specific crime was. The villagers curled their lips and replied disdainfully, &quot;They were digging up the graves of ancestors.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This crime that made the neighbors sneer and kept my aunt secretive turned out to be tomb robbing. Because there is a large group of Liao Dynasty tombs just to the east of the village, among which the Qianling Tombs of Empress Dowager Xiao and Jingzong of Liao are the most famous. The so-called people rely on mountains to eat mountains, rely on water to eat water, and rely on tombs to eat tombs. At first, the villages next to the cemetery were populated by the descendants of the tombkeepers. I don’t know how many years have passed, but grave robbers appeared in the tombkeepers’ village. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese people attach great importance to cemeteries. When many people become prosperous, they will be told that their ancestral graves are well buried. At the same time, digging into ancestral graves is considered the greatest insult. These people who rob tombs will always be called bitches and thieves and will die a good death. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grandma asked my uncle, are you not afraid of retribution for marrying a girl from such a family? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My uncle replied that it was my aunt&#39;s father who robbed the tomb, not my aunt. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When grandma saw that her uncle was struggling, she stopped arguing with him and directly showed her trump card, saying that if she wanted a daughter-in-law but not me, she would not want a mother. If she dares to associate with the children of tomb robbers again, grandma will jump off the building. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My uncle had never seen grandma get so angry, and he was frightened. He didn&#39;t dare to argue with grandma anymore, but he didn&#39;t know how to explain it to his aunt, so the matter ended in a stalemate. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And my aunt is such a smart person. Seeing that her mother-in-law&#39;s path is not working, she wants to follow her father-in-law&#39;s path. On New Year&#39;s Eve, on a snowy day, she carried dumplings, wine, and two hand-knitted scarves to wait for my grandfather outside the compound where he worked. It just so happened that my mother had just gone to the south to go to college that year. Looking at the young girl shivering in the snow, my grandfather couldn&#39;t help but think of his daughter who was alone in a foreign land without anyone to take care of her. Grandpa felt soft and took her aunt back with her. Home. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In this area, my aunt has taken root in this family. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The difference between my aunt and my grandma is like ice and fire. Although my aunt has never read anything, she is smooth and diligent, and she smiles when she meets everyone. . As the old saying goes, don&#39;t hit anyone with a smiling face. No matter how dissatisfied grandma is, she will be suppressed when she gets to her aunt. Half a year later, seeing that her aunt&#39;s belly was getting bigger and bigger, my grandmother made a prenuptial agreement with her: first, only the uncle&#39;s name would be written in the wedding room; second, her parents&#39; family would not be allowed to attend the Daqing celebration after the marriage; third, all property and children would be lost in the event of divorce. Return to uncle, aunt cleans herself and leaves home. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although it was a bit humiliating, my aunt finally settled down in the city. After marrying her uncle, in order to please her grandparents, she took over all the housework in the family. Later, when my mother graduated from college and got married, she gave my mother two jade plaques as gifts, saying they were antiques and worth a lot of money. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My mother was very happy at first and kept it for me as a dowry. Unfortunately, before I got married, she threw away the jade plaque full of Buddha statues because she believed in God and could not worship idols. I was heartbroken over the loss of these two priceless jade tokens. It was not until I later learned that they were dug out of the soil that I felt relieved. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Not long after my aunt moved into my grandma’s house and before the child was born, my uncle was laid off. At first, my uncle didn&#39;t take it seriously, because with his grandfather as his support, he could work whenever he wanted. After he was laid off, he happened to be at home with his wife, and his aunt was pregnant and needed someone to take care of her. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As it turned out, my grandfather was diagnosed with liver cancer shortly after my uncle was laid off. Although he went to many places to seek medical treatment, he still could not save his life. Once his grandfather passed away, my uncle&#39;s life collapsed. sky. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When my grandma went to Luoyang to take care of my grandpa’s death, my uncle who stayed in Daqing met his father-in-law for the first time. He had just come out of prison and heard that his daughter and son-in-law had nothing to do, so he proposed to sell antiques with him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My uncle was afraid of breaking the law and refused, but my aunt agreed. My aunt said that her father had received several years of education in prison and had long since washed up his hands. Now it is just selling some imitations, which is no different from setting up a street stall to sell small ornaments. And there is no need for my uncle to actually work, just invest some money, study in the antique market, and open a shop if possible. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Uncle said it was selling fake goods? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My aunt was annoyed and got angry at my uncle for the first time, and she got out of hand from then on. Auntie said that the baby is about to be born, you have no job, your father is gone, and your mother has gone to Luoyang, trying to find a way to make money. Do you want us, mother and son, to stay in Daqing to enjoy the northwest wind? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Though the words are harsh, they are true. After a stalemate all night, my uncle bought a train ticket to Jinzhou early the next morning. After many twists and turns on the road, I finally saw a scene that I could only see in novels before. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beside a pile of brand-new copperware is a large basin of water. The water is blended with chemicals and is corrosive. My uncle&#39;s father-in-law scooped up a ladle of water and said to his uncle with a smile, &quot;Next, let me show you a unique skill.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many years later, my uncle discovered that many people who practice magic also like to repeat his father-in-law’s words, or in other words, they magically changed his father-in-law’s words into--the following is a testimony A moment of wonder. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A miracle did happen. As the ladle of water was poured down, the brand new bronze changed color. My uncle&#39;s father-in-law said that this is called one ladle of clear water, two ladles of Song Dynasty, and three ladles of four ladles of mountain caves. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As he said that, he gave the ladle to his uncle and asked him to pour a few more ladles and take the bronze with him through time and back to the Yin and Shang Dynasties. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My uncle didn’t dare. Years of university education told him that he couldn’t do this. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But my uncle’s father-in-law said that this was much more moral than digging in the soil. Digging graves is harmful to nature. Who is being harmed by making a handicraft? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My uncle said, I don’t make fakes, nor do I sell fakes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My uncle’s father-in-law had no choice but to give his uncle a sack of copper coins and broken porcelain pieces and said, these are real, you can take them to the antique market and sell them. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My uncle knew that the origin of these genuine goods could not be clean, but if he did not sell them, he would not be able to explain it to his wife and children when he returned home, unless he had other ways to make a lot of money. After much deliberation, he still took the sack from his father-in-law, but as soon as he went out, he threw the sack into the river. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My uncle, who was used to gnawing at old age, called my grandmother and explained the situation. My grandmother quickly gave my uncle a sum of money and asked my uncle to live with her in Luoyang. The uncle agreed and said he would go to Luoyang as soon as the child was born. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But when the child was actually born, my aunt was unwilling to leave the Northeast. She found a job selling insurance. She said that when she went to Luoyang, she just ate what she had. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If the aunt doesn’t leave, the uncle can’t leave either, because the child is still young and still needs someone to take care of him. After selling the insurance, my aunt stopped sweeping the land and cooking. My uncle became a full-time cook at home. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When the children reached kindergarten age, my uncle also started selling insurance with my aunt. But with a character like my uncle&#39;s, it can be said that he has no sales ability. In order to expand his customers, he spends more money on cigarettes than he earns. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the stumbling life, in the blink of an eye, we have arrived in the 21st century. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The regrets and pain at the end of the last century are slowly turning over with the new calendar. Only my uncle&#39;s life seems to have stayed at the moment of being laid off forever. Grandma called many times and said that she had bought a house for her uncle in Shanghai and that he would be able to settle down when he came. But my uncle just couldn&#39;t make up his mind to leave. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If the uncle’s initial hesitation was due to his aunt’s obstruction, after several years of being constantly rejected, rolled his eyes, and expelled with harsh words, he has completely lost his ability to stay in society. The courage to fight alone. He begged his grandmother to find him a job where he didn&#39;t have to deal with people. He just wanted to live in the Northeast and watch over his wife and children. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grandma was angry that he refused to fight, but she was helpless. She left the Northeast for many years, and her connections were gradually cut off. After many contacts, she finally found a job for her uncle as a gatekeeper in a warehouse. Although it sounds unseemly, a pension is paid and there is security after retirement. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My uncle thought that his life would be settled, but like all intellectuals, he made a very naive mistake due to his subconscious arrogance, that is, he took it for granted that there are jobs in the world, because Generally, because there is little money and because it is easy to come by, one can do well easily. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He overestimated himself and underestimated others, so in the first month after taking up the job, his uncle&#39;s salary was deducted due to theft from the warehouse. Because of his grandmother&#39;s kindness, the person in charge did not fire him, but found a dog. Since then, my uncle&#39;s job has changed from looking after the warehouse to feeding the dogs. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While my uncle became a dog slave in order to survive, my aunt&#39;s insurance business became more and more prosperous. She became the top seller in the city and her business expanded to several surrounding counties. With the money she saved from selling insurance, she bought a car and a cabinet of colorful mink coats. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One day she disliked the dilapidation of her home, so she decided to renovate it and let her uncle live in her grandmother&#39;s house, while she and her children rented a house outside. But after the renovation was completed, my uncle never got the key to the new home. Sometimes he would deliberately pass by his former home and watch his colorful aunt walk into the house alone and live a colorful life that had nothing to do with him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was abandoned by his accustomed life and accustomed lover. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When my grandma learned what happened to my uncle, she took me to the northeast. Originally, she could go alone, but my parents didn&#39;t have time to take me, and they were afraid that there would be violent conflicts if grandma went alone. I was already in elementary school at that time, and I was in a position where I could help the adults more or less, but I also needed adults to watch over me. age. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My uncle went to the airport to pick us up. He talks very little, unlike some elders who, in order to get close to juniors they haven&#39;t seen for a long time, pretend to be surprised at how old they are, or ask about their academic performance when they come up, making both parties very embarrassed. My uncle&#39;s face was even more shy than mine, which only a child can have, which made me feel an inexplicable fondness for him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grandma’s house is in a mess because my uncle lives in it. In order to cover up this mess, he hid his old clothes under the quilt and swept a few dirty socks under the sofa, but his grandmother still saw through them one by one. Grandma was furious at the unkempt sloppiness emanating from this home. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The next morning, my aunt took the initiative to come to the door. At this time, my aunt no longer looked like a village woman. She had a big wave perm and painted her lips very red. The burgundy mink fur on her body was smooth and smooth, and the double G logo on her satchel was shining. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My aunt&#39;s beauty is like the kind of roses that are dried and then painted with oil paint. Because of the excessive use of force, they appear cheap and gaudy, which is counterproductive. But you have to admit that this blatant vulgarity is sometimes more arresting and convincing than natural beauty. It is a manifestation of a deeply troubled woman trying her best to love herself after getting rid of her difficulties. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My uncle seemed to be shocked by the strange aura on his aunt&#39;s body, and was stunned in place. Grandma tugged on his sleeve and said, Xiaojun, please take Bingbing out to play while Mom talks to your wife about something. The uncle nodded, went back to the house, picked up a cloth bag, and walked out the door with his head lowered. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I followed behind, and my eyelashes quickly became frosty, and my nose also ran clear tears. I was scared by the cold weather I had never experienced before, but my uncle didn&#39;t notice at all and just mind his own business. Head forward. Finally, I couldn&#39;t help shouting, where are we going? My uncle turned his head suddenly, looking as if he had just realized that there was a child behind him. Then he smiled apologetically, leaned over and hugged me into his arms, saying that he would take me to smoke ice cream. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The so-called Bingyi is the top in Northeastern dialect. Different from my common wooden tops and electric plastic tops, my uncle&#39;s top was made of metal. The surface was already rusty and it felt heavy in my hand. We walked onto the frozen lake, and my uncle took out the whip from the bag. He raised his eyebrows and said, &quot;Look, this is much more powerful than the wooden knots you used to whip.&quot; Before he finished speaking, there was only a snap sound, and the heavy metal top began to spin lightly. I was only ten years old at the time. I was so excited when I saw a novel toy that I couldn&#39;t move my eyes away. My fear of the cold was immediately forgotten. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I clapped my hands and asked my uncle to give me the whip, imitating his example and giving me a hard whip on the ice. It only took a few strokes. Due to my lack of experience in walking on the ice, I used too much force when swinging the whip, and my whole body slipped on the ice. The ice was cold and hard, and the half of my fingers exposed outside my gloves instantly became numb from the cold. This senseless swelling reawakened my fear, so I begged my uncle to take me back. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the uncle ignored him and just turned around and shouted, &quot;It&#39;s okay.&quot; Then he picked up the whip and whipped the ice ball that was about to stop spinning. Seeing that Bingyi was saved by him, a satisfied and proud smile appeared on his face. I have never seen such a smile on other male elders, or even if they showed such a smile, it was never on such an occasion. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The last time I saw such a smile was when the weather was warmer. I was roller skating with several children in the community. The youngest one tripped over a stone, and the oldest one who was leading the The boy didn&#39;t mean to help him up at all. Instead, he accelerated with all his strength and shouted almost like a carnival: &quot;I win.&quot; Naturally, he had no ill intentions, he just had no time to care about other people, because in a child&#39;s world, only games are the most important. He is too young to understand what responsibility is. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That night, I developed a high fever and cried in fear when I went to the hospital. Grandma thought I was afraid of injections, and I thought I was afraid of the cold. It was many years later that I realized that it was a fear of disorder. It began to grow the moment I walked out of the house with my uncle. When it grew so strong that I could no longer bear it, it turned into a cold and heat and burned me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As for my aunt, her life has been swallowed up by the fear of disorder from the moment she was born. Her mother died early, her father was imprisoned, her younger brother was buried in a coal mine, and her life or death was uncertain. She was homeless and suffered humiliation. She thought that grabbing a man with a good family background was grabbing a life-saving straw, but she only caught countless disappointments. She wore the brightest clothes and turned herself into a ball of inhuman fire, but her heart was already freezing. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As for my uncle, he was like an iceberg that couldn&#39;t move. The whip of the times fell on him, and he fell; his aunt&#39;s whip fell on him, and he struggled twice, but still fell. Grandma felt that her aunt&#39;s way of wielding the whip was wrong, so after reaching an agreement with her, she took her uncle from Daqing to Shanghai. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At that time, my uncle was already in his forties. Although he had a good academic qualification, he did not have any decent work experience. In addition, it coincided with the financial crisis in 2008. Grandma wanted my parents to help my uncle find a job. There is no way to find a job in a foreign company. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One day my grandma went to Shanghai Bookstore to buy calligraphy copybooks and saw the words &quot;Postgraduate Entrance Examination Sprint&quot; on the teaching aid bookshelf. She remembered that her Xiaojun had been the teacher&#39;s favorite student when he was a child. With a thought in her mind, she packed up all the tutorial books and took them home. Although the uncle who cannot integrate into society has many problems, this society is also full of shortcomings. Perhaps a simple person like my uncle is only suitable to live in an ivory tower. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In this way, with the support and encouragement of my grandmother, my uncle began to prepare for the postgraduate entrance examination. If my uncle can still pick up politics and mathematics despite his hard work, he has no clue about English. When my uncle went to college, there was no such thing as CET-4 or CET-6. Although he knew a few words, his level was not as good as that of primary school students today. After spending several years in the sea of ​​books, both my uncle and my grandmother gradually realized that returning to school was just a dream. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, before grandma could think of a new way out for her uncle, cancer knocked her down first. Sudden illness is like a robber. It robs health and also robs a family of all their time and emotions. Just like when he was a child, my uncle became a full-time son again at the age of fifty. It&#39;s just different from his childhood. At this time, my uncle is slightly hunched and his hair is gray. No one in this world will treat him as a child except grandma. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After returning home from the hospital, my grandmother became weak. She no longer makes silk screen flowers and seldom writes calligraphy. Instead, she rushes into the kitchen and concentrates on studying pasta techniques. For a while, in order to make fermented dough cakes, my grandmother’s house was filled with sour and smelly fermentation gas almost every day. I pinched my nose and vomited, but she made a bet with me, saying that she would make you cry when the cake comes out of the pan. However, her pussy never conquered me once. Especially those fermented dough cakes always become very sour due to poor timing of fermentation, and they look like they have gone bad right after they come out of the pan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grandma worked tirelessly, just to make up for the maternal love that my uncle lacked in childhood. She thought wishfully that it was childhood shortcomings that made her uncle unwilling to grow up and not knowing how to fulfill the responsibilities of a mature man. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So in addition to cooking, grandma also bought many toys for my uncle. For example, the old-fashioned slingshot bought from the ancient town. My uncle was really happy when he got the slingshot. His eyes were shining like that year when he saw the rotating ice cap on the lake. There is a river behind the community. My uncle pulled out a small stone from the grass beside the river and shot at the egrets in the river. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I looked at my uncle shooting and suddenly felt a little sad. I usually see people around the same age as my uncle by this river, and they are all fishing. It seems that only such a quiet and patient sport can truly belong to a sixty-year-old. Everyone says that childlike innocence is precious, and losing it is a terrible thing. But what&#39;s more terrifying than losing one&#39;s innocence is probably growing old before one learns to grow up. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With a pop, the stones sank to the bottom of the river, and the egrets scattered in all directions. Uncle lowered his head and walked home. Grandma will be eighty-three soon. Every time the calendar turns, there is one less day that grandma can stay with her uncle. Maybe my uncle will understand sooner or later, or maybe he has understood a long time ago and is just pretending not to understand. Some growth in the world has nothing to do with our parents. We will eventually set sail alone to break the huge waves of this era. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Li Jialong&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see @ONE Studio’s pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FpeR0h0SvASC3l3Ve3XoN3pkxB9z&quot; alt=&quot;Palace Master Ice&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Palace Master Ice&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;Weibo@宫主Bing&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Writer, his representative work is &quot;No Way to Say Goodbye&quot;. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/article/6121&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Learning is useless&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Palace Lord Bing&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr >; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Read&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6144&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div >;The Masked Chronicle&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Huang Yuning&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text- align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6149)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/ div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 07:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>