<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[你见过哪些“民间玄学”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3941]]><description> &lt;div>;13 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Question from ONE Editorial Department&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>; What “folk metaphysics” have you seen? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; ONE Friendly Answers&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FkGIu3NOu26gZZV49uZGMx9_XWFW&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FkGIu3NOu26gZZV49uZGMx9_XWFW&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot; font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Living in modern society, if you encounter any problem, you must turn to science as soon as possible. Through your own efforts, science, material, and logic can help you face most of the problems in life. But if your problem cannot be solved by science, then turn to spiritual beliefs. If it still can&#39;t be solved, then turn to folklore. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;Zhanshan Temple&amp;middot;Master Daoxuan&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;I had insomnia every day for a while in my second year of high school, and then I went with my family during the holidays A temple in the city next door to us asked for a Guanyin pendant to make my wishes come true. The implication is that I hope my exams will go smoothly and my grades will rise step by step. Then one day while walking on the road, the rope hanging the pendant suddenly opened, and the Guanyin statue fell and a small crack appeared. My dad said this was a disaster for me. I didn&#39;t take it seriously, but I did stop having insomnia for a long time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@不farewell&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Far away A relative&#39;s child said to his mother &quot;I am your uncle&quot; not long after he could speak, and he could call many elders who were no longer alive. But when he got older and his family asked him, he didn&#39;t remember it at all. This uncle died long before the child was born. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@小点乐乐&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I have herpes zoster, which is so painful that I can’t cure it. A colleague introduced me to someone who didn’t know whether to call a doctor or something. I drove more than two hours to find him in a remote county. He scratched me with a small piece of iron, without even touching my body. He just let me go and asked me for another three hundred yuan. At that time I felt I had been deceived and was so angry! But on the way back... in just over half an hour, I got better... I get goosebumps just thinking about it now. (Go seek medical treatment when you are sick, don’t believe this, but my experience is true...ah, I am so conflicted)&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128); &quot;>;@王白衣 is not a nurse&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The boss used to be a real estate worker. The boss said that more than ten years ago, he was hesitating between two plots of land across the street, so he hired someone. The man walked around and pointed at one piece of land and said no, so the boss took the other piece. The piece that didn&#39;t work was later claimed by another developer, and many cultural relics were dug up, causing the project to be suspended. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@ anonymous Haiyan&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Previous The &quot;Pan Bowen incident&quot; that has been going viral on the Internet for two years is simply as mysterious as it is mysterious. The blogger, a classmate, and Pan Bowen entered the abandoned dormitory building to pick up badminton balls, but Pan Bowen never came out again. What’s even more bizarre is that except for the two of them, no other students in the class remember Pan Bowen at all, and his name is not even on the student list. This incident triggered heated discussion and analysis by countless people. Later, the blogger said that everything was made up by himself. However, there are still conspiracy theories that the blogger did not want to cause trouble. In short, this matter has always been extremely mysterious...&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@ Late Night When the Moon is Not Bright&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; It is popular in our family to eat dumplings with a coin wrapped in them. Anyone who eats them will have good luck in everything in the new year. On the first day of the Lunar New Year the year before last, a cousin of mine was the only one in the family who got coins. It was originally a very happy thing, but after the Spring Festival, bad luck continued. First, his car was hit and his wages were owed, and then he broke his leg and was hospitalized. After I was discharged from the hospital, my aunt took me to the temple to worship Buddha and burn incense. The rest of the year was considered peaceful. If you think about it, this can be considered as using magic to fight magic. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@this year rrr&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;I often go for massage because of my back pain. When chatting, the masseur told me a story about a legendary Chinese medicine doctor. It is said that the old man was a doctor in the army in his early years. After his retirement, he opened a bone setting shop in his hometown. There is no need to take pictures or take medicine. You can know where the root of the disease is by just touching it. No matter it is a difficult or complicated disease that has troubled you for many years, it can be solved in a few minutes. The old man doesn&#39;t ask for anything in return. If he has money, he will give you money. If he doesn&#39;t have money, he will bring a pound of eggs and treat you just the same. The masseur finally said that the old man passed away a few years ago. I heard that his son inherited the store, but his skills were far behind. I think this technique will be completely lost in a few years. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@loudlylili&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Across the brazier. In the past, in rural areas, if a child got sick and couldn&#39;t take medicine well, the older generation would take out an iron basin and fill it with charcoal to burn. Then they would pray to God while chanting, and finally let the child step over it. It was said that the effect was excellent. You will be cured on the same day, of course, it may be because the medicine is taking effect= =&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@chu waist slender palm light&lt;/span >;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I heard that many wealthy bosses buy one-story mansions not for living in, but purely for Feng Shui: for example, putting a coffin on the roof means &quot;Get promoted and make a fortune.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@leftJialian&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; All kinds of urban legends and street stall literature are quite mysterious, otherwise they would not be passed down from generation to generation on the Internet. The world is actually controlled by the Rothschild family. A certain star has joined the Illuminati and is secretly in various public places. On certain occasions, he made a mysterious sign to join the club, and then he was discovered by netizens with extraordinary powers... In short, they all said it with a nose and an eye. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@ Twenty-four poems in dreams&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;There is a custom in our rural hometown, which can also be said to be superstition, that is, &quot;dirty things&quot; will possess children, the elderly and animals, also known as &quot;evil&quot; and &quot;hysteria&quot; &amp;rdquo;. Over the years, there have been countless methods to treat evil spirits. One of them is to put an egg on a mirror and stand it up when a child has a high fever. Then boil the egg upright and feed it to the child. The medicine will cure the illness immediately. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@夜不&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Previously in junior high school When I was in high school, I often encountered such a situation: when chatting with friends, I found that I had discussed the exact same thing before. When I went to a new restaurant to eat, it seemed like I had been there a long time ago, and even the dishes I ordered were exactly the same. Later I learned that this was not a bug that I discovered in the world, but a common physiological phenomenon called déjà vu. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@张一一&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128 , 128);&quot;>;Editor&#39;s supplement: This is a physiological phenomenon called &quot;hippocampal short circuit&quot;, that is, a short circuit occurs between the sulci of the brain that are responsible for episodic memory, causing a new scene to appear as a familiar scene in the past. memory experience. This is a good explanation for the &quot;déjà vu&quot; phenomenon that people often experience at the physiological level, but there is no clear conclusion as to why and when &quot;hippocampal short circuit&quot; occurs. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Li Jialong onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;See @ONE for call for papers information A studio pinned it to the top of Weibo. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8 &quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Complex The cutest people in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3939&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What are your weird &quot;life theorems&quot;? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3941)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我与一亿棵大树相逢]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6127]]><description> &lt;div>;13 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Wu Zhongquan&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fn6BvJ3lWYSF1VCmZ8qc2y6mHzIB&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fn6BvJ3lWYSF1VCmZ8qc2y6mHzIB&quot;>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;This is a decades-long history of logging in China. From the northeastern forest area with towering trees to the urban jungle made of steel and concrete, people and trees have been caught up in the torrent of history and exiled, but they are always looking for another piece of soil where they can grow and survive. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;I went back to my hometown in Northeast China some time ago, and the radiator of the rented house leaked, flooding the downstairs. The tenant asked me to handle it, so I went to see the situation. I also found someone to replace the radiator, and then someone to shave the white spots downstairs. After working for a long time, I finally finished it, and I was very hungry. I went downstairs and casually walked into a small shop and ordered a bowl of noodles. I saw that on the seats next to me, there were middle-aged people drinking in groups of three or two. They were so drunk that they felt like they were going to have dinner. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I looked up at the time and it was only around two o&#39;clock in the afternoon. It wasn&#39;t a holiday either. What kind of work were you doing? Don&#39;t you go to work in the afternoon? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After eating noodles, I had nothing to do. The weather was nice, so I just wanted to take a walk. I haven’t lived in this house for more than ten years, and there are some strange things around me. Things that have been alienated for a long time or things that I have taken for granted are all here. Easily forgotten by us. I only roughly remembered that there was a park nearby, so I followed my memory and walked there. I took the wrong path, but I still made it there. The park is quite big, and there are quite a lot of people inside. First, I met a few people who were doing live singing, and their singing was quite unpleasant. Then I met a man about fifty years old in the square. He was wearing professional skating clothes and roller skates, circling around in circles. I thought that I love skating so much that I can’t wait for autumn to come. This is what Wu Dajing should be like when he gets old. Then I walked forward and met another group of people, also in their forties and fifties, gathered around and having fun. When I got closer, I realized they were playing shuttlecock. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was completely confused. What is going on with these people? I don’t go to work until I reach retirement age. I start skating and playing shuttlecock at around two o’clock in the afternoon. What kind of family is that? Are there people above or are there mines below? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I continued walking with this doubt in mind, and was blocked by a small steam train. It looked very old, but with a new coat of paint, it became an ornament and an attraction. I jumped on the front of the little train and suddenly realized that the little train was used to transport wood, and the park I was in was also called Forest Park. Expanding further, the area where my house is located A large independent area, the size of a small town, but it is not a town, nor is it affiliated with the county. It falls on this piece of land uniquely, and even governs more vast mountains and forests. It has a very local atmosphere The name is Forestry Bureau. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Forestry Bureau is a state-owned enterprise established by the country in the 1950s and 1960s for the purpose of developing forest resources. However, most of the so-called forest resource development is only Mainly felling trees, it was a period of infrastructure construction and high population growth, and the country needed a large amount of wood to meet demand. As the eldest son of the Republic, the Northeast Forest Region has carried out a huge blood transfusion project for the whole country. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to data, the Northeast forest area produced more than one billion cubic meters of wood for the country that year, and Heilongjiang was the main force. The highest output accounted for 35.5% of the country&#39;s total. The most famous one is the Greater Khingan Mountains. In the forest area, my forestry bureau belongs to a branch below. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At that time, the forestry industry was subject to a general war. As much as could be harvested, timber was purchased and sold uniformly, and the state formulated production plans. Therefore, the workers did not make much money, but a number of forestry enterprises emerged. Model worker. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the reform and opening up, the planned economy transitioned to a market economy, and each forestry bureau has the power to price and sell timber. In order to sell more and gain more, they cut down harder. The same goes for workers. The more they cut down, the more they earn. For a time, a large number of outsiders came to work as forestry workers and poured into the forests of the Northeast, joining the rhythm of large-scale felling. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With money in their hands, the workers have a comfortable life. They go to the mountains to cut trees during the day and eat stew and drink wine on the hot bed at night. Children have become a hot commodity in the marriage and love market. When I got married, I went to Shenyang to buy quilt covers and Beijing to buy fur coats. I wore them and walked around in the streets. Every piece of clothing was covered with a pile of fallen trees. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Such good days lasted until the mid-1990s. The sparseness of the forest was revealed, and the trees that had grown taller for decades fell down in a minute. Although time was vast, it did not give A chance for the trees to grow back. With fewer trees, there appear to be more people. In the past, when we went into the mountains and the saw came on, we cut them down. Now we have to go around the forest to find trees that can be used for timber. You can&#39;t just enter the mountain casually. You have to draw lots and have indicators. Whoever draws the lot will get the money. Those who don&#39;t draw the lot will lose their income. Days without money will be tight. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At this time, those forestry workers waiting to enter the mountains are no longer the first generation of forestry models, but their descendants who have taken over the loud chainsaw. But as soon as they took over, they faced such an embarrassing situation. The mountains and forests no longer generously gave gifts, and their enthusiasm became an empty echo in the mountains and forests. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the number of exploitable forest resources continues to decrease, the lives of forestry workers are becoming increasingly difficult. If you are poor, you will want to change. If you have ideas, you will quit your job and go to the south to work. There are too many reinforced concrete jungles growing rapidly. As long as you are willing to endure hardships and have the brains, you can buy mink clothes and still shine brightly after working for a few years. Walking around the streets. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those who have no idea will still guard this forest. Few trees have been cut down, but there are many unproductive trees. Just sweeping down two trees is enough to keep the fire in the furnace in winter. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The days pass by without any hope. The sharp decline of forests in the past few decades has also received natural feedback. Floods and mudslides occur from time to time. The dilapidated houses at the foot of the mountains have collapsed again. They were knocked down, but apart from wielding the chainsaw, they were helpless. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the time entered the 21st century, things seemed to have turned around. The Forestry Bureau launched a self-rescue project and gradually shifted its focus on tree felling to coal and coal. Agricultural transformation, coupled with the government&#39;s intervention to renovate forestry workers&#39; shanty towns, moved workers scattered in various forest areas to this small town that now belongs to the central forest farm. So within a few years, rows of resettlement houses were built, and families moved in one after another. For more than half a year, every day was a happy event of housewarming, with firecrackers blasting and the days seeming to be beautiful again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But it didn’t last a few days. The old worries were still there. The living environment had improved, but most people still had nothing to do, so in this forestry town, people quietly touched the ground. A new industry was hatched. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If you have been to this place in those years, drank too much in a county ten kilometers away, and want to go sing with friends, then the taxi driver will usually recommend you to go to &quot;Howling Wolf&quot; a street. &quot;You didn&#39;t know where it was, so the taxi driver just laughed and didn&#39;t answer. He took you all the way to the Forestry Bureau and parked on a street next to the hospital. That whole street was full of KTVs, which were still called karaoke halls at that time. The neon lights were flashing brightly and superficially. If you walked into a house at random, someone would come over and say, &quot;Brother, come and sing. What kind of kid are you looking for?&quot; My sister will sing with me? Is it good to sing? Or someone who looks good, or someone who can play and drink? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These three specialties are generally not concentrated in one person. Those who sing well are said to be able to score 100 points for each song in the KTV song-request scoring system, but the person is not good-looking. She&#39;s good-looking, but doesn&#39;t like to drink much. She likes to drink Nutritional Express. That thing sells for ten yuan a bottle here, which is five times the price of beer. I know how to count, and I feel sorry for her. Finally, there are those who can play and drink, but they all look pretty average. They tend to go crazy, yell and argue when they drink too much. When trouble breaks out, the big brothers don’t want to spend more money to take it away. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This not-so-secret industry was considered a part of the scenery here in those few years. People in the entire county and surrounding areas knew it well. If you learned that you went to &quot;Howling Wolf Street&quot; the night before, &amp;rdquo;No matter how much you argue that you are going to pure K, no one will believe it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most of the people who love to go there are middle-aged men who have no money and care about face. The private room costs 20 yuan an hour, and the girl costs 50 yuan. It doesn’t cost much in total. It is enough for them to immerse themselves in the lively excitement and become the masters of their own lives. There are also some old forestry workers who like to go there and sit there. It feels like they have returned to an old dream of youth in the past, and the heroic feelings they have had have passed by in a flash along with the old songs. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This street has been prosperous for several years. Later, as the country’s crackdown on pornography and illegal activities became increasingly strict, each store began to have difficulty operating. They may have fought, and given money to the police officers, and they were able to survive for a while, but in the end, they were unable to cope with the tide of the times, and they all disappeared when the iron gate was pulled. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By the time I bought a house there, &quot;Howling Wolf Street&quot; was almost unknown. Out of curiosity, I wanted to find evidence of this small piece of history. After wandering around a few times, I came to this street, but I only saw it lying there in plain sight, with a few hardware stores and a few small restaurants. , a small supermarket and a lottery station, no longer have the smell of the fireworks of the past. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I am a little disappointed, it is the loneliness of failure. Turning around to leave, I saw a very old signboard in front of a bungalow in a small alley with the words &quot;Korean Practice Hall&quot; written on it. A woman who was no longer young was squatting on the ground skewering dried chili peppers and beans. When she saw me coming, she got up and patted her clothes and said, &quot;You guys come to play alone?&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was stunned. It turned out that the street did not disappear, but disappeared behind the dust. I shook my head. She looked slightly disappointed and sat down again to skewer chili peppers and beans. I turned around and left, but couldn&#39;t help but look back, trying to guess which of the three types she was. I couldn&#39;t figure it out, and suddenly I felt ashamed of my guess, so I had to think more broadly. She sat there waiting to come, much like those forestry workers who were waiting for the lottery. If she won the lottery, she would go up the mountain and make money. If she didn&#39;t win, she would collect wood and food and string them together to survive the cold winter. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Starting in 2014, in order to protect the ecological environment, the country began to gradually stop commercial logging of forests. Many forest areas held events to cut down the last tree or hang trees. Ceremonies such as the sawing and stopping of axes also symbolize the end of more than 60 years of logging history in the Northeast forest area, thus entering a new stage of protection and development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The last batch of forestry workers completely withdrew from the mountains and forests, except for a small group who stayed and became forest rangers. They suddenly changed from tree cutters to tree caretakers. They used to select mature trees. He is jealous, and now he is trying to straighten every weak tree. I don&#39;t know if he can adapt to this change of action for a while. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is also a group of people who have become service personnel in the forest tourism industry. They are in their forties and fifties and they want to learn new tricks, welcome guests from all over the world with a smile, and guide the way. You can&#39;t drive a battery car too shaky, and you can&#39;t stand still at the produce counter. You need to be able to sell, live broadcast, and call your family members. Blessed are you. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The forestry bureau where I live has converted the steam train into a special tourist line. The ticket costs thirty yuan a ticket, starting from the county seat and ending at the forestry compound ten kilometers away. The compound is a large farmhouse, located in a hidden alley. I took a small train to get here, and I couldn&#39;t go back without having a meal. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This farmhouse is also quite unique. A large area of ​​bungalows has been transformed into a village from the 1960s and 1970s. A large radio is erected on the telephone pole and red songs are played on a loop all day long. Each room and courtyard are It&#39;s like a private room. When you walk into the room, the furnishings are all from that era. The waiters are all workers in the forest area. They wear simple floral clothes and turbans to sell you special local chicken and hazelnut mushrooms. The price is not expensive. But it&#39;s not cheap either. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This has quickly become a new place for locals to entertain and gather. Those who have never experienced that era are curious to experience it. Those who have experienced it have their memories beautified and are filled with nostalgia. There are also many educated youths who joined the queue here from other places in the past. They held a banner and gathered here. After drinking too much, they burst into tears. They sang the songs of the past, talked about the events of the past, and lamented that they would never be able to go back to the past. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But this seemingly bustling tourism industry cannot provide that many jobs, so more people can only receive the minimum wage guarantee and try to find some new ways out. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But how can there be so many ways out? The entire Northeast economy is in trouble, and it&#39;s not just their mountain forest. Those who are capable will have left long ago, and those who are left must have a reason for being left. In this life that seems to be slowly getting better day after day, they gradually lose their fighting spirit. After seeing the ups and downs of some others, they pessimistically believe that this is the true meaning of life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They may have tried and struggled with it, but the world is too vast and they can’t afford to stir up any smoke and dust. The earth is still vast, but it is also lacking. Facing such land, they have nothing to do, so they can only do it at two o’clock in the afternoon. He started drinking and playing shuttlecock. Faced with such a life, they no longer resisted, so they could only continue drinking and playing shuttlecock. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I have watched a TV series &quot;The Glory of My Fathers&quot; about forestry workers before. In it, the old father was faced with the fact that his children had no trees to cut down and their lives were in embarrassment. He was very emotional and said that he had cut down more than 30,000 trees in his life. This was too much and he must have angered the gods, so he took retribution. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When people have no choice, they love totemize all things, but there is no god. Most natural disasters are man-made disasters, or they are not man-made disasters, but are just the inevitable process of natural and social development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Agriculture has been around for thousands of years, so we need to industrialize. If we have been at peace for too long, we have wars. If there are too many wars, we need to cultivate our lives. When trees are cut down, we need to learn to protect forests and protect the environment. Green mountains and green waters block the sand and dust. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although the issue of environmental protection is always said to be a conspiracy by developed countries against developing countries, when faced with fallen trees and batches of dead creatures, it is difficult for us to ignore it. It&#39;s hard not to be moved. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;People are sometimes living beings and trees. They grow themselves into timber and then wait for the opportunity to be harvested. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was already evening when I came out of the forest park that day, and I remembered the words of the old father in the TV series: He cut down more than 30,000 trees in his life. The younger generations in my forest area, even with a discount, should be able to cut down more than 3,000 trees each, and there are more than 30,000 workers in this forest area. Every tree has a soul, so as long as I stand here, it is equivalent to meeting 100 million big trees. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Li Jialong&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see @ONE Studio’s pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FuesooEpr13-iy8Yt-6-tZtu9dZD&quot; alt=&quot;Wu Zhongquan&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Wu Zhongquan&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@ Wu Zhongquan&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Writer/Screenwriter&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2 , )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6100&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;The swaying world&lt;/div>; &lt; div>;Text/Wu Zhongquan&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td >; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6085&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Look there is light in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Wu Zhongquan&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td >; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6127)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4024]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4163]]><description>&lt;div>;13 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FhJjcTTEA5sh-JdIzuN4RM13qpQi&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4024&lt;/span>;Photography | Nick Chen&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;13&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oct. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;If If you cling to emptiness, emptiness will also become an obstacle. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 13 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>