<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[人生是不是根本没有坦途？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3909]]><description> &lt;div>;14 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; ONE Studio Question&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p >;Is there no smooth path in life at all? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Zhu Deyong replied&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FiN0GgDxbsuQ1sM7haqokKndk25y&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FiN0GgDxbsuQ1sM7haqokKndk25y&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Nana onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Deyong&#39;s Q&amp;A column &quot;Me≠We&quot; is exclusively updated on the &quot;ONE&quot; APP. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmPuzv4rbuXt8DD2ZiWPWVY5GDQ3 &quot; alt=&quot;Zhu Deyong&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Zhu Deyong&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;Weibo@朱德yong&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style =&quot;&quot;>;Cartoonist. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Question and Answer&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/question/3901&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What is the life service you need most? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3894&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Have you been changed by society? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3886&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;How would you rate your life? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3909)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[正街店铺]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6089]]><description>&lt;div>;14 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/He Xiaodao&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmQ_IWV52PbUqMdD9a2uoG7w6DFz&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmQ_IWV52PbUqMdD9a2uoG7w6DFz&quot;>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Household registration and foreign residence are two thresholds that most people cannot avoid. In a hard-working family, not only the parents must be submissive to others, but also the children must be subordinate to others. In the abnormal reality, when people are swimming against the current, their value will inevitably be trampled on at will. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu’s shop is at the end of the side street in Beijing Town. Compared with the main street, the side street is open during the day. The passenger flow is low and the doors are empty. In the evening, business will be better, because opposite the store is the restaurant opened by Cao Qing, the wife of Ma Zhengguo, director of the town government general office: Taichang Hotel. Many government-funded entertainments are held at Tai Chang Hotel. The hotel&#39;s daily purchases are made at Fujia store, which brings in a lot of income. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is another reason why business is good at night: next door to the store is a dance hall managed by the Cultural Station, which brings a lot of people. Not long ago, China&#39;s bid for the Olympic Games was successful, and a celebration dance was held in the ballroom. I bought several boxes of beer and more than a dozen packages of melon seeds at Laofu&#39;s store. China is about to host the Summer Olympics in 2008. For Chu Chu, this is too far away. She is only 12 years old. She will graduate from primary school next year and go to college in another seven years. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cao Qing has a daughter named Ma Xiaoyan. She has a face with oval seeds, sharp teeth and a sharp mouth. Adults say she is clever and looks exactly like Cao Qing. She is the same age as Fu Chuchu and is in sixth grade this year. Because they are neighbors, the two girls are very close and usually play together - Fu Chuchu actually doesn&#39;t like Ma Xiaoyan very much: she hates Ma Xiaoyan&#39;s vanity and love of showing off, and sometimes he bosses her around and shows off his arrogance. Fu Chuchu could only swallow her anger. She knew the importance of maintaining a good relationship with Ma Xiaoyan: the importance of Taichang Hotel to her own store was self-evident, and a breakdown in the relationship would be embarrassing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ma Xiaoyan also knows this fact: there are department stores on both sides of the side street, and there are many stores where you can choose to buy goods. If you don&#39;t have Fu&#39;s store, you can still go to Li&#39;s store or He&#39;s store. Her mother&#39;s restaurant was a steady source of income for any shop. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing Town is located on the Taichang River, a tributary of the Yangtze River. It has beautiful scenery. In the early 1990s, it was selected as one of the top 40 tourist attractions in China. During the National Day holiday, Beijing was overwhelmed with tourists. The business of Taichang Hotel increased several times than usual. Cao Qing was extremely busy, inside and outside, urging the cook to cook quickly, and scolding the waiter for not being neat enough to serve the dishes. Food is slow. Lao Fu stood in front of the glass cabinet in the store and clearly saw Cao Qing&#39;s fuss. The pressure cooker on the stove emits white gas from its vents and makes intermittent &quot;pop, pop, pop&quot; sounds, which makes people even more upset. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lao Fu turned around and said to Fu Chuchu who was doing homework: &quot;Chu Chu, you will do your homework later. You see Aunt Cao is so busy, go and help her.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu understands her father&#39;s intentions, and this is not the first time she has laid hands on Taichang Hotel. There was a lot of homework during the holiday, but she didn&#39;t want to pay attention to it. Without raising her head, she muttered: &quot;There is a lot of homework during the holiday and no time.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lao Fu came over, patted Fu Chuchu on the shoulder, and said, &quot;Chu Chu, be obedient.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu threw away the pen in his hand, pouted and said, &quot;Ma Xiaoyan is playing there by herself and doesn&#39;t help, so why should I help?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lao Fu didn&#39;t know how to explain it, so he softened his tone and said, &quot;Chu Chu, just go and help Aunt Cao wash the dishes. It only takes ten minutes.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu couldn’t resist and put away her homework. After sorting out her mood, she trotted to Taichang Hotel and said to Cao Qing with a smile: &quot;Aunt Cao, your business is very good today. Seeing that you are too busy, I will help you wash the dishes.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cao Qing was very happy to see that it was Fu Chuchu, and hurriedly said: &quot;Good boy, you are so sensible.&quot; I don&#39;t need your help, I can handle it. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu said: &quot;It&#39;s okay, it&#39;s good to exercise.&quot; &amp;rdquo;After saying that, he walked to the sink filled with plates. She was relatively short, so she took out a square whetstone from the shelf under the sink and placed it under her feet, so that she could just reach the faucet of the sink. She turned on the faucet with one hand, picked up the dishwashing liquid with the other hand, squeezed a few drops into the sink, and started cleaning skillfully. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ma Xiaoyan was sitting on a stool at the front desk of the hotel, watching &quot;Huan Zhu Ge Ge 2&quot; on TV intently, not noticing Fu Chuchu at all. Cao Qing felt bad and deliberately raised the decibel level, scolding Ma Xiaoyan: &quot;Xiaoyan, look at Chu Chu, she is as old as you and much more sensible than you!&quot; I know how to watch TV in one day. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Lao Fu heard Cao Qing reprimanding his daughter, he quickly walked out of the store and said, &quot;Sister Cao, you said this, I should help you with a little help.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cao Qing put his hands on his waist and sighed, &quot;It would be nice if he could be half as capable as Chu Chu.&quot; This kid just knows how to play. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Water flowed through Fu Chuchu’s hands, and there was greasy residue floating in the sink, which was disgusting. A group of middle-aged men with fat heads and big ears were sitting on several round tables nearby. They were shirtless and drinking wine as if no one else was watching. Fu Chuchu felt noisy, so she hurriedly finished washing, drained the sewage in the pool, and washed the dishes. She suppressed her complaints and acted as if nothing had happened. I thought to myself: If the business of my family&#39;s shop was better and I could make more money, there would be no need to come to Taichang Hotel to please me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu is not a native of the town. His hometown is in a remote mountain village. When I was a child, my parents often picked some crops and sold them in the town to make a living. Lao Fu has always wanted to rent a store in the town to do business, but Beijing is a Three Gorges immigrant town. The government prohibits new housing and there are no redundant stores. Later, the cultural station was reformed and the activity center was abolished and an additional store was opened. Stores of this kind of unit were not originally available for rent, but when Lao Fu was selling crops, he became more considerate and often sent some fresh vegetables to the head of the cultural station. After frequent visits, they became familiar and the activity center was vacated. Later, Lao Fu asked for a lease, and the webmaster offered a favor and rented it to Lao Fu. Although the location is remote, it has finally taken root in the town. Fu Chuchu knew that she couldn&#39;t compare with the locals who had better conditions, so she had to make ends meet in order to survive. She learned this from her father, Lao Fu. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cao Qing likes Fu Chuchu. He thinks she is sensible and has good grades, so she often praises her in front of Lao Fu. Sometimes after school, the two girls would do their homework at an unused dining table in the hotel. Fu Chuchu would teach her questions that Ma Xiaoyan didn&#39;t know. After Fu Chuchu watched &quot;Huan Zhuge Ge&quot;, she felt that she was the maid Jinsuo on TV, while Ma Xiaoyan was the unruly and willful little Yanzi. She felt a little better when she compared it like this. After all, gold locks are good-looking. Her pencil case was covered with gold locks&#39; stickers, and she felt a sense of sympathy across the screen. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the final exam of the first semester of sixth grade, Fu Chuchu scored more than 90 points in Chinese and mathematics, ranking among the best in the class. He will graduate from elementary school next semester. Seeing that this kid has a lot of potential, the head teacher came to visit him not long after the winter vacation. The class teacher said that Fu Chuchu was capable and had a bright future. After graduation, the child should be sent to Dengyun Middle School in the county town to educate him well. In the town, parents with money and status will send their children to junior high schools in the county. The junior high school in Beijing Town is on the other side of the Taichang River. The quality of education is worrying, and only a few students are admitted to key high schools every year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lao Fu felt embarrassed. Of course he wanted to cultivate his daughter well, but with his current income, he could not afford this part of the expenses. Moreover, if you go to the county town to study, you have to pay a considerable school selection fee. Lao Fu did not accept the head teacher&#39;s suggestion directly, but said cautiously, &quot;I will think about it.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu was listening to the conversation between his parents and the head teacher, his face full of depression. She really wanted to go to the county town to study. This was the largest city she had ever been to. Sometimes when Lao Fu went to the county town to wholesale goods, he would take Fu Chuchu with him. She followed Lao Fu and shuttled through this small town located on the Yangtze River: the crowded docks, the noisy streets with cars and horses, and the patchwork of mountains and rivers in the county all fascinated her. She never dared to ask for it, but today&#39;s head teacher&#39;s words gave her a sense of hope. The businesses in the shops on the main street are good, and adults can afford to send their children to the county town to study, but how can this humble little shop on a side street compare? She looked at Lao Fu pitifully, hoping to receive a favor beyond daily care. Of course Lao Fu understood what his daughter meant, but he just felt helpless and unable to give a firm answer. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the class teacher finished talking to his parents, he touched Fu Chuchu&#39;s head when he left and said, &quot;Chu Chu, study hard and you will be successful in the future, no matter where you study.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu knew that this was the head teacher trying to comfort him, so he remained silent. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the evening, there were more and more guests at Taichang Hotel, and Lao Fu asked Fu Chuchu to help as usual. She did not dare to shirk, and absentmindedly washed the dishes in the sink. As I rubbed it, I remembered the home visit of the head teacher during the day. The more I thought about it, the sadder it became, and tears kept falling from my eyes. Cao Qing was busy greeting the guests and didn&#39;t notice it at all. Fu Chuchu sobbed for a while, stopped her tears, and neatly stacked the washed dishes on the cabinet table aside. Without saying hello, he slipped out of the back door of the hotel. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She didn&#39;t go home and wandered the streets without a clue. At this time, the main street was very lively, with several children chasing each other and playing in the street, and groups of residents chatting on the benches. There are several department stores and clothing stores on the main street, and there are still many customers. I heard from Lao Fu that the gross income of the shops on the main street is five to six hundred per day, while the gross income of the shops on the side streets is two or three hundred per day. Excluding costs, the profit is even less. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu stood across the road, looking at the rows of bustling shops, and couldn&#39;t help but feel envious: It would be great if his own shop was also here. In this way, her parents can earn a lot of money and support her to study in the county town. She doesn&#39;t have to go to Tai Chang Hotel to help either. At that time, I will be Little Swallow Gege, and Ma Xiaoyan is the golden lock - no, I should be Ziwei Gege, Ziwei is more like me, knowledgeable, beautiful and considerate. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chinese New Year is almost here, and all the junior high school students studying in the county have returned to Beijing Town. Wearing the latest styles of down jackets, they look energetic and radiant, and are the focus of the town. Fu Chuchu knew some of them and had played together when they were in primary school. But she realized that there was a gap with them, so she took the initiative to distance herself, reduced contact, and left the close circle in elementary school. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The streets are full of residents buying new year’s goods. This is the busiest time in Beijing Town. But this kind of excitement does not belong to Laofu shop. The main customers of Taichang Hotel come from official entertainment. The government departments are on holiday and there is no catering expenses. The business of Laofu shop has not improved. Seeing the booming business of the shops on the main street, Lao Fu felt anxious. He asked a carpenter to make a chopping board the size of a bed, put two rough benches on it, and set up a stall at the crossroads of the main street, deciding to grab a wave of customers going to the market. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the first day, there was not much traffic. Lao Fu thought it was not a solution, so the next day he put up a 10% discount sign next to the stall and asked his wife to shout. This method worked, and the stall was quickly filled with people. Gradually, Lao Fu&#39;s business improved. When the goods at the street stall were sold out, Lao Fu asked Fu Chuchu to bring more from the shop. Setting up a street stall was a disgraceful thing, so Fu Chuchu was reluctant because she was afraid of being looked down upon by other classmates, so she hurried back to the shop after moving the goods. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;A street stall can earn so much, let alone a shop on the main street. &amp;rdquo;When we were settling the accounts at night, Lao Fu was counting the money and talking, his mouth full of envy. Fu Chuchu was also very happy, and suddenly thought of helping out when Taichang Hotel was busy. She pouted and said, &quot;We are so busy during the New Year, so we should let Ma Xiaoyan come and help us.&quot; Lao Fu knew that his daughter was angry, so he said sincerely: &quot;Chu Chu, we are sensible, don&#39;t worry about this.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The street stall has been booming for several days. This morning, Lao Fu was setting up the stall early in the morning when Boss Li, Boss Zhang and Boss Niu from the main street shop came over. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lao Fu knew what was going on, and he had long expected that such a day would come. He kept his composure, pretended not to know anything, and greeted with a smile: &quot;Good morning, bosses.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Boss Li held a cigarette in his left ear. He took it off and handed it to Lao Fu. He wanted to light a cigarette for Lao Fu, but Lao Fu declined, knowing that the other party wanted to be polite before fighting. Boss Li saw that Lao Fu ignored him and said tactfully: &quot;Lao Fu, what you are doing is a bit unkind.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Because the town is small, the residents in the town all know each other and are very polite. Lao Fu was startled for a moment, then said with a smile: &quot;It&#39;s not like I&#39;m here every day. Just a few days ago, I didn&#39;t block your business. Let&#39;s do business together.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;This street stall is illegal and the government does not allow it. The one who spoke was Boss Zhang, with a tougher tone. He added, &quot;It&#39;s not that we are making things difficult for you. You set up a stall here. The street is already narrow and it blocks the road. You see, cars and other things can&#39;t pass. It&#39;s too much.&quot; inconvenient. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lao Fu explained: &amp;ldquo;Most of the people passing by my position are government vehicles. Now that government units are on holiday, there are no government vehicles coming and going. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Boss Niu&#39;s temper was not that good. Seeing that Lao Fu was confident, he said coldly: &quot;I said Lao Fu, we are all from Beijing. Don&#39;t make it unpleasant. You&#39;d better move as soon as possible.&quot; . &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hearing what Boss Niu said, Lao Fu became angry. He pointed at the stall with his right hand and responded forcefully: &quot;You have the final say in this place?&quot; If you have the ability, go to the government staff and they will evaluate whether this place can set up a stall. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lao Fu knows that all government units are on vacation now, waiting for the Chinese New Year, so he won’t pay attention to these things. These bosses couldn&#39;t do anything to him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The three bosses look at me and you, at a loss. At this time, a man about fifty years old wearing glasses came over. He was the boss of Zhengjie Department Store, Yuan. Boss Yuan was much older than these three bosses, with a charitable face, like a retired teacher. He said calmly: &quot;I told you that there is nothing to fight about among the big bosses. Calm down, everyone who is going to the market is coming soon. Everyone is doing business well. If there are any conflicts, we can wait until after the New Year to discuss them. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The three bosses Zhang, Li and Fu didn’t know why Boss Yuan, who was also a businessman on Zhengjie, turned his elbow outward to help Lao Fu. But Boss Yuan has been doing business in the town for decades and is highly respected. Now that he has spoken, the three of them stopped arguing. After saying a few polite words, they all went back to their shops. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Lao Fu saw Boss Yuan helping him to speak, he was very grateful and said with a smile: &quot;Thank you very much, Boss Yuan. Boss Yuan is still very generous and not as petty as them.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Boss Yuan waved his hand and said: &quot;It&#39;s all trivial matters, but it&#39;s all Beijing people. For a few small bucks, why do we have to be so stiff.&quot; If you want to set up a street stall, just set it up in front of my store. This way, the product range will be complete and the business will be better. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lao Fu was very happy after hearing this and said: &quot;Boss Yuan is too upright. I will definitely pay New Year greetings in person during the Chinese New Year.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taichang Hotel has also been closed these days. Cao Qing took Ma Xiaoyan to Dengyun County for a few days. I bought a bunch of high-quality frozen meats and seafood, which are all very high-quality ingredients, and I plan to eat them during the New Year. Especially seafood is so expensive that people in Beijing are reluctant to buy it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu guards the store and delivers groceries to his parents who run a street stall from time to time. After finishing her meal, Ma Xiaoyan wore a new down jacket she bought in the county and sat in front of Laofu&#39;s shop. She talked eloquently about her experiences in Dengyun County, including the ice rink, amusement park, Yangtze River Department Store, etc. Although Fu Chuchu has been to Dengyun County several times, she has never played much. She just followed her father through various wholesale markets. Ma Xiaoyan told her that Dengyun is building a new city, which is more prosperous than the current old city. When the Three Gorges Dam fills water, the Yangtze River will rise and the old city will be demolished and moved to the new city. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu vaguely knew about this. There were several stone walls erected in the town that marked the Three Gorges immigration water level, 135 meters, 165 meters, and 175 meters. Fu Chuchu never knew what the numbers on them were. mean. After entering fourth grade, there were often classmates in her class who immigrated to other provinces and cities. At this time, she would go to the dock with the school band to see off the immigrants. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ma Xiaoyan mentioned Dengyun New Town, but she has not been to the new county town yet. I heard that Dengyun Middle School is located in the new county town and the school is very beautiful. There are several students in the town studying at Dengyun Middle School. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After talking about what she had seen in Dengyun County, Ma Xiaoyan said mysteriously: &quot;Chu Chu, let me tell you a secret.&quot; Don&#39;t tell others. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu said: &amp;ldquo;What a secret. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ma Xiaoyan leaned into Fu Chuchu&#39;s ear and said, &quot;I will go to Dengyun County to attend junior high school after graduating from elementary school next year.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu’s face darkened, as if he had suddenly been hit hard in the chest. It&#39;s so unfair that Ma Xiaoyan, whose grades are so poor, can go to the county town to study. She didn&#39;t know how to answer, so she suppressed her emotions and said calmly: &quot;That&#39;s great, that&#39;s great.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Seeing Fu Chuchu&#39;s little reaction, Ma Xiaoyan thought she must be jealous and said, &quot;I will come back to see you in the future and bring you a lot of delicious food.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu replied calmly: &quot;Thank you very much.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu had been feeling dull all afternoon when he heard that Ma Xiaoyan was going to Dengyun County to attend junior high school. She remembered that she had worked hard to wash dishes at Taichang Hotel before, but what she had gotten in exchange was a bigger gap. She recalled her father&#39;s embarrassed face when her head teacher visited her home. She felt that the whole world had abandoned her. She is a child from a poor family and she is not qualified to expect a better life. She said to herself over and over again in her heart. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the evening, when the couple finished setting up their stall and went home for dinner, they saw that Fu Chuchu had been unhappy and thought she was a little tired from carrying goods during this period. Lao Fu said softly: &quot;Chu Chu, you have worked hard during this period. You don&#39;t have to carry goods anymore.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu lowered his head and said &quot;Oh&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lao Fu smiled and said: &quot;Chu Chu, there is still half a semester next year. You must study hard and do well in the exam. I will send you to Dengyun Middle School.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu suddenly raised his head, his eyes glowing, and said to Lao Fu: &quot;Really?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lao Fu looked proud and smiled proudly: &quot;How could dad lie to you.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu knew about her family&#39;s income and thought that her parents must have heard that Ma Xiaoyan was going to the county town to study. He said this deliberately to comfort himself, so he pouted and glanced at Lao Fu: &quot;I don&#39;t believe it.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lao Fu patted his chest and said seriously: &quot;Why are you lying to me? After a while, we will move to the main street. Boss Yuan will sublet the shop to us.&quot; . &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lao Fu also explained that Boss Yuan came over a few days ago to talk to him about subletting. Boss Yuan was an employee of the original supply and marketing cooperative. After the supply and marketing cooperative went bankrupt, the stores of the supply and marketing cooperative were privatized. Business in Zhengjie was good, so Boss Yuan has been doing business here. Now in his fifties, his son has bought a house in the county town. They are too far apart. I hope that Mr. and Mrs. Yuan will come to live in the county town and help take care of their grandchildren. The old couple also felt that their son was right. First, he was getting older and the shop was busy from morning to night, which was too much for his body. The second is that both his son and daughter-in-law are at work, and there is no one to take care of his grandson, so he goes to the county town to relieve his son&#39;s burden. This shop has a prosperous business, and Lao Yuan has been reluctant to transfer it. His son has been talking about it for several years, and Lao Yuan finally made up his mind this year. Seeing that Lao Fu and his wife were very diligent and thoughtful, they decided to transfer this prosperous shop to Lao Fu. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lao Fu spoke vividly, and the smile on his face could hardly be kept. He felt that this was God&#39;s mercy. Seven or eight years ago, he came to the town with a heavy burden to sell crops, and then he rented this shop on the side street. Now he wants to take over the prosperous shop on the main street, step by step, and develop in a good direction. . This incident may be a turning point in the business. The business of the main street store is guaranteed. If it operates well for three to five years, it will be possible to buy a house in the county. Sending her daughter to study in the county town is no problem. Lao Fu thought that by September next year, the money saved should be enough to pay for school selection in the county. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After listening to Lao Fu’s story, Fu Chuchu put down her bowls and chopsticks and couldn’t help but dance. She can finally go to the county town to study like Ma Xiaoyan! After moving to the main street, I no longer have to go to Tai Chang Hotel to help! She will soon be Ziwei Gege, and she will no longer be called Ma Xiaoyan&#39;s maid by her classmates. Happiness came so suddenly, Fu Chuchu couldn&#39;t wait to run to Lao Yuan&#39;s shop on the main street and dream about her future life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Seeing Fu Chuchu&#39;s excited look, Lao Fu made a &quot;shush&quot; gesture and said, &quot;Chu Chu, don&#39;t talk about this anywhere, keep it secret.&quot; Let’s wait until we officially move there. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu understood what Lao Fu meant and kept a low profile to avoid Cao Qing being unhappy. It is human nature for people to go to higher places, but in general, thanks to the care of Tai Chang Hotel in the past few years, it has been able to survive. Now that it&#39;s leaked out, it will inevitably hit people&#39;s lips. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When chatting with Ma Xiaoyan these days, she never mentioned this matter. When Ma Xiaoyan showed off her glamorous life, Fu Chuchu echoed her and said nice things. She thought to herself: It doesn&#39;t matter if I stay as a golden lock for a few more days, I will move out immediately. Maybe Ma Xiaoyan will envy me in the future! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One night 5 years ago, Lao Fu and his family quietly moved to Lao Yuan&#39;s shop on the main street. Everyone was surprised. Cao Qing was confused and became angry when he saw that the shop he supported had been moved away. He called Lao Fu a white-eyed wolf when he met everyone. The three bosses Li, Zhang and Niu also gritted their teeth and hated Boss Yuan in their hearts for giving themselves another competition. opponent. They and Boss Yuan used to be employees of the supply and marketing cooperative. Unexpectedly, they didn&#39;t say hello to them before leaving. This was too rude. The residents in the town were envious of Lao Fu. There were many people in this shop. The coveted property has now fallen into the hands of Lao Fu, a foreigner, which makes many locals quite unwilling. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On New Year&#39;s Eve, Lao Fu hangs red lanterns on the door and windows of the shop to usher in a new year. My wife prepared a table full of dishes, which was more sumptuous than any previous reunion dinner. Fu Chuchu was wearing a new cotton-padded jacket and was beaming with joy. The family is enjoying themselves happily and has an indescribable sense of satisfaction. This is a new starting point. The difficulties of the past have finally cleared away, and the future is bright. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lao Fu made a promise: In 2002, he must work hard to run the store well and send his daughter to study in the county town. He had humbled himself and made sacrifices for a living, and it was all worth it. As an uneducated rural person, I am satisfied with living like this in the town. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In spring, the earth wakes up and stretches itself, and everything begins to revive. Wild ducks play on the surface of the Taichang River. The sunshine gilded this tourist town. After a peaceful Spring Festival, Beijing Town is full of new vitality. At the beginning of March, all walks of life officially started working, and the town became lively. The number of tourists coming to Beijing Town is gradually increasing. After visiting the Three Gorges of the Yangtze River, these tourists take a look at the Taichang River, a tributary of the Yangtze River. They stop at the Beijing Town Pier at noon. The tourists come down to eat, buy things, and then return. The people of Beijing have benefited from the Taichang River. Otherwise, like other towns in the county, they can only rely on agriculture. The Taichang River brings tourism and makes the town a business card of the county. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu was playing at the pier, watching the boats passing by on the river, and felt extremely comfortable. She thought: This year I will take a boat to study in the county town. Beijing Town is surrounded by mountains on three sides, and the Taichang River is the fastest channel to the outside world. From here you can reach Dengyun County, as well as Yichang and Wuhan downstream and Chongqing upstream. Fu Chuchu has only been to Dengyun County. Maybe he can go to these real big cities in college in the future. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the first day of school, Fu Chuchu saw Ma Xiaoyan. Since moving to the main street, the two of them rarely play together. Fu Chuchu was very sensible, greeted her warmly, and took Ma Xiaoyan to play with her. She felt that she no longer had to be Ma Xiaoyan&#39;s maid, but could still be her friend. But Ma Xiaoyan didn&#39;t think so. She used to be able to boss Fu Chuchu around, but now she can&#39;t. She no longer has the same status in the class as before. She glanced at Fu Chuchu and said angrily: &quot;I thought it would be great if I moved to the main street.&quot; &quot;Fu Chuchu ignored her. Anyway, she would graduate in a few months and there would be no need to interact with Ma Xiaoyan in the future.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The shop on the street that Lao Fu used to live in was rented by another person, who also opened a department store. All the daily expenses of Taichang Hotel were transferred to this newly opened store. Cao Qing wanted to tell the people in the town: With the scale of Taichang Hotel, it can support any store. It&#39;s no big deal that Lao Fu left. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lao Fu knew that Cao Qing had a grudge, but he didn&#39;t care. As he expected, the business of the main street store was extremely good, and the daily income was several times more than before on the side street. In the past, the two were relatively frugal, but now Lao Fu can drink a bottle of beer for dinner every day, and Fu Chuchu, his daughter, has an extra piece of pocket money every day. Fu Chuchu has never been so happy. This is the happiest day in her memory. She was motivated to study and was waiting to graduate and go to the county to study. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One day in early April, Fu Chuchu walked to the main street after school in the afternoon and saw a bunch of people watching and talking at the poster board next to the street. Fu Chuchu was a little curious, so she got into the crowd and saw a notice posted on the bulletin board:&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/ div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Dengyun County About Beijing Town in the Three Gorges Project Reservoir Area&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt; strong>;Notice on Several Issues in Resettlement Work&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All agencies directly under Beijing Town:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the official implementation of the resettlement in the reservoir area of ​​the Three Gorges Project in 1993, with the strong support of the people across the country Under this circumstance, through the active efforts of governments at all levels in the reservoir area, the first phase of the resettlement task was successfully completed, ensuring that the river closure was realized as scheduled. Since 1998, the second phase of immigration work has been fully launched. According to the requirements of the higher-level government, all the second-phase water level resettlement in Beijing Town must be completed before June 30, 2002. The relevant issues are now notified as follows:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1. Take practical measures to actively and steadily carry out urban resettlement work. During the relocation, ensure the property and personal safety of residents...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2. The town government and various agencies will take the lead and take the lead in relocating to Beijing New Town before May... &amp;hellip;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3. Beijing Town residents should make preparations for relocation in advance to ensure that the relocation is completed in an orderly manner... For people or families who rent in the town without household registration, they can move to their original place of household registration, or they can move on their own Choose to rent a house in Beijing New Town. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Four...&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Five... align: right;&quot;>;Chongqing Dengyun County Government&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;April 2002&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The notice contains a lot of text , so densely packed that Fu Chuchu’s eyes were blurred as she emerged from the crowd. When I got home, I saw my mother sitting by the container, silent and with a sad face. She asked Lao Fu: &quot;Dad, what was written on that bulletin board, that it was about to be relocated? What was it about?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lao Fu had a straight face and was furious, cursing: &amp;ldquo;I was cheated! Scammed! This old guy, Lao Yuan, whose son works at the county immigration office, must have known about the relocation of Beijing Town in advance, so he transferred the shop to me. I thought he was kind-hearted! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu’s mother was heartbroken and kept shaking her head, “This is life.” &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu knew that Beijing was a Three Gorges immigration town for a long time, but she was not sure when she would move there. Now I know that I will have to move out in the first half of this year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu asked: &quot;Where should we move?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lao Fu said: &amp;ldquo;Where else can we go? Go to New Town to see if there is a suitable store. If not, we have to go back to our hometown! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My mother sighed repeatedly, &amp;ldquo;Oh, I have only rented this store for a few months, and I haven’t even made back the transfer fee yet. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Chuchu seemed to have lost her soul, looking left and right, looking at this main street store that she had dreamed of. This was her whole hope of going to Dengyun County to attend junior high school! Following the government&#39;s order, she seemed to see shops being wiped out and collapsed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A family of three sat in the store, silent. Fu Chuchu felt depressed and walked out of the store. On the streets, people are talking about the relocation. She came to the pier and saw two workers, one holding a paint bucket and the other holding a thick paint brush, scribbling huge &quot;demolish&quot; words on the outer wall of the tourist building at the pier. I heard that if the Three Gorges impounds water in two years, the Taichang River will rise and submerge Beijing Town, so the entire town will be relocated in advance. Why is it so sudden! Isn’t it possible in a few years? She looked at the Taichang River. The rushing water made her feel dizzy, and the expectation that was so close in her heart just sank to the bottom of the water. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Mei Butan&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see the @ONE studio pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/Fq2_j5d23xfDojzkLVTNdFw05u0u&quot; alt=&quot;He Xiaodao&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;He Xiaodao&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@一何小刀&lt;/span >; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Novel author and pop culture commentator. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/article/6088&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Autumn&#39;s pause button&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Su Gengsheng&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/div>; tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Read&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6087&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt; div>;Visiting the Past in Dongxiang｜Song of the Pillow Man&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Rabbit Grass&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td >; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6089)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/ table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.3995]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4124]]><description>&lt;div>;14 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FoKGNYmrS7mCqwXGJNdOm7MCes9a&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;VOL.3995&lt;/span>;Photography | Jonas Liubartas&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;14&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sep. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;No objectivity的记忆这回事，所有的记忆都是偏见，都是为了自己的存活而重组过的经验。 &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>