<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[一周的心情｜本周小记精选]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3997]]><description> &lt;div>;3 Dec. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Question from ONE Editorial Department&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>; Hey, it&#39;s been a week, how are you? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; ONE Friendly Answer&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1 ;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;On the weekend, listen, there is a new echo in the tree hole. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FtYXHNHXwMq9U6YXi2-Jmso2S9Sf&quot; data-source=&quot; &quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FtYXHNHXwMq9U6YXi2-Jmso2S9Sf&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http:// image.wufazhuce.com/FiS0qxciTWZLALD330A4syeomFhj&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FiS0qxciTWZLALD330A4syeomFhj&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FqbiKPwj3QmAH9kozsgqiaGO3Crl&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FqbiKPwj3QmAH9kozsgqiaGO3Crl&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot; false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgS0nVdGLDFPbjnlUGScx_vGcfbB&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgS0nVdGLDFPbjnlUGScx_vGcfbB &quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmEZXBxVhfue2Jd-SRI-28xYCoJX&quot; data-source=&quot; &quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmEZXBxVhfue2Jd-SRI-28xYCoJX&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FjC_xMpljzmQt2Mhu4X2SR1rSNmf&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FjC_xMpljzmQt2Mhu4X2SR1rSNmf&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author= &quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmbT7KjPAWBDnM498B-PJCBonX6i&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmbT7KjPAWBDnM498B-PJCBonX6i&quot;>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fk1dwOsNsF1PFyTwtwPEYVn6Ashl&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image .wufazhuce.com/Fk1dwOsNsF1PFyTwtwPEYVn6Ashl&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fi3RGFtGd0rMdTAv33e1SVvQLXMK&quot; data-source =&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fi3RGFtGd0rMdTAv33e1SVvQLXMK&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http:// image.wufazhuce.com/FkkKitXeECogVATngie6RkweObPZ&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FkkKitXeECogVATngie6RkweObPZ&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FjLW3HbDfDK7Gf3YrhPn3qLOyGfO&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FjLW3HbDfDK7Gf3YrhPn3qLOyGfO&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot; false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fk8XYTlkNV7YCKjlzdD4-w5qEPvM&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com /Fk8XYTlkNV7YCKjlzdD4-w5qEPvM&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fujuzu2e5qgp0pn4Yc7DTDTK5hUZ&quot; data-source=&quot; &quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fujuzu2e5qgp0pn4Yc7DTDTK5hUZ&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image. wufazhuce.com/FvoFJuMN9LkA-2trDZi04kLakLCf&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FvoFJuMN9LkA-2trDZi04kLakLCf&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author= &quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fh2cUemlMmCC-nOZNPhyGxe8P31L&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fh2cUemlMmCC-nOZNPhyGxe8P31L&quot;>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FoarMDoQ17oE2Dfmo9mzk8rOzEcz&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image .wufazhuce.com/FoarMDoQ17oE2Dfmo9mzk8rOzEcz&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FuWUFIUSz1C2s14xlHh5vDQFChUB&quot; data-source =&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FuWUFIUSz1C2s14xlHh5vDQFChUB&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http:// image.wufazhuce.com/FjpKhtm5yXmqyOo8KI4Cb-5tkv-p&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FjpKhtm5yXmqyOo8KI4Cb-5tkv-p&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt; /p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Zhou Ziheng onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Click on the &quot;pen&quot; below the daily signature on the homepage to leave your life moments in the tree hole , and your feelings that you can&#39;t express to others. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8 &quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Complex The cutest people in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3989&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;The mood of the week | Selected notes of the week&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Question and Answer&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3983 &quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;The mood of the week | Selected notes of the week&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table >; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3997)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https:// feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[结婚]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6185]]><description> &lt;div>;3 Dec. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Ren Shuoran&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmzcCpK0-mNu0WCSZGlEsSBuAoOJ&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmzcCpK0-mNu0WCSZGlEsSBuAoOJ&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;After graduation, Du Lin discovered that marriage was a shortcut across classes. A tool to change the direction of life and an antidote to heal family wounds. He discovered that marriage can be everything except love. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Du Lin took annual leave on May Day and returned to his hometown to discuss marriage matters with his mother. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At six o&#39;clock in the morning, Du Lin heard the door closing. The sound was a little dull at first, and then &quot;bang&quot;. The door lock of the iron security door is a little short of oil and it is difficult to close it at once. He stared at the guardrailed windows that he had counted so many times as a child. The sun has risen, and the light is divided into even horizontal grids by the railings. It passes through the thin curtains and falls on the quilt, like a page of notebook paper. A long time ago, Du Lin lived in the dormitory of his work unit. When he was woken up by the sound of his colleagues getting up to exercise in the morning, he would often stare at the railing outside the curtains for a long time like this. Looking at it like this, my mood actually becomes calmer, even a little relieved. Those bars on the windows were metaphors for many things he encountered in life, which were revelations of reality. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A little longer, in the days after the college entrance examination, Du Lin had not had time to learn to sleep in, and he would wake up to the sound of his mother&#39;s door closing every morning. Du Lin lay on the bed with his eyes closed, feeling the sunlight shining on his face through the railings and curtains. Du Lin had good grades and performed exceptionally well in the college entrance examination. My mother was very happy to go out every day. She took her notebook, pen and water bottle with her to attend every college counseling meeting in the school, and chatted with the teachers in the admissions office of each college for a while. When I got home, my mother and Du Lin discussed which college was worth attending every day. One day Du Lin couldn&#39;t bear it anymore and told his mother at the dinner table that he didn&#39;t want to hear it, that he would take his own path and that he had his own plan. Du Lin remembered that his mother&#39;s face darkened at that time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At that time, Du Lin had his own ideas. Du Lin&#39;s plan was to report to the same city as his then girlfriend Lin Weiwei - Shanghai. His mother didn&#39;t know that he had a girlfriend in high school, and she thought he was a good student who only read books about sages. On the day he received the admission notice, Du Lin used the money he earned from working in a tutoring institution to treat his mother to a meal. His mother scolded him for spending money, but there were smile lines in the corners of his eyes that he couldn&#39;t hide. At that time, Du Lin was high-spirited and had endless fantasies and plans for his future life, vowing to take the world into his pocket. When he broke up with Lin Weiwei three years later, Du Lin felt that life was like a dream, but the fact that Lin Weiwei quickly got together with a local Shanghainese after breaking up with him made him wake up from the dream faster. To this day, Du Lin doesn&#39;t know whether she was with that person before she broke up with him, or whether she was with that person after they broke up. But these are not important anymore, the so-called past is like the wind. Of course, it’s not just the past that is like the wind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The alarm clock rang, Du Lin touched the cell phone under the pillow and was about to call his girlfriend. My girlfriend is a Chinese teacher at school and also the head teacher of a class. She gets up at six o&#39;clock every morning and goes to the class on time at seven o&#39;clock to supervise students&#39; morning reading. My girlfriend was very angry when she woke up. It was only after Du Lin&#39;s wake-up call that the key was matched. At that time, Du Lin was not sensitive to such colorful words. According to his girlfriend, she was attracted to his simplicity at that time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The phone rang for sixty seconds and no one answered. Only then did Du Lin remember that today was the last day of the May Day holiday. His girlfriend was probably still sleeping and the phone was set to silent. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From six to seven-thirty, an hour and a half was suddenly freed up. This was the first time in recent years that Du Lin experienced the so-called feeling of being bored. Familiar music sounded outside the window. Music is the divine song sweeping all major short videos right now. Du Lin stood up, opened the curtains, opened the windows, and ventilated the room. Downstairs, an old man was opening a trash can. There were stacks of cardboard boxes and crushed plastic bottles at his feet. After a while, the complex smell in the trash can drifted to Du Lin&#39;s house with the wind. It was the smell of urban indigestion burping. Du Lin closed the window, walked to the desk, and randomly picked out a book, which was a reference material for him when he was in high school. &quot;53&quot; and &quot;Knowledge List&quot; take up most of the space on the desk, and a small part of the space is dedicated to magazines such as &quot;Reader&quot;. Eleven years have passed since Du Lin graduated from high school, and these reference materials are still here, which makes people feel sympathetic and also gives people a sense of oppression from the college entrance examination. Du Lin got dressed and went to the bathroom to wash up. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The underwear that my mother washed last night was hanging in the bathroom. They were plain beige with some blue flowers on them. Du Lin was a little embarrassed. After his father passed away, his mother always paid attention to these details when facing her adolescent son. The balcony where clothes were hung at home was in Du Lin&#39;s room, but Du Lin had never seen his mother&#39;s underwear on the balcony in those years. Du Lin half-hooked his waist, being careful not to let his arms touch his mother&#39;s underwear, and then poured water on his hair while thinking about his mother&#39;s possible path every morning. My mother retired five years ago and worked as a dairy product promoter in a supermarket for two years after retirement. In those years, every time Du Lin came home for annual vacation, he would be surprised by the variety of milk and its long shelf life. One time, her mother was admitted to the hospital after drinking milk. Du Lin, who was thousands of miles away, was a little angry and asked her mother to give up her job. In Du Lin&#39;s case, his mother is obedient, even so obedient that it makes people feel distressed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At Du Lin&#39;s request, her mother now refuses all job opportunities and has a lot of time every day. She might go to the vegetable market first, then burn incense sticks at the Chenghuang Temple near her home, and return home around 7:30. Du Lin once went to incense with his mother. The mother first bowed in the four directions of east, north, west and south, praying to the gods of the four directions to protect their orphans and widowed mothers. Then she knelt on the futon and silently said a few words to her father or someone in heaven. Du Lin felt that this moment was When their home is more like a real home, the family is reunited in a certain sense in their minds. They are not troubled by illness and pain, and they can temporarily forget about their embarrassing life. Although this prayer itself does not mean much. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After washing up, Du Lin sat down on the sofa in the living room and heard the sound of the TV coming from next door. The local station was playing back the news from last night: &quot;This city&#39;s special project&quot; The Action Office and each member unit announced to the public how to accept reports, and opened a &quot;Special Action Column on Combating Pension Fraud&quot; through various publicity channels and media platforms. The flush toilet of the house opposite made a clanging sound, and then the iron door &quot;clanged&quot; was opened. Although it is a holiday, for most people, it is no different than usual. The floor leather under Du Lin&#39;s feet was a little wrinkled, and he also saw that the edge of the floor leather by the living room window had become warped. He opened Taobao and measured the dimensions of the living room with his feet. When he walked to the window, Du Lin saw that the gap formed by the two missing protective railings on the living room window was still there. When he was in high school, Du Lin once forgot to bring his keys and was in a hurry to go home to get Lin Weiwei&#39;s birthday gift. Du Lin went to Xu Ge&#39;s house to borrow a saw blade, and together he and Xu Ge cut off two railings. The gap formed by the railing was exactly the width of Du Lin&#39;s body at that time. Under Xu Ge&#39;s exaggerated description, it seemed as if Du Lin had demolished his own home for Lin Weiwei. Lin Weiwei smiled happily listening to Xu Ge&#39;s description. At that time, Du Lin felt that even if Lin Weiwei wanted the moon in the sky, he could find a way to build a ladder to pick it off for her. Later, Lin Weiwei didn&#39;t want the moon in the sky, she just wanted a house in Shanghai. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It’s hard to say how much of a catalytic effect a house in Shanghai played in the end of Du Lin and Lin Weiwei’s relationship. In his junior year, Du Lin felt that a house was just a house. There was no difference between the one in Shanghai and the one in his hometown. The only difference was that Shanghai had more convenient transportation and better medical and educational resources. The two had a protracted quarrel over this issue, and neither of them could convince the other. Du Lin felt that Lin Weiwei was too anxious. They had not finished college yet, but Lin Weiwei counted the benefits of a house in Shanghai one by one. When talking about the education of the next generation, Du Lin was finally able to interject. He said confidently: &quot;Our children will definitely have super IQs in the future. They can learn well without any school district. You teach Chinese and English, and I teach mathematics, physics and chemistry. We two top students are afraid that we will not be able to tutor one child?&quot; &amp;rdquo;Unexpectedly, the next day, Lin Weiwei sent a breakup message to Du Lin. Then Du Lin went to find her, but Lin Weiwei avoided seeing her, or didn&#39;t say anything when he saw her. Lin Weiwei turned her breakup into a performance art of refusing to speak. Later, Du Lin heard that Lin Weiwei was getting married with a Shanghai man. The day he learned the news, Du Lin spent the whole night watching the moon on the balcony of his dormitory. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking out from the gap, the old man who was digging through the trash can had already reached the door of the third unit. The trash can lid was closed, and the sound of square dance music stopped in the distance , the sound of the TV next door also disappeared, and the world suddenly became quiet. Du Lin suddenly remembered some scenes from his childhood. It was such a morning. The day before, he had taken leave at home because of illness. When he opened his eyes in the morning, the world was silent, and a kind of fear seized his heart. He started to cry loudly and kicked the security door of his home naked. In an instant, the world came to life again. The neighbor went to the factory and called my mother back. When he threw himself into his mother&#39;s arms, Du Lin felt that the warm world had returned. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a blink of an eye, many old people dancing in the square appeared in the community. They were gathered in small groups of twos and threes, wearing red tops and black trousers, carrying fried dough sticks and vegetables, laughing and chatting. Du Lin opened the window and tugged on the remaining railings. The railings are very rusty, and the rusty pink color is charming to the eyes. Now that Du Lin&#39;s house in Shanghai is on the 28th floor, there is no need to install protective railings. It&#39;s not Du Lin&#39;s house in Shanghai, it&#39;s his girlfriend&#39;s, so there&#39;s no need to bother. It&#39;s a house that was demolished and divided by his girlfriend&#39;s family. It has been nearly seven years since graduation. Du Lin always rushes home every Chinese New Year. After dating his girlfriend, he tries his best to spend the annual leave with her during the summer vacation. After so many years, the protective railings of this window have become completely rusted, and they are like deaf ears. There was no need to borrow a saw blade from Xu Ge&#39;s family, Du Lin could break two saw blades with his bare hands. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xu Ge was Du Lin’s best friend when he was studying. After he and Lin Weiwei became acquainted, Xu Ge stayed with him. Xu Geshu was not very good at reading books, but later it turned out that whether he read books well or not was increasingly irrelevant to how well he lived. What was equally irrelevant to life was maybe feelings. Sometimes Du Lin finds it quite ironic that his father&#39;s last words when he passed away were that he should study hard in order to get ahead. Du Lin&#39;s studies also led to him becoming the city&#39;s number one scholar. When he arrived at university, he found that eight top students lived in a dormitory building. There is also less correlation between &quot;study hard&quot; and &quot;getting ahead&quot;. The fact of &quot;good at studying&quot; only got bonus points when I went to my current girlfriend&#39;s house to meet her parents. My girlfriend&#39;s father was very happy that Du Lin was once the city&#39;s number one scholar. When they first met, the conversation at the dinner table even extended to the future of their children with good genes, good grades, and superior IQs. My girlfriend’s father said that being the top scorer in the college entrance examination is somewhat valuable. Du Lin wasn&#39;t sure whether &quot;it counts&quot; meant he was satisfied or dissatisfied. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xu Ge went to college in Beijing. After graduation, he and his college girlfriend planned to buy a house. He and his girlfriend have good family conditions, but it is difficult to buy a house in Beijing. In addition, during the two years of waiting to settle down, housing prices in Beijing have risen a lot. Xu Ge and his girlfriend scraped together money from their parents&#39; homes to make the down payment for a house in Beijing. On the day the house was decorated, Du Lin made a special trip to Beijing to warm Xu Ge&#39;s house. At that time, Du Lin already had his current girlfriend. Eating hot pot and singing songs in the new house was not easy, but at least he was able to get ashore. Xu Ge and Du Lin both drank that day and inevitably talked about Lin Weiwei, Lin Weiwei&#39;s new boyfriend and new life. &quot;It&#39;s really not Lin Weiwei&#39;s fault,&quot; Xu Ge said, &quot;Lin Weiwei&#39;s boyfriend has settled the Shanghai household registration for her and has a house in Shanghai. We can&#39;t blame her girl for her reality. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At half past seven, mother came back. Mother bought the fried dough sticks and side dishes that Du Lin had been eating since he was in school, and filled up the porridge that he had been cooking when he went out. Du Lin and his mother sat together to have breakfast on an ordinary morning, as they had done many times before. For a moment, Du Lin felt as if time had taken a detour, bypassing the days when he was not around, and returning to the original days. He suddenly noticed that his mother&#39;s hair was very white. In the light that flickered like powder dropped by a moth, Du Lin saw that his mother&#39;s hands holding the chopsticks were shaking violently. He couldn&#39;t help feeling shuddered and buried his head in drinking porridge. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After breakfast with his mother, Du Lin put away the dishes while his mother chose what to cook for lunch on the dining table. Du Lin told his mother about the marriage. Apparently, his mother was a little overwhelmed by the surprise. She held the dish in her hand for a long time before she realized what girl she was from and when it happened. Asked a lot. Du Lin felt a little nervous in his heart, fearing that his mother would ask about the marriage and housing. There was a ready-made house, but my girlfriend&#39;s family proposed that Du Lin move in. But the mother was obviously immersed in joy and had not thought of this level. My mother has always been like this. Whenever there is a good thing related to him, she always chews the happy part first for a while. Since his father passed away in the second year of junior high school, Du Lin has learned to report good news but not bad news. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After breakfast, my mother turned on the TV as usual, and Du Lin watched it for a while. When I turned around, I found my mother sitting on the sofa and falling asleep. The sofa cushions supported my mother&#39;s chin, and the inner bladder squeezed out from the torn hole in the cushion cover, like a mouth with white teeth. In this family, it was easy for Du Lin to find some flaws. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At one o&#39;clock after lunch, after the dishes were put away, my mother seemed to have remembered something, got up and went to the house to get a bankbook. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;This is the 120,000 yuan I have saved over the years. &quot;My mother said, &quot;You also know that your father spent a lot of money due to illness in the past few years, but this is all my mother can give you. You have to earn the rest by yourself, and it&#39;s not easy for other girls to follow you. I heard that housing prices in Shanghai are high. If not, you can discuss it with a girl and come to our hometown to buy it. I will help you take care of your children. If you still want to work hard in Shanghai, that&#39;s fine. However, if you can buy a house, you should try to buy a house. If a girl follows you with a name, we can&#39;t treat her badly. She doesn&#39;t even have a place to stay. I thought, it shouldn&#39;t be difficult for two college students to buy a house in Shanghai, right? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Du Lin felt that there was wind in the room, and the light shining on his mother&#39;s face was a little shaken. &quot;Her family wanted me to come over.&quot; Her family&#39;s house was demolished and divided.&quot; Du Lin said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Then, do you want to marry me? &amp;rdquo;Mother murmured. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Yes. I also hope you will come to Shanghai with me, and you can also find a companion. &amp;rdquo; Du Lin said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mother said nothing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Until dinner, Du Lin and his mother prepared to cook as usual. Du Lin proposed that he should do it. He saw that the gas line in the kitchen was last inspected a year ago. The hoods and stoves in the kitchen are all labeled as &quot;one person lives alone&quot;. There is a stove, a pot, and a barrel of oil with one third left, and the date is last year. Du Lin touched it and found that the dust on the cabinet was almost a finger thick. Du Lin couldn&#39;t find chopsticks after cracking the eggs, and couldn&#39;t find salt after putting the eggs in the pan. After asking his mother several times, her mother kicked him out of the kitchen. In the house he lives in Shanghai, his girlfriend has never entered the kitchen once, and he knows every item in the kitchen by heart. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is really no longer his home. Du Lin was a little disappointed. This feeling was like a basin of cold water pouring down his head, overwhelming. He didn&#39;t know what his mother thought. From the day he went to college, Du Lin found that he could no longer detect his mother&#39;s thoughts. The outside world is so big, although life is just a matter of going back and forth. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Until I was about to go to bed after watching TV at night, my mother did not say &quot;yes&quot; or &quot;no&quot;. There was no clear answer to Du Lin&#39;s mention of going to Shanghai, to his upcoming marriage, or to the fact that he was about to get married. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Du Lin is the only son in the family, which was not a big news in the era of family planning. But Du Lin&#39;s family received special treatment from his grandfather&#39;s family at that time. Although the treatment was only a few acres of land and an old house in his hometown. After his grandfather passed away, his father gave the land to a neighbor for farming, and the old house was sold for funeral arrangements, which also made Du Lin&#39;s uncles very unhappy. No matter how difficult the family was in the years after my father passed away, my mother never spoke to her uncles or asked her natal family for help. Except for the matters related to Du Lin, my mother seemed extremely strong. She was always too worried and wanted to do good for him, but her personal life was cold and cold, like the snow caught in the ice deep in the glacier. Du Lin didn&#39;t know whether his mother suddenly became like this after his father passed away, or whether she became like this slowly. He still remembered that half a year after his father&#39;s death, the neighbor&#39;s aunt introduced retired cadres to his mother. Du Lin was playing games in his room that day. Although his voice was low, Du Lin could guess pretty well. After deciding to marry his current girlfriend, Du Lin thought it would be good if his mother really married that retired cadre, at least she would have a companion. Also worry less about yourself. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These thoughts take root and grow like vines. Du Lin felt shameless. Recently, he often thinks about the past, probably because of the habits he developed when he was a good student. When entering the next stage, you must always summarize and look back on the life of the previous stage. It seems that only in this way can the next plan be carried out. Sometimes, because you are too rational, you appear to be excessive. Not only do you have to convince others, but it is even more difficult to convince yourself. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Du Lin remembered watching a family mediation program with his mother at home during the winter vacation from college. In the program, the son firmly opposed his mother&#39;s remarriage on the grounds that if his mother became someone else&#39;s woman, he would have no mother. In front of dozens of people, a man in his thirties burst into tears at the show as if he had been cheated out of money. Du Lin looked at his mother with some embarrassment. His mother was staring at the TV screen, her face was blank, and she could not see any special emotions. The show ended with the mother and son embracing and reconciling on stage, while the audience and guests wiped away tears and smiled. Du Lin was the only one who cared about whether the mother had successfully remarried. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The moonlight was bright, and the wind slipped in through the window, caressing people&#39;s faces. Summer has just entered in the north in May, and the night breeze is light and gentle. Tonight was his last night sleeping in this home. Du Lin got up and sat at his desk, turned on the light, and found that he could no longer understand the topics in the mathematics book &quot;Five Three&quot; that he had opened in the morning. Many things that he was once proud of when he was a student are being lost unconsciously. Maybe these things themselves are not that important. Du Lin thought, picked up his phone and saw Xu Ge&#39;s photos of working overtime late at night in his circle of friends. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On his trip back to his hometown, Du Lin specially reserved a day to visit Xu Ge in Beijing. Xu Ge is starting a business, and it is said that it is doing well so far. People say that in thirty years Hedong will be in Hexi and thirty years in Hexi. In fact, it won’t take that long. They can be inseparable in just a few years. For some people, there is a bridge between Hedong and Hexi. For some, the distance is as vast as the Milky Way. Some people were born in Rome. There is nothing to compare. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The year Xu Ge bought a house, Du Lin had just switched jobs from a start-up company to work as an automotive engineer in a local state-owned enterprise in Shanghai, in order to obtain a Shanghai household registration. In the first half year of work, I have to go to the workshop to tighten screws. After a month, my arms are thicker and thinner. At that time, Xu Ge told Du Lin that he should start a business with him, and Du Lin said he would think about it for himself. It was just an excuse to think about it, Du Lin had his own plan. At that time, Du Lin had officially dated his girlfriend, and his girlfriend&#39;s house was determined to be demolished. He had already read the red-headed documents for the demolition. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A year later, Du Lin moved in with his girlfriend and took his girlfriend’s father to the hospital for dialysis every week. His girlfriend’s family was very satisfied with him and treated him like half a son. Du Lin didn&#39;t let his mother know about all this. This time Du Lin returned to his hometown during the annual vacation to discuss marriage matters with his mother. More importantly, he wanted to discuss her marriage matters with his mother. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This idea was planted when Du Lin and Xu Ge were chatting. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After Xu Ge learned that Du Lin’s girlfriend was a demolished household in Shanghai, he teased him that he could easily own the market value of a start-up company. He also said that at the beginning of the millennium, there were many intermediaries specializing in this kind of business in Shanghai. It is mainly aimed at the elderly who fake marriages and split up their houses. They earn money once they get married, and then use the money earned from multiple marriages to buy a house again. This is a circular economy. Many Shanghainese whose ID cards do not start with &quot;310&quot; are like this. Become a new Shanghainese. &quot;&#39;310&#39; has become a golden number. This world is so damn funny,&quot; Xu Ge said with a smile. It was an expression that Du Lin was all too familiar with. The disdain was filled with envy, and the envy was mixed with contempt. In the end, it became a force and became one of Xu Ge&#39;s motivations for starting a business. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Du Lin laughed a few times, and his girlfriend was from &quot;310&quot; Shanghai. Once, when Du Lin and his girlfriend took out their tickets from the self-service ticket dispensing machine at the train station, his girlfriend took two ID cards and looked at them in the sun. A golden one and a wooden one. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Du Lin still remembers the bright sun hitting people’s faces that day, which was more painful than scratching someone with a knife. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Du Lin never thought that his mother would be allocated a house. This policy was stopped more than ten years ago, otherwise his name would appear on his girlfriend’s household registration book. A suite. Du Lin just thought that his mother could find someone who knew both the cold and the hot, preferably around Shanghai, with a place to live, and he could visit her on the weekends. It didn&#39;t matter even if he had to do a pre-marital property notarization. This idea has been lingering in Du Lin&#39;s mind for several years, ever since he was with his girlfriend. I am also quietly asking people to find suitable candidates. When everything was ready and ready to be explained, Du Lin didn&#39;t know how to explain it to his mother in detail. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My girlfriend’s family has decided to hold a wedding for Du Lin before school starts in September. One day, Du Lin sent his girlfriend&#39;s father to the hospital for a physical examination. Along the way, his girlfriend&#39;s father talked a lot about his daughter&#39;s childhood. Finally, he said to Du Lin: &quot;I am old, and I also took a fancy to your character and talent, so I gave my daughter to you.&quot; For you, I want you to promise to be good to your little girl. Du Lin said: &quot;I promise to be good to her.&quot; ” But in my heart, my judgment on the meaning of “also” and “talent” was erratic. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While waiting for his girlfriend&#39;s father to check his health in the hospital, his girlfriend&#39;s mother said: &quot;Your mother will come to Shanghai. I can&#39;t help you. I know, Ala&#39;a is not in good health. I heard that my mother is not in good health.&quot; Nan said that Nong’s mother was in good health, but Yi probably disliked the small place where she lived in Shanghai. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Du Lin didn’t know how to answer, his girlfriend was stamping her feet beside him. Du Lin knew what his girlfriend meant. She had told him earlier that it was impossible for her to live with any elder. She could help him, but living together was extremely annoying. People in Shanghai say that &quot;the most annoying thing&quot; is always arrogant and coquettish. It&#39;s not that it&#39;s better not to do it, but it&#39;s not that you don&#39;t want it at all. There are fine needles hidden in the seemingly gentleness, which makes you want to stop. Sometimes Du Lin even hates his girlfriend&#39;s &quot;utterly annoying&quot; coquettishness. She seems to have never grown up and can act like a coquettish girl in front of her parents and him without restraint. She can act coquettishly and cutely and make these requests become Reality. One time Du Lin forgot to wake her up, his girlfriend would tell her parents that Du Lin was &quot;very annoying&quot; for a long time, just like suing a teacher. Du Lin&#39;s feeling of being willful in front of his family disappeared when his father became seriously ill. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mathematics, physics, chemistry... Du Lin flipped through those reference books, and his name and name were written on the first page of each book. An inspirational saying that was quite popular at the time was something like, &quot;I have been studying hard for ten years in cold weather, and I am not afraid of difficulties, and I hope to fight with my parents to win the championship despite the odds.&quot; On the first page of a comprehensive &quot;Knowledge List&quot;, Du Lin unexpectedly saw a photo of the three of them as a family. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He quickly closed the book. Until now, Du Lin hadn&#39;t figured out how to introduce that person to his mother. He had a quarrel with his mother a long time ago, so he really didn&#39;t know the feasibility of persuading his mother to &quot;get married.&quot; But in Du Lin&#39;s case, his mother has always been obedient. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was the summer vacation after his high school entrance examination. He and several classmates made an appointment to ride bicycles to their classmates&#39; houses in the countryside. After the lunch break, most of the heat had dissipated, and a few of them were galloping through the streets of the small town happily and with a sense of adventure. Before leaving the city, Du Lin&#39;s bicycle tire went flat. While repairing the tire at the car repair shop, Xu Ge pushed Du Lin, pointed at the person in the distance and said, &quot;That seems to be your mother.&quot; ” Du Lin saw his mother talking to a middle-aged man together, looking very happy, and his mother even gave the man a shove. After the tire was repaired, Du Lin took the car and turned around and rode home. My mother was a little excited when she came back in the evening. She didn&#39;t even ask why Du Lin didn&#39;t go to the countryside. However, there were several dishes added to the dinner table. Du Lin couldn&#39;t hold back. Before he even picked up the bowl, he asked his mother who she had been with all day. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My mother was stunned for a moment and just asked someone to find another job with a higher salary. Du Lin felt that his mother had talked to friends while hiding from him, and even let his friends see it, which made him lose face. His mother repeatedly promised that she would not look for him again and would live a good life with him. Du Lin said that after his father passed away, everyone felt sorry for him and he did not want to be pitied by others. Du Lin later kept recalling the quarrel he had with his mother, but he could never recall what his mother said specifically or how it ended. That quarrel seemed like a rebirth. He still remembered that in the dusk that came in through the broken window, his mother became less like a mother and more like an expressionless stone statue. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At this moment, Du Lin, who was standing in the moonlight, thought about this incident, and felt sour in his heart. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In fact, after the quarrel, my mother had no good feelings towards the matchmakers who introduced her to her partner. Thinking about it now, my mother was only a little over forty when my father died, and she was barely more than halfway through her life. Du Lin didn&#39;t know how he could have such stupid thoughts at that time. Now he is getting married, but he has to leave his mother alone thousands of miles away. The idea that I want my mother to get married that lingers in my heart is not just for myself to get married. I had it a few years ago when I was in college. Du Lin hopes that his mother will have her own feelings, real feelings, and also hopes to make up for her mistakes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thinking of this, he felt much better. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; nbsp; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The person at the moment was mentioned by Du Lin and his colleagues in the chat. The old man lived in Songjiang and took one hour from Du Lin&#39;s house to the subway. Although her mother has never been sitting in the subway in her life, people will always adapt, just like the long -term love. As long as the character is good, the time is over, and after the weighing of the advantages and disadvantages, the feelings will naturally have it. The old man&#39;s surname is Wang. He lost his wife for three years and was five years older than his mother. Du Lin had seen the old man with his colleagues on a certain weekend. The old man didn&#39;t talk much, and cleaned it up. He insisted that he had to look at his mother&#39;s photos and medical reports. After reading it, he was still satisfied with his mother. The last three people drink coffee money. This detail touched Du Lin, after all, this is Shanghai. If you want to come to his mother to follow him, you should not be wronged. Of course, Du Lin will never let her mother be wronged in money. Now Du Lin does not need to repay the mortgage. He is lining up the car sign, and his salary is relatively rich. He can drive to see his mother on weekends. Mother has always wanted to hug her grandson and watch his next generation of growth. As long as the mother agrees to contact the retired teacher and can finally achieve it, ten months later, the mother&#39;s wishes can be realized. The realization of these plans is close. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Du Lin&#39;s girlfriend is pregnant. In fact, it is already a wife, and the certificate has been received in early March. The girlfriend&#39;s father had a dream, and he dreamed that he was going on. He dragged his daughter and Du Lin&#39;s hand and asked them to get married. Du Lin sometimes feels that life is particularly unreal, because life has never been seriously implemented according to the plan. Although his way along the way is planned, planning a blind date, planning to get married, plan to give birth, plan to be promoted job. The girlfriend&#39;s house was demolished, and his girlfriend&#39;s father had planned it when he and his girlfriend had dated. If they received a certificate, they wrote the materials to the unborn grandchildren or granddaughter. Du Lin&#39;s name has not yet appeared on any real estate certificate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; But these thin branches are diluted by Du Lin&#39;s about to be his father. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;br>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At two in the night, Du Lin had no sleep, and heard the cough of the mother next door. Mother has done most of her life in the textile workshop, and her lungs are not good. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; Pap &amp; rdquo; With one sound, he heard the sound of his mother turned on the lights, and then heard the sound of footsteps and poured water. Du Lin silently distinguished her mother&#39;s actions in her heart. The mother did not return to the room, as if sitting on the sofa. The moonlight was a little cold, and Du Lin suddenly wanted to find a mother to have another quilt. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The TV is on the TV, her mother squinted her eyes, and she tried to identify the subtitles. Seeing Du Lin standing in front of her, she was scared. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; The wind at night is still a bit cold. &amp; rdquo; In the colorful light of the TV screen, Du Lin smiled and said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The mother was going to get up and took the quilt to Du Lin, and he pressed him. &amp; ldquo; I can&#39;t sleep every night, &amp; rdquo; My mother seems to be broken as a bad thing, and said shyly, &amp; ldquo; Let&#39;s take a look at the TV and disturb you to sleep? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Du Lin watched the scene where the old man teased the child on the TV, turned to look at his mother, and said: &amp; ldquo; Mom, I have to be a father too. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The mother is obviously a little excited. She seemed to have forgotten that she had not expressed their views on her son&#39;s marriage all day, and blindly held the health of the fetus and the diet of pregnant women. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; That&#39;s right, mom, you come to Shanghai, &amp; rdquo; Du Lin interrupted his mother and said: &amp; ldquo; Anyway, the wedding is about to do. You have only seen it in the photo before, and your grandson, I am relieved when you are here. Last time I told you that looking for your companion is not a joke. Then there is a teacher Wang, and I especially think about it. It&#39;s okay to find a companion. You can see it by the way. Teacher Wang is very satisfied with you. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After talking about a lot of important and unimportant things, Du Lin finally said. The curtains of the living room were not pulled. Looking out from the railing, blue to the dark sky, a large and round moon. Du Lin has never seen such a majestic moon. From the perspective of Du Lin&#39;s perspective, this magnificent moon is just hanging on the head of the mother. He suddenly was afraid that the moon fell and hit his mother. Du Lin&#39;s heart was holding. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Du Lin&#39;s heart was embarrassed, fearing that his mother was opposed, and he was more afraid of his mother&#39;s silence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; Okay. &amp; rdquo; Mother said, &amp; ldquo; you help me buy a ticket. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;br>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In mid -August, Du Lin&#39;s wedding was held as scheduled. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; One month before the wedding, the mother met with the teacher Wang. Seeing that Du Lin took his mother to Shanghai&#39;s largest shopping mall to buy clothes. The mall was surrounded by huge glass without railing, and the light lamps were hung everywhere. As much as possible, the mall was as bright as possible, and there was no shadow. When Du Lin saw that his mother became smaller in the translucent flashing space. When her mother tried her clothes, Du Lin couldn&#39;t help but sigh in her heart: How can anyone be so small? how come? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The mother seemed a little timid and forgot to stop Du Lin spend money. Du Lin felt that he was actually cruel, and could only hide it with money, and bought one piece after the clothes inside and outside. In fact, my mother said &amp; ldquo; OK &amp; rdquo; better than &amp; ldquo; not good &amp; rdquo; make him more sad. He suddenly envied Xu Ge. Xu Ge could turn everything into the power of response. He did not find a block for himself, but in the end he was a retreat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Teacher Wang&#39;s satisfaction was amplified after seeing his mother. One night before the meeting, Mr. Wang sent a document before going to bed, saying that he would do a notarization of property before receiving a certificate with his mother. The real estate certificate did not add the mother&#39;s name. We all said in advance. This is the document I drafted. Let&#39;s find the time to sign. Are you optimistic? &amp; rdquo; Teacher Wang said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Du Lin Reply: &amp; ldquo; Okay. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Mother and Teacher Wang attended the wedding. After receiving his wife&#39;s hand from his father -in -law, Du Lin turned his head and found that his mother wiped tears secretly below. The wedding Si Yi talked about Du Lin&#39;s teenager and worked hard. In the end, he was admitted to Shanghai as the champion of a city college entrance examination. When he was happy with the bride, Du Lin cried. Others only loved his wife. moved. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After Du Lin took care of his wife asleep in the evening, he received a call from Xu Ge. &amp; nbsp; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; Your kid, &amp; rdquo; Xu Ge said, &amp; ldquo; if you do n’t say a word, you will make the girl ’s belly big, so you dare to give birth to a baby, I and my wife and me Now I am too busy to die, and no one will bring it. Hey, I think my aunt and an old man are together. The old man will not be the boyfriend of aunt, a wow in Shanghai dialect. Yes, my aunt also married to Shanghai and was caught up to help you bring your children. You have no worries about it. Your kid will have a plan since he was a child. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Du Lin on the balcony, looking up at the moon in the sky, and found that this moon was the same as what he saw on the balcony of the dormitory. . &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Li Jialong&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see @ONE Studio’s pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. Editor&#39;s official WeChat: OneApp2020. Regularly publish Q &amp; A collection, gift books and surrounding gifts, and readers are welcome to add. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Author &lt;/p>; &lt;hr style = &quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style = &quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src = &quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/fsegjzddargujxoxljie51xp4goa &quot;alt =&quot; Otherwise &quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;div>; Otherwise &lt;span style =&quot; font-siZe: 10px &quot;>; &amp; nbsp; Weibo@任- &lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style = &quot;&quot;>; I want to be a tree. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width = &quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-&lt;span Onclick = &quot;OneApp.Opendetail (2,)&quot;>; Follow &lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href = &quot;/article/6181&quot; data-ajax = &quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>; True game &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; text/boli &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr >; &lt;td style = &quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>; Read &lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6187&quot; data- ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>; sword &lt; /div>; &lt;div>; text/Hou Zhang &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;l>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style = &quot;text-align: center; padding: 5px; >; &amp; nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4075]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4219]]><description>&lt;div>; 3 DEC. 2023 &amp; Nbsp; &lt;/DIV>; &lt;DIV ROLE = &quot;Main&quot;>; &lt;DIV>; &lt;IMG SRC = &quot;Http://image.wufazhuce.com/fiawwwwwwwwww5isuy3mo4CF38AHTS-&quot; Alt = &quot;Homepage Figure&quot;/ &quot; &lt;p>; &lt;span>; Vol.4075 &lt;/span>; Photography | Hans Isaacson &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 3 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; DEC. 2023 &lt;/P>; &lt;/DIV>; &lt;p>; Winter It is lonely, Xia is parting, and spring is a bridge between the two. Only autumn, penetrate all seasons. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &amp; nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 03 Dec 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>