<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[「在一起」最重要的五件事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3950]]><description> &lt;div>;20 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Question from ONE Editorial Department&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>; What are the five most important things to do &quot;together&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; ONE’s answer&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;p>;What are the five most important things in an intimate relationship? Are they consistent in love and marriage? The ONE editorial department conducted a survey with readers. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Of the 200 questionnaires distributed this time, 91 of the ONE friends interviewed were male and 109 female. Among them, &lt;strong>;56%&lt;/strong>; are single, &lt;strong>;34%&lt;/strong>; are in a relationship, and &lt;strong>;10%&lt;/strong>; are married. &lt;/p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmNquuj_E-pFSgLUX4Qvk9-XwkjL&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src =&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmNquuj_E-pFSgLUX4Qvk9-XwkjL&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http:// image.wufazhuce.com/FmcKH6VPbc6EvymWmqos5roXyajc&quot; ​​data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmcKH6VPbc6EvymWmqos5roXyajc&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;It can be concluded from this questionnaire survey that when talking to a When people fall in love or get married, the most important thing for ONE friends is &quot;three views&quot;. The consistency of the three views is regarded as a decisive factor in the development of an intimate relationship. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The last one is &lt;strong>;&quot;Food Taste&quot; and &quot;MBTI Personality&quot;.&lt;/strong>; It seems that the popular personality test on the Internet does not have much influence on the choice of the other half in reality. As for whether you can eat a piece of it, you can also rely on takeout to solve the problem. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;ONE friends who are in love shared four other things they value, namely: &quot;&lt;strong>;Companionship&quot; and &quot;Emotional stability&amp;nbsp;/&amp;nbsp;Emotional intelligence&lt;/strong>;&lt; strong>;&quot; &quot;Responsibility&quot; and &quot;Communication Skills&quot;. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The other four things that ONE friends who enter marriage value most are: &quot;&lt;strong>;Sense of responsibility&quot; &quot;Personal financial conditions&quot; &quot;Family situation&quot; &quot;Emotional stability/ Emotional intelligence&quot;. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Let’s take a look at the choices made by ONE friends of different genders, ages and emotional statuses. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Gender&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;a. Difference&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Sense of Responsibility&quot;&lt;/p>; strong>;This is the biggest difference between men and women in love. 30% of men cited it as their first choice, compared with 46% of women. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Economic conditions&quot; and &quot;Family situation&quot;&lt;/strong>; are the two items with the biggest differences in choices between men and women in marriage, with 35% of men and 57% of women. Perhaps we can see the impact of the division of labor between men and women in the traditional family structure. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Horoscope&quot; and &quot;MBTI Personality Test&quot;&lt;/strong>; are the two items with the smallest difference. Everyone still pays more attention to the appearance of the person in life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;b. Commonalities&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In love, men and women &lt;strong>;commonly care&lt;/strong>; about &lt;strong>;&quot;companionship&quot; &lt;/strong>;, 56% of men and 48% of women respectively believe that the companionship of their partner is the most important. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In marriage, what both men and women care about is each other&#39;s &lt;strong>;&quot;motivation&quot;&lt;/strong>;. To maintain a relationship and build a stable family, the other party needs enough enterprising spirit and positive motivation in both career and life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition, ranking second to fourth are: &lt;strong>;&quot;Family situation&quot;, &quot;Quality of sexual life&quot; and &quot;Ability to tolerate and compromise&quot;. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Age&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among college students aged 18-22. The TOP3 things they value most are &quot;three outlooks&quot;, &quot;sense of responsibility&quot; and &quot;economic conditions&quot;. &lt;strong>;0 people&lt;/strong>; included the &quot;MBTI Personality Test&quot; in their selections. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among the relatively financially independent office workers aged 23-30, the top three are &quot;three outlooks&quot;, &quot;sense of responsibility&quot; and &quot;companionship&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Between the ages of 31 and 42, the top three are &quot;family situation&quot;, &quot;responsibility&quot; and &quot;emotional stability&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Single men and women&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Single men generally regard &quot;hobbies&quot; as an important factor in marriage. 0 women selected this factor. The number of single men and women who choose &quot;hobbies&quot; in their relationships is about the same. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Single men value each other’s consumption level more than women. The opposite is true for men and women in marriage. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Marriage Story&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The top three qualities of married men are: &quot;Three outlooks&quot;, &quot;Sense of responsibility&quot;, &quot;Tolerance&quot; and the ability to compromise.” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The top three factors for married women are: &quot;three outlooks&quot;, &quot;personal financial conditions&quot; and &quot;sense of responsibility&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Special mention&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Single men and women put &quot;three views&quot; first, while being in love and being married People pay attention to the two factors of &quot;three views&quot; and &quot;sense of responsibility&quot; at the same time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Appearance&quot;&lt;/strong>; is no longer the core factor for generating love and establishing intimate relationships. 6% of single people regard it as a choice, and only 3% of people in love and married . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;They said &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All the foundations of marriage are based on love. As a girl, I I can’t guarantee my tolerance for a loveless marriage. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@王杰丽 (female, 23 years old, in love)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;It is also important for two people to remain independent individuals after they get together. Don&#39;t have a sense of sacrifice, which will easily consume the enthusiasm of being together. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@小宇(female, 25 years old, single)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If you are in a relationship and have love, you can throw away all the above. If you have money to get married, you can also throw away the above. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@obession (male, 24 years old, single)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;It is difficult for people who are in love to explain clearly, and the desires of singles are always too far away from reality. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@Lairin (male, 29 years old, in love)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text- align: right;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;In an intimate relationship, you What are the things that matter most to you? &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Li Jialong onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/ p>; &lt;p>;This issue of Q&amp;A comes from the ONE Editorial Department WeChat Moments solicitation. To participate in the solicitation, add the Editorial Department WeChat: oneapp2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8 &quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Complex The cutest people in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3944&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What are the &quot;withdrawal reactions&quot; when losing someone? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3946&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Should I endure vs. Should I change | Eternal multiple choice question&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP. openDetail(4,3950)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[最初与最后的一个梦]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6133]]><description> &lt;div>;20 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Zhang Juan&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fjvhj8OaHy5aUEIE48hkJUysjzJc&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fjvhj8OaHy5aUEIE48hkJUysjzJc&quot;>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A magical dream-seeking journey, I am drifting in the clouds, past and future Intertwined, reality and fantasy are layered. It turns out that dreams are memories that people have forgotten. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking back on my childhood, one thing often surprised me - how quickly I fell asleep as a child. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even the feeling of surprise has become so rare. Only once, when I traveled to Tibet, I borrowed a friend&#39;s astronomical telescope to watch a lunar eclipse, and the same feeling was triggered in my heart. An inexplicable, distant, clear feeling of surprise. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I was a child, I never stayed up late and fell asleep around 9 o&#39;clock (I can remember this time because at that time I waited in front of the TV every night to watch the provincial TV station&#39;s &quot;Good Drama Seven&quot; &quot;Half-past&quot; column, when I watch the last episode of a TV series, I am often so sleepy that I can&#39;t keep my eyes open). Not to mention the situation of going home and falling asleep after playing wildly. Sitting on a long bus ride with my mother in the afternoon, I could stagger to sleep, and then wake up from the small bed in my room in a daze, as if I had fallen into a deep pool and surfaced again. . Many nights, when I lay on my father&#39;s shoulder, my mother held my sister&#39;s hand, and our family passed through crowds of cars, street trees and bushes, or roads and streets, the lights and shadows and various noises were like the tricks that a hypnotist can skillfully use. Lead me to fall into the vivid dreamland. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the experimental observations of brain scientists, human sleep is actually divided into three stages: light sleep, deep sleep and rapid eye movement sleep, which move from one stage to the next in a cycle every night. Dreams are usually born in the rapid eye movement sleep stage. If you sleep well, like a fisherman returning home with a full load, a person can harvest five dreams in one night. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After many years, going to bed late, staying up late and having insomnia have become the norm in my life, and my dreams have disappeared. Or so broken that you can never remember it when you wake up (if you fall asleep). Dreams escape from my sleep, just as animals migrate from place to place due to poor soil, extreme climate, or invasion of natural enemies. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later, I met a 30-year-old woman who was still recording her dreams. She gave me a vintage buckle notebook and encouraged me to record my dreams. &amp;ldquo;Write those dreams down and they won&#39;t fly away. &amp;rdquo;The woman said. This reminds me of a dream notebook I once had. When I was a child, I didn’t have a diary, but I had a dream book that recorded countless nights. It was a messy record book composed of hard-shell paper, picture books, and large square notebooks for writing essays. It contained my 4-year-old drawings, 6-year-old crooked pinyin, and 8-year-old tadpole-like handwriting. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I was 36 years old, I got promoted at work, bought a property on the outskirts of the city, and married the woman who originally asked me to write down my dreams. After years of hard work, I finally found stability. There is also another person&#39;s dream beside the pillow. I thought about the dream notebook again, opened the buckle of the notebook my wife gave me for the first time, and began to write down my own dreams. Today&#39;s dreams are completely blank. I plan to retrieve the lost dreams of my childhood first, just like the recovery of an injured person, and regain the ability to dream little by little. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I wrote a dream about oranges. I sat on the top of the snow mountain, took the oranges out of the snow, and peeled off the orange peel and vein-like white strands until each segment of the orange flesh was as crystal clear as a gem. My hands are hot and sticky, but eating the most beautiful and sweet oranges in the world makes me so happy that I want to cry... Dreams of jumping from the sky again and again... /p>;&lt;p>;A heavy rain of one-yuan coins fell from the sky... In another dream, I was in a country of giants, walking between pairs of giant shoes that were as tall as me. Looking up at the face of the giant in the distance above our heads. It felt a bit like the feeling when passing by the high-rise buildings rising from the ground in the county, but it was a little more terrifying-the giants were all people I knew, my parents, my sister, my classmates and teachers, and the people downstairs. Convenience store owner, community doorman. The giants did not hear my cry and stepped over me unconsciously. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My mother was looking for something and asked me to stand under the overpass and wait for her, but in the end she took my sister and disappeared. They seemed to fly away on a trampoline across the overpass, and I was left alone on the crowded and noisy street. Dad turned into Godzilla, a masked knight, and then into the green-faced and fanged monster in the 1986 version of &quot;Journey to the West&quot;... Now I can clearly find these complicated and messy things. The context behind the dream. When I was young, my family was not wealthy. I wanted money and wanted to eat my favorite oranges without restraint. During the time when I dreamed about jumping from the sky, I grew a lot taller. The giant may represent my uneasiness about the violent and traumatic urbanization of the county. Dad was laid off, his temper became moody, and he developed a bad habit of drinking. My mother has returned to work and has to go to the supermarket seven days a week. She spends a lot less time with me. I feel resentful towards her in my heart. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dreams are traceable, like a map, leading to the secrets of people&#39;s lives. At that time, my family and living environment made me feel lacking, uneasy and even afraid. However, even though I remembered these dreams when I was a child, I still couldn&#39;t explain clearly what I&#39;m talking about now. I couldn&#39;t see clearly or avoid looking at what was happening around me. At that time, I, like everyone around me, came to the conclusion that there was no logical relationship between dreams and reality. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I spent several weeks in my spare time recalling and writing about my childhood dreams. Dreams flew into the notebook like returning birds, more and more. There are more than 500 dreams in my childhood dream book. I can retrieve at least half of them. I somehow feel like I can write down more dreams. Dreams generated by physical development, dreams driven by good wishes and fantasies, and various dreams affected by external environments such as family, campus, city, etc. I am excited about this grand dream-seeking project. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One night, my wife took me to watch her favorite childhood cartoon &quot;Moomins&quot;. Spring is here, and the elves in Moominvalley emerge from their hibernation rooms. Moomin and his friends float into the sky on pink clouds floating from their magic hats. Seeing this scene, tears seemed to have turned into some kind of self-aware elf, and they kept coming out of my eyes one after another. I couldn&#39;t stop crying. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I suddenly felt that there are two childhoods in this life. Between one childhood and another, there are countless days and nights of running around, tiredness, involuntary and sourness. When we leave childhood, we are always looking for that other childhood. A very small number of people have no gap between their two childhoods. For most people, the other childhood comes late, and for some people it comes earlier. I am also one of these lucky people. At the age of 36, I started another childhood. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the same time, I remembered a dream. One of my favorite dreams ever. After watching the animation, I couldn&#39;t help but think back to that dream over and over again. After my wife fell asleep, I walked to the living room and solemnly wrote down this dream in my notebook. For the next period of time, I was still obsessed with this dream, just like a historian immersed in research. Whenever I thought of some details or fallacies in the dream, I would write down the changes and rewrite the dream many times. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I remember that when I was a child, it took me several days to complete this dream - yes, dreams sometimes appear in the form of a series, and anyone who is good at dreaming knows this. But recalling and describing it over and over again has long since made that dream lose its illusory halo and become more like a real day in my life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, I finally felt that I had written down this dream completely for the first time. From page 32 to page 41 in the notebook. The following is the last recorded version of this dream:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;That day was a spring afternoon, and the clouds over the plateau in my hometown were changing. Unpredictable. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;The family members all disappeared without saying hello. I walked alone into the long and narrow space connecting the kitchen and the balcony, walked past a row of yellow-painted wooden frame windows, and stood under the clothes hanging to dry. A drop of water fell on the top of my head, itching. I laughed in surprise, reached out and touched it, and found a small piece of disgusting white goo. I looked up and saw that all the clothes spread their wings and turned into colorful giant birds and left. The clothes hanger swayed on the pole, making a tinkling sound like a wind chime. I turned my hand over and the bird poop was gone. I touched my head again, and the hair on my head became smooth and dry again. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;I walked to the balcony window sill, stretched out, supported my body with one leg, and raised my head He stretched out the window sill with two arms, leaned against the wall and looked around. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;The street under the balcony is empty, shining white in the sun, with several yellow puppies sticking out their tongues walk around. I looked into the distance again. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;The clouds accumulated on the mountains are like surging waves. Higher up in the sky, one cloud after another floats by, with strange shapes and different colors of light and shadow, like the dazzling schools of fish swimming in the blue waters of an aquarium. Also like migratory birds, flocks of sheep, and dandelions. Between these cumulus clouds, the blue velvet-like sky seems to be sunken into the universe, with pieces of cirrus clouds dotted in it. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;After a series of larger clouds, there was a baseball cap-shaped cloud. I kept looking at that cloud. The little cloud suddenly fell away from the team. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;The clouds are getting closer and closer, falling in front of my window. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;It trembled slightly, climbed up the windowsill, and flowed in front of me. It is taking the initiative to get close to me. I tentatively approached it and touched it. Pat, scratch. I embraced this cloud, which was not much wider than me. The clouds feel like the fur of a cat or dog. It floated in and out by the window, beckoning me to hang out with it. I climbed onto the cloud carefully. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;At first, it was difficult for me to maintain my balance, and the slowly rising clouds were shaken. of. The clouds rolled up around me and held me steady. With Yun&#39;s help and cooperation, I finally learned the skill of driving Yun, and my posture changed from prostrate to all fours on the ground, to sitting leaning forward. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;At this time we have come to the oldest intersection in the county. It&#39;s a red light. Among the few pedestrians walking on the sidewalk, there was an inconspicuous boy, thin, dark, wearing conspicuous blue-rimmed glasses. But just from the boy&#39;s square head shape, I recognized him as my deskmate. I rode the clouds and flew over his head. I felt in my pockets and there was anything I wanted in there. So, I grabbed a handful of eraser crumbs and scattered them. Eraser crumbs fell on his head. He stood in the middle of the sidewalk, sneezed, scratched his head and looked up. Yun snickered and I immediately flew away. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;I want to go to places that are difficult for me to go to, places that are further away and more interesting. So we turned our backs to the sun, passed through the city, and flew around the arc around the edge of the city. We passed through a large field of yellow rapeseed flowers and green cornfields, crossed the entire hillside of pink peach groves, and flew over a highway. Among several large trucks, a yellow crane spreads its boom and dances like a conductor. The passengers on the bus were sitting swaying around, and most of them were asleep. A child pressed his face against the glass and looked at us. I made a face at him and left. Then, we jumped off the viaduct between the canyons, passed through a hundreds of meters high, noisy, steaming waterfall, and came to the mountains. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;The passage formed by the gaps between the mountains is winding and winding, and the clouds are coming and going. Dizzy and excited. On several low mountains, there are many people and many kites: swallow kites, goldfish kites, seven-color plate kites, pig-shaped barrel kites, jellyfish kites, and even a dragon-headed centipede kite at the highest point. The sky turned into a kingdom of kites, and we shuttled among the subjects of the kingdom. When I flew to the top of a mountain, I saw a boy crying. His Sun Wukong kite was hung on the top of a pine tree. I helped him take off the kite and left quietly. When we arrived at a sparsely populated area, animals appeared again: cranes and eagles perched on the tree canopy, apes and deer on the cliffs, and a group of wild boars running down the hillside. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;We were tired and went around to a river in the canyon. Here, the crowd occupied the river and both banks. There are women wearing various swimsuits everywhere, middle-aged men with beer bellies exposed, and children and teenagers wearing swimming rings or holding water guns. Some people were lying on swimming rings and floating down the river, some were swimming and having water fights, and some were barbecuing on the shore. There was also a middle-aged man hiding behind a large rock that no one noticed, quietly taking out soap and taking a bath. I don&#39;t want to go down. And the clouds are floating here and there, as if we too are swimming in mid-air. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;I noticed a figure in the crowd below. Long hair, round face, wearing a sunflower swimsuit. That&#39;s my Chinese teacher. There were some adults in the noisy crowd that I knew well, but I forgot their names. The teacher was taking a girl wearing swimming rings and teaching her how to swim. But the girl stopped swimming after a while, pouted, and complained to the teacher. Once in class, the Chinese teacher cried while reading Shi Tiesheng&#39;s article. The teacher was crying just like that time. I was very angry, grabbed a handful of chalk dust from my pocket, and threw it at the girl. The girl sneezed many times and fell over from the swimming ring. The teacher picked up the girl and they both smiled again. The whole river seemed to be laughing. Gradually, people are getting tired, and almost no one is playing in the river. Adults and children are resting on the bank. I flattened my mouth, took out a lot of fish from my pocket, and threw them into the river. One fish even accidentally hit a middle-aged man on the bald head. People discovered those fish one after another. Waves of surprises erupted from the crowd again, and people rushed to the river to catch fish. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;The sun is setting in the west. I was even more tired, so I drove the cloud home. When passing the highest mountain around the city, the clouds took me to the top of the mountain and stopped there for a while. I walked off the clouds for the first time, sat on the warm lawn, and looked at the small town not far away. I saw all the high-rise buildings, roads, stadiums, squares and parks, rivers or bridges in the small town. The city stood quietly like a model, dyed with a light rose color under the colorful sky. I never thought that the city I live in would be so beautiful. So beautiful it makes me want to cry. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Getting closer to home. Under the setting sun, I saw three back figures, from tall to short, from big to small. That&#39;s my family. My father was walking aside with his trouser pocket in his pocket. My mother was holding my sister in one hand and holding two plastic bags in the other. My sister was carrying a schoolbag. They kept walking quietly, completely unaware of me behind them. The setting sun stretched their shadows long. I landed, quietly pulled out a piece of my father&#39;s hair, patted my mother on the shoulder, and poked my sister&#39;s elbow. My father, mother, and sister all stopped, opened their mouths, and turned their faces around with confused expressions. I snickered and flew upwards as they blamed each other. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;I urged Yun to fly forward quickly, trying to get home before them. The dogs below ran over and kept chasing us. Ahead is the building where my home is located. At the same time, the clouds began to carry me higher and higher. After a while, the puppies looked like a few bouncing dots. I scolded the cloud and made it fly downward, but it didn&#39;t listen to me. I looked up and saw a string of clouds in front of me. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;I finally realized that the cloud was going back to the string of clouds it belonged to, just like a Only the lone bird returns to the queue of migratory birds. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;When I realized this, the cloud immediately turned into a mist. &lt;/span>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;I fell and kept falling. I was so frightened that I also realized that I was holding my breath as I was lying on the bed, safe and sound. Fortunately, I landed gently like a parachute. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I woke up, my whole body was light and weak, and my head was a little dizzy, as if I was still riding on that cloud. It was late at night outside the window, and the echoing sound of demolition construction could be heard in the distance. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There was no sign of my sister in the room. Memories from several days came flooding back. I remembered that I had a cold and a fever. Dad still hasn&#39;t found a job. Sister&#39;s cry. Mom and dad quarrel. Smashed cups and plates. There are also some plots from last night’s good drama at 7:30. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After a while, the door finally opened in the living room. I walked down the aisle. The white energy-saving lamps flickered on, reflecting the simplicity, emptiness and shame of the family, as well as the mother&#39;s lonely figure. Mom didn&#39;t find her father and sister, or if she found them, they still refused to go home with her. I felt like something collapsed at my sternum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After seeing me, my mother was stunned for a moment and asked me if I had been woken up by her. With a child&#39;s intuition about a mother, I could see that she shed tears on the way to find her loved ones. I feel like crying again. But I held back and told her calmly, &quot;You didn&#39;t wake me up.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That dream became the last dream recorded in my dream book. The next year, when I was in fifth grade, my dream book was lost. My sister said that my mother sold it to a scrap collector. My mother said that my father tore it up after seeing the sentence &quot;Dad&#39;s head turned into a turtle&quot; written on it. My father said that my sister took it to a cram school to prepare for the high school entrance examination. Repeated neglect, abuse and destruction soon caused the dream book I had recorded for 7 years to fall apart. I didn’t cry or make any noise. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Anyway, I have stopped recording dreams since the previous year. At that time, I was determined to live up to my expectations, but the numbness I felt in my heart far outweighed the pain. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Li Jialong&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see @ONE Studio’s pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/Fk2_Z8K7cfOi8QZFz5M4RjfaYjVg&quot; alt=&quot;Zhang Juan&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Zhang Juan&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div >; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Novel author. Also write some poetry. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/article/6132&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;The comfort of autumn&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Su Gengsheng&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Read&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6134&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>; My Genius Girlfriend&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Xingxingchen&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text -align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6133)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt; /div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4031]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4173]]><description>&lt;div>;20 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FkdzwiwbVa-UT9GDJjmfTIfNplEV&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4031&lt;/span>;Photography | Richard Stachmann&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;20&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oct. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;You The first half of your life may belong to others and live in other people&#39;s opinions. Give yourself the rest of your life and follow your inner voice. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 20 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>