<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[你的童年在哪个瞬间结束了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3942]]><description> &lt;div>;12 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; ONE Studio Question&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p >;At what moment did your childhood end? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Zhu Deyong replied&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fi_1nHzelfghYMfRUmIRkO0GPWcZ&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fi_1nHzelfghYMfRUmIRkO0GPWcZ&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FlFsFiE3SiZa3al8GEJAfzhy6ITG&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FlFsFiE3SiZa3al8GEJAfzhy6ITG&quot;>;&lt; /div>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Nana onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Deyong’s Q&amp;A column &quot;Me≠We&quot; in &quot;ONE &quot;APP exclusive update. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmPuzv4rbuXt8DD2ZiWPWVY5GDQ3 &quot; alt=&quot;Zhu Deyong&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Zhu Deyong&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;Weibo@朱德yong&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style =&quot;&quot;>;Cartoonist. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3942)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/ div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[献给朋友的花束]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6125]]><description> &lt;div>;12 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Wang Qiuying&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data -author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmjOZgynf4mWfvXP4UW3jSD9HANL&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmjOZgynf4mWfvXP4UW3jSD9HANL&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;I am a cat. A country cat with an ordinary name. If you want, you can call me Xiaobai. In 2023, my owner of Sheniu Mingming received a diagnosis of lung cancer. Everything changed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Living in the huge city of Beijing, Mingming realized for the first time that he had no friends at all. And that true friend has been forgotten by her in a corner of her life for some time... strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Except for sleeping, she was never alone. Someone will accompany you when you eat, go shopping, watch movies, do your hair... Even when you go downstairs to the supermarket to buy a pack of cigarettes, you have to call your colleagues who live in the next unit... each by name. , constitutes her life history in Beijing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Part of the reason why I was raised was that I couldn’t stand a moment of silence in the house. Therefore, the good thing about being in her house is that even if I scratch the sofa, push everything on the coffee table to the floor, break the cups, uproot the plants... and make a big fuss, she will take it all in. , never the slightest bit harsh on me. Not because she was tolerant enough, but because it was all evidence of the hubbub. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I am a cat, an ordinary garden cat. I have an extremely ordinary name, Xiaobai. She is my master, and her name is equally ordinary, Mingming. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was abandoned and adopted by Dalei, a male friend of Mingming. At that time, Da Lei crushed a girl who loved cats. He was very fond of her. In order to let the girl come to the house to suck the cat every day, he took me back. Within a month, he started to get angry at girls because they liked to eat. From then on, I became the most unnecessary presence in the family and was stuffed into Mingming&#39;s place. When she picked me up, Da Lei had forgotten to shovel my poop for two weeks. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Obviously I don’t like cats much. She will support me. Firstly, she feels that her friend is asking for something and it is hard to deny her face (she is a person who doesn’t know how to refuse). Secondly, she feels that having a little thing can make some noise in the family. In this world, there are people who are afraid of noise, and there are people who are afraid of silence. They obviously belong to the latter group. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I heard that in the human world, &quot;people who enjoy being alone are either beasts or gods.&quot; They clearly know that they are neither beasts nor gods, and they need a lot of playmates. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He is obviously a warm-hearted person with many friends (at least on the surface it seems so). She often cooks at home to entertain friends. After dinner, everyone gathers at the coffee table to drink, play games, poker, and gossip. Because she works in marketing at a film company, she also organizes dinner parties from time to time to bring people from various professions in the industry together. Sometimes, after the dinner party, there will be another party, such as playing Frisbee, karaoke, watching movies, etc. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the early hours of the morning, Ming Ming opened the door to his home, smelling of alcohol, dove into the sofa, and sent messages to his friends one by one, reminding them to report that they were safe at home. Alas, in my little cat&#39;s opinion, this is a typical people-pleaser personality. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To be honest, I really don’t like saving meals at home. Greedy humans, even though they have food, still want to take our cats’ food for themselves, such as salmon, chicken breast, and shredded squid. At the party, all these things were available at home, but I could only watch helplessly as the &quot;dinner on the plate&quot; became their &quot;dish to go with the wine.&quot; And human beings are really hypocritical. They are all ordinary working people. After a few cups of yellow soup, a certain boss becomes the &quot;big brother&quot; who watches him grow up. The director of a certain company is hers. Good ladies, a certain celebrity had a life-long friendship with him (at first glance, they were at the wine table), and he acted as if the listed company was his family. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moreover, sometimes I really feel that it is quite pitiful. In order to fit into the so-called circle and not to be left alone, she is often the one who pays the most. But what kind of existence is she to others? He is nothing more than a &quot;talker&quot; and a &quot;trash can&quot;. In other words, people will only think of her existence when they have problems that need coordination or emotions that need to be poured out. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In many quiet nights, there was only a quiet mobile phone and a not-so-quiet me beside her pillow. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After three years of epidemic, the friendship between people has evolved into a fragile digital relation. I like you today and leave me a message tomorrow. Although everyone is staying at home, they have never really had an in-depth communication on any topic. This is obviously the case. When she was first locked up at home, she often organized online activities. Dozens of friends gathered online to play the piano, read poems, and tell jokes. Amidst the noise, she Responsible for toasting. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A few months later, everyone began to call themselves &quot;social terror&quot; and lived in caves, never showing up again. When we could arrange to meet offline, people were often not available. Today he had &quot;close contact&quot;, tomorrow she would have &quot;home observation&quot;, and the day after tomorrow they would &quot;have sex&quot;, so everyone had to postpone one party after another. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This year, when the epidemic was released, before I had time to organize offline gatherings, I was diagnosed with lung cancer and was ordered by the doctor to undergo chemotherapy and resection immediately. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was the first to notice something was wrong - I was lying on her computer keyboard while she was working at home, typing out a bunch of garbled words, and just as she was about to raise her hand to pat me, my whole chest There was a violent shaking, followed by coughing day and night. Late at night, even though I was sleeping on the sofa in the living room, I was awakened more than once by a violent cough coming from the bedroom. On a sunny day, she took me out for a walk, and went to the community supermarket to buy vegetables. She picked up a piece of pork belly, half a winter melon, a few tomatoes, potatoes and a handful of spring onions, and then she carried me up to the sixth floor, resting two or three times on the way. Feeling chest tightness and shortness of breath. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the phone with her family, her parents advised Mingming to go to the hospital, but she didn&#39;t take it to heart. &quot;Maybe it&#39;s the sequelae of Yang. I see that many people on the Internet have coughs.&quot; Besides, young people in their early thirties nowadays are not in a sub-healthy state, and they have more or less minor health problems. As long as you don&#39;t find out, you&#39;ll be fine. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Well, when it comes to physical health, humans should not be too arrogant. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A few weeks later, Mingming switched to a new company and was offered a free physical examination. She simply added some money and upgraded the package to arrange a full physical examination. CT showed that there was a shadow of about 9cm in Mingming&#39;s lungs. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That day, he dragged himself back with difficulty. From the moment her butt touched the sofa, the atmosphere in the house was horribly depressing. I licked her pant leg, trying to please her. Seeing no response from her, I jumped on her lap and sat down, trying to provide some energy and companionship. It is said that as long as the body is warm, the heart will become warm and the mood will become better. After all, I am also a long-haired kitten, and Huan Re obviously has this little heart, which is more than enough. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This time, my little kitty is obviously arrogant. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the next few days, I obviously didn’t go out. Even the takeaways for three meals a day were only left by the deliveryman at the door. On weekdays, what she does most is take out her phone and look at the piles of colorful avatars in her WeChat friend list in a daze. She clicked on each one, then exited, then clicked on each one again, and so on. Once, she finally mustered up the courage to type &quot;I&#39;m sick&quot;, then quickly deleted it and locked her phone. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These days, I rarely open the curtains, so I can’t get any sunlight, and my mood is getting gloomier day by day. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the sixth day, an old lady in her 80s next door came. Usually, Mingming&#39;s only communication with her is when cooking and taking out the trash. She obviously likes spicy food when cooking, but the old lady knocked on the door with a deafening cough and asked her to close the window. In the morning, she went downstairs to throw away the garbage. The old lady had trouble with her legs and feet, so she took it down with her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At this moment, the old lady was holding a cloth bag in her hand and said that her daughter had come back from Pinggu and brought a box of big peaches. She couldn&#39;t finish them all, so she wanted to give her a share. Seeing the large and small bags of take-out garbage at the entrance, the old lady was concerned: &quot;Is everything okay, little girl?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the thick layers of social relationships, without any warning, this sentence hit my heart hard. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;3&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was easy to cheer up, but my first reaction was to send me back to Da Lei. Home. Unexpectedly, after a phone call, he found out that Da Lei had a new relationship and they were living together. Moreover, his girlfriend now had a precious stuffed animal, and after mating, he gave birth to four kittens, each of which was extremely precious. Yes, his family still can’t tolerate me. In my opinion, human beings are the most ruthless creatures in the world. As long as it affects themselves, old feelings are not old feelings, it is just a slogan on their lips. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He had no choice but to look around for people, hoping to find me a temporary home. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After looking around, no one was willing to take me in during the operation - Xiao Zhang said that she was going on a business trip (if I remember correctly, she had just resigned), and Xiao Liu said that her cat I have a hair allergy (he is the one who comes to my house most enthusiastically to masturbate me). Xiao Zhou said that since he has a dog, he is afraid that cats and dogs will fight and make him uneasy (he clearly said that life is most satisfying when both cats and dogs have both)... It was outrageous, saying that my relatives were coming and there was no room for them at home. I really want to ask her through the screen, what kind of house is so crowded that there is no room for even a cat? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For some reason, I can feel that I am very tired, as if I have just experienced a long journey, and the energy in my body is slowly losing little by little until it is exhausted. At that moment, she must be like me, hating human beings and hating dealing with people. On the coffee table, the reading calendar turned to a new page, Emerson wrote: &quot;I hate that people misuse the name of friendship and use it to express fashionable and vulgar alliances.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;The room is so quiet. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ming Ming leaned on the sofa and sighed. This feeling reminded her of when she was in middle school, when her parents were doing business in the county town and she lived alone in an old house in the town. She didn&#39;t dare to turn off the lights when she went to bed at night. In order not to get up in the middle of the night, she went to the toilet outside. She usually didn&#39;t do it after dinner. Drink more water. During the long night, even if I couldn&#39;t sleep, I didn&#39;t dare to make the sound of counting stars or sheep, because it would make me feel more lonely. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This situation was not broken until Leilei transferred to another school in her third year of junior high school. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After dinner, Leilei’s mother went out to play mahjong and locked her at home to prepare for her homework. As soon as Lei Ma walked away, she was clearly at the corner of the yard. &quot;Ding dong&quot;, after a crisp sound, the stolen spare key was thrown steadily from the courtyard to the wall. Mingming picked up the key and opened the door, took Leilei out, and then locked the door as it was. The two of them have been working together seamlessly all year round, and there has never been anything wrong. Lei&#39;s mother came home from playing mahjong in the middle of the night. When she saw the dark bedroom, she thought Lei Lei was sleeping soundly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the long night, two little heads squeezed together on the single bed, reading comics, listening to Jay Chou, imitating the walks of the boring boys in the class, and fell asleep laughing. The next morning, we washed together again and went to school hand in hand. I clearly remember that Leilei loved &quot;Anne of Green Gables&quot; the most at that time. Anne in the book is a charming girl who is not afraid to reveal her true feelings and her desire to truly have a like-minded soul. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I don’t know how Leilei is doing lately. &quot;Mingming clicked on Leilei&#39;s dialog box and found that the last time the two of them chatted was a year ago. Her eyes were fixed on a photo. The kitten in the photo looks a bit like me, with a slim figure but a big head. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There should obviously be a cat. If she had adopted the one Leilei gave her then, nothing would have happened to me later. A year ago, Leilei planned to give Mingming a kitten so that she could have a companion in Beijing. After quietly completing all the procedures online, the adoption center informed Mingming to pick up the cat. On that day, because the company had an important meeting, Mingming did not go. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Why didn’t you tell me in advance? This is Beijing, everyone is very busy, and everything needs to be planned in advance. &amp;rdquo;This was the last sentence Ming Ming sent to Leilei in the dialog box. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In human friendship, many unexpected things will happen, causing the friendship to be destroyed or decline on its own, even if neither party has betrayed each other, even if neither party has deliberately said hurtful words , those friends who were once inseparable will also drift apart and part ways due to different life paths. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Actually, Mingming had wondered a long time ago whether Leilei was not his friend at all, but just a childhood playmate. After graduating from college, Mingming came to Beijing alone to work hard, while Leilei followed the steps to get married and have children. The two of them talked less and less and had already drifted apart. The novelty of the city tempts Mingming all the time, but Leilei only cares about whether her husband&#39;s salary will increase every month, which kindergarten her children should go to, or sharing in her circle of friends what she eats and drinks when she travels in her free time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two of them had fewer and fewer topics to talk about. In the beginning, they went from not chatting for ten days and a half to no contact for half a year and a year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;It seems that I only have you. &amp;rdquo;Mingming touched my furry head and slumped on the carpet, feeling a bit self-pitying. She opened the mobile app and started looking for a pet sitting center. After determining where I was going, I began to place orders for daily necessities for my hospitalization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the whole process, she made no sound. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;4&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When the Xiehe International Department got the new inspection results, it was obviously very shocking. , there are many uncertainties. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The examination results showed that the shadows on the CT were not cancer cells, but large-area high-density shadows caused by long-term compression of the pulmonary lobes by malformed blood vessels next to the hilus, causing repeated lung infections. &quot;Your vascular malformation is born. It has been squeezed here and there for a long time, and the shadow has become bigger. I really agree to be diagnosed with lung cancer.&quot; But you too, for such a big person, with such a serious disease, you don’t have to check and confirm clearly, and you are ready to go to the operating table? Today&#39;s young people really don&#39;t care about their bodies at all, and they don&#39;t even have basic common sense and countermeasures... The older doctors are still chattering, but at this moment, they have already suffered from the previous &quot;misdiagnosis&quot; ; and fell into ecstasy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The doctor once again told Mingming that if he was really worried, he could still undergo a biopsy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A week later, the biopsy results came out. There were indeed no cancer cells, just mild inflammation. Doctors say inflammation may also be related to prolonged coughing after COVID-19 infection. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After coming out of the hospital, the first thing Mingming did was to pick me up at the pet care center. On the way back, she was humming happily. We arrived home, and the canned salmon we ordered in advance also arrived. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After dinner, Mingming scratched my chin while choosing new toys for me online. It&#39;s great, I&#39;m back to being that happy and comfortable little kitten. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Dang! &amp;rdquo;The mobile phone WeChat message rang. That was a WeChat message from Leilei. &amp;ldquo;How are you doing? I saw in your circle of friends that the kitten is up for adoption. I happened to come to Beijing to visit relatives. I have to stay here for a few months. If it is not possible, I will say hello to my relatives and let me take care of the kitten for you. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;No, I’ve already taken care of it. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mingming replied quickly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Okay. Just say if you need help. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It’s still the familiar tone. Ming Ming thinks that maybe a true friend is someone who doesn&#39;t need to deliberately maintain a relationship. Even if they don&#39;t see each other for a long time, they will still feel comfortable and natural when they get along again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;When did you arrive? Do you want to have a meal together? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Obviously, I took the initiative to send out the invitation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Just arrived yesterday. OK. I should have time these days. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Let’s do it tonight. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mingming sent the location of a restaurant, then took out a beautiful little skirt from the closet, and spent a long time picking out lipstick and eye shadow. After everything was ready, she ordered a bouquet of yellow carnations symbolizing everlasting friendship. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sitting in the taxi on the way to the appointment, Ming Ming held the bouquet that had been prepared in advance, and thought about her boyhood, and those nights when Leilei read &quot;Anne of Green Gables&quot; to herself before going to bed. . Anne said:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A close friend is better than a hundred casual acquaintances. Each friend represents a world in our hearts. The door to this world was originally closed. Until this friend comes, this new world will be opened for you. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Nana&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For information about the call for submissions, please see the @ONE Studio pinned on Weibo. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FmY6JmpVhLtc2Bb90tW1SXPVarwy&quot; alt=&quot;王秋玎&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;王秋玎&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@王秋玎&lt;/span>; &lt;/div >; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Screenwriter, young writer. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/article/6069&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Gift&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Wang Qiuying&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6121&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Learning is useless &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Palace Master Bing&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6119&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Huisheng Temple&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Ahu&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6125)&quot;>; Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4023]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4164]]><description>&lt;div>;12 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FrizdFjerSa5fpVoGQa-XYSyKnTY&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4023&lt;/span>;Photography | Chris Jarvis&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;12&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oct. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;No Yes, Mariko. You are not wrong. It&#39;s just that the people around you blame all their weaknesses on you. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>