<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[怎样才算好好休息？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3911]]><description> &lt;div>;16 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Wild Wolf Asks&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>;How? Is that considered a good rest? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Yi Chao Nan Da &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data- original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FvdVTq30EhIjerbQv-knIlRi63R6&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FvdVTq30EhIjerbQv-knIlRi63R6&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>; &lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many years ago I went to Hangzhou and stayed at a friend’s house. The two friends are my high school classmates, they are close and know each other well. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In those days, I woke up and ate every day before starting to think about where to go today. My male classmates commented that I lacked planning when traveling and was very unorganized. He mentioned another high school classmate, F, who was also on a trip to Jiangnan. His itinerary, route, and time were arranged in an orderly manner. At first glance, you can see that they have done the strategy carefully and are experienced players. Their time and money have been spent reasonably, correctly, and efficiently. On the other hand, I feel like I am wasting my vacation and my life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I waved my hand coolly and went out to play. Having fun is the most important thing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Actually, I was under a lot of pressure during that time and didn’t want to make any plans at all. When I work in the company, I am wrapped up in various plans, including Project, Excel, and PPT all day long. Horizontal line graphs, network graphs, column graphs, the graphs make me bald. It’s so easy to find a long vacation during the May Day holiday and escape to a place thousands of miles away with beautiful mountains, rivers and beautiful scenery. It’s impossible to rush around and make a travel plan to keep yourself busy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the other hand, at that time, I was trapped in anxiety and confusion about the future direction of my life. I was troubled by various thoughts every day, and my head was about to explode. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So before I went out, I thought about &lt;strong>;this&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; trip to eat well and sleep well&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;,&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; Just shop&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;when you’re shopping, and rest&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; if you don’t&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;want to &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;shop. &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Don’t force &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Don’t pretend &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; , &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Don’t set goals &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong >;,&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;without tasks&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;,&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;unhappy&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;not thinking about things&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;,&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Don’t do anything against your will&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;,&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Be a sucker for a few days. &lt;/strong>;It&#39;s said that mud can&#39;t hold up the wall. Mud is just paralyzed and has no intention of climbing on the wall. What is rationality, correctness, and efficiency? Are there not many places in this world that require me to be reasonable and correct, but that require me to be efficient? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Since &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;it’s &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;rest &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, I want &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;all the rules &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; strong>;&lt;strong>;His&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;fuck&lt;/strong>;, all the disciplines to maintain orderliness, professionalism, and efficiency have collapsed. Everything revolves around one principle: As long as I am happy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I call this for short:&lt;strong>;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Go&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;fuck&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; &amp;rdquo;Rest&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;and&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;rdquo;Rout&amp;rdquo;Relaxation&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In daily life and work, I am a person who likes to make plans, follow steps and advocate efficiency. When I become another me in the specific environment I created, I will look at my past life from a third-person perspective. The anxiety I once felt suddenly lost its weight and became light. The vague difficulties that once prevented me from escaping became clear and traceable. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I walked in the woods of Jiuxi, the abundant oxygen allowed me to experience the feeling that my whole body, every pore, was breathing like never before. Very pleasant, very relaxing, and peaceful. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This feeling of detachment is very specific, as if I only took myself with me when I went out, and all the stress and confusion were left in the past and in another space. It was like completing the plan from another angle and achieving the purpose of that trip. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is my personal experience of &quot;taking a good rest&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the same time, I cannot assume that my friend F, who is good at making travel plans, did not have a good rest during his trip to Hangzhou. &lt;strong>;If you do it step by step&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;,&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;well organized&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;will&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;let&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;her&lt;/strong>;&lt; strong>;Relax because of a sense of security&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, then&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;make a plan&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, and then&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;complete it according to the plan&lt;/strong>;&lt; strong>;Travel&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;goal&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, just&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;is&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;she&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;gets open&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; strong>;heart, the&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;experience&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;to&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;rest&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;the&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;way&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong >;. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The most fearful thing is that obviously the purpose of taking a vacation is to relax, but in the end, going on a trip to catch up with the schedule makes you more tired than a war. In the end, the fatigue overcomes the pleasure. Putting the cart before the horse. Or because they didn’t plan well, their partners blame each other and let anger replace happiness. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;So the &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; prerequisite for a good rest &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;is that &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;know how to rest &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; strong>;&lt;strong>;’s&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;needs&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I spent the entire weekend lying at home, watching TV shows and playing games, but I still felt tired. This type of situation is very common. Explain&lt;strong>;Simply circle the concept of &quot;rest&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;in &quot;no&quot;&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;Have&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;be engaged in&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;thing&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;physical or mental work&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&amp;rdquo;This&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;scope&lt; /strong>;&lt;strong>;,&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;are already too narrow. After all&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;this&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;is&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;everyone&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;has&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;number&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; I am&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;in&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;experienced or experienced a&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;time&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; of &quot;spiritual internal friction&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; . &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In most cases, in work and life, emotional fluctuations caused by stress factors such as interpersonal relationships, personal desires, expectations of others, childcare and elderly care, etc., are what we really face. question. All fatigue caused by stress accumulates to a certain extent and will eventually be reflected in the body. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I once had a colleague who suffered neurological deafness in his left ear due to work pressure and spent his own money to get a cochlear implant. But no matter how good the artificial one is, it is better than the natural one. Every time we talk to him at a gathering, the left side of his body will lean forward slightly. He also joked that he was disabled in the last class. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That was many years ago. It was the first time I knew that emotions have such a huge impact on the body. Now, this is common knowledge that even children know. The same is true when it comes to rest: &lt;strong>;physical rest&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; is&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;appearance&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, and&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;emotional and mental relaxation can essentially Achieve the&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;effect of rest. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;If the rest&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;is&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;shallow&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;of&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;self&lt; /strong>;&lt;strong>;I&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;recuperate&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;,&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;so a good rest is a deep&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;self&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong >;Fixed. &lt;/strong>;In this process, we may not solve anything, but we can regain energy and courage to face those things that cannot be solved. After all, &quot;Lie down wherever you fall&quot; is just a joke, just for fun. The real situation is that we will be knocked down by difficulties and pressure time and time again, but we will also stand up through self-repair time and time again. In the process of being knocked down and struggling to get up countless times, the ups and downs of life were born. The general outline of personal destiny is thus cast. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Having a good rest is the rare and light blank space in the mixed flavors of life. It is also the gap embedded in the outline of our lives, allowing light to come in, rain and wind to come in. &lt;strong>;Let the elastic&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;vitality replace the breakable&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;rigid&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;s. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Mei Butan onewenzhang@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see the @ONE Studio pinned Weibo for the call for papers information. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpKk5N9eg_v2zyAkX7XPWYqc8YtG &quot; alt=&quot;伊Chaonan&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;伊Chaonan&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@伊Chaonan&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;I am my obstacle and my path. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Question and Answer&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/question/3908&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;How did our desire to talk disappear? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3909&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Is there no smooth path in life at all? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3911)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[新衣]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6091]]><description> &lt;div>;16 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;文／Xin Qiao&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FsJ_zTatYYtrKcD4TV0-R29YhvVJ&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FsJ_zTatYYtrKcD4TV0-R29YhvVJ&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;This is a class fable on an island. A young girl from a wealthy family encounters unexpected malice and betrayal. Under the moonlight, she shed her old shell and put on new clothes, but the subsequent truth plunged her into a mist. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;1&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My name is Zhang Ling. From childhood to adulthood, I always remind and urge myself when dealing with people in the world. , don’t show off your wealth. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My parents are in business. I don’t know much about what they do, but I just feel that they always have enough money. It was only after I entered high school, and started to have more relationships and more birthday games that defined our friendships, that I discovered that a meal at the restaurant where my parents used to take me to celebrate birthdays would be enough for my classmates to eat in the school cafeteria. It’s half a semester. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And this discovery opened up horizons just like Columbus&#39;s discovery of the New World. It&#39;s just that Columbus was the conqueror and I was the coward. In order to mingle with the &quot;aboriginal people&quot;, I also took off my &quot;clothes&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The clothes I buy are all low-key styles with logos that can only be found in nooks and crannies. Although I don’t deliberately stain them, the stains on my white shoes make me feel at ease. When chatting after dinner, I will be more careful if someone mentions my parents. If you insist on asking, I will try my best to make my parents an ordinary couple. If the conversation goes deeper, I will always say I don’t know. I don’t know where my family’s money comes from. I once joked that my family was lucky and money came from strong winds. It was only after I laughed that I realized something was wrong. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This scale is too difficult to hold. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sure enough, the class gap cannot be bridged by individual efforts. Still, I try to be a kind person. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But I still learned a lesson on my eighteenth birthday. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My birthday is at the end of August. Everyone is about to go to school. This birthday should be more interesting. Son. What moved me very much was that my friends had already discussed a plan and said they wanted to give me a surprise. I was excited for several days and dressed up carefully. I hesitated for a long time before going out. I wanted to wear some jewelry to make it look grander, but I was afraid it wouldn&#39;t be good. In the end, I only wore the necklace Deng Ziping gave me. Although it was cheap, I always cherished it and was willing to wear it that day. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Deng Ziping, my best sister, my family drove her home every night throughout her senior year of high school. Our two families live in the south of the Yangtze River and in the north of the Yangtze River. But her family owns a small barbecue restaurant, and the business is good. There are several tables of people drinking and drinking every day. By late at night, her parents were too busy, so I took the initiative to take her home. Son, this way I can chat with her more along the way. She knows that my family is rich, so I am more relaxed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That day, I don’t know whether she didn’t see it or felt it was unnecessary. She didn’t mention anything about me wearing the necklace she gave me, and even her eyes deliberately didn’t fall on my neck. I didn’t think much about it, it wasn’t a big deal. But starting from this detail, I feel that today&#39;s game is a bit strange. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I didn’t think it was a big deal when I ate in the hotel. The main thing was that they took me to another place after the meal. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;First of all, this location is in the wilderness, an hour and a half drive from the city. Although the scenery on the shallow lakeside at dusk is really good, there are almost no passers-by, and it is very clean, but it is still too far. Cell phone signal is not good. The second thing is the joke they made. They said they wanted everyone to go swimming in the lake together and swim naked. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although I am only eighteen years old today, I have actually heard this kind of joke about the eighteen-year-old ban for a long time. I also followed the booing, and Yang Chuang, who wanted to make suggestions, jumped down first. Yang Chuang is the most charismatic leader in our class. He can tell the truth straight, and everyone is willing to believe him. Yang Chuang wasn&#39;t very intolerant to begin with, and I didn&#39;t take him seriously. Even if he started to take off his shirt, shoes, shoes, socks, socks and pants, revealing his childish boxer briefs, I didn&#39;t take it seriously. But when he really took off the last covering on his body, I really didn&#39;t know whether I should scream to show my respect for what I saw. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yang Chuang jumped into the water with a plop, and then called on everyone to strip naked and get into the water with him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The boys began to follow Yang Chuang&#39;s example one by one and went to the lake to soak naked. I looked at the only girl besides me, Deng Ziping. I know her secret, she loves Yang Chuang. Of course, there is someone here that I am curious about. I won’t say who that person is, and no one knows. But in fact, at that time, I couldn&#39;t think of love or love at all. I just felt that this scene was beyond the scope. In my previous life experience, no book or person told me what would happen when someone invites you to swim naked together. Do you want to join? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I saw Deng Ziping heroically removing her crossbody bag from her body, unzipping the waist of her dress, and then crossing her hands to lift the skirt up. I saw her hand paused for a moment when her panties were about to leak out. Then she glanced at the men in the lake who were making noises, then she took off her skirt and threw it into the pile. She also had a set of lingerie on her. To my surprise, they were two pieces of the same color. Because as far as I know, she didn&#39;t pay attention to this before and wore it randomly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Deng Ziping put her hands on the bra buttons behind her, she glanced at me. I probably called her name, probably to make her think again, but instead she quickly took off her clothes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Deng Ziping also went into the water. The moment her head emerged from the bottom of the water, she felt very comfortable. They started calling on me to get in the water too. The boy I like is also calling me. I can’t decide whether I’m happy or unhappy. Do I want to fall into the same lake with him? I don’t know which one is the one between me with clothes on and me without clothes. More likable. I asked, can I enter the water with my clothes on? Later, maybe it was because I could only see their shoulders and heads on the shore, but not their naked bodies. Maybe it was because Yang Chuang said, &quot;Your clothes are so expensive that you can&#39;t bear to take them off?&quot; &quot;No one was wearing any clothes.&quot; In the end, I took off all my clothes, threw them into the pile with everyone else&#39;s clothes, and got into the water. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The evening at the end of August is actually quite cool. But the water is warmer than I thought. I don’t know if what I did was right, but at the time I felt that it was a great joy to mingle with everyone and do something unconventional together. Most of this joy comes from the peace of mind of being the same as others. I couldn&#39;t help but glance at the boy I liked, and I found that he was also looking at me. I was actually very excited, but I tried to control it because my mother told me since I was a child that you can&#39;t bare your teeth before a boy smiles at you. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Deng Ziping and I were naked and hugging each other. She was soft and so was I. I felt that my internal organs were desperately expanding outward. The entire lake is my body. She finally saw my necklace. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That day, I felt like I understood for the first time that men’s and women’s bodies are actually beautiful in their own way. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I suddenly felt very free. This lake was like a pure new world, and there was no difference between people. I saw that the sky was like a huge egg white, and the setting sun was like an egg yolk beaten into the lake by the hand of God. The egg liquid flowed into my body along with the ripples of the lake water! I was so excited that I wanted to run towards the sun. I wanted to eat more, and eat more! I wanted to call my friends together, but when I turned around, I was dumbfounded. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is no one behind me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Deng Ziping? Yang Chuang? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I looked around, called their names, and went under the water, but there was no one there. I was a little panicked, thinking something had happened to them, but when I got ashore, I found that they had already put on their clothes. Maybe they left. But, my clothes weren&#39;t there either. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I have been idle for an unknown amount of time, because the current situation is not as scary and urgent as a murder scene, but it is also really mind-numbing, mainly because I have never encountered it before. I was wondering if this was a prank on everyone and maybe they would come back later. But the sun had completely set, and even the last rays of light were taken away by the night. It was then that I realized that I had to solve the problem on my own. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I went to find my cell phone, and I found that it had also been taken away by my &quot;friends&quot;. I think I can find clothes to wear first, so that I can even go to a place with people to ask for help, but let alone clothes here, there are not even rag bags for homeless people to collect waste! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I took stock of my current situation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What is the difference between me now and a person living naked on a desert island? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is late at night, and at this moment, the world is no brighter than the night sky. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I huddled in the corner, taking care to cover all my key parts. I looked so pitiful that I didn’t know who to show. I cried for a while and then needed to pee. After a fierce psychological struggle, I finished what I had to do, and then I figured it out: there was no one here anyway, and it was dark, so I walked around the island in the open. What doesn&#39;t work? Even if we encounter a wild beast, we are not of the same species. Even if we are eaten by a wild beast, we can save our clothes from being digested by it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So I gradually relaxed myself and learned how to relax my muscles and bones in the water before, and then walked carefully to the open space and walked to the place where the moonlight shone. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I think I did the right thing. I have already encountered a situation. I can only solve the situation by encountering another situation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Just when I was thinking this, something happened. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I saw a flashlight gradually approaching me from a distance with a particularly dazzling artificial beam. I was so surprised that I wanted to call out to the person, but when I stretched I realized I was naked. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I found a rock, hid behind it, and shouted for help. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I saw the light of the flashlight moving to the other side of the rock on the ground, but when it was about to turn along the rock, I stopped. He asked me what was wrong? As soon as I heard the movement of a man, I naturally trembled. Before I realized that I was afraid and why I was afraid, I was already trembling. My body&#39;s reaction told me that this was no beast, but probably more dangerous than one. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I cannot answer his questions truthfully at will. I just said, I have something going on here and it’s not convenient for me to show up, but I need help. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I needed some clothes, but I was afraid that if I said it so bluntly, he would guess that I was not wearing any clothes, so I changed my explanation. I said I was cold, very cold, and wanted some clothes to put on me. He said he was also cold and he only wore a short sleeve shirt. I asked him to leave his contact information and said that in order to thank him, I would give him a new one afterwards. He declined a few words and prepared to leave. I watched the light of the flashlight go away from me, and I became anxious. In my haste, I pulled off the necklace Deng Ziping gave me from my neck and threw it to the other side. I said I could exchange it for this necklace, but the man used a flashlight to carefully study the &quot;polishing&quot; of the necklace, and then asked disdainfully how much is this piece of plastic worth? Do not care. I don’t know why, but I was a little happy when I heard him say that, because he objectively belittled the taste and financial strength of my “best friend”. This was the truth that I didn’t dare to say out of love before. . So I said, if this old plastic one doesn’t work, I can give him back a Gucci or Prada top later, and I’ll buy him whatever he wants. If that doesn’t work, I can give him money. His flashlight finally came back. How much, he asked? I said it’s almost the same, it’s fine. He started to test, a few hundred or a few thousand? Ten thousand? Twenty thousand? I said it was fine, because I thought it was normal to pay 10,000 to 20,000 yuan for a piece of clothing in a mall, not to mention that he was responding to an emergency for me. But when he heard that I could exchange him for a piece of tattered clothes for 20,000 yuan, he felt that this was not an easy matter. He began to ask me what happened. I asked him for clothes but didn’t even show his face. Was it not sincere? I hesitated, but he immediately guessed that I had no clothes on. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I found a stone on the ground, ready to use it for self-defense at any time. I warned him that if he dared to bully me, I would die with him. He immediately comforted me and said that he had no other ideas. He was also afraid of encountering some new type of scammer trap, so he wanted to ask me first what the situation was and how I lost my clothes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I told the truth. I said they took my clothes while I was swimming naked with my friends. He asked my friend why he did this? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I subconsciously said, I don’t know, but then I thought about it, there is no need to hide my true inner thoughts with a stranger. I told the truth, saying that they were all jealous of my family&#39;s wealth. I feel that I have been very careful in my daily life. In order to prevent them from feeling unbalanced, I eat and use the same food as everyone else, and I have to be careful even when I say something, so as not to unconsciously reveal my &quot;superiority&quot; to others. I don’t know that I’ve put in so much effort, but it’s just that they can’t see my good intentions, so why are they still trashing me? The more I talked, the more aggrieved I became and started crying again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He began to comfort me, saying that he understood me and my classmates very well, but there were some things that just couldn&#39;t be helped. He said he was willing to help me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Perhaps because I am in an extremely helpless situation, I feel that he is particularly gentle at this moment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Immediately afterwards, he said that he might not be able to lend me clothes, not for any other reason, but because he was a homeless man and was originally looking for a place to rest here, but he didn’t expect to meet him. Fucked me. He felt that his clothes were dirty, and a girl like me who loves cleanliness would definitely not want to wear them. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I heard that he was a homeless man, I felt a sense of disgust. It wasn’t that he was homeless or poor, but I simply thought that his clothes must be smelly and dirty. But I needed his clothes very much...I looked at the lake opposite. He also wanted to go somewhere with me. He said he could take the clothes to the lake and wash them. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I think this is great. I am finally about to be saved. I want to be lucky that I have met a good person! I wanted to get dressed, walk to the road, and if I was lucky, catch a ride. I think my parents must have gone crazy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He also said that he did not need any payment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said that was so embarrassing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said that he felt that in this case, he gave me what I needed most at the moment, so I should also give him what he needed most at the moment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I had a bad feeling, so I asked him what he needed most at the moment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said that he needed me to go to the lake and wash this short-sleeved shirt with him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I emphasize again, I am not wearing any clothes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said he knew. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then how can we go to the lake together? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said, weren’t you swimming naked with your classmates? There are also men among your classmates. You can take off your clothes and go into the lake with them. Why can&#39;t you do it with me? Or are you saying that you dislike me for being a homeless person and think that homeless people are not as noble as your family who raised me to study? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I am speechless. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said that he also knew my difficulties and he did not want to take advantage of others. He promised not to touch me. He just hadn&#39;t seen a woman for a long time. If I could let him vent his desire, he would be grateful. I&#39;m only eighteen years old, my parents are very strict, and I haven&#39;t seen pornographic films yet. I don&#39;t know why he doesn&#39;t touch me to vent his desires. I just confirmed to him that you really won&#39;t touch me, how can I trust you? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said that he knew that my family was rich and did not want to get into a lawsuit. Moreover, he said that he did not become a tramp because he did not study, but that he did not study because he was a tramp. Therefore, he is a person with a moral bottom line. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later, I believed his &quot;moral bottom line&quot;. I took the stone, my last weapon, and swam into the lake. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He commanded me to swim under the moonlight. I obeyed. He was in a dark corner, and I couldn&#39;t see his whole person clearly. I only knew that he could see me clearly under the moonlight. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I crossed my arms over my chest. He told me to put my hands down, his voice trembling. I listened and put my hands down. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I could hear his rhythmic breathing and the muffled snapping sound under the water. I actually can&#39;t quite imagine what he was doing at this moment or what he looked like. I only heard him groan, and then there was silence. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I waited for a long time, but could not feel any movement from him. I&#39;m still wondering if he drowned? At this time, I saw a worn-out short-sleeved shirt floating in front of me along with the lake water, along with some white liquid. I don&#39;t think about what it is, I am just happy that I finally have clothes to wear, no matter what I use to change them. I put on my clothes and swam ashore. That T-shirt must have been stretched out from years of wearing it. When I put it on, it just went up to my thighs and I wore it as a skirt. I saw the flashlight left by the homeless man on the shore. I picked it up and tried to look for the homeless man, but he was probably gone. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I lit this flashlight and walked toward the city. When I saw the highway, I felt like everything that happened before was just a dream. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I have mixed feelings. I don’t think I am very happy after I successfully obtained a dream dress. However, to say that I am sad, I cannot tell what I lost on this night. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I saw cars speeding by on the highway. I don’t know why, but I didn’t dare to stop them. I was wearing clothes, but I lost my sense of security even more. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I walked barefoot and the soles of my feet were exposed. I walked all night until the sky was bright. I couldn&#39;t feel the length of the road, and I didn&#39;t feel tired. I kept thinking about the tramp&#39;s breathing and moaning in my mind. My heart was beating fast, thinking about this night: Although the tramp was a tramp, he kept his promise, did not touch me, and left his clothes. Not only that, he also kindly left a flashlight. Give it to me, isn&#39;t this better than those classmates who abandoned me? But...he kept looking at my naked body...but he just looked at it. He looked at pornographic films and illustrated magazines, and there were also naked bodies. He could see women&#39;s naked bodies, and I could also see men&#39;s bodies... ; So in the end, what did I lose tonight? Why do I feel so ashamed, angry, and depressed? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later, I was picked up by the police and settled down. They contacted my parents and asked me what happened? I didn&#39;t know where to start, so I didn&#39;t say anything. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then my parents came. I saw them chatting with the police for a few words, then turning to lift up the police uniform jacket covering me, and then their dark eyes looked at me from top to bottom, head to toe, as if I was naked at this moment. . Then they collapsed. They asked, who bullied me? I thought about it and said that there seemed to be no one. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later I found out that they thought I had been raped. Am I? I actually don’t know it myself. In my heart, I was still angry at Deng Ziping, Yang Chuang, and that boy I was curious about. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I haven’t gone out for several days. My father bought me a new mobile phone, and I didn’t add any contacts to my address book. No one discussed my matter, and my parents didn’t say a word to anyone. But I couldn&#39;t calm down in my heart. I always felt that I should get an explanation. I wanted to tell my &quot;friends&quot; about my experience that day, exaggerating the reality ten times and a hundred times. The stone pressed heavily on their chests, at least, making them feel suffocated before their consciences were exhausted. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I went to the high school class reunion before entering high school. I wore all the famous brands in my wardrobe and took the initiative to sit next to Deng Ziping, chatting about the value of this layer of skin on my body. In front of her, I took the initiative to attract Yang Chuang&#39;s attention, and I let Deng Ziping know that rich people attract more attention than poor people. I knew that Deng Ziping had been trying to interrupt my topic, but I didn&#39;t give her a chance. It&#39;s not that I don&#39;t hate other people, I just couldn&#39;t control myself and blamed Deng Ziping alone for the fault of that day. Who told me to wear the necklace she gave me that day? Who told me that she used to be my best friend. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Finally, I decided to give her a chance. I excused myself to go to the bathroom, and sure enough she followed me. She asked me what happened? I washed my hands and said it was nothing. She asked me why I had no contact at all since that day. I really don’t know why she asked that, and I didn’t expect that she would be so shameless as to put herself in an innocent position! At that moment I decided that I would no longer be merciful, I would be a judge and judge her crimes one by one. I poured out the experience of that day, I added it, I over-exaggerated it, I let myself become a woman who had been raped by a homeless man in a lie, and I wrote my own tragic novel! I have no reason to ruin my reputation, just to make her blame herself and make her hate herself! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I finally finished speaking, with tears streaming down my face. I gasped and looked at Deng Ziping, waiting for her reaction. As expected, she regretted the &quot;joke&quot; she made that day. I was &quot;proud&quot;, but she cried and said that they just wanted to make a joke at that time. They secretly got dressed and went ashore to pick wild fruits nearby, and then came back to scare me. But they didn&#39;t expect that when they came back, I was alone. I was no longer in the lake and my clothes were not on the shore, so they thought I had left and were worried that I would be angry. They even tried to contact me on the phone to explain, but they never received a response... She said that they did not take it away. my clothes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was stunned because the facts I thought were completely different from what she told me. I insisted that she was lying and that they must have discussed it and made up a story to excuse themselves. But Deng Ziping asked, why should I suspect that they took my clothes and not the homeless man? I didn&#39;t say anything because I felt that the homeless man didn&#39;t actually touch me that day, and he even left a flashlight for me. Immediately afterwards, Deng Ziping said what I was most afraid of hearing: because you have always looked down on us. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Do I look down on them? Do I think highly of them...? Looking back, I think I looked down on them most of the time, but occasionally, not too. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since then, I have no contact with all my friends from high school.邓梓萍承诺自己不会把我身上发生的事说出去，但是我知道，在未来的某一天，我一定会成为高中同学口中的八卦对象，一个因为高傲而被流浪汉强暴过的可怜女人。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我仍然想不明白，我的衣服到底是被谁拿走的，那天客观真实的情况究竟是如何。也许，不是他们，也不是流浪汉，而是什么山猪野兽呢。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我仍然想不明白，明明我没有做错什么，但是现在，我却讨厌起自己来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我仍然想不明白，我到底失去了什么。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新学期马上就要开始了，我马上要去到一个陌生的城市，交很多新的朋友。在收拾行李的时候，我还是选择将那些低调朴素的衣服装进行李箱。我想，接下来，我还是继续做一个好人吧。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;责任编辑：李嘉龙&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;征稿信息见@ONE一个工作室置顶微博。更多编辑部的有趣日常请关注小红书：ONE一个编辑部。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FlA0nRfb_u_Px_DK5EZ-PtRW-S_T&quot; alt=&quot;馨乔&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;馨乔 &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;豆瓣@Joecyqiao&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;这辈子当不了艺术家。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;关注&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;相关推荐&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6021&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;东北新娘&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 馨乔&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6091)&quot;>;点击可下载ONE一个app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.3997]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4131]]><description>&lt;div>;16 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FhhrKGW9q7Ev-t4LrX5DtJNWtFYe&quot; alt=&quot;首页图&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.3997&lt;/span>;摄影| Mesut Cicen&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;16&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sep. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;人类的底里是悲伤，我们都在用厚重的颜料，覆盖那些粗糙的线稿。&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 16 Sep 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>