<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[放弃了这么多，我们在逃避什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3971]]><description> &lt;div>;7 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; ONE Youwen&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>;Give up So much, what are we running away from? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; hashtaganswer&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original- src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fn6v4c0PEqN139cGKgw8ygFGqISb&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fn6v4c0PEqN139cGKgw8ygFGqISb&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;Some time ago, I had dinner and chatted with Amiao, a college classmate whom I had not seen for a long time. I originally wanted to chat with him about his recent work situation, but he came up and told me that he had applied for a one-year leave of absence, and his tutor also agreed. I was a little surprised, because he was going very smoothly in his studies, including postgraduate study, publishing papers, and winning national scholarships. At this time a year ago, he was preparing to apply for a Ph.D. I asked him why he decided to postpone his graduation. He said that he just wanted to slow down and not think about the future. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In fact, in recent years, too many young people have chosen to stagnate their lives on the eve of entering society. Or they choose to go home and grow old, or they can barely find a job that can’t support themselves. Or, like my classmate A Miao, they create a “Gap Year” for themselves and hide between school and work. the vacuum zone between. So, what are our generation running from? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is such an inspiring story circulating on the Internet: A blogger said that when he was 38 years old, he was wondering whether to study for a two-year junior college degree in radiography. Then she told her friend about this: &quot;I feel that I am too old. By the time I get my degree, I will be 40.&quot; &quot;My friend said: &quot;If you don&#39;t study, you will still be 40 years old, a 40-year-old without a degree. &quot;At the end, the blogger wrote: &quot;I am now 60 years old, and that degree certificate has changed my entire life. &amp;rdquo;Amiao was once inspired by such a story, but as the application process for further studies progressed, he was exhausted from dealing with interpersonal relationships with college teachers and the intricate and intricate implicit interpersonal rules. He realized that he had a lot of energy. They were all consumed with non-academic matters, and the unfair competitive environment completely disappointed him and made him anxious. Under such circumstances, going home to rest is not the best option. His parents had great expectations for Amiao since he was a child, but at the same time they rarely praised him. When facing relatives and friends, they would always say words that undermined and denied Amiao and were self-effacing. So at this moment, he used his little remaining savings to rent a room outside the Fifth Ring Road, as if living in seclusion. Rather than getting a degree, Amiao is more willing to take the initiative to escape the pressure from society and family. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While eating, I also asked him, what are your plans for the future? This is a problem that Amiao is unwilling to face at the moment. He said that in the past, I had clear plans for myself, including graduate school, Ph.D., college, and academic studies. But the closer I get to the future, the more I find that ideals and Huge gap in reality. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Turning back a few decades, from the iron rice bowl in the factory to the rising period of rapid economic development, the future in the eyes of previous generations It’s both predictable and full of opportunity. Today, the challenges and pressures brought about by huge competition have become the main theme of contemporary social life. The civil service examination is highly competitive, and there is an endless stream of applicants in front of large and small factories. The lucky few who &quot;entered the factory&quot; were also rolled into darkness by 996. Every time midnight approaches, the office buildings in major CBDs are still brightly lit. And this is already the most successful group among China&#39;s young people. The remaining 99% will still face a moment where they see no prospects.&lt;strong>;Shrouded in uneasiness and anxiety, how can we talk about what will happen decades later? future? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under such a living background, many young people have given up getting married, having children, starting a family, and even refusing to socialize and fall in love. Two years after graduation, Xiao Zhou&#39;s daily life is extremely simple as he works as a programmer in a large factory. Go to work, write code, get off work. Xiao Zhou has no interest in dating, and his social circle is limited to a few of his college classmates. He can only go out for dinner with friends once a week at most, and his energy will run out any more. For him, his current stable and regular life has allowed him to run at full capacity, and the emotional cost of falling in love will exceed his life budget. Communication, companionship, empathy, what you give in love is much more tiring than what you receive. Naturally, Xiao Zhou&#39;s parents are urging the marriage every time they call. They can neither put forward substantive opinions nor have the ability to sympathize with young people. They can only make Xiao Zhou more disgusted. The responsibilities of getting married and starting a family at this age are too heavy. Individuals are still passive in the face of modern society. And powerless, how can we accept others into our world and endure the unknown future together. &lt;/strong>;He just wants to think about the immediate things now. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xiao Zhou also had grand ideals. He has been a game enthusiast since he was a child. While other classmates were still playing online games in Internet cafes, he was already proficient in major game manufacturers. history of development. He determined to become a game developer at a very early age, entered Nintendo, and became Shigeru Miyamoto&#39;s successor. But as he graduated from college and survived the fierce battles between spring and autumn recruitment, he had not talked about his former ideals for a long time. He returned to the rental house after work every day and played Zelda with his Switch for a while. The closest he&#39;s come to his ever ideal moment. As the department&#39;s business volume dropped sharply and performance declined, he fished almost every day, waiting for the N+1 compensation after being laid off and unemployed, which was his only goal at the moment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A questionnaire survey shows that the biggest ideal of young people over the age of 22 today is to obtain huge sums of money and achieve financial freedom. As for those dreams buried deep in our hearts, we can only have the courage to mention them again after the long-awaited sudden wealth comes true. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;James C. Scott wrote in &quot;Weapons of the Weak&quot;: &quot;Peasants and those who try to extract from them labor, food, taxes, There is a prosaic but constant struggle between those who pay rent and profit. Most forms of such struggles avoid the risk of overt collective resistance. The daily weapons that I can think of for these relatively disadvantaged groups include: laziness, pretending to be stupid, desertion, pretending to be submissive, stealing, pretending to be stupid, slander, arson, sabotage, etc. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From the farmers in Malaysian villages in the 1970s, we can intuitively feel that the escape of contemporary young people is actually a kind of &quot;non-resistance&quot; resistance. Everyone tries to hide in a vacuum environment and try their best to avoid contact with people and things that make them expend energy, consume themselves, and get hit, because there is always no place to hide from the harm caused by the outside world. 996. The epidemic, the wave of wage cuts, the wave of unemployment, the pressure of the original family, the embarrassment and worry when giving love, in the coordinate system of life shrouded in a huge shadow,&lt;strong>;The younger generation has no past and no future, and escape has almost become a maintenance The only anchor of life. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One day A Miao sent me his current life process: getting up, eating, walking, playing ball, reading, playing games, and sleeping. He no longer has to rack his brains to write greetings and emails to his tutors, nor does he have to consider the brutal competition in the job market. This step-by-step life that could collapse at any time brings him peace he has never had before. He said he now feels the focus of his life is back in his hands, even though his savings will be exhausted by the end of next month. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Li Jialong onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the call for papers information, please see @ONE Studio pinned to the top Weibo. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FuqQsP2On7q_qtpDF3gHZB1nxeSZ &quot; alt=&quot;hashtag&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;hashtag &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Tomorrow never knows &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Question and Answer&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/question/3968&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What sudden insights did you have last night? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3954&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What are the young people who make incense and make wishes seeking? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3971)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[永远不在一起的喜欢]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6156]]><description> &lt;div>;7 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Zhou Hongxiang&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data -author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fg2gi-K1RNZM2XOq_SCvV3OhVMxK&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fg2gi-K1RNZM2XOq_SCvV3OhVMxK&quot;>; &lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;From the conversation between Sun and Muzi, we see a sober and Independent love relationships, lovers in the world each have their own sweetness and embarrassment, but it is rare to have such a free and relaxed understanding. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Sun:&lt;/span>;Love is a way The quantitative coefficient, from 10 to 1, will keep fluctuating even if it is placed on one person. It is difficult, but we like to quantify it. You don’t love me = 0, you like me a little bit = 1, you love me very much. Bar = 4, you are mine =+&amp;infin;, of course there are negative numbers, and they may even be values ​​that cannot be found in the universe, like a black hole, absorbing energy, but you will never get it. If you understand this, you should have no fear of love. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(89, 156, 215);&quot;>;Muzi:&lt;/span>;I can’t imagine what it’s like to be overly dependent on one person in love, at least not myself. I like freedom. If love requires sacrificing freedom, then I would rather be single. Therefore, in all the loves I have experienced, I have never considered losing it. If a person cannot adapt to my situation, he will not be able to be with me from the beginning. I am together, but the people who are with me know that people who are truly secure are not afraid of the other person being too free. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After Muzi finishes this specimen exhibition, she will fly from Beijing to Yunnan. She works in her specimen studio all year round, and her daily work is She collected various specimens in the mountains, often in the afternoon when the sun was shining, and sometimes in the evening. But in order to better observe the color of the plants, she would wear a hat and walk through the woods under the bright sun. The studio was in the mountains and she was a bit isolated, but it was the freedom she wanted. A few hours ago, she stood in the exhibition hall of the Botanical Garden and introduced to everyone the plant specimens she had collected throughout the year. She would seriously tell everyone who came to the exhibition how to identify the specimens, and a few hours later , she and Sun were sitting in a coffee shop that was about to close, waiting for a burger, listening hungrily to Sun telling some funny jokes. She was five years older than Sun, but Sun was more mature than her. This was their third year together. , just enough to withstand the entire epidemic period. Every time at this time, she would hold Sun&#39;s hand, not as a farewell ceremony, but to enjoy the compact and short time together. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sun works as an editor in Beijing, and they went to Cambodia together some time ago. For Sun, it is enough for the two of them to take such a trip once a year. The rest of the time, they are busy with their respective jobs in their respective cities. They are not the kind of lovers who have to call each other to say good morning and good night every day. They won&#39;t even contact each other deliberately, but they will appear at the moments when they need each other most, such as Muzi&#39;s specimen exhibition, Sun&#39;s annual meeting, birthdays, anniversaries, and moments when they think they should be together. For Sun, he never defined their relationship as &quot;long-distance love.&quot; In his words, as long as you are on Earth, you can say that you are together. If there is anything, you must stay together all the time. Of? Those were the feelings of students, and they no longer need them. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I can feel their affection, love, or intimacy for each other. Every time they meet, they are inseparable. They have to make out in public first, and then they start to get busy. Either Sun is helping Muzi take photos, or Muzi is helping Sun tie his tie again. The kind of care you can&#39;t imagine, in their It is vividly reflected in the body. Sun loves her very much, but he will not go to Yunnan to disturb her. Muzi also loves Sun very much, because Sun will never force her to do anything she is unhappy with, such as moving to Beijing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They met at a friend&#39;s party. Sun liked that special kind of weirdo. When he found out that she studied plants and was serious about exploring the relationship between man and nature, he was deeply attracted to her. Attracted. Sun took advantage of Muzi&#39;s short stay in Beijing to quickly confess and confirm his relationship with her. The impulse of an Aries boy was clearly reflected in him. Muzi is not in a hurry to enter a relationship, and she is not the kind of person who lacks love, but it is too important for her to have someone who can accept her work and respect her choice. Muzi was hesitant at first, but Sun really He knew how to control their relationship very well. Interesting conversations were of course an important part, and more importantly, his thirst for knowledge. He listened to Muzi on the phone and carefully popularized her findings, and then secretly went to Baidu to check those things which he pretended to listen to. Things that I understand but don’t understand at all. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Sun:&lt;/span>;Don’t say I’m not afraid of losing, no one Don&#39;t be afraid, it just depends on how you understand the meaning of &quot;lost&quot;. The end of a relationship does not mean the end of a relationship. The departure of a person does not mean that you have lost everything between you. In fact, the real loss is what has appeared in your heart. There has been a huge turmoil, and you no longer trust the other person. Don&#39;t say that you lost him, but you lost yourself. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(89, 156, 215);&quot;>;Muzi:&lt;/span>; It’s not about how confident I am in relationships, but I think it’s more about being a friend. Loving the person you love will last far longer than loving him as a lover. This is what my grandmother told me. You will have requirements for your friends, but you will not easily criticize them, but you will for your lover, that is Your lover does not deserve such injustice due to your emotional double standards. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For a while, Sun kept asking me for drinks. I said that I was actually curious about the way you get along with your partner. How do you manage to be so relaxed and comfortable? At that time, he poured himself a full glass of Riesling and said, It&#39;s very simple. You and he were strangers at first, and you were also strangers in the end. You didn&#39;t start this relationship, but you wanted to start this relationship. This It’s just how we get along. We never started, and we will never end, but we did start, do you understand? This passage sounded very convoluted at first, but I soon understood his love scheme. Whether they are together or not depends on what you see on the outside, but whether you like them or not is the real key. How many people go from liking to being together, and then going from being together to not liking each other again? This is the cyclic pattern of most love, but he and I just go from liking to not being together, and then not being together to continuing to like each other again. This is our love cycle. Pattern. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The year I met Sun, he had just returned from New York. His first stop was Beijing, and he refused to leave. Beijing had the freedom he liked, the culture he loved, and everything he wanted to see. The weirdo who arrived. He invited friends to his home to record podcasts. The restricted niche voice columns were all airtight and private, but they were only open to those who wanted to listen. Later, there were subculture performances. As a planner, he contacted friends very seriously to attend and watch those weird and weird urbanites laughing and cursing in a decadent and absurd way. He knew many cultural people, and he had made some gains in this circle within a year. He lived in a single apartment on Dawang Road, with no cats or dogs, only wine and records. During the 365 days after he fell in love with Muzi, he spent half of the time alone in a late-night cinema watching movies with a bottle of beer. His love seemed to be just a noun, and his life was so &quot;single.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;How many people can&#39;t understand his feelings and scoff and say, &quot;Then what kind of love are you talking about? Do you call this love?&quot; He just slapped it with a brick. It&#39;s none of your business. Do you still want to interfere with my love? Hot-tempered, but very real. When you live to this age, what you want is to be happy. Compared to me, how much happier are you with your entangled love? roll! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Sun:&lt;/span>;I don’t quite understand the &quot;checking post&quot; The meaning seems to be to confirm that you are very important in the other person&#39;s heart, but whether it is important or not does not depend on reporting. When a person&#39;s mind is not on you, discipline is the most meaningless option, but if you are not so If you care about these dogmatic rules, you won&#39;t always feel tired in the relationship. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(89, 156, 215);&quot;>;Muzi:&lt;/span>; I can’t accept frequent contact. That will quickly lose the freshness. Everyone is In this way, no one will fall in love with someone who is too familiar. It is a feeling of family. The so-called freshness is actually mystery, unknown, and strangeness. If you always talk about everything, you will soon become speechless. It can be said that love should not be like this. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For a period of time after I fell out of love, I told Sun my story. I originally thought he could enlighten me with his views on love, but in the end he just said Used a declarative sentence: Oh, such a conventional story is not new. Sun told me his stories in New York. Whether he was hanged, dumped or played with, or was deceived and hurt by his mistress, these are all his very precious assets. As long as you have been in love for seven or eight times, you will understand that in too many cliche stories, there is only one problem. If you are nervous about him, you will lose him; if he is nervous about you, you will dislike him. This is the eternal rule of love. In my story, he found a fulcrum. It&#39;s not that you don&#39;t love me anymore, it&#39;s that you are too close, and everyone wants to take a breath sometimes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He bought a ticket to go to Yunnan to see Muzi. He would stay there for two or three days. They would climb mountains together, and then Muzi would take him to a forest he had never seen before. They would watch the sunset together and sleep in. Sleeping until they wake up naturally, every reunion between them is like a honeymoon, and their reunion is a vacation after daily tiring work. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Will you get married? Of course people will ask this question, but what is the point of getting married? This is what they asked back. If starting a family is to make both parties better, that is an option that should be implemented, but if not, it is the most fatal way to destroy two people. If the marriage is for a stable commitment, it doesn&#39;t matter whether they have it or not, but if the marriage is for both parties to move, then they will kill the idea before they have it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It’s not that he doesn’t want to have children, Muzi is just as concerned about children as he is about plants. However, after observing the lives of so many creatures, she became more aware that the essence of reproduction is continuation, which is carried out when you want to pass on what you want to continue. But she does not have this idea now. What to continue? She still has too many things to explore, and her heart is not rich enough. What she will pass on to the next generation will only be a lack of body. Only a truly rich person can pass happiness to the next generation. She hopes that she will be happy, But I want my children to be happy even more. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Sun:&lt;/span>;Meet someone you like and like you It&#39;s not easy for people, and in this situation, it&#39;s too easy to mess up. I&#39;ve messed up before, so adults shouldn&#39;t make mistakes again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(89, 156, 215);&quot;>;Muzi:&lt;/span>;I will be interested in the person I like, but I will never reply to messages 24 hours a day. Although many times I see it, I don’t necessarily reply because I have my own affairs, and I hope that my partner also has his own affairs, not just me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Sun invited me to dinner, he was editing the vlog they had just finished traveling. I asked him where he wanted to post it. So serious. He said he wouldn&#39;t send it anywhere, but I wanted to keep it. He said that they were very tired during the trip, but he still carefully recorded their fatigue. Looking back now, those moments that he almost forgot are precious. Because we don’t live together, or even in the same city, traveling is like a celebration for two people. They can seriously hold their own exhibitions, hold their own parties, and hold work-related activities. Why can’t they keep a good record of the two of them? holiday? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sweet love has its own sweetness, and embarrassing love also has its own embarrassment. I also asked Sun, don’t you think your love is too idealistic? It&#39;s like a story in a novel. Sun said that if the stories in novels are as clear as ours, the novels will become more advanced. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The last few seconds of that travel vlog was posted on Sun’s circle of friends. In a dilapidated jeep, Muzi fell asleep. He held up the camera and went over to kiss her. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Li Jialong&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see @ONE Studio’s pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FnG6mnVK6opY4g75Tw-7h415dwbd&quot; alt=&quot;zhouhongxiang&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;zhou hongxiang&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@zhouhongxiang&lt;/span>; &lt; /div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Young writer, representative works &quot;Famous Fair&quot; and &quot;They Are Burning&quot;&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot; OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Read&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6141&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Lovers love each other as expected until they are separated &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Zhou Hongxiang&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6123&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Crazy love practice&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Zhou Hongxiang&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Read&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6095&quot; data-ajax=&quot; false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Memory is often in vain&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Zhou Hongxiang&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6156)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt; /div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4049]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4191]]><description>&lt;div>;7 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgeR8OEqeFwlRfP5tUSLT4yK_RLx&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;VOL.4049&lt;/span>;Photography | Artem Kovalev&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nov. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;I don’t want to I won’t write to you again. Because I finally felt that all our correspondence was just a big phantom, and each of us was just writing to ourselves. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>