<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[你成为对世界有用的大人了吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3979]]><description> &lt;div>;16 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; ONE Studio Question&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p >;Have you become a useful adult to the world? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Zhu Deyong replied&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmtaoiW8716Gaj1gOT5m-fL5EXxB&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmtaoiW8716Gaj1gOT5m-fL5EXxB&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Nana onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Deyong&#39;s Q&amp;A column &quot;Me≠We&quot; is exclusively updated on the &quot;ONE&quot; APP. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmPuzv4rbuXt8DD2ZiWPWVY5GDQ3 &quot; alt=&quot;Zhu Deyong&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Zhu Deyong&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;Weibo@朱德yong&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style =&quot;&quot;>;Cartoonist. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Question and Answer&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/question/3972&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Where do you hide your dreams? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3964&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;How long do you think the shelf life of sincerity is? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3958&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Is it okay not to grow up, boss? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3979)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[豌豆少年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6166]]><description>&lt;div>;16 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;文／Ahu&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FueSCt8k9p6g26JL4jbWIN2JE_Wp&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FueSCt8k9p6g26JL4jbWIN2JE_Wp&quot;>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;My friend Zhou Jupiter suddenly passed away. In order to &quot;squeeze&quot; his last value, Jin Jingyi was persuaded to go to Shanxi to film Zhou Jupiter&#39;s documentary. In people&#39;s descriptions, she got to know Zhou Jupiter again and recalled that she and he had a forgotten secret. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;1&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I don’t I know why, but I really don’t know why. I instinctively feel that I should do something, find something, seize something, even if I oppose something or deny something, but what is it? I have no choice, I can do nothing but wait... After one sentence, the waves of emotion piled up one after another, and the whole process was extremely sad. He was deeply depressed, sad, weird, and twisted. When you stay with him for a while, you feel like you are going to die together. Jin Jingyi has been tortured to the end by this mentally ill person. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The recording lasted for more than two hours. Jin Jingyi turned off the single-frame video camera, folded the tripod legs, pressed the holder, screwed the base, and put it in her bag. My neck aches terribly. As a close friend, being able to turn on the camera and listen to someone &quot;mutter&quot; for a few hours is considered the most benevolent thing. This is the last shooting, maybe we won’t meet again in the future. Stay away from depressed people and stop being infected and eroded by negative emotions. Jin Jingyi left without even saying goodbye. Going downstairs, as usual, she deleted all the material. There was no need to preserve the desperate performance of a weirdo, or the despair of the performance. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It happened without any warning. Half a month later, Jin Jingyi appeared in Zhou Jupiter&#39;s room again. The scene is fixed, but Zhou Jupiter is completely different. A policeman was taking pictures, &quot;slapping, snapping, snapping,&quot; as if weird hands were peeling off the hard shell of a crustacean. Jin Jingyi was dizzy. The computer was playing &quot;Xu Meijing&quot; softly, and the singing sound was like a thin thread of grass entering Jin Jingyi&#39;s ears, picking back and forth on the eardrum, and at the same time, it was accompanied by a breaking sound, coming from the bent body-- &quot;The snow-white back and open arms are gray lifeless regrets. Under the regret is Zhou Jupiter&#39;s head, which is tilted against the pillow. The camera&#39;s flash flashed several times on the face, digging out the deceased&#39;s clear facial features. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The regrets are laid out on the bed and cannot be put away. The police showed Jin Jingyi the photo of the corpse they had just taken and asked her if it was the renter herself. Jin Jingyi gave an affirmative answer. If not, who else would have died in his room? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;How is his health? &amp;rdquo;The policeman asked again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;He has a little irregular heartbeat and occasionally takes some medicine. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;As a friend, you don’t come to take care of me? &amp;rdquo;The police looked reproachfully. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;We don’t have much contact. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;But the last call in his cell phone call list was for you. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The police handed over Zhou Jupiter&#39;s cell phone. Jin Jingyi looked at it and found that it was indeed a call to her. But that was still the last call for an appointment, and Zhou Jupiter took the initiative to call her over. This can only show that Zhou Jupiter never contacted anyone before his death. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jin Jingyi explained: &quot;I am making a documentary, and he is my subject.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;He is the only one living here? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Yes. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Put your phone five centimeters away from your head. His cell phone was switched off. The phone was down and the emergency number could be dialed, but he didn&#39;t call it at all. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jin Jingyi was silent. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhou Jupiter has been dead for about eight days. This is the inference obtained by the police through surveillance. Zhou Jupiter would go downstairs on time at eight o&#39;clock every night. The last time was eight days ago, when he went downstairs to buy cherry tomatoes. After two o&#39;clock in the morning, no light came on in the room. The process of discovering the body was rather tortuous. First, a poodle smelled the stench emanating from the crack of the door, then the neighbors came, then the agent came, then the landlord came, and then the locksmith company came. The cherry tomatoes I bought eight days ago have turned into dark red and smelly water. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The police were still looking over the body, looking for other possible causes of death. The possibility of homicide was low, it was death from illness, but they still had to toss a dead body. The eyelids were opened, opened, and could not be closed, leaving some thin gaps. Jin Jingyi felt that Zhou Jupiter was looking at her, and she felt ashamed because Zhou Jupiter was naked and he had the habit of sleeping naked. She was embarrassed by a corpse. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She and Zhou Muxing met at an art exhibition in Gulangyu Island, Xiamen. It was the summer two years ago. At that time, Zhou Jupiter, who looked like a teenager, stood tall in front of the metal device he made, turning the beautiful light, inviting the audience to enter his super-time and space dream. In that huge space, the audience has to hold their pacifiers in their mouths, as if entering a warm womb, and use their fingers to poke the curtain wall made of special materials that is as soft as skin. The pressure-sensitive sensor transmits the fantasy pattern unique to the audience. . Zhou Jupiter is like a devil. While the audience is still immersed in happiness, he rushes nitrogen into the closed device. The dose is not large, but it is enough to create the fear of suffocation. Due to the temporary chaos, the curtain wall of the installation transformed into an even more bizarre landscape. Every participant gained a unique experience, and Zhou Jupiter also completed his most unique work. As a peripheral bystander, Jin Jingyi was strongly attracted to Zhou Jupiter and she wanted to photograph him. As an artistic young woman and documentary director, she has been involved in the documentary circle since she graduated from ULA and returned to China, attending various art exhibitions all year round to capture interesting subjects. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With a simple contact, Zhou Jupiter agreed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhou Muxing is from Shanxi and has been stationed in Heiqiao Village, Beijing for many years. Jin Jingyi is a native of Beijing and does not have a studio. She works independently as a guerrilla in daily shooting. Shortly after returning to Beijing, she contacted Zhou Jupiter and began to follow him. It was quite exciting at first, and Zhou Jupiter was also very happy. She filmed him working, filming him buying groceries and cooking, and filming him walking. Freshness is quickly followed by boredom. After that, in order to cooperate with the filming, Zhou Muxing became more and more suspected of acting in front of the camera. He kept saying that it was difficult for Jin Jingyi to interrupt. Once the phone is turned off, Zhou Jupiter immediately becomes dull and sluggish. He would rather stare blankly at a piece of wood or a pea in a daze, and is too lazy to pay attention to Jin Jingyi as a living person. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jin Jingyi once said: &quot;I didn&#39;t expect that your daily life is quite boring.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhou Jupiter said: &amp;ldquo;I think so too. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;But why do you have so much creative interest in your mind? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Because it’s boring. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then there was no dialogue. Zhou Jupiter continued to check his things. Jin Jingyi mocked him for pretending to be Wang Yangming again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After Zhou Jupiter&#39;s body was cleared out of the room, Jin Jingyi turned off Xu Meijing on the computer. From now on, she should be able to say goodbye to filming Zhou Jupiter. But the sudden intrusion of death brought discomfort and a headache that was about to burst. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;2&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The farewell did not come so completely. The police called Jin Jingyi and said that Zhou Jupiter&#39;s parents came from Shanxi and wanted to see her. Jin Jingyi thought that it might be a couple full of regrets who wanted to get some information about their son&#39;s life from her. In order to show humanitarian concern, Jin Jingyi went. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After meeting, the first thing Zhou Jupiter&#39;s father asked her was his son&#39;s bank card password, and his wife couldn&#39;t wait to ask about Zhou Jupiter&#39;s financial situation. Jin Jingyi said she didn&#39;t know. There was not much sadness on the faces of the couple, which was puzzling. Later, Jin Jingyi learned from the police that the woman was just Zhou Jupiter&#39;s stepmother. Zhou Jupiter&#39;s mother died when he was very young. The man was Zhou Jupiter&#39;s father, but he basically didn&#39;t raise him. Zhou Jupiter was raised by her grandmother. It was the father who insisted that the police call Jin Jingyi. He didn&#39;t know where he heard it and thought that Jin Jingyi was Zhou Jupiter&#39;s girlfriend. Jin Jingyi didn&#39;t want to explain, but she explained it anyway. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhou Jupiter will be sent to the crematorium to be burned. Before burning, there was a brief funeral. Several college classmates of Zhou Jupiter came, as well as the art dealer Xu Zhengjiang, who was responsible for the copyright brokerage of Zhou Jupiter&#39;s works, and a policeman. Jin Jingyi went to see the body, mainly to see if the person was still bent. It&#39;s a pity that people are leveled. She didn&#39;t bother to express her sympathy for Zhou Jupiter, which was very boring. Didn&#39;t he want to die a long time ago? This time I got my wish. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jin Jingyi walked around the body surrounded by wreaths. Zhou Jupiter&#39;s face was rosy with powder, his cheeks were plumply filled, and his eyebrows were still lifelike. There should have been depressed wrinkles between the eyebrows, but the kind-hearted funeral makeup artist pushed them away, and there was actually a slight smile at the corner of the eye. A pair of hands are also carefully decorated, half hidden in the neatly stitched suit sleeves. Zhou Jupiter had never dressed so formally before, but he managed to live up to the expectations of a living person. But it would probably be weird if he was lying there wearing a baggy sweatshirt or skateboard shorts. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After Zhou Jupiter was burned, it turned into a small package. His father stuffed the bag into a white clay pot like a bag of millet. There may be some smoke belonging to Jupiter floating over the crematorium. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The clay pot left with a car. There were some disappointed faces at the door, headed by art dealer Xu Zhengjiang. The businessman seems to be a particularly tearful character. He never stopped crying from the beginning to the end. He would turn on varying amounts of water according to key points in the funeral process. He probably admired Zhou Jupiter, but there was a businessman-like hypocrisy on his face. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The great ability of a businessman is that he can start negotiating a deal immediately after wiping away his tears. After relatives and friends left one after another, the businessman approached Jin Jingyi and said, &quot;Give me a copy of the shooting materials, and I will make a short film to promote his legacy.&quot; I can pay for it. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jin Jingyi said: &amp;ldquo;Deleted them all. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xu Zhengjiang frowned regretfully, &quot;That&#39;s not possible.&quot; If you filmed him for two years, it&#39;s impossible that you didn&#39;t leave any material behind. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Anyway, he was just talking about the wheel, and the mustache on his chin kept shaking. Xu Zhengjiang didn&#39;t give up until Jin Jingyi promised him that he could look for it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xu Zhengjiang got the manuscript from Zhou Jupiter&#39;s computer, and he planned to hire someone to complete the installation - the value of the artist&#39;s legacy must be maximized at the cost of his life. He boasted that he had the potential to win international awards. Jin Jingyi didn&#39;t want to hit him. Zhou Jupiter was almost unable to create before his death. He was stagnant for nearly half a year, unable to find suitable materials, suitable craftsmen, or good and fresh ways to make his installations interesting. The stainless steel shelves piled up in the warehouse are basically a huge waste. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xu Zhengjiang’s eyes were intense and his mustache was upturned, and he said: “Although that work is not completed, it just reflects the dilemma of artistic creation, doesn’t it? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xu Zhengjiang planned to exaggerate this point. His passionate conspiracy made Jin Jingyi feel that he would definitely write Zhou Muxing into the history of contemporary art together with some art critics. Jin Jingyi saw a wooden stick under her feet, like a cane. She wanted to pick up the stick and hit Xu Zhengjiang hard on the head twice. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;The heartbeat of an artist should not be stopped by the times. Yes, it is like that! &quot;He said excitedly, &quot;Artists are the barometer of the times. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jin Jingyi thought to herself that this person must have been a half-hearted poet before, but then he was swept away by the commercial tide, and finally he returned to the art world with his evil intentions. Sure enough, Jin Jingyi found a poetry collection belonging to a businessman in Douban Books, with a rating of 4.9, and most of the comments were &quot;rotten&quot; and &quot;stinky&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xu Zhengjiang drove away in his Maserati. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;3&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Forgetting is faster than Jin Jingyi imagined Slower. Zhou Jupiter was not formatted like a hard drive. He remained in Jin Jingyi&#39;s mind in a curved shape, and occasionally transformed into various ways of death in dreams, mixed in with the chaotic plot. The most exaggerated plot is that Jin Jingyi lifts up the crooked Zhou Muxing like a bow and shoots arrows repeatedly. The snow-white body of Zhou Muxing bounced on Jin Jingyi&#39;s hand, and the vitality in his waist and abdomen was as hot as burning. When she woke up, Jin Jingyi felt cold all over. In the darkness, she seemed to see the resurrected Zhou Jupiter. His sad and tangled look was the last chatter. He couldn&#39;t cope with himself and was insane. He couldn&#39;t escape the shackles of chaos. His persistence to prove his existence became time and time again. of self-flagellation. He tried hard to perform interesting expressions, but in the end he only proved boring and hopeless boring. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jin Jingyi thought sadly that the crooked Zhou Jupiter must have been killed by boring pain. His heart was the first to sense it and stopped beating like punishment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Soon, Jin Jingyi seemed to be possessed by an evil spirit, or had her head kicked by a ghost. She rented the house that Zhou Jupiter had rented and used it as her own studio. The reason is, it&#39;s cheap. The landlord&#39;s face was filled with gratitude. There have been deaths in the house, and the landlord has become very pessimistic that no one will want to rent a house with dead people. Jin Jingyi gave him a low price that he could accept, and the deal was successfully concluded. The house was so painted that no trace of the past could be seen at all. The furniture had been changed, the curtains had been changed, and even the doors had been changed. However, the bed in the bedroom that Jin Jingyi wanted to change the most had not been changed. On the first day she moved in, she discovered that it was the one where Zhou Jupiter&#39;s body was left, and the wood grain edges were exactly the same. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; During the day, Jin Jingyi comes here to edit films and receive guests, and at night he goes home to stay. One day the filming lasted until late at night, but she simply didn&#39;t leave. Essentially, she does not believe in the immortality of the soul. She didn&#39;t have to explore the existence of the soul, so she boldly went to sleep on the bed where Zhou Jupiter had slept, hoping that something would happen in her dream. I just thought about it briefly, without tossing and turning at all, and actually slept until dawn. It seemed like I had a dream, but it seemed like I didn&#39;t, and I couldn&#39;t remember it at all. This is not a house that is easy to accommodate dead souls. The windows are large and the sunlight is very bright. Even the sky outside the window is as blue as if it was painted with paint. Jin Jingyi thought to herself that the house was about to be picked. If Zhou Jupiter had been &quot;killed&quot; in this house before, she would be resurrected now. That child, alas, was short-lived and was not blessed to enjoy the sunshine here. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After that, Jin Jingyi often spent the night in the studio. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Jin Jingyi got up one morning, the bed board smacked. When I opened the mattress and looked at it, I found that a piece of the bed board was broken. When looking for someone to repair it, the repairman picked out a photo album from under the bed. It was very thick and had hundreds of pages. This was Zhou Jupiter&#39;s thing, and Jin Jingyi recognized it at a glance. After flipping through it at random, something happened suddenly that frightened Jin Jingyi. She was so frightened that she almost threw the photo album out of the window, which also startled the repairman. In the photo album, there are various postures of bends and gray naked bodies... If it weren&#39;t for her rationality to control her fear, Jin Jingyi would have thought that the dead Zhou Jupiter had photographed her after death. Jin Jingyi gingerly picked up the photo album and looked through it nervously. It can be seen that they are all selfies, panoramic views, the exposure is not very accurate, and there is a lot of noise. Maybe Zhou Jupiter wants this kind of roughness. He bent over a bathtub filled with water, next to a burning flame tree, on the edge of a snow-covered cliff, under a crumbling rock... He bent in various dangerous environments, taking pictures of his naked body and curled up posture. It was exactly the same as when he died. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jin Jingyi looked through them one by one. He thought that Zhou Jupiter would at least change into different positions, or at least show his face, clamp his legs, and hide his exposed genitals. No, he stubbornly repeated his exaggerated gestures, and even the placement of his hands and feet seemed to be precisely measured. The angles and sceneries are basically the same, only the environmental background and light color are different. The body is the absolute subject, astonishingly white, as if it is about to leave the picture, jump together, and merge into one. Taking selfies again and again, Zhou Jupiter seems to be conducting a long-term death rehearsal. Having practiced hundreds of times, this persistence probably indicates a problem. Zhou Jupiter is full of fascination or deep fear of death. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jin Jingyi temporarily put away the photo album. She was so confused. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That night, Zhou Jupiter finally haunted the house. When lying on the bed, Jin Jingyi always thought that Zhou Jupiter was under her and might climb up and fall on top of her at any time. She was a little tortured and couldn&#39;t sleep, so she had to stay in a hotel. She, who had always adhered to materialism, began to lose her mind to the idea of ​​the immortality of the soul. On the third day, she changed the position of the bed from northeast to north-south. She thought she could sleep peacefully, but the naked Zhou Jupiter was still lying across the most active part of her brain, looking shockingly white. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jin Jingyi felt so weak that even her friends said her appearance had changed when they saw her. She had pain in her back and went for cupping. Two rows of six large bottles made her body feel even more uncomfortable. During cupping, she saw Jupiter beating in the cup for six weeks. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She had to move back home. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;4&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xu Zhengjiang called Jin Jingyi, Request video material about Zhou Jupiter. More than a month had passed since Zhou Jupiter&#39;s funeral, and Jin Jingyi had almost forgotten about this person. Jin Jingyi said that she could share the material with him on a cloud disk, but Xu Zhengjiang wanted to meet her. Xu Zhengjiang said: &quot;You have been photographing him for two years, and you should be regarded as the last witness of his artistic career.&quot; That&#39;s what I think. I&#39;m here to invest, so why not finish filming Xiao Zhou&#39;s documentary? You&#39;ve persisted for so long anyway, so if you didn&#39;t finish it, you must have regrets. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jin Jingyi went to Haituo Valley on the outskirts of Beijing, a leisure resort area located at the junction of Yanqing and Zhangjiakou. On the sunny lawn, Xu Zhengjiang once again emphasized that &quot;artists are the barometer of the times&quot; and said: &quot;When Xiao Zhou first came to Beijing, we were very iron-clad.&quot; He was depressed and closed himself off, which was only in the past one or two years. Artists have been overwhelmed by the times, and they must make this sacrifice gain some meaning. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jin Jingyi waited for Xu Zhengjiang to get down to business. But this man kept adding value, his mouth kept opening and closing, and his mustache twitched. The businessman recently went to Nepal for spiritual practice. He has obviously lost weight. What has not changed is his sad eyes. When he talks about exciting things, he still sheds tears at the corners of his eyes. On the eighth round of coffee, Xu Zhengjiang finally said: &quot;The artist&#39;s spiritual trajectory is worth sorting out.&quot; Isn’t his family from Shanxi? I went to Shanxi to dig up his childhood memories. After filming, use your previous materials, finish it, send it to exhibitions, and go to the three major European film festivals to appear. Xiao Zhou&#39;s installation works may attract traffic and be noticed by wealthy gentlemen. &amp;rdquo;The businessman&#39;s vulgar and sour outlook. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For the sake of Xu Zhengjiang inviting her to drink high-quality coffee and enjoy the sunshine in the suburbs of Beijing, Jin Jingyi agreed. In fact, she already had an impure purpose in coming. A high-class poor person like her, who has &quot;gold on the outside but bad on the inside&quot;, has long been afraid of poverty, but she still pretends that &quot;the situation is not bad&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She had to step on something first. If this shooting was regarded as reviving Zhou Jupiter, and she had to get entangled with this person&#39;s past, then she could believe in the saying that the soul is immortal. The day after returning from the suburbs of Beijing, Jin Jingyi couldn&#39;t wait to embark on the journey to Shanxi. After a two-hour flight, I landed, transferred to the bus, and suddenly landed in X County, surrounded by loess ravines. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is only one large intersection in the county seat, and noisy vegetable vendors gather at the intersection. When Jin Jingyi walked by here, she happened to see Zhou Jupiter&#39;s stepmother. It can be seen how small the crowd size in this place is. The woman was shopping for groceries. After shopping, she left on an electric motorcycle. Jin Jingyi followed and saw the motorcycle parked in front of a tea shop. After the woman entered, she tucked herself behind the counter. It seems like this is her family&#39;s business. From the door on the side of the counter, you can see the backyard, where a fat child squats by the faucet and plays with water. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jin Jingyi walked in. The woman didn&#39;t even raise her head and asked, &quot;What do you want?&quot; &quot;Jin Jingyi called out, &quot;Hello, aunt,&quot; and the woman raised her eyelids and looked at her with unfamiliar eyes. She hesitated and said, &quot;Hello,&quot; and then recommended the newly arrived tea. Before Jin Jingyi could introduce herself, Zhou Jupiter&#39;s father came over from the backyard, picked up the fat boy and threw him into the shop. The fat boy was very unfriendly. Jin Jingyi took one look at him and immediately pointed the water gun at her, slapping her face. Zhou Jupiter&#39;s father kicked the boy&#39;s butt and said, &quot;Let&#39;s play.&quot; &quot;He didn&#39;t apologize. He just stared at Jin Jingyi. He recognized her and said coldly: &quot;She must be from Beijing.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Yes. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What are you here for? Worship? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Well, on the one hand. &quot;Jin Jingyi couldn&#39;t find a way to get to the point for a while, so she had to find a temporary excuse and said, &quot;I have some videos of Zhou Jupiter that I want to give to you, if you need to keep them as a souvenir. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I know, the police told me a long time ago that you photographed him. Is this even worth traveling all the way? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;No. Can I talk to you first? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What do you want to talk about? Nothing to talk about. &amp;rdquo;The man lit a cigarette, his eyes full of anger. &quot;Raising a son means nothing.&quot; I never counted on him in my life. Alive, he is a living father. If he dies, I will bury him. I still thought that he had become famous in art over the years, but I didn&#39;t expect that he didn&#39;t even lose a hair and even borrowed money. I still have to pay the debt to him. Is this reasonable? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jin Jingyi told her the purpose of coming, and made it very vulgar. She said that maybe she could sell Zhou Muxing&#39;s works by making documentaries, which would also be considered as leaving a legacy. The man&#39;s bad mood subsided slightly and he said, &quot;I don&#39;t care whether there is an inheritance or not.&quot; He has been embarrassing me for more than ten years. If you make a movie and sell those crappy things he made, you can make me look proud. Are you sure you can make it? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jin Jingyi does not guarantee that it will be successful. Anyway, just sell Zhou Muxing as a story. Whether it will be successful in the end is Xu Zhengjiang’s business. Jin Jingyi said: &quot;Please take me for a walk first.&quot; The main reason is to take a look at our environment first and get familiar with it before deciding how to shoot. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I am very busy. I asked my eldest son to accompany you. &amp;rdquo;The man made a phone call. His eldest son&#39;s name is &quot;Huanhuan&quot;. &quot;Huanhuan, come here... come back as soon as I ask you to come back. There is so much nonsense.&quot; &amp;rdquo;The call was immediately hung up. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huanhuan appeared soon. If Jin Jingyi hadn&#39;t pinched the back of her hand, she would have thought she was hallucinating. Except for her clothes and hairstyle, Huanhuan looked very much like Zhou Jupiter. He is Zhou Jupiter&#39;s twin brother. But Zhou Jupiter never mentioned it. Jin Jingyi looked at this face carefully. The eyebrows, nose, lip line, the protruding bones on the cheeks, and the sadness between the eyebrows when frowning, all seem to be cut out of the same mold. Even the sounds are very similar. The fat boy ran out and called Huanhuan &quot;dad.&quot; Huanhuan picked up the boy and wiped the child&#39;s nose. This scene seemed like the resurrected Zhou Jupiter suddenly abandoned his artistic life and followed the rules to marry a wife and have children. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huanhuan saw Jin Jingyi staring at him and said, &quot;Beauty, don&#39;t look at people like that, okay?&quot; Weird and scary. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jin Jingyi realized that she was dumbfounded. She quickly introduced herself and told her the purpose of her visit. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huanhuan said: &quot;I understand your business.&quot; One year, my brother introduced me to the production of a literary film shot in Xia County, and I also worked as a lifestyle producer. Quite boring. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huanhuan is very talkative, and his chattering voice and demeanor are very similar to Zhou Jupiter. The posture of smoking is also similar to that of the hand holding the cigarette. It has little blood, is pale, thin and boneless, and has exposed veins. Jin Jingyi has taken many shots of Zhou Jupiter&#39;s hands, and she is very familiar with Zhou Jupiter&#39;s physical characteristics. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huanhuan was impatient and took Jin Jingyi away without even saying a few words. He boasted that he would lead her to a smooth life. Huanhuan planned to take Jin Jingyi back to the rural village where the brothers were born and raised as children. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huanhuan said: &quot;When my mother gave birth to us two, she originally wanted to remove one, but my father said it would be better to have two children, so we gave birth to two anyway.&quot; My brother and I both inherited my mother’s heart disease, and it didn’t surprise me that my brother died young. The doctor said that there was a defect in my heart valve, as if someone had bitten it. My brother is different from me, he has an extra piece. The doctor also joked that it would be great if he could give me the extra piece of my brother&#39;s body. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Are you afraid of death? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Isn’t this nonsense? Who is not afraid. But no regrets, the baby is also here. I heard that there is an artificial heart. Once I make a lot of money, I will transplant it. Now I can only rely on medicine. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Are you willing to change your life with your brother? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huanhuan looked disdainful again and said, &amp;ldquo;Aren’t you just worrying about this? We sucked on one nipple, but two kinds of people. I don&#39;t think my life is worse than his. He has read more than me, met more people, and been to more places. But I have a wife and children, and he is not as good as me. Well, life, marry a wife and have children, that&#39;s not all for life. Pigs have to give birth to pigs, chickens have to hatch eggs, and so do people. No matter what, can you live like a god? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The conversation between the two channels is completely impossible to continue. A straight man from a small county would never question the reproductive attributes of humans as a species, as natural as animals. The result of being domesticated by human intelligence is to constantly question the meaning of human existence. Jin Jingyi barely listened to what Huanhuan said after that. She just felt and fully felt the differences between the two brothers. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jin Jingyi is curious whether the twins can have telepathy. Huanhuan looked disdainful and said, &quot;You thought they were the kind of twins played in Jackie Chan&#39;s &quot;Twin Dragons&quot; movie.&quot; Nothing like that. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jin Jingyi wanted to touch Huanhuan&#39;s face and verify whether Zhou Jupiter&#39;s skin was on his brother. But reason doesn’t allow it. That body was changing repeatedly, which continued to give Jin Jingyi illusions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;5&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The car drove into the village and saw a deserted old house. , overgrown with weeds. Zhou Jupiter&#39;s old house is also covered in weeds. After peeling off the thick thorn fence, Huanhuan led Jin Jingyi inside. There is a portrait of Grandma Zhou Jupiter hanging on the wall of the old house, and there are some dried fruits in front of the portrait. The cave was dark, and there were traces of smoke on the walls. Huanhuan took Jin Jingyi to the depths of the cave. Huanhuan lit up the flashlight and said, &quot;These were all painted by my brother before.&quot; &amp;rdquo;Jin Jingyi saw a row of faded gouache paintings, including birds, figures, and trees. There are no thumbtacks, but jujube thorns are used to fix the painting. A piece of wall peeled off from the roof of the cave, almost hitting her and Huanhuan. The two of them had their heads covered with dust. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huanhuan said: &quot;This was originally a kang, and my brother used to sleep here.&quot; My brother came back last time and cried when he saw that the kang was gone. That year, when I got married and went home to worship my ancestors, he came to see me. He was quite crazy. There were so many people and he cried. On my big day, he actually cried. He told me that he missed his grandma. You miss grandma, can you cry secretly by yourself? He didn&#39;t. A group of people came to ask for a memorial tablet, and he cried whenever he asked. He even hugged a brick and knelt there crying. The most irritating thing is that he had to ask me to help him find a car, pack up the piles of broken soil and broken bricks, and then pack them into packages and transport them to Beijing to create his stupid creation. I really don’t understand. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huanhuan opened the door on the inside of the cave. There was a cellar embedded in the door, and there was actually a white coffin inside. A beam of sunlight came in through the skylight, and it happened to shine on the coffin lid. . Jin Jingyi considered herself materialistic, but her heart still tightened. The earthy smell in the cellar and a hint of coolness swam in front of his face repeatedly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huanhuan said: &quot;We all have the habit of preparing longevity materials here. As people get older, they need to prepare something like this. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Whose is this? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;My brother’s. Huanhuan immediately explained, &quot;Don&#39;t get me wrong, he&#39;s not here.&quot; My mother passed away at thirty-nine. He always felt that he would not survive until thirty-nine, so he got some longevity materials for himself in advance and put them here. He told me that if you live one more day, you will earn one more day. But my dad didn’t like this and bought a more expensive one. Now, I also feel that thirty-nine is a hurdle, and this breath seems to be reserved for me, alas... Huanhuan&#39;s sigh seems to contain Zhou Jupiter&#39;s sigh, long and long The earth echoed in the silence. Using death to reflect on oneself may be a way that ordinary people will choose sooner or later. Even a vulgar person like Huanhuan is counting down his life, not to mention the sensitive and fragile Zhou Jupiter. Maybe at the moment of his mother&#39;s death, He started counting down to death. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huanhuan took Jin Jingyi to the village primary school. The primary school is also abandoned, covered with broken walls and rubble. On a section of damp wall, Huanhuan pointed to a few green seedlings hidden in the grass and said they were his brother&#39;s peas. Huanhuan said that Zhou Muxing likes to plant peas in hidden corners. No one will damage the peas when he plants them. It is his own pleasure anyway. He likes to plant peas in spring and look for peas in autumn. When the pea pods were dry and cracked, he crushed them with his feet and stamped the peas into the soil. The next year there were more pea shoots. Many peas are grown on dangerous ditch beams. Zhou Jupiter stumbled and almost became crippled, but he still went to find and plant peas every year. Later, the children in the village learned Zhou Jupiter&#39;s secret and began to look for the peas he had planted. It became a game for the village children. This game was quickly stopped by adults because the children always climbed up the ditch beams, and one of them lost his footing and fell, becoming disabled. Zhou Jupiter became the culprit and could no longer grow peas. But vetch was always found in the village. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Peas are Buddha beans, which keep you safe. They were given to him by the old monk in the temple. Huanhuan pointed to the low mountain in the distance, &quot;The temple was originally on the mountain.&quot; But in the past few years, lime was dug here and the temple was dismantled and moved to the county seat. It was a pity. There is now a lime kiln. The old monk died too. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jin Jingyi didn&#39;t know why Huanhuan said to him. This should not be the emotion of people such a person, and he feels more and more like his brother. Perhaps the two brothers have a similarity, but Huanhuan is deliberately suppressed and try to make themselves vulgar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The car drove through the village road. After passing through a wheat field, Huanhuan refers to a small soil bag not far from Jin Jingyi, saying: &quot;The grave is there. &amp; rdquo; Brown red burst on the fresh soil, and the skeleton remains on it. In a moment, Tian Yan was blocked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Huanhuan suddenly said: &amp; ldquo; I don&#39;t want to stop the medicine, you are fucking disobedient. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jin Jingyi was startled. Huanhuan is talking to the dead. Jin Jingyi immediately noticed the sadness of Huanhuan oil. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Back to the county seat, passing the Confucian Temple, Huanhuan said that the temple stone removed from the mountain is now there. His brother often went there to paint, draw stones, stone monuments. The door locks. Huanhuan asked Jin Jingyi if he wanted to go in. Jin Jingyi was also interested in, agreed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Huanhuan went to the Cultural Bureau opposite the key and opened the door. Entering the door, a large piece of stone accumulation, a broken Buddha statue, and a stone base. The disabled temple is not old, and it is built by cement and stones. The grass climbed from the roots of the wall to the room. Going forward is the Confucian Temple, with an iron chain hanging on the door. On the plaque &amp; ldquo; Jin Shengyu Zhen &amp; RDQUO; The old locust tree in the courtyard was almost touched, and the prayer belt of the trees fluttered. Walking through a martyrdom is a large wasteland, there are several abandoned houses, and there are several collapses on the roof. The side wall of the house is a blackboard, and the blackboard is left with a board. Huanhuan said: &amp; ldquo; This is the old school of the county middle school, and we are all junior high school here. In the year we graduated, the school moved. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Huanhuan pointed to the lace of a board, saying that it was painted by his brother, and the color of the chalk solidified on the cement wall. Huanhuan was staring, caught in a moment of memories. Jin Jingyi shook God again, and Jupiter seemed to appear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Go forward again, pass through the circular wall, there is an old shed with beams, and a stone monument in the center of the shed. Huanhuan said: &amp; ldquo; Teach you some knowledge, that is the Ming Dynasty test shed. In this cultural sacred place, Confucius, Buddha, and ghost fight. &amp; rdquo; Huanhuan &amp; ldquo; Hehe &amp; rdquo; laughed. Only when he laughed, his brother suddenly disappeared on his face. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The shed is covered with thick wooden pillars, and the ground is covered with aslene slabs, concave convex, very bright, refracted in the sun. The shed corner is piled up the sesame pile of the sesame. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; My brother often comes here to draw and draw that. &amp; rdquo; Huanhuan pointed at a corner of the yard, under a ancient locust, there is a stone monument. Outside the courtyard of gray, there was a brick tower. Jin Jingyi did not know that he was talking about ancient locust, stone monument or ancient tower. The stele was holding a pig feed bag, maybe it was scraped here. Jin Jingyi walked over and looked at it, and saw the big characters engraved &amp; ldquo; the five martyrs&#39; monuments &amp; rdquo;, behind the historical facts of the anti -Japanese period. The five martyrs were the young people in the county at the time, and they were killed. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; There is a stool on the east wall, directly leading to the residential area outside, and the brick tower stands in the residential area. There are modern anti -theft doors on the door. The door frame may always be kicked and have been severely deformed. Huan Huan shook the door handle and said: &amp; ldquo; Look at the tower, you have to go around. &amp; rdquo; Huanhuan tried to break the door, as if hateful with the door, kicked a few feet. The surplus physical fitness of the rural men must always be used in this matter, as if destroying public property is natural. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jin Jingyi walked away, took out the camera, took a few photos, one of them took Huanhuan and took it in. Huanhuan didn&#39;t hide, and he put his posture, leaned against the pillars, and came to patter with me. &amp; rdquo; In a moment, like the soul, Zhou Jupiter&#39;s gloom fixed on that face. Moving the camera, Huanhuan was himself. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A puppy in the door of the scene, a fat woman in black runs in. The woman first glanced at Jin Jingyi, and glanced at Huanhuan. She went to chase the dog. The woman was panting, she probably knew Huanhuan, and glanced at him again. She seemed to laugh and laughed. She left. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Huanhuan said: &amp; ldquo; The woman was called Li Jinfang, and Xinxin drew her before, naked, very abnormal. She used to sell it on the street. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; Haven&#39;t heard of the shampoo? I guess she might have slept with my brother. When she returned to the street and met me, she regarded me as my brother, and for a while. Big fat ass, sow, now think of nausea. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the eyes of vulgar people, fat women are not women, fat prostitutes are more bad. Jin Jingyi did not take over the stubble, and Huanhuan stopped saying anymore. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; nbsp; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: center;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; 6 &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Huanhuan asked Jin Jingyi to eat meals And she helped her find a hotel again. The hotel business is deserted, and the presidential suite is less than 300. Huanhuan said with a smile: &amp; ldquo; Don&#39;t you come to the presidential treatment? &amp; rdquo; Jin Jingyi ignored his joke and booked a standard room. In the afternoon, Huanhuan accompanied her to walk around the county. After being familiar with Huanhuan, the hallucination of Jin Jingyi began to disappear. Huanhuan is Huanhuan. Zhou Mobin is Zhou Mobin. Their nature and appearance of the brothers are relatively easy to distinguish. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At eight or nine o&#39;clock in the evening, Jin Jingyi received a call from the front desk, saying that a woman wanted to see her. The woman said on the other side: &amp; ldquo; we met in the shed. I know Jupiter Zhou and want to ask what he died. &amp; rdquo; It was the woman named Li Jinfang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; How do you know me? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; I have asked Huanhuan. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; What do you want to ask? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; Are you going to make a documentary? I mainly want to give you something. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jin Jingyi hesitated, and said: &amp; ldquo; Then come on. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Jinfang came up, holding a few rolls in his arms, and a bit bleak on his face. Jin Jingyi told her some situation after Jupiter&#39;s death. Li Jinfang didn&#39;t say anything, just said: &amp; ldquo; People are just like this, anyway, they are going to die. &amp; rdquo; Although she said so, she could still hear. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; Listening Huan Huan said, did he paint you? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; Then you still support art. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; What support does not support, just feel fun. &amp; rdquo; The woman held her rolling, very cautious, &amp; ldquo; Huanhuan should tell you what I did earlier. Maybe you don&#39;t look down on me. But it&#39;s okay, I&#39;m so thick, I am willing to talk to you. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; Does he draw you, do you want to pay you money? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; At that time, he was only sixteen or seven, where did the money from? I just happened to meet on the bus. He went to college for four years, and I helped him out. Do you think, how much does it cost to learn art? His father didn&#39;t care about him, I recognized him as a brother, we are the relationship. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; Are you not married? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; There was a child who died at the age of four or five. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; So what do you help him? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; Know you will ask so. &amp; rdquo; Women are cold, &amp; ldquo; Do you have to make a picture? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; There are always reasons for people to do things. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Jinfang snorted in his nose, like laughing, unlike, a disdainful explanation. After that, she said: &amp; ldquo; I want to tell you something, I plan to burn me. If you are willing to take a look, you can look at it, unwilling, I will leave. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jin Jingyi said indifferently: &amp; ldquo; you are free. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; A woman was a little disappointed. When I got up, I said: &amp; ldquo; Listening Huan said, do you have Jupiter&#39;s album this week? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; I did not bring it. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; It&#39;s okay, you take a picture, send me a few photos. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; I&#39;ll show you. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jin Jingyi never wants to interact with this woman. She found Zhang paper, scribbled to see Jupiter&#39;s curved posture to women. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; Generally. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Jinfang suddenly blushed, saying: &amp; ldquo; Is it so curved? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; The same is true when he died? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; I thought Huan Huan said to play, but I didn&#39;t expect it. Why do he have to die like this? There is no intimate person around, none of them. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The heart of Jin Jingyi was suddenly poked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Jinfang pulled out a painting from the roller and said: &amp; ldquo; I don&#39;t know what you have to do with Jupiter Zhou, let&#39;s show you. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jin Jingyi was forced to accept the woman&#39;s &amp; ldquo; Give &amp; rdquo;. After the painting was unfolded, Jin Jingyi immediately recognized the content on the picture. The brick tower, the shed and the stele under the snow. A few reds in the middle of the snow, a flying bird in the air, and the door of the round view wall, a woman&#39;s face full of tears. There are five outlines of the five dead corpses in the snow. The skin tone and snow are blended together. Jin Jingyi looked carefully. The dead corpses were naked, each bent, and there were black holes in the back. In such a clean scene, there are amazing deaths and violence. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Jinfang said: &amp; ldquo; I often haunted in the sheds. Everyone knows. I told him not to grow old. He is too old and his body is easy to get sick. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jin Jingyi shuddered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Jinfang pulled out another. That looks like Li Jinfang. She stretched her body on the loess land. The yellow of the skin was integrated with the Huang Rong of the earth, fully revealing her wide motherhood. The screen is sufficient, yellow thick, mottled, and layered. Jin Jingyi never thought of, Jupiter Zhou had so bright and brilliant. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jin Jingyi asked: &amp; ldquo; When did this be painted? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; The summer vacation of the Academy of Fine Arts. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; This one. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Jinfang opened several more, almost all related to death. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Jinfang said: &amp; ldquo; He always likes to paint me with dead birds, dead frogs, and dead bugs. I don&#39;t like it. But he always painted like this. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The state of death in painting is shocking. Dead worms, dead birds, and dead beasts are all bent. The curve of destiny, a stroke. Only the pity of motherhood is lonely and vivid. The two breasts are like two floating clouds, so soft and light. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Jinfang said: &amp; ldquo; One year, I said, you have to draw like this, don&#39;t come to me. As a result, he no longer came, and even my phone was deleted. That year, he just graduated from college. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; He always goes to you, the reputation will not be good? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; Not good, the spit star can&#39;t reach his face. I don&#39;t care, he doesn&#39;t care. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; I still want to ask, why are you willing to help him? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; You can&#39;t ask. &amp; rdquo; The woman&#39;s mouth is still tough, &amp; ldquo; This is a matter between us, do not look at me and him with a secular perspective. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Looking at the table full of drawing paper, Jin Jingyi hesitated, and said: &amp; ldquo; Is the painting really burning? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; I don&#39;t like it anyway. Burned, just give it to him. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; You give me, maybe you can take it to the exhibition. &amp; rdquo; Jin Jingyi suddenly &amp; ldquo; calculated the matter &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; Are you going to sell it? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; Maybe. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; You really think! &amp; rdquo; The woman once again showed disdain, &amp; ldquo; The painting was his, I still gave him back. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Li Jinfang quickly rolled up the painting and stuffed it into the rolling tube. Even the polite words of goodbye, he left with the obese body. Women have their own pride. She thinks that Moby has always had a intimate girl around Zhou, otherwise she would not come away, and she was pregnant with &amp; ldquo; thorns &amp; rdquo; then I decided to see the previous side. After a while, the hotel window drifted into a faint flavor of fireworks. Jin Jingyi stepped onto the balcony, looking at the fields in the distance, and there was a tiny fire light. Jin Jingyi felt a little regret. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; nbsp; &lt;/p>; &lt;p style = &quot;text-align: center;&quot;>; &lt;strong>; 7 &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jin Jingyi returned to Beijing, soon Complete the shooting plan. Later, he took the shooting team to Shanxi X County again. The shooting was not complicated. I took some shots in the village and school, got a few groups of aerial shots, and finally found a place to interview the scene temporarily, calling Jupiter Zhou&#39;s father, Huanhuan, Teacher Enlightenment, and three or five students. , &amp; Ldquo; interrogative &amp; rdquo;, excavated some Jupiter&#39;s childhood and the past from all aspects, and focused on the artistic talent. They are all temporary actors who induce them to express their sincerity as much as possible and inspire themselves. Jin Jingyi said that Jupiter&#39;s death was extraordinarily desolate. Normal people were not lacking in the same mind, and squeezing a few drops of tears was not to say, especially the father of Jupiter&#39;s heart, crying, cried the most. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After cutting out the sample, Xu Zhengjiang finished watching, and the corner of his eyes also grown with tears, saying that he was very satisfied. He did not expect that Jupiter Zhou also had a twin brother, and when he said, he must be the publicity point for the release of the work. Jin Jingyi was in his heart &amp; ldquo; 呸 &amp; rdquo; The film later gave a few art exhibitions, and did not hit any water. Zhou Jupiter&#39;s artistic life is cold. Later, Jupiter&#39;s oversized steel architecture was also sold by Xu Zhengjiang. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the spring of the following year, a girl named Peng Yinyin wanted to find Jin Jingyi and asked the police to call. The police said: &amp; ldquo; she is the ex -girlfriend of Jupiter Zhou, who has just returned from the United States. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Peng Yinyin said on the phone: &amp; ldquo; You are the last person who has contact with Jupiter Zhou, I want to see you. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jin Jingyi probably knows that Jupiter has a ex -girlfriend, but she is not clear about the specific things between them. She didn&#39;t want to know. Based on humane care, she agreed. Who asked her to be the closest person of Jupiter Zhou&#39;s death? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Meeting, a woman with clear soup is a few years older than Jupiter, but the temperament is in line with. With the ability of Jin Jingyi, the two should have a long history of communication, and there may be a heartbroken time. The woman&#39;s deep sadness hit Jin Jingyi, which was called real heartbreak. Jin Jingyi was a little envious, she never had such this, she was only numb. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; I have no time to send him, I haven&#39;t had time &amp; hellip; &amp; hellip; how could he die like that? &amp; rdquo; Peng Yinyin repeatedly said several times, choking while choking, and soon wept couldn&#39;t say. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jin Jingyi thought that there should be no second person in this world who is so sad for Jupiter Zhou. Jin Jingyi thought of himself more and more, and he would not give such a turbulent emotion throughout his life. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Peng Yinyin finally calmed down and said: &amp; ldquo; What did Zhou M Qing say when you last contact? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; No, it is a very common farewell. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; What was his state at the time? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; Not very good, I mean spirit. I have videos to show you. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; I don&#39;t look at it, I still want to listen to you. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Peng Yinyin insisted on the description of Jin Jingyi, tears holding Jin Jingyi&#39;s eyes, and the last breath of Zhou Jupiter was tapped from Jin Jingyi&#39;s eyes. Jin Jingyi worked hard to make memories, and she had to renders meticulously and put some delicate feelings. She talked about Jupiter&#39;s chattering, talking about his sadness, depression and weird, saying that he did have symptoms of depression in the end. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Peng Yinyin asked: &amp; ldquo; Zhou Mobin mentioned me to you? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; Nothing? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; Why do you have to figure it out? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; Then he pursued you? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; You think too much, we have seen it less than ten times before and after. I&#39;m just a documentary. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Peng Yinyin looked at Jin Jingyi with suspicion, &amp; ldquo; Then why did you rent the house he lived? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; because of cheap. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; You didn&#39;t tell the truth. &amp; rdquo; Peng Yinyin seemed to be here to crusade, without waiting for Jin Jingyi to respond, and said, &amp; ldquo; If you have had it, I might be better. If you look at it, it is quite pure, can you not be sincere? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; What do you mean? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; I didn&#39;t want to ask, but now I want to ask &amp; hellip; &amp; hellip; you and Jupiter went to bed, right? You have a tattoo &amp; hellip; &amp; hellip; &amp; rdquo; Peng Yinyin ordered the position of the shoulder. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The shoulders of Jin Jingyi suddenly seemed to be serious. There is indeed a rose tattoo on her shoulders. Jin Jingyi&#39;s shoulder was burned when she was a child. When she was traveling in Japan when she graduated from college, she had a skilled female text division to help her with a pattern. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; If Peng Yinyin does not mention, Jin Jingyi almost forgot. She and Jupiter had once, but it was only the one that belonged to the night stand. It was the first day when they met Gulangyu, a group of people went to drink. There was a behavior artist proposed to be a game. They closed their eyes and found partners through stroking. I felt that the breath was linked to each other. Put, after opening your eyes, pair. Jin Jingyi and Jupiter Zhou are the only one successfully paired. In the game, Moby Star touched Jin Jingyi&#39;s face, Jin Jingyi&#39;s hand rubbed on the corner of Jupiter&#39;s mouth, took away a trace of moist, and completed the game. With a sense of performance, Jupiter left with Jin Jingyi. The feeling of Jupiter Zhou&#39;s arm is wonderful, mysterious, seductive, and the youthful face is more charming in the blurred night. On the bed in the hotel, the warm chest and the alcoholic breathing covered the soft body of Jin Jingyi. Jin Jingyi didn&#39;t think there was anything wrong. She had a similar experience when studying abroad. After trying to kiss at the hotel, they fell asleep quickly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jin Jingyi didn&#39;t think she had a substantial relationship with Jupiter Zhou. Even after Jupiter Zhou became his shooting object, Jin Jingyi did not feel that the relationship between the two was uncomfortable. Meet regularly, shoot the material, fix it for two to four hours. At the same time, Jin Jingyi was shooting six targets. After two or three shooting, she expressed doubts about Jupiter Zhou as the protagonist of the documentary, but insisted on shooting it was her career requirements for her career. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; Did he tell you? &amp; rdquo; Jin Jingyi asked. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Peng Yinyin pushed her mobile phone to her, Zhou Moboxing actually filmed the situation of the one -night stand &amp; rdquo; that night, the two were shot together. Jin Jingyi remembered the details that night. The light and shadow is beautiful, and even a little erotic, Jupiter&#39;s face is hidden under the hair of Jin Jingyi. The rose text in the middle of the hair is looming, and the body is close from time to time. On the arm. Somehow, Jin Jingyi suddenly felt that there was a substantial relationship that night, but she deliberately didn&#39;t want to remember. Hidden, self -persuasion, and even the whole thing are unwilling to mention it. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; Why did he send you things? &amp; rdquo; Jin Jingyi couldn&#39;t stop a little angry. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; He is not intentional, it is cloud sharing. He forgot that our account was tied together after we broke up. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; Then what else do you ask me? &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; Because I don&#39;t believe you don&#39;t have it. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; I don&#39;t want to explain! &amp; rdquo; Jin Jingyi&#39;s face is hot and hot, &amp; ldquo; What do you want to think, that&#39;s your own business. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; I just want to know more about him, there is no other meaning, after all, &amp; hellip; &amp; hellip; he is my son&#39;s father. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The absurd sound in Jin Jingyi&#39;s mind suddenly sounded, and the curved Zhou Moby was like a pod, and suddenly broke, and a small bean shot. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; I was born with him, and in San Francisco in September the year before. I originally planned to hide him for a lifetime, but he died. &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jin Jingyi seemed to have been deceived, sad, depressed, weird, and twisted Zhou Mob -Star seemed to have seriously folded fun before. In love, he never said that he had a bad father -son relationship, never talked about his twin brother, and he never explained that he worked hard to make a perfect installation work. His weird thoughts floated in the sky, covered the earth, and eventually landed on his mouth, only fell into a chattering nonsense. boy! artist! fraud! He died, and Jin Jingyi could no longer ask him everything. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; Then why did you break up? &amp; rdquo; A tear sense quickly expanded in Jin Jingyi&#39;s body. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &amp; ldquo; We originally planned to get married. When I told him that I was pregnant, I immediately saw the fear in his eyes. He didn&#39;t speak, holding his hair, and looked painful. In the end, he said, let&#39;s get rid of the child. But he also said, don&#39;t let him know that he does not want to memorize the crime of murder. He looked like he was in pain. It made me feel that the new life in my stomach and me suddenly became cumbersome. Well, there is always a sacrifice, I can sacrifice, anyway, all sacrifice, don&#39;t add a new life. I then thought of his mind, and went abroad to gone &amp; hellip; &amp; hellip; If you know he is about to die, I will tell him how to tell him that in this world, he is very healthy, and he has no heart problems like him. &amp; hellip; &amp; hellip; &amp; rdquo; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The curved Zhou Moby has once again bounced into the golden clothes, folded the painful past, ups and downs. He burst into tears, chatted endlessly, unstoppable language flow, and the sound of &amp; hellip; &amp; hellip; Peng Yinyin&#39;s voice was stacked into Jupiter&#39;s voice, that kind of expression, physical appearance, that kind of idiot dream, the crazy crazy kind of crazy Sadness, twisted together, shaking it like a root whip. Jin Jingyi dodged a layer of beating, and suddenly identified something called love. She seemed to like Jupiter Zhou, who was finally enriched by Jupiter now. But she was too late to love him, and he died with a curved gesture &amp; hellip; &amp; hellip; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Jin Jingyi suddenly collapsed. &lt;/p>; &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; Responsible editor: Na Na &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; See @ONE&#39;s studio on Weibo. For more interesting daily life, please pay attention to Xiaohongshu: ONE an editorial department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Author &lt;/p>; &lt;hr style = &quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style = &quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src = &quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/fh8goknt2kmrw1bzrfehvmguxxa7 &quot;alt =&quot; Ahu &quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;&quot; Ahu &lt;span style = &quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>; &amp; nbsp; &lt;/sps>; &lt;/div >; &lt;div style = &quot;&quot;>; screenwriter, novel author, currently live in Beijing. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width = &quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-&lt;span Onclick = &quot;OneApp.Opendetail (2,)&quot;>; Follow &lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>; Related recommendations &lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style = &quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>; Reading &lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href = &quot;/Article/6162&quot; data-ajax = &quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>; Sober Dream &lt;/DIV>; &lt;DIV>; Text/Li Tang &lt;/DIV>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/TD>; &lt;/TR>; tr>; &lt;td style = &quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>; Read &lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/Aarticle/6119&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>; Sheng Temple &lt;/DIV>; &lt;DIV>; Text/Ahu &lt;/DIV>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/TD>; &lt;/TR>; &lt;TD STYLE = &quot;Width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>; Reading &lt;/span &lt;/span >; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6164&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;DIV>; The lifetime of the courier box >; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;l>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style = &quot;text-align: center; padding: 5px;&quot; Onclick = &quot;OneApp.Opendetail (2,6166)&quot; &quot; >; Click to download ONE APP &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &amp; nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4058]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4200]]><description>&lt;div>; 16 nov. 2023 &amp; nbsp; &lt;/div>; &lt;div Role = &quot;Main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src = &quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/fuxdh8uoslek5vxqo39vxqo&quot; alt = &quot;Home Figure&quot;/>; &lt;/>; P >; &lt;span>; Vol.4058 &lt;/span>; Photography | Luis Wittenberg &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 16 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Nov. 2023 &lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; Because everyone is because everyone They are all novice in life. If you have no responsible suggestion to others, you can get the pleasure of being a predecessor. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; &amp; nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 16 Nov 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>