<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4045]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4186]]><description>&lt;div>;3 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fu9uRfby5uhuUf3Zsr7X67vSsHTj&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;VOL.4045&lt;/span>;Photography | Ksenia Chernaya&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;3&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nov. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;We are who we are The person you pretend to be. &lt;br />;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net &quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 06:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[你觉得真心的保质期有多久？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3964]]><description> &lt;div>;2 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; ONE Studio Question&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p >;How long do you think the shelf life of sincerity is? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Zhu Deyong replied&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fq9nUt6bqIl-zj-zuR1Np57ASRmJ&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fq9nUt6bqIl-zj-zuR1Np57ASRmJ&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Nana onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Deyong’s Q&amp;A column &quot;Me≠We&quot; is exclusively updated on the &quot;ONE&quot; APP. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmPuzv4rbuXt8DD2ZiWPWVY5GDQ3 &quot; alt=&quot;Zhu Deyong&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Zhu Deyong&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;Weibo@朱德yong&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style =&quot;&quot;>;Cartoonist. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Question and Answer&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/question/3958&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Is it okay not to grow up, boss? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3948&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What was the last time you cried? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3942&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;At which moment did your childhood end? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3964)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 07:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[蒙面纪]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6144]]><description> &lt;div>;2 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Huang Yuning&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data -author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FqiqiRPlrRG5Z3Ama-pa2GEhWbWT&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FqiqiRPlrRG5Z3Ama-pa2GEhWbWT&quot;>; &lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Looking back at the future world, it is called the &quot;Mask Era&quot; During the catastrophic period, human memory is only a fog. Can we find the answer by looking back in time and space with the help of technology? Perhaps, it is difficult for humans to learn lessons from history, because the past can also be modified or deleted. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;One&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wear a virtual mask At that moment, I saw Qiao Yisi who had just entered the cubicle on my right through the surveillance camera. A cloud of fog suddenly spread in front of my eyes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Ms. Qi Nanyan, all your indicators are normal. Your slight discomfort is a normal phenomenon when you are about to enter the scene and will not have any negative impact on your health. &amp;rdquo;The cochlear implant reverberated with a soft tone, vaguely hearing the main theme of a classic science fiction film. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I feel like my discomfort is far more than mild. But I couldn’t tell how much of it came from the sudden tightening of the retro mask’s elastic band, and how much of it came from Qiao Yisi’s face. The smart devices in this room instantly detected my mental activity, and the camera focused on the light gray mole on his right eyebrow bone. I remember, ten years ago, he had the last argument with me. His facial muscles were twisted at a strange angle, pulling the mole ridiculously, and a red light appeared around it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qiao Yisi’s expression froze after three seconds. I know he also saw me through the surveillance camera. The corners of his mouth twitched a few times, probably saying a few words. He is the kind of person who will feel that he lacks depth once he speaks too clearly, and no smart device will give appropriate feedback. I slowed down my speech and protested clearly and accurately: &quot;Can I ask for a different partner?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Your partner was carefully selected and your match is almost perfect. There couldn&#39;t be more perfect data than this. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fuck you perfection. In the world of Joyce and I, nearly perfect score means falling into the abyss at the moment when you are about to reach for the stars. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Your heartbeat is slightly accelerated, and the parameters are within the upper limit of the preparation phase. This is a normal phenomenon that is about to enter the historical virtual time and space. You don&#39;t need to be nervous, close your eyes, sit quietly, and take deep breaths to help transition modes more smoothly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I should actually have thought of the possibility of meeting Qiao Yisi here. I told myself that I had not, never secretly expected to see him again here. I quickly called up Qiao Yisi&#39;s current identity on my phone. After our divorce, he really regained his former major. Historical research restorer, special level, specializing in masked history. Well, it’s still the same Qiao Yisi who is always working no matter how many clones there are in the virtual space. After the experiment is over, once he steps out of the virtual world, his papers, results, and smile on the podium will all turn out to be colorful bubbles like a basin of water with detergent thrown into it under the sun. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Of course I know how important Qiao Yisi’s work is. Thirty-eight years ago, a global digital catastrophe completely changed history, or in other words, changed the way &quot;history&quot; is stored. A hacker group that has not yet been detected has precisely attacked human digital files, especially causing a near-destructive blow to graphics and images. Since then, libraries and archives have begun to receive sufficient government funding and private donations, and paper documents and photos have once again become indispensable carriers of memory-because the harm of sporadic fires is far less than that of large-scale fires. Large-scale digital terrorist attacks. However, the damage that has been done is difficult to make up for. Those once vivid memories, all the moments that were thought to be preserved at that time and place, have been permanently deleted, leaving not even a scrap of paper or a wisp of smoke. Qiao Yisi was born in that year, and this coincidence seemed to be the only reason for him to choose his major. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was born with a mission, he said. The right corner of his mouth twitched slightly, as if with sarcasm, which destroyed all the touching power that might have been evoked when he said this. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Why did the mask era, which began in the 1930s and lasted for nearly eighty years, become the hardest hit area in this digital terrorist attack? Qiao Yisi talked about a lot, but I only remember two: First, the comprehensive upgrading of human memory carriers almost started at that time - people gradually became accustomed to tying everything about themselves to their mobile phones and immersed themselves in something. In an optimistic illusion that everyone can control memory. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;People at that time found that every moment could be broadcast live to the whole world, or thrown on the cloud, and they no longer bothered to use their brains or any tangible entity to store it. Memorized. So much so that when we look back now, the physical archives and materials from that period are much less than before. ” Qiao Yisi said thoughtfully. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secondly, &quot;That period of history was originally like a fog.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mist? What&#39;s the meaning? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Fog is just fog, the kind of thing where you can vaguely see the outline but can’t tell the boundaries. &amp;rdquo;Speaking of this, Qiao Yisi himself seemed to have fallen into a fog, and his words were filled with moisture. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;In the opinion of some people, this period of history should be forgotten. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;People’s opinions about the Masked Era are always confusing. All I know is that humans at that time were besieged by waves of microorganisms, starting from the respiratory tract and gradually spreading to the digestive tract, skin and blood. The corresponding chemical countermeasures - whether it is prevention or treatment - are always slow. After cheering for a new drug for a while, people always have to return to the oldest physical method of isolation. There are various versions of casualty figures, and the statistical calibers vary so much that you don&#39;t know which one to believe. The remaining records are filled with accusations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All kinds of protective equipment became a symbol of that period, sometimes fought for, sometimes abandoned, periodically appearing in the pitiful few paper documents and images. From masks and face shields to protective clothing and filter membranes, styles and materials are constantly being updated, which has become the most important basis for experts to judge the year. There have even been several local wars over new protective materials. All protective equipment starts from the mouth, nose and entire face, so it is reasonable to use &quot;mask&quot; to collectively refer to that era. However, by the later stage of the &quot;Mask Era&quot;, the covered part had already extended to the whole body. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I saw several original art masks covered with graffiti through the glass showcase in a museum (mostly online museums), I felt that human beings were living increasingly absurdly. In ancient times we had dinosaurs and chalk, in ancient times we had bronze. In modern times, we can only use masks to mark an era of amnesia. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;We lack first-hand information. What was the living situation of people during those gloomy eighty years? What were they thinking? We seem to know and yet we don&#39;t seem to know. &quot;At that time, Qiao Yisi was like a true thinker. No matter whether he was holding an ancient book or a soft pillow, he seemed to have grasped the lever that could move history. Ten years later, through the surveillance camera, I saw this expression on his face again. He must be the main creator of the large-scale virtual reality academic experiment &quot;The Masked Age&quot;, I have no doubt about it. More than ten years ago, he had a friend who was a well-known entertainment software designer in the VR industry. It is said that after making enough money in the past two years, he switched to cooperating with academic institutions. It was probably Qiao Yisi who had the connection. I even remember the man&#39;s name was Wu Jun. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As for me - I am just a curious volunteer in the pilot project of this large experiment. They said that this experiment requires sensitive writers who can quickly enter the situation and be good at detaching later, preferably women. They say that female writers&#39; ability to capture details is very important in restoring that important historical memory. I said yes, I qualify. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I lied, I did not meet the last condition. I&#39;m not sure how long it will take to get out of the overly realistic experience. If this experiment is as &quot;unparalleledly realistic&quot; as its operation instructions suggest, and reproduces that &quot;vacant historical detail&quot; for the first time, my consciousness may be trapped in that mess for a long time. I thought I would throw up, my stomach would shrink into weird shapes, and I wouldn&#39;t be able to write anything. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You have signed a confidentiality authorization agreement. In other words, during the entire experiment, we have the right to use your physical data, brainwave images and conversation records for academic research, and guarantee not to disclose any of your privacy to any third party. These usage rights do not include your VR videos. In order to reduce your concerns about historical time and space, we will not record virtual videos throughout the process. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Confirm. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Please confirm again. Selecting the semi-immersive mode means that you can always maintain a clear sense of time during the entire experiment. Your current identity and memory will conflict with the situation in the experiment to a certain extent. It&#39;s a shame that you won&#39;t be able to fully experience the realism of this experiment. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I confirm... So Joe - I mean my partner, what mode did he choose? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;No one answered me. The music in the cochlea begins to change, the melody line gradually blurs, and the notes stick to each other. A series of dissonant intervals with an overly strong electronic feel. These scattered elements eventually coalesce into a sound similar to whooshing through a tunnel. I lay flat in the sleeping cabin, closed my eyes according to the prompt, and allowed the sound to gather a hurricane, sucking me into the world of the Masked Era (120 to 200 years ago). &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Two&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The streets are empty. But this kind of emptiness still carries traces of being full not long ago, and it is completely different from the kind of emptiness I am used to. In the real world where I live, virtual reality technology has made breakthrough developments in the past ten years, and many people have spent more time in sleep cabins than outside. In the virtual world, they can go to Chicago for an academic conference in the morning and go surfing in Tahiti in the afternoon. In reality, the streets are really empty - you occasionally take a walk there, and you are surrounded by a safe and confused atmosphere. This aura is so stable, as if it originates from eternity and leads directly to the future. But in the sky one or two hundred years ago, there was hidden uneasiness that was about to emerge. The glass curtain wall of the commercial building reflected the dazzling sunlight boringly. I turned sideways to avoid the direct sunlight, and my eyes fell on a row of store signs. McDonald&#39;s. HUAWEI Digital Experience Center. A showroom for some Japanese and Korean brand cars. No wonder, I thought. Since this experiment is going to flaunt the fidelity of details, these superficial things, which are the easiest to do, must be done enough. After all, as we all know, the last sunset of the era of globalization falls on those highly similar and indistinguishable street scenes of the &quot;Era of Masks.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the city&#39;s landmark buildings will never appear - I have seen this in the experiment guide. Virtual reality scenes will abandon all markers that allow you to accurately locate time and space. You can&#39;t judge from the explosion marks on the Millennium Bridge that you are standing in London in 2088, nor can you expect to guess that you are trapped in the predicament of the early 22nd century (microorganisms are raging) from the distant snowy view of the pyramids. , rapid climate change and the resulting disputes will soon make the negative growth of the earth&#39;s total population exceed the warning level). Yes, you can&#39;t. In this experiment, you don&#39;t know what night it is, and you can&#39;t tell where you are on the earth. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Times have changed. If mankind has learned any lessons from those years, it is: put aside what should be shelved, blur what should be blurred, and use the time cost of mutual accusations to solve practical problems. The rights and wrongs of the Masked Chronicle, various true and false traceability behaviors entangled with political intentions, gave rise to unexpected secondary disasters. So much so that, now, even if it is an academic VR experiment, it must carefully avoid all hidden dangers that violate political correctness and protect this well-kept scar in human history. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;We do not participate in value judgments. Our research object is not historical events, but daily life. In our view, the Masked Period is a whole in the time dimension. As for the spatial dimension, that is the entire earth. Our destiny is connected and we all live the same life. &amp;rdquo;Not surprisingly, the slogans in the guides are always so empty and correct. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In short, I feel that my body is standing on a chaotic virtual coordinates, and about half of my consciousness is still stuck in the real world. Some slight centrifugal force seemed to pull me up from the ancient streets at any time. I took a hard breath through the mask, and finally I didn&#39;t let myself hang dangling in the air like a balloon. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Have you worn it for a long time? Qi Nanyan, you need to regulate your breathing. But don’t take it off—Qiao Yisi’s voice seems to come from far and near, and the distortion gradually decreases. In fact, I realized, his coordinates were right next to mine. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I can&#39;t believe he&#39;s here with me. As soon as we opened our mouths, the other person&#39;s name - the name one or two hundred years from now - came out naturally. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qiao Yisi’s tone contained a bit of the nervousness I was familiar with, but it seemed to be given new content. He muttered something, half of which was the latest protection guidelines issued by the city, and half of which was the newly updated case data. This is a typical performance of information overflow when entering an experiment, and it is completely normal. Qiao Yisi&#39;s choice was obviously the opposite to mine. He was in full immersion mode. During the process of entering the sleep chamber, a large amount of environment settings and background knowledge were input through the brain-computer interface, temporarily overwriting his existing memory of the real world. He is sinking wholeheartedly into a certain stage of the Masked Era. He will unconditionally accept all the chaos and anxiety of that era, accept the partner assigned to him by the program, and the entire story line about this partner. I thought about what I would do if this damn program gave me a vulgar personality. The kind of sweet and sensible wife who will definitely shut up when she should be silent. The woman I never became in reality. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I didn’t expect him to choose this way. As a historical research restorer of the Masked Chronicles, his research results (the fragments of history left behind by family memories, a collection of unclear and even contradictory oral accounts) are woven into the storyline and image scenes of the entire VR experiment; But he himself had to put aside the sophisticated external perspective, give up his sense of security, and run naked in the experiment. In other words, he will be severely squeezed and ridiculed by the historical details of his &quot;repair&quot;, and what he can get from this experience is a direct reaction of all thoughts, emotions and bodies uploaded in real time. I even had some doubts that my encounter with him was not a coincidence. As a member of the experiment&#39;s development team (and possibly a consultant), he has access to the list of volunteers. I imagine he would have convinced himself that emotion must give way to valuable historical research. From any angle, we are the most suitable and matching partners. The dislocation of the roles of rationality and sensibility can spark unexpected sparks. I remember him saying such incomprehensible things before. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;His excitement, which was obviously in a state of stress, was like a magnetic wind, picking me up and stuffing me dizzy into an off-road vehicle with luggage piled in the back seat. He stepped on the accelerator and the car went ten kilometers. In just these five minutes, I roughly pieced together the story that the brain-computer interface had instilled in him from the turbulence of information that was constantly flowing out of Qiao Yisi. We have been married for five years, have no children, and have a cat - currently sleeping happily in a transparent backpack in the back seat. Our relationship was a bit strained - which was totally unoriginal. Our city has seen a recent surge in cases and deaths, along with entirely new symptoms. Once the virus enters through the respiratory tract, it may invade every corner of the body and quickly trigger immune hyperactivity. The stronger the immune system, the greater the intensity of this hyperactivity. Most of the victims are young adults. They are like sycamore trees that stretch their branches and leaves ignorantly in the face of the typhoon, and are falling one by one. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This city is becoming the center of a new round of virus mutation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I think, at this pace, the city will soon enter sleep mode. He glanced at the news that kept popping up on his digital watch and muttered to himself: &quot;Fortunately, I just got a pass.&quot; There&#39;s enough time. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All the passively received information was finally synthesized in my consciousness. &amp;ldquo;Are we... running away? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You were strangled by the mask and your brain was deprived of oxygen, right?...Didn’t we agree? We&#39;re going out of town. What time has it been? Stop being willful, okay? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even Qiao Yisi felt that things were getting out of control, so she had to quickly turn up the volume of the car stereo to try to swallow the last sentence. It&#39;s like there is a thick code book between Qiao Yisi and me. The word &quot;willful&quot; alone is enough to restart all the unpleasant memories from ten years ago. In my imagination, everyone&#39;s consciousness is a small building with seven or eight floors. If these memories are suspended on my sixth level, then they should be buried in Joyce&#39;s vault - they were squeezed, crushed, and scattered by his full immersion mode, but they still permeated tenaciously. in all his actions. I have no way of distinguishing which part belongs to his stress reaction to the experimental scene and which part belongs to his inexplicable reaction to me driven by residual memories; I don’t know which part belongs to the Masked Era and which belongs to the Post-Masked Era. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I let out a sigh, and the mask bulged out. A stream of hot air surged upwards, overflowing from the sides of the mask, and a layer of wet mist formed in front of my eyes. I think the current VR technology is too realistic. In an era when it has become an antique and only a few examples still lie in museums, it is actually possible to recreate the feeling of wearing a face mask through sensors. Moist, sticky, almost suffocating, that legendary classical ambiguity, how exactly does it simulate it? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I can’t go with you. It would be best for us to go our separate ways. &amp;rdquo;I heard myself say softly but firmly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It&#39;s like a quarrel that lasted for a hundred or two hundred years. The past and the past are irrelevant, but the emotions are all connected. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qiao Yisi didn&#39;t care to answer my words, she clenched her fist and smashed it on her thigh. The car stumbled one after another, and finally stalled completely. The navigation showed that our coordinates were less than 500 meters away from the intersection of the expressway out of the city, and we were unable to move due to the traffic flowing in front, back, left and right. I looked out from the passenger seat. To the right of us, there was a driver yelling at his cell phone, then pressing it down, lowering his head, and burying his face in his broad palms. Then he got out of the car and walked back and forth in the gaps between cars, borrowing fires from others to smoke, and after chatting with each other for a few words, he became more and more excited. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;He should have been here several times. Knowing that there was little hope, I wanted to try my luck again. &amp;rdquo;Qiao Yisi said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;At least, there is someone waiting for him outside. Someone deserves this. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You are still like this, you like to make up stories. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You are still like this, unable to understand the story. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ten minutes later, a drone hovering on the roof of the car got closer and closer, issuing instructions. Qiao Yisi pressed the button to open the sunroof, and the remote sensing physical sign detection system collected our data in ten seconds. After another ten seconds, the drone turned on a red light and my ID number was announced. The machine repeated over and over again: &quot;One or more of your physical signs are not up to standard and you are not eligible for passage.&quot; Please go to the hospital to check by yourself. Thank you for your cooperation. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The light is green on the other side of Qiao Yisi. He reacted quickly and held my hand that was about to open the door. &quot;Don&#39;t be stupid,&quot; he said, &quot;Can I let you go to the hospital alone?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You still have time to get out. I deserve it, who allowed me to be willful? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He snorted, as if he wanted to sneer at it, but I could see that his shoulders and arms were stiff. The new strain has just spread in local areas, virologists around the world have only limited samples, and there is no consensus on many issues. One can imagine Qiao Yisi&#39;s nervousness. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Just the same old thing. Delay, divert, and control the number of spillovers. You may have been picked at random. &amp;rdquo;He was comforting me, but his tone was more like comforting himself. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The vehicles on both sides seemed to be frightened by the red light and gasped. They all used their driving skills to turn at incredible angles and actually made way for a narrow road, allowing Qiao Yisi to fall out. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There was a rustle in the back seat, and the cat turned over in the transparent bag. She obviously had a good dream. She raised her flesh pads and stretched out her claws to hook the ventilation holes on the bag. She grunted and was reluctant to open her eyes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;三&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The testing point at the entrance of the hospital was chaotic group. The originally designed closed-loop system was deformed by the flow of people from time to time and branched into two or three tributaries. There are always people who line up in the wrong line, or who suddenly faint when their legs give out while standing in line, causing a burst of exclamations. There were not enough staff wearing medical protective equipment. Two robots trying to guide the flow of people in accordance with operating regulations were slapped several times by more than a dozen angry hands and finally collided. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My heart was beating hard and I was retching. The sound field in the hospital is too realistic, with countless sounds bouncing and flapping on the eardrums at the same time. It was like I was sealed in a glass bubble, surrounded by invisible solids. It’s also semi-immersive mode after all, I guess. It’s true that half of me—maybe more than half of me—is already a believer in virtual environments. I am getting more and more into the character, and those abstract symptoms that once appeared in historical materials seem to be fulfilled in me. Dry cough, body heat and cold, chest tightness and shortness of breath. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My sense of reality is weakening at a steady pace, and the only connection between me and the outside world is a kite string that is about to be broken, wrapped around my wrist. I subconsciously wanted to hold on to it. I have indeed never seen these pre-modern hospitals - in real life I rarely even need to go to the hospital. I live in a world where telemedicine has long been mainstream. Even if a minor surgery is required, within an hour a sterile tent can be set up in your living room. This is just enough time for a medical surgical robot to arrive with a large set of instruments and prepare for surgery. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hospitals during the mask rule, especially those at the center of the epidemic storm, were really oppressive. I glanced at Qiao Yisi. Even though he was wearing a mask, I could still clearly see that his face was turning pale from the edge of the mask. He was even more flustered than me because he didn&#39;t have the kite string in his hand. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We all wear plastic gloves. He was afraid that I would be scattered by the crowd, so he held my hand. In the heat of the room, my gloves and his were almost sticking together. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You still have time to leave now. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Stop making trouble. We still have time to quarrel, it doesn&#39;t have to be now. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Now I know for sure that this is a storyline that works for us. I don&#39;t have to think hard at all and can just follow along. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;How do you know we still have time? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Then what else do you want? All places to apply for certificates are now closed. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As expected. In this story line, our relationship only needs a divorce procedure to end. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When the robot inserted the probe into my nasal cavity, the soreness and numbness seemed to reach my tear ducts. The inspector sitting aside hardly even raised his eyelids, and motioned to me, with blurred eyes, to quickly follow the team on the right. Only those patients who fainted in the queue or were obviously out of breath while clutching their chests were likely to be carried on the stretcher on the left side and sent to the intensive care unit. But stretchers are also queuing up. I glanced over and saw that the two stretchers that had been carried into the glass door on the left an hour ago were still lying in the same position. There are no more new hospital beds available. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The whole city is busy. But most of the energy is consumed on various assembly lines. People are transported from one level to another, and then, like being stuffed into a revolving door, they turn around and are sent back. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Ms. Qi Nanyan, within three hours, your test results will appear on your mobile phone, and your data will enter the CDC monitoring network. We will take countermeasures according to the priority of the situation. Please go home and wait. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is no medicine, there are people to verify vaccination records, precautions for home isolation and self-healing of mild illness were repeatedly broadcast, among which the word &quot;believe&quot; appeared most frequently. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I followed Qiao Yisi numbly, got in the car, got out of the car, and visited three supermarkets in succession, each one more deserted than the last. We soon realized that looking at the shelves was in vain. Only on the open space next to the shelves could we pick up a few potatoes and two bags of instant noodles (one of which had a tear in it) that had rolled off the shelves during the scramble. ) and a small package of cat food with a buy three, get two free label. Qiao Yisi scanned the code at the automatic checkout counter, but the machine had no response. She didn&#39;t know who had unplugged it. I waved my hand at Qiao Yisi who was in a daze, urging him to leave quickly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Don’t be stupid. I&#39;ll settle the money with them later. &quot;Although I also know that in the Masked Era, the sense of time becomes erratic - when you talk about the future, especially &quot;after the disaster,&quot; you never know how long it will be.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My test results arrived at the same time as the city’s hibernation announcement. &amp;ldquo;Negative. This does not mean that your risk is over, as the incubation period can range from three to 30 days. Please observe your physical signs closely and consciously maintain social distance from others. &amp;rdquo;Just when Qiao Yisi finished reading this sentence word for word, we happened to walk to the door of Room 101. His face was quickly scanned by the camera, and the door opened with a sound. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is the home of Joyce and me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The lights are turned on one by one, and the furniture seems to emerge one by one from the depths of memory. The dark green matte leather sofa and the pumpkin-colored wooden carved fruit plate are obviously second-hand goods that Joyce picked up from an antique store; all the lead-gray bookshelves look like they have been washed twice by cold water or moonlight, and those minimalist lines are deliberately cold. , I should have chosen them all. One or two hundred years later, our tastes are still completely different. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The cat returned to its familiar residence and suddenly lost its sleepiness. She quickly found the darkest corner of the living room, her pure black fur gently disappearing into the shadows, her yellow-green cat eyes getting wider and wider, shining with a faint light. But she didn&#39;t seem to be interested in us. She just stared at the patio outside the floor-to-ceiling windows of the living room. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Corona, don’t run around. &amp;rdquo;I heard Joyce calling the cat’s name. Coronavirus is a well-known global epidemic before the Masked Era. Although its scale and intensity are smaller than a series of viruses during the Masked Era, it is generally considered to be a warning preview of the Masked Era. It&#39;s more my style to give a cat such an ironic name. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kona ignored Qiao Yisi’s warning and still approached the floor-to-ceiling window step by step. I walked over and pushed it gently with my hand, and the floor-to-ceiling window opened along the slide rails. Connor jumped out and without hesitation found the familiar small hole at the root of the patio wall. She curled up and got out, blending into the dusk outside the wall. Like a piece of dark chocolate dropped into endless milk tea. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What are you doing? Cats don’t understand, and neither do you? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I turned my back to Qiao Yisi, not wanting him to see the first smile on my face since I entered this experiment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Four&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In virtual experiments, the measurement of time It&#39;s a wonderful thing. I will never understand how ten minutes in real life can be expanded and contracted at will in the virtual space - it can be squashed into one second, or stretched into a month or ten years, and not only do you take it for granted, And it&#39;s not as chaotic as in the dream. You feel the passage of time precisely. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When did the kite string disappear? In other words, when did I start not realizing that I had a cable in my hand? I have no idea. I seem to fall asleep easily in my virtual home. When I vaguely saw the reflection of reality in my dream for the first time, and when I dreamed about the present during the Masked Era, I may have already crossed that dividing line, and have been wandering between semi-immersion mode and full-immersion mode ever since. in the gap between. All the memories about the outside world are broken into strands of gossamer, floating in my subconscious, and will not emerge until the critical moment. I have to declare that for all the narratives from that time on, I have lost my reliable footing and no longer have the same stable and complete memory as I did before. The text you read below mainly relies on the chaotic tracing after the experiment, the splicing of fragments, and even fiction. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Of course there are benefits to this. The two time and space no longer collided, and my body and heart accepted the reality of a hundred or two hundred years ago: I was locked in the same house with my husband, who was about to divorce. The farthest distance we could go was the lobby on the first floor. There, we wore face masks (with goggle lenses embedded in the masks), exchanged glances with our neighbors, and received rationed daily necessities stacked by drones at our doorsteps. The supply of supplies has not been cut off, but the varieties and portions are getting smaller and smaller. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I had no further symptoms worth recording. I might have a slight fever in the afternoon, but it seemed to only add a little change to my body feel and complexion. After observing my health data for three consecutive days, Qiao Yisi also lost interest. &quot;Well,&quot; he said, &quot;psychologically induced sympathetic and parasympathetic imbalance. In the past two years, such &quot;false mental positives&quot; have been very common. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;There is really nothing you can’t explain. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He didn’t intend to refute my sarcasm, but just used a little force to bury his body deeper into the dark green sofa, making a dent in the leather. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At first, everything was self-explanatory. We each occupied a bedroom in a tacit agreement, staggered the time to go to the living room, kitchen, bathroom and patio, and moved all sharp and fragile things to places where we could not easily grab them. Projection TVs on the walls scrolled with updates on the epidemic, from the city to neighboring provinces and around the world. Most of the time, we set the sound on mute, no one was interested in watching it seriously, but no one wanted to turn it off. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Occasionally, when Qiao Yisi was having a video conference with a foreign company headquarters on the desk next to the floor-to-ceiling window, I looked at his back from a distance through the sliding glass door of the kitchen. Wear suit and tie on the upper body, striped pajama pants and cotton slippers on the lower body. I am familiar with this kind of backstory - during the years when we got married in real life, he also worked a job that had nothing to do with the history major. These meetings are obviously of no consequence and are probably just there to give the boss the illusion that the world is still functioning. From time to time, Qiao Yisi raised his head and smiled at the screen with a standard smile (the beauty lens was enough to fade his mole to almost disappear), then lowered his gaze and quietly glanced at the left side that the desktop camera could not capture. He is left-handed and can play games on his laptop with one hand. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I remember his left hand. I remember the subtle touch of my index finger and ring finger, and the deliberate pause when it slid across the back of my neck. My breathing also stopped for half a beat, one beat, one and a half beats. His right hand is not so evil. He would only gently press my shoulder with his thick right palm. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;No matter what, it is always a weird thing to watch a person playing games in a VR game (even though the games in the Masked Era are really very low-level), even if I didn’t realize it clearly at the time. at this point. My temples were throbbing slightly, and some parts of my body vaguely felt like they were trapped in an infinite loop of matryoshka dolls, and I was afraid of being stuck in a layer and not being able to get out. But at that time, I told myself that I didn’t like watching Qiao Yisi play games just because he once got carried away chatting with other women in online games in the real world. That was a classic topic of argument for us. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All couples who have ever quarreled so much that they want to die together know the value of silence - not to mention you have no idea how long you will be locked up together like this. I was making soup in the kitchen, leaving just enough in the pot for him to fill a bowl with; he was frying eggs, leaving an extra one on the plate and placing it on the stove. I left the only piece of cartilage in the soup, and the eggs he threw down must have been the kind with the egg whites just burnt and only a layer of curled edges, and the yolks were one-third congealed. I guess, given his cooking skills, in order to fry one to the right temperature, he would have to eat two fried ones. We didn&#39;t need to speak to arrange the dwindling food rations. I wrote down all the food stocks in the house on paper and stuck it on the surface of the refrigerator. He silently followed me and ticked it. It was as if we were holding a loose box tacitly. If one end was tilted, a snake might come out of it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The silence was broken on the third day, because the cat food was almost running out, and there was no pet in the ration. I picked up a colander and rubbed it against the edge of the stainless steel pot, making an unpleasant sound. The moment Joyce passed by the kitchen door, I sighed heavily. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Tomorrow is only enough for tomorrow. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What? As expected, he stopped and asked, &quot;Aren&#39;t there still so many unchecked boxes?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I only mentioned Kou Na lightly, and he came back to his senses. He immediately went to open the refrigerator door and wanted to check whether there were chicken breasts or salmon mince in the freezer. You can check it out online. The recipe is made. His hands were busy and his mouth was not idle: &quot;I know what you are thinking.&quot; No, really not. Don&#39;t you watch the news? Too dangerous. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Kona would often go out for a walk, and she could find her way home. This is how people grow up. She doesn&#39;t understand what isolation is. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;But we never let her go out at night. We always sprinkle her favorite catnip on this end of the cat hole in the evening to lure her back, and then plug the hole. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Night is the best time for cats to hunt. &amp;rdquo;I imitated the tone of the animal documentary and read it loudly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My eyes must have been shining irritatingly through the goggles on the mask, because Qiao Yisi suddenly pulled the mask down, exposing her nostrils and breathing heavily. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Is it necessary for you to deliberately not understand me? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I know what he is talking about. I know that many people are now throwing their anger at animals. The candidate list of intermediate hosts for the virus is getting longer and longer. People&#39;s attention gradually shifted from Asian bats and American deer to all household pets around the world. While the detection of viruses in these animals does not prove that they can be transmitted to humans, militant groups that lynch and trap pets are nothing new. When they perform humane destruction on a teddy or stuffed animal, they will record a video. They showed test reports in front of the camera and lit scented candles. They will wear white simple protective gear. You can&#39;t see their faces. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I don’t believe they can catch Connor,&amp;rdquo;I said coldly, &amp;ldquo;Her IQ is much higher than theirs. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You are simply... unreasonable. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You are unreasonable. We&#39;ve already lived our lives like this, and you still want to lock up a cat? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My words have no effect on Qiao Yisi. In the end, he gave in because Korna didn&#39;t like eating what he cooked. In the evening, she used her paws to fiddle with the white meat paste that he had spent two hours tinkering with. Her pupils first dilated in a circle, then shrank into a vertical line, and she almost fell asleep hugging the cat bowl. I couldn&#39;t help it, and burst out laughing, spraying most of my mask. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The night is getting darker. Qiao Yisi finally opened the French window. Connor walked around the cat hole twice in disbelief, and found that we had no intention of stopping her. Then she let out a whimper of joy and got out. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I put a GPS collar on her,&amp;rdquo; Qiao Yisi murmured, &amp;ldquo;There is a pinhole camera on the collar. If something happens...&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;She will be fine, don&#39;t worry,&quot; I said. I was shocked when I found that my voice and tone suddenly became much softer. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Five&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;Kona is a special cat , so special that no ready-made guide to raising pets can cover her. Qiao Yisi said that it was because I picked her up from the air conditioner unit eight months ago and I have been working against the guide. The small group of black figures huddled there, their bodies vibrating slightly as the external machine operated. She doesn&#39;t stick with you all day just because someone wrapped her in a blanket, moved her into the house, gave her a few sips of milk, and made her eyes light up. She likes to find dark corners with similar fur colors to hide in. She believes that observing is safer than being observed. It seemed that from the moment she entered the house, Connor consciously maintained a minimal dependence on humans. Apart from one time when she wet the carpet, she didn&#39;t seem to be having a hard time during her heat period. She could certainly hear the shrill cries of wild cats outside the window, but as long as we were home, she maintained a noble silence. Faced with such a cat, you can&#39;t think of neutering or trimming her claws. There are always a few scratches on the wall, but you just can&#39;t see when she scratched them. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For several days, we were in the courtyard early in the morning and saw an exhausted Kou Na sleeping on a small patch of half-yellow and half-green grass. The sun shines on her furry ears, making them dark and shiny, and the color saturation is so high that it almost overflows the frame. If she carefully cleans the battlefield, she can still find a few blood-stained ocher bird feathers near her paws, and even a gray rat tail. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since Kou Na went out every night, Qiao Yisi and I got up early at the same time. Our schedules seemed to suddenly overlap. The small and hidden cat hole in the patio became the only air hole leading to the outside world in this stuffy jar-like house. Not only Connor, we also need to take a breath from there. The night vision infrared camera on Connor&#39;s GPS collar will transmit the video to Qiao Yisi&#39;s computer. Every morning, Qiao Yisi projects the video on the wall in the living room, and we take turns pulling the progress bar to see what Kou Na went through last night. There&#39;s something strangely attractive about the images framed by Connor&#39;s chin, a few drooping beards, and the ground. Unable to take our eyes away, we foolishly followed her out from under the car chassis. The holly hedges in the community gradually became clear before our eyes, and then blurred again. GPS showed that her range of activities was far beyond our imagination, and she ran to a park one kilometer away in one breath. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Preying is not as beautiful as expected because the action is too fast. The camera follows her body as she shakes violently, and follows her as she jumps to a height that is more than seven times her body length. Groups of shadows flashed across the screen. The camera can barely capture the prey, and coupled with the sound of biting and fluttering, you will feel that Kou Na is fighting with herself. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The screen shows one o&#39;clock in the morning. In the darkness, Connor&#39;s steps slowed down, and a familiar gurgling sound came from her throat. Suddenly, the lens trembled, and after shaking twice, it focused steadily on two glimmers of light in the trees ahead. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Huh? &amp;rdquo;Qiao Yisi also became excited. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From the direction of the flickering light, a clear and loud long sound came. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;This is...&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;A cat. The other cat,&quot; I said, &quot;is male. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;How do you know? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Intuition. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qiao Yisi was speechless for a moment. We just watched in silence as Connor stood motionless in the screen, confronting the tom cat opposite. Kona had clearly invaded the other party&#39;s territory. I think the one who can stand on the central lawn of the park must be a strong male cat. Under infrared light, his gray outline gradually became clearer in the lens, and he indeed looked larger than Connor. In a confrontation, the first principle of animals is not to expose their backs to each other, so such confrontations often last for a long time. Qiao Yisi waited until the cat opposite the camera turned around first, then breathed a sigh of relief. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Our Connor,&amp;rdquo; he almost laughed out loud, &amp;ldquo;is not an ordinary cat. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I think you said the opposite. Maybe this just shows that Connor is also an ordinary cat, and like all ordinary cats, has the instinct to discharge towards the opposite sex. This is not a miracle, it is just a different type of story. But I didn&#39;t say it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The progress of the next few days confirmed my suspicion. Connor&#39;s coordinates would be fixed on the big lawn in the park every night at midnight. The martial arts film has indeed turned into a romantic drama, but they test each other slowly and patiently, as if they are sure that this love will last a hundred years. They don&#39;t have to worry about what kind of chaos the world has become, and they don&#39;t have to worry about being consumed and overwhelmed by the exciting topics that come from all directions day after day. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vaccination, specific medicine, or precise isolation? How much potential is there for cities to repair themselves? Will the virtual reality economy usher in an epoch-making opportunity? Why are face mask meltblown cloth facing elimination? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Eliminate? Wasn’t there a huge rush a while ago? Two countries almost came to war. &amp;rdquo;I asked casually. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Nano. For example, meltblown cloth uses thick threads to weave a fine mesh, and nano uses thin threads to weave a fine mesh. Therefore, whether it is breathability or filtration, the advantages of nano are obvious. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;According to this situation, sooner or later the mask will have to grow on the face. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Maybe&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash; materials are being developed to their extremes, and with the mutation of human genes, maybe in another hundred or two hundred years...&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Qiao Yisi&#39;s tone sounded like she was sleepwalking. It&#39;s been a long time since I&#39;ve seen him look so nonchalant. It was really rare that at this moment, he realized that there were more important things in the world than saving the world. He almost pressed his entire face against the wall, as if he thought he could clearly see the cat seducing Connor. I said that infrared photography in the middle of the night is pretty good, maybe we have to rely on our imagination. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Imagine the grass wet with dew late at night in early autumn, and imagine the eyes and smells of one cat and another cat entangled with each other close to the ground. Every docile stillness of Connor, every tremor accompanied by a low-frequency sound, seemed like something was happening or about to happen. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Actually, we can&#39;t know for sure,&amp;rdquo; Qiao Yisi shook his head, leaned back, and lay crookedly on the sofa. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Why? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Because the camera is mounted on the collar, almost at the throat. You couldn&#39;t have seen the back of her neck being gently bitten by his teeth... Do you think that stupid guy could control the intensity just right? I&#39;m worried about Korna getting hurt. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Why does it have to be the neck? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Because this is the standard posture for cats to mate. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Oh. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Similarly, from that position, it is difficult for you to judge when she bends her front paws and crawls close to the ground, giving him a signal to tell him that I am ready. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Oh. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Aren’t you worried? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Don’t worry. The cat I have is not that easy to chase. She warms up slowly. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;As slow as you? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It’s too late. When I said this, I knew it was too late. My back was facing him, and there was just enough distance between us for his arms to wrap around my shoulders comfortably. My mind is still resisting, but every nerve ending on the surface of my body is waiting to be touched, bumped and rubbed. Then, in what seemed like only ten minutes but seemed like a century, the shell chandelier he chose on the ceiling and the beige carpet I chose under the coffee table appeared in my field of vision alternately and rotating. I tried to keep my eyes half open, not wanting to faint. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I only remember one thing. The last thing we took off was the mask. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Six&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sampling of Virtual Academic Experiment (Masked Period) Transcript of the conversation. The identities in the experiment are husband and wife, and the scene is a closed room. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;1. The ninth day (the time in the scene has nothing to do with the real world. The same as below)&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Okay...sofa...give me a blanket. Damn it, when did Kou Na come? She&#39;s looking at us. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It’s okay, she’s watching the projection. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The video is always on? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Not at all. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Guess, does Kou Na know that the person on the projection is herself? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hard to say. I thought I would at least be able to recognize that kid. You looked down at Connor&#39;s neck. He had bitten the hair off near the collar. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What can she do? There was no place for her to escape. When the sky fell, there was finally another cat carrying it together. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I know what you are thinking. People like us are only suitable for staying together when the sky falls, right? When things got ugly again, we started quarreling and getting divorced. I said, Qi Nanyan, you haven’t put on your clothes yet, can you please stop being so disappointing? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then let’s not talk about this. Let me ask you, why didn’t you go out of the city that day? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Why should I leave the city? Even if you escape, what&#39;s the point of being a lonely wild ghost? Do you remember that guy on TV, running back and forth on the highway between two cities, not accepting him at either end? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I feel now that it would be better if you didn’t leave than if you left. Maybe a lot better. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Oh. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2. The Thirteenth Day&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those people dropped leaflets in the material distribution group again. We were dividing the compressed biscuits, and suddenly an animated slogan came down. Let me ask you with a face: Do you want cat rights or human rights? You can&#39;t imagine how capable they are. Starting from the saber-toothed tiger, we will go through the entire feud between cats and primates. Bats and deer are too far away from us for them to look down upon. Only cats—bearing the humiliation and humiliation of the family mission, lurking in thousands of households—don’t tell me, all the rhetoric must be followed, it seems like that. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Be patient and pretend they don’t exist. I couldn&#39;t bear it any longer and had already quit the group. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But if you quit this, where else can you go? Which group is not quarreling now? How much truth is flying in the sky? You fly yours and I fly mine, no matter where they are. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Humanity is a scattered patch of sand and needs a common enemy. They can&#39;t see or touch viruses, so how can they fight them? Cats that are neither big nor small and within arm’s reach are most suitable. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Farewell them theirs. Humans are not them, they are us. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Okay&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;us. I guess the wishful thinking of us humans is that a cow falls from the sky, and a milkmaid must be a female, pleasing to the eye, the type of Kate Winslet. In this way, the British man named Jenner could look at her more and be interested in hearing a few more common words from her. While chatting, the secret of cowpox was revealed. We humans have been fighting infectious diseases for thousands of years, and this is the only one that can be called a complete victory. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But what if there are no cows and no Winslet? The virus just rubs you softly and soaks it hard. You can&#39;t kill it with a slap. It changes its vest and slips out of the back door, circles the earth, and then comes back in a month. The problem is that you can&#39;t lock every door in the world at the same time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From a historical perspective--another historical perspective. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition to history, what else do we have in our hands? I&#39;m playing a game about the rise and fall of the Roman Empire. After all the calculations, the plague and smallpox - what was called the Galenic Plague at that time - were not taken into account, so the points were cleared in a flash. I went to find a book to read. In those days, the population was literally cleared, and the population was in the millions. What do you think is the cause? But the Romans won the battle and took away a lot of loot from other cities. The virus returned home along with the gold, silver and jewelry. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Poor—us humans. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But you humans quickly learned to use it. Just a few hundred years later, an army attacked a city and besieged half of the city. I was about to be wiped out by the plague. Guess what, they thought of a trick, tied the corpses of their own people to the crossbows, and shot arrows into the city... Oh my god, is this a biological weapon? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The earliest biological weapon. The effect is remarkable. ending? Definitely a fucking comeback. This method has been tried and tested many times. The fastest way to conquer alien races is to bring advanced weapons and unfamiliar viruses with them. The group was wiped out, very simply. You - we - let&#39;s just say we humans will always win. When the two armies confront each other and fight to the end, until your whole army is wiped out, even if there is only one person left here, I will win. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But now--it&#39;s hard to say. The population flow is so fast, it’s hard to say who will surround whom and who will survive to the end. Isn&#39;t the whole world connected together? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The truth is this, but--they--I mean we--if we all understand this truth--(made a cup Coffee time)&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are even beans--how many have you stocked up? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Not much. The last few Mandheling beans are in it, and the rest is instant and will last a month. Let’s start setting a certain amount tomorrow. No more than one cup a day, and no more than one cup on two days next week. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Have you never thought that maybe we can’t survive the hoarding of these things? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Never thought about it. No use even thinking about it. From a literary perspective--well, it&#39;s finally literature&#39;s turn. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;How should I put it? The attitude of novelists is actually very different. Defoe, the man who wrote Robinson Crusoe, was more like a reporter—well, he was a reporter. He has a good sense of space. If he were to write about our current lives in the same way as &quot;Chronicles of the Plague Year&quot;, I think he might not be as interested in us as we are in our house. He would first draw a map of the city, noting exactly where each house was. Only he would put a mark on the cat hole on our patio. He would emphasize the need for isolation while embodying distant, abstract sympathy for us. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;So this Mr. Fu experienced the plague outbreak in London? Then we have to go back to the historical perspective. I remember it was the seventeenth century. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was only five years old when the plague struck London. Novelists are liars. He played the role of a survivor who wandered the streets of London and witnessed the whole process with his own eyes. He said a hundred thousand people were wiped out and I was still alive. I can just imagine his face when he said this. Like a superhero in a movie, the one covered in plastic. He writes very well. Every word is as vivid as seeing it with your own eyes. From then on, the memoir he forged became part of history and a sample of disaster narratives. Such as Camus. When Mr. Jia wrote the big scenes in &quot;The Plague&quot;, he basically stayed within Mr. Fu&#39;s framework. &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;You mean Camus copied it? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That can’t be said. Camus added a Sisyphus-style disaster relief team to the framework of Defoe&#39;s disaster film, and the pattern was completely different. Human nature suddenly has a bright side. However, I think that if Camus and Defoe met across time and space, they might not have a good conversation. Camus would think Defoe was too crude and utilitarian, while Defoe would think Camus was too pretentious. Camus said: &quot;Perhaps one day, in order to teach mankind a lesson, the plague will wake up the rats and let them die in a happy city.&quot; Guess what Defoe&#39;s expression would be when he heard this? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Can’t guess. But I really want to see them fight. From a scientific point of view, the plague is not without any benefits. It is said that the survivors of the Black Death have a certain degree of genetic mutation. Human beings may have been driven by viruses to evolve... From a historical perspective, the plague has also fulfilled religion... In this way In other words, from a literary point of view, the plague has fulfilled love. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Well, even I have seen it. &quot;Love in the Time of Cholera&quot;? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I don’t like that book very much—maybe because I liked it so much before. In Marquez&#39;s world, cholera is just the backdrop for love. Those two people met in troubled times and separated in troubled times. Only such a long separation can extend the shelf life of love. Let him write our story. You should have escaped from the city that day, while I was stopped in the gate, and we spent half a century missing each other. Our love is immortal because of this. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So you also admit that we are in love? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ha, what I meant was a quote, no, a paraphrase. All in all, it was Marquez talking, not me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From your literary point of view--all I heard were not good words. A thief, a liar, or at least a pretender. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to this logic, there are still instigators. I mean The Decameron. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Is this the one that teaches people to have fun? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than just having fun? It was an orgy. Revel while the plague spreads. You know, I have read the first chapter of this book three times in the past few days. Boccaccio&#39;s heartless writing style actually made me burst into tears. Think about it, the plague is rampant in the city of Florence, and there are several pages written in the previous chapter where corpses are everywhere. It is said that even close relatives are isolated from each other due to fear and become strangers. Suddenly, he made a U-turn, and a group of handsome men and beauties appeared, gathering together and heading out of the city. It was also inexplicable outside the city. There was a Garden of Eden waiting for them for no reason. The tablecloth was snow-white, the wine glasses shone like silver, and gorse flowers were dotted everywhere. They don&#39;t have to do anything but tell the story one after another, and that&#39;s enough. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Boccaccio failed in his writing - the novelist does not have to bear any responsibility anyway. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But why did he collapse in that direction? Guess, did that really happen, or was it a dream, a near-death hallucination, an indescribable intracranial orgasm? Do you think these good-looking, carefree men and women who turn tragedy into comedy are people or ghosts? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Look, you think too much. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Don’t stare at me. The best stories have the shadow of death lingering behind them. Must have. Believe me, the sense of the apocalypse - the fact that we know that people will definitely die - is the basis of all literature and art. The closer this feeling is, the more fascinating the work becomes. For example, ancient people whose life expectancy was less than half that of modern people - (Pause. Silence. The sound of the mask being taken off and the mouth being softly blocked.)&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;3. Day 21&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;How many rounds have your groups reached? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Let me take a look. If you look at it from Boccaccio&#39;s perspective, the funniest thing today is that the anti-vaccination guys are clamoring to wear masks that they never want to wear. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Why? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Because the number of people who have been vaccinated has exceeded those who have not been vaccinated. They said they need to be wary of those guys passing denatured proteins into uncontaminated bodies - it&#39;s so damn funny. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Let them wear it. Masks are going to grow on your face someday, really. They&#39;d better get used to it now. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Interesting, I don’t think you are joking. Like a witch who predicts the future. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;No kidding. Isn’t the mask material evolving round by round? I think, when it becomes thinner and thinner, so thin that you gradually can’t feel its existence... it’s like putting a film on the screen. ? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Polymer. It&#39;s breathable and sweat-resistant, soft and fit, and it can also receive bioelectrical signals, such as blood pressure, electrocardiogram and so on. I&#39;ll give you an alert from time to time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This seems to have been studied. Electronic flexible skin. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That’s easy. Take a small step forward and put a membrane that can kill or filter viruses on you from head to toe as soon as you are born, and change it every ten years. If an invisible filter or something is implanted in the nose or mouth, wouldn’t the virus be wiped out? Can’t the mask be thrown away? Hmm - you can keep two good-looking ones for the museum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Where is this small step for you? There are so many problems to solve. How can we keep breathing and filter viruses at the same time? What kind of material can provide a long-lasting fit that can’t be washed off with just a shower? Even if all these problems are solved, I guess many people&#39;s skin, mouth and nose will be allergic to this kind of stuff, and some people will get rashes all over their heads and faces even if they wear a woolen sweater. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Scientists will find a way. The materials will get better and better, and the human body will become more and more adaptable. The genes that survived the Black Death probably weren&#39;t just good luck. Only those who survive the virus and are able to wear masks are more likely to survive and deserve to survive. After one or two generations, it will be time for some genetic mutation, right? By that time, the early rejection and allergic reactions of the human body to the film have basically disappeared, and only a few unlucky ones will still be allergic. They would say this is called atavism. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Is this science fiction? All things in the world, when mentioned to you literary people, are as if they were a joke. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It should be said that things in this world are becoming more and more like a joke. How would you live your life if you didn&#39;t pass the time like Boccaccio, drinking wine and telling jokes? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If one day comes, if everyone sticks to the membrane, I--well, I mean we--like this, when we reach out our hands, will we touch people or people? membrane? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Don’t take advantage of it...it’s membrane. So humans in the future are safe. Absolutely safe. You don’t need to show your electronic health certificate first if you want to kiss anyone. Your skin, mucous membranes, and any organs are not in direct contact. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, wouldn’t having a sense of danger make the whole process more exciting? There is a huge difference between kissing a piece of skin and kissing someone who you think will die tomorrow even if you kiss her, but you still have to kiss her today. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Let me think about it - at that time, people with the membrane could play retro VR games, lie in the sleeping cabin, and return to the dangerous masked era. The most advanced sensors and brain-computer interface will convince him that this is real skin contact, and he will forget that he is wearing a membrane. He didn&#39;t even know that there were poison filters in the world. Yes he can. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What can he do? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;You can kiss that person who even if you die tomorrow, you still have to kiss today. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Fifteen minutes. Gradually blurred words to rising and falling monosyllables. Panting. Breathing.)&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I feel--I have never felt better. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Really? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Really. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That’s good. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I am still thinking--if there is an entrance to these two eras, a shining revolving door like in the movie. You can pick one to go in, how do you choose? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sleepy. Which two? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Now, is there a future with film? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Women talk a lot... Then which era are you in? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ha, maybe, I’m both here? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Oh. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hey, wake up, wake up. Go to bed and sleep. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;4. Day 28&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Listen, Qi Nanyan, let’s all calm down. I can&#39;t hear a word you say. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;You just don’t want to hear it. you are always like this. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;You are quarreling for the sake of quarreling. This is emotion, not fact. Every time we quarrel, we forget what we are arguing about. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Because I&#39;ve had enough. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yes, you&#39;ve had enough. The whole city has had enough. Typical symptoms of claustrophobia. This is normal, but you cannot achieve psychological balance by torturing me. I&#39;m about to collapse too. Something&#39;s not right with you and Connor. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What happened to Konna? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Irritable, too lazy to move, and unkind to others. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She doesn&#39;t care about others. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I took a walk outside yesterday evening and came back before midnight. I found a useless cardboard box, curled up in it and fell asleep. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Does she have enough to eat? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That’s enough. Even if she didn&#39;t bother to catch a mouse or something, her boyfriend, the guy in the park, wasn&#39;t willing to starve her. Don&#39;t you think her whole body is round? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I understand. Is there any milk at home? Coax her to eat some at least. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There was finally a carton of fresh milk in the ration yesterday. What do you mean? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kona is pregnant. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ah--our Konna is really no ordinary cat. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;You are saying the opposite again. This just shows that Connor is also an ordinary cat, and like all ordinary cats, has the instinct to reproduce. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In this messy world, it takes courage to maintain your instincts. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;5. Day 30&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I think something is going to happen. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Receive their warning on your phone. Let me take care of my cat. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ignore it. They send it out every day. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But...Kona didn&#39;t come back in the morning. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I see that you have been sleeping deeply and I dare not wake you up. I thought if I waited just one more hour, Connor would come back. But no. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I...can&#39;t open my eyes. Qi Nanyan, don’t come here. Do not touch me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What&#39;s going on? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I think I have a fever. No need to test, it must be over thirty-nine degrees. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;You mean&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I think, yes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;How is that possible? We haven&#39;t gone anywhere, where is the source of infection. I don&#39;t believe it, I need to call the hospital. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wait a minute, let me think about it first. But I have a severe headache and I feel sleepy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wake up. Don&#39;t fall asleep. I beg you. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Loud sobs. A shrill meow in the distance.)&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt; span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Preliminary assessment&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;1. &amp;nbsp;In the five dialogues intercepted above, you can see a large number of keywords from the Masked Period. The frequency of the words is evenly distributed, full of the atmosphere of daily life at that time, and it is a very representative sample. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;2.&amp;nbsp;The subject’s personality and social relationship in the experimental scene, to the greatest extent Continue its true appearance in reality, including name and identity. Practice has proven that this can make the story line in the experimental scene progress more smoothly. &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;3.&amp;nbsp;从第三段中可以看出全沉浸模式与半沉浸模式的差异。两个时空的冲突，让处于半沉浸模式的受试者饱受困扰。她的&amp;ldquo;预言&amp;rdquo;之所以与如今的现实有高度相似性，甚至随口说出了&amp;ldquo;蒙面纪&amp;rdquo;这个专用名词，显然是受到了现实的干扰，尽管她似乎浑然不觉。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;4. 由于不明原因，实验出现卡顿，继而宕机，第五段被迫中断。受试者未完成预定程序即被动退出实验，特此标注。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;七&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;实验故障事后访谈。编号019。调查人员代号C。实验志愿者代号V。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：在你陷入类昏厥状态之前，你记得最后看到的是什么？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：雪白的台布，闪着银光的玻璃酒杯，金雀枝花朵。男人，女人，一个接一个地讲故事。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：这已经在类昏厥状态之中了，你的意识已经模糊。紧跟着你就醒过来，回到现实中。当时你所在的虚拟实验遇到了故障，VR处于卡顿状态，什么情节也没有记录下来。你的大脑中出现一定程度的信息奔逸，都是正常。我要问的，是在此之前，你在虚拟现实里的那条故事线，发生了什么？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：让我想想，使劲想想。他病了，症状凶猛。他说他应该是中招了。我想给医院打电话，他说这样不行。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：为什么不行？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：因为&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;寇娜不见了。我们的猫被那些人定位，追踪，他们说家猫才是真正的中间宿主，他们一直在搜集更多的证据。如果我们马上去报告新增病例，你们猜他们会对寇娜怎样？寇娜快要生了，一窝小猫，不知道会有几只黑，几只灰，几只黑灰相间，我&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：抱歉，请平复一下情绪。你们紊乱的体征指标很可能是导致本次实验报警、卡顿、提前退出的原因。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：我们？乔易思好吗？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：你是说你的实验拍档吗？他很好。但是全沉浸模式苏醒的时间更长，他的脑机接口毕竟是深度植入&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;尽管是极微创。他应该还在睡梦中。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：我记得，当时乔易思嘴里还含含糊糊说了几句，我想我听懂了。他说我也会有嫌疑，因为我在一个月前出城时体温异常但再没有出现别的症状，人们会认为我是传说中的超长期无症状传播者&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;据说我这样的人，血清很有研究价值，弄不好会被抢购。也就是说，在上报之前，我和寇娜都要做好被关起来当成试验品的思想准备。现在人们已经失控了，他说，谁知道他们会干出什么来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：那你当时怎么判断？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：我能怎么判断？我觉得我成了一只快要爆裂的气球。是的，有那么一瞬间，我好像突然想起了外面&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;呃，我是说，想起了一百多年以后的&amp;ldquo;现在&amp;rdquo;，你懂我意思吗？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：明白。半沉浸模式的时空冲突。请说得再详细一点。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：我知道蒙面纪之后的研究结果表明，这事跟猫没什么根本性的关系。没有什么动物能替人背上这口锅。我当时不知道哪来的底气，但我很清楚这一点。我甚至想去找那些组织，我以为我能说服他们，当时乔易思已经说不出话来，可他拼命挥手拦住我。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：他是对的。蒙面纪的很多失控事件，都是因为一个人以为能说服一群人。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：我记得的最后一件事，就是我们在僵持。从僵持到出现雪白的台布之间，是一片空白。那种感觉，就好像手术台上的全麻你懂吗？时间就那么凭空不见了，此前与此后毫无空隙地咬合在一起。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：好吧，了解。看来这个实验的细节还有很多可改进之处，谢谢你的全程参与。你还有什么问题吗？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：我&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;我想知道为什么会有这个实验。除了学术研究以外到底还有什么意义。我以为我会进入一场曲折的冒险，我以为我会发现一个阴谋，或者见证一个发明，等到一个足以拯救世界的奇迹。我以为我会扮演一个角色，比如在某个抢救中心跟死神抢时间的医生，最后自己染上了病毒，绑在呼吸机上无助地望着惨白的天花板。然而没有，什么都没有。我只是又演了一遍我自己，傻乎乎地跑到一百多年前隔离了一个月。在漫长而琐碎的日日夜夜里渐渐失去时间感。我对一切都无能为力，就好像被白白偷走了一生。最后连结局都被偷走了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：但是你的投入程度，丝毫不亚于一场真正的冒险。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：我还是想知道为什么？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：这个实验可能有一定的实用价值。比如可以为你提供写作材料，再比如，也许能治疗心理疾病。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：真的？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：这么说吧，齐南雁女士。有一类人，也许你见过，他们深深地陷在后蒙面纪综合症里无法自拔。尤其是具有相关惨痛家族记忆的人，对那段历史深感好奇的人，以及有专业研究背景的人，诸如此类。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：我想我见过这类人。比如，历史修复师。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：他们无处倾诉，但总是被噩梦惊醒。他们相信即便是最新版本的滤毒膜也无法阻挡病毒的变异，我们终有一天会被进化到X代的超级病毒攻破防线&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;而那时，我们的肌体甚至不具备与我们的祖先相当的抵抗力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：我懂。因为他们读完了传染病与人类缠斗了几千年的历史，他们知道病毒与人类的任何和平共处的时间都是短暂的，短得像一场初恋。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：呃&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;你形容得很准确。是那么个意思。你身边是不是有过这样的人？这种创伤渗透到他们的日常生活，伤害他们的心理状态，也影响他们与别人的关系。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：当然有。而且我知道这种影响会很严重，很持久&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：你在想什么？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：我跟他说，看着我的眼睛，我们真的不考虑生个孩子？他说，为什么要让这世界多一个潜在的受害者？在这个乱糟糟的世界里，维持本能是需要勇气的。我知道他偷偷地加了一道防护&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;说真的，他还不如一只猫勇敢。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：什么？我听不懂你在说什么？感觉像是两辈子的事。你还是需要休息。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：没什么。是两辈子的事。有点串。你们这个虚拟实验里出现的宠物，我是说那只黑猫，有原型吗？它做得那么逼真，是不是用到了&amp;ldquo;真猫捕捉&amp;rdquo;的动画特技？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：让我查一查。还真有。一只被收容进实验室的流浪猫。年纪不小，快要退役了。你看，我把这只猫的DNA谱系资料调出来，她居然还有隐性的蓝金渐层基因。你看，往前推几十代，她的生活在前蒙面纪时代的祖先叫作&amp;ldquo;奶茶&amp;rdquo;，长得多好看啊。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：我能不能收养她？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：抱歉，这个我真不知道。回头你跟公关处再打听打听。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：好的，谢谢。再耽误你两分钟可以吗？我想知道，这样的治疗，让饱受后蒙面纪综合症的病人亲身经历那段历史，真的会有用吗？难道不会让他们更恐惧吗？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：你知道，实验刚刚开始，对疗效的评估还需要时间。何况，就算有了第一批数据，那也一定是保密的。我只能说，有风险，但值得尝试。除了恐惧，齐南雁女士，我相信你在这个实验里也感受到了别的东西。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;V：好吧。我没有问题了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C：再次感谢你的参与。对了，有件事也许你有兴趣知道&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;刚才，一分三十秒以前，你的拍档，乔易思先生&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;他醒了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;责任编辑：舟自横&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文选载自《钟山》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FoIosTASxA6efZbi0eCt3jwjHN6Z&quot; alt=&quot;黄昱宁&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;黄昱宁 &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@黄昱宁&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;上海译文出版社副总编辑。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;关注&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;相关推荐&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/3465&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;海外关系&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 黄昱宁&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6144)&quot;>;点击可下载ONE一个app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 07:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>