<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[我们的想象力是如何消逝的？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3929]]><description> &lt;div>;27 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; ONE Friendly Question&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>;We What has killed your imagination? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Palace Lord Bingda&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data- original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FseAvIpMWvFzYkwJSvDMX39gwJ_8&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FseAvIpMWvFzYkwJSvDMX39gwJ_8&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The passing of imagination It is a result, and there is more than one killer who caused this result. For example, busy life, blind obedience to prejudices, standard and only answers. These three act simultaneously, but kill our imagination from different angles. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Killer 1: &lt;strong>;Busy Life&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the way home in the evening, a child suddenly stopped , said to the adults around him: Look at the sky, it’s so red. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The adult said: Don&#39;t look at it. You have to go home early to do your homework today. There will be a test tomorrow. Addition, subtraction, multiplication and division must be clarified today. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Did someone set fire to roast sweet potatoes in the sky? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was amused by the child&#39;s innocence, so I stopped and looked up at Huo Shaoyun. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Adults continue to criticize and educate children: You only know how to eat, that is when the sun sets and the sunshine turns the clouds red. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The child asked: Why wasn’t the sky so red when the sun set yesterday? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The adult said: It rained yesterday. Oops, why do you have so many questions? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It can be seen that the adult wants to try his best to fool the good child and let him go home to learn addition, subtraction, multiplication and division. Although the sky is beautiful at the moment, the adult does not have time to look at it. He is too busy and has taken good care of the child. He still has a lot to do. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The child was very disappointed by the education of the adults. Although he followed the adults, he still raised his head from time to time and looked at the sky in confusion. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was worried that a future great poet would be destroyed by busy parents, so I followed up and said to the child: There were monsters fighting in the sky, and the blood of the monsters dyed the clouds red. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The child was frightened by my answer and shouted: Dad, there is a monster. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;While the adult picked up the child and walked forward quickly, he did not forget to turn back and give me a blank look and said: I am sick. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In fact, many people are just like this grown-up who is tired of coping with life. They are &lt;strong>;too busy to think about things other than survival&lt;/strong>; and have no time to use their imagination. As time goes by, imagination becomes exhausted. No longer exists. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Killer 2: &lt;strong>;Blind Obedience to Prejudice&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I read Wang Xiaobo’s essay &quot;About Claustroenteric Novels&quot; online, I saw that the sentence &quot;&lt;strong>;The only misfortune in life is your own incompetence&lt;/strong>;&quot; was underlined by many people. Most of the people who underlined it were critical, and those who were not critical were just lying flat. What&#39;s wrong with me is just incompetent. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The reason for criticism is nothing more than that there are many kinds of misfortunes in life besides one&#39;s own incompetence, or one might argue that these misfortunes are not all caused by one&#39;s own incompetence, such as family of origin, natural and man-made disasters, etc. Some people even attacked Wang Xiaobo as a straight man in name only, and the books he wrote were nothing more than that. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These underlined comments successfully misled me, and I gave up reading this article. It was not until much later that I began to reflect after reading Wang Xiaobo&#39;s &quot;Searching for Wushuang&quot;. He is such an interesting, intelligent and imaginative writer. When he wrote that sentence, he must have expressed something else, and because of other people&#39;s misunderstanding, I I am biased and unwilling to imagine other possibilities. In the end, I miss the opportunity to understand a good article in the first place. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So I put aside my prejudice and re-read it, and finally found that what Wang Xiaobo’s sentence means when combined with the context is that there is no nightmare or prison that we cannot escape from. We must work hard and work hard. Only by thinking about the problem can you save yourself. There is only one misfortune in the world that cannot be escaped, and that is one&#39;s own incompetence. All other misfortunes can be escaped. Since you can get rid of it, there is no need to let yourself fall into this misfortune and talk about it over and over again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Why do readers feel offended when Wang Xiaobo satirizes claustrophobic novels? Why do claustrophobic readers who think they are incompetent and unfortunate suddenly appear in large numbers? I think it is also the collective imagination of the public that has grown rapidly in recent years. manifestation of loss. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Reading requires imagination. Without imagination, there is no way to enjoy the world built by the author with words. &lt;strong>;For people without imagination, literacy is just literacy. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Killer Three: &lt;strong>;Standard Answer&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Combined with Killer Two, we can see that in one sentence Can be interpreted in many different and even opposite answers. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Everyone imagines the answer based on their own experience, and ultimately forms a bias. If you don&#39;t discern and follow blindly, you will eventually lose your imagination, be trapped by the iron wall of prejudice, and even doubt whether there are other possibilities in life. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I have never believed in standard answers since I was a child. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some people say that being a writer will lead to poverty and suffering. I don’t believe it. I imagine a writer’s life to be interesting, meaningful, and joyful. In fact, it is indeed the case. The happiness level of people immersed in hobbies cannot be understood by people who only know how to make money. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some people say that low education means low quality, and high education means high quality. I don’t believe it. Education only represents how many years a person has been educated. It does not mean that the person has been taught to be cute and respectable. &lt;strong>;The academic qualifications in my imagination are the experience of learning, just like reading a lot of books. It is a process of enriching life, not a capital to show off. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are many &lt;strong>;so-called standard answers like this, which are killing our imagination step by step&lt;/strong>;, making us follow what others say and stay stuck in our ways. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Why are the elderly generally stubborn and children generally have a certain degree of imagination? It is because the elderly have heard too many standard answers. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Maybe we can’t change the result that our imagination will eventually be stifled, but we can slow down the process and try to maintain an empty cup mentality when facing people and things.&lt;strong>;When the standard answers disappear, Imagination is born. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Li Jialong onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see @ONE Studio’s pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpeR0h0SvASC3l3Ve3XoN3pkxB9z &quot; alt=&quot;Palace Master Ice&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Palace Master Ice&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;Weibo@宫主冰&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Writer, his representative work is &quot;No Way to Say Goodbye&quot;. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Question and Answer&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/question/3885&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;When your former idol fades away completely, will you still like him? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3876&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Why do young people start to &quot;break up&quot;? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3929)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[明天会更好]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6112]]><description> &lt;div>;27 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Su Gengsheng&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fj6QFsQrCfuIw1YtB2KjNF5KL4BK&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fj6QFsQrCfuIw1YtB2KjNF5KL4BK&quot;>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Stand on the steps built yesterday, do what you do today, and come tomorrow Before, we just had to think silently that tomorrow would be better. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The weather has cooled down. It is cool but not cold during this period. It is the best day in the city where I live. Every fall, I am usually busy for a few days with nothing more than trivial matters. Wash the summer clothes, put them in the closet, take out the coats, wax the floor, find someone to clean the windows, take a bath late at night, and finally lie in bed, with a warm body, a clean bed, and a pounding heartbeat. Lie in bed and read a book. If you can&#39;t fall asleep, you can&#39;t fall asleep. The wind outside the window is gradually picking up, and it is still a gentle whimpering at this moment. In winter, the wind will become louder in a while. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past few days, I feel that time is passing faster and faster, there are fewer and fewer things left in my memory, and life has entered a state of confusion. rhythm. As spring turns to winter, time is whizzing by. I vaguely remember certain moments, the day I took my first bite of watermelon, the day I put on my coat, the day I needed to cover myself tightly with the quilt at night. Year after year goes by like this, and I don’t know what is left in my life. I just feel at a loss. Looking around, there is no certainty. I just feel that it is not easy to live in a daze. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One day I was reading and saw someone saying something that Chinese psychology is actually social psychology. I thought about it immediately, this sentence is really wonderful. I am obsessed with writing about the subtleties of personal feelings, but I am not actually writing about me. Over the past few years, we have been connected by a common pain, and the bits and pieces we have written about it have meaning. But now, I feel tired, a kind of emptiness and exhaustion caused by going crazy with a vengeance. I am flustered by the passage of time. What on earth are we doing in our lives? Apart from adapting and resisting, do we still have our own lives? ? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I couldn’t find the answers to many questions, so I returned to doing trivial things in life. The weather got colder, so I put on a thick quilt, the rice jar was empty, and I bought this year&#39;s new rice and put it in. When it was time to eat, I cooked myself a bowl of hot soup. I felt like I was suffering silently at the bottom of the valley, waiting until exhaustion left my body. But no, years of fatigue almost destroyed me. I moved slowly and endured it silently. Even my anger disappeared. I just felt so tired. So I decided to forgive myself. This tired and silent me, maybe I should try to retreat in the autumn. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I thought about the saying &quot;knowing how to advance and retreat&quot;. In the past days, I only knew how to advance. Go for it, it doesn’t matter even if you fail. But what is retreat? I originally thought it was about giving up and pausing. Giving up when you don’t get what you want is wisdom. Maybe it’s about pausing and advancing when it’s time to advance. This is strategy. Until now, I don’t know what retreat is, but I’m trying to figure it out before winter. Just like moving forward, you also need to think clearly about retreating. Even if I give up, I have to convince myself why I gave up. Will I be able to gain peace and happiness after letting everything go? Obviously this is not the case. In life, there is only a moment of stability, and the most is a state of uncertainty and anxiety. Don’t look for stability in uncertainty, this is something I have learned over the years. If you are not sure, then you are not sure. If you cannot see the future clearly, then you cannot see clearly. Who can guarantee whether the future will be good or bad. But we must be prepared to accept the good and bear the bad. Perhaps this is knowing how to advance and retreat, understanding human limitations, accepting one&#39;s own uneasiness, and remaining calm in the gap between advancement and retreat. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past few years, I have liked a word called &quot;quiet energy&quot;. This is the wisdom of the ancients. Whenever something comes up, I pretend to be calm. Over time, I really have calmness, and I can cope with all changes by remaining unchanged. I pursue my own heart in everything, without asking for results. Outcomes are beyond our control, and neither are things in the world. We cannot decide the direction of things, nor can we predict the future path. We are wrapped in time. When the wind blows, the direction changes, but we don’t have to be afraid, stay calm, and try our best to live at our own pace. The seasons change, the wind blows in all directions, and we only go to our destination. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I am getting better now. Originally I thought I would go back to the darkness in the winter, but I am braver than I thought. I take care of myself and my days without saying a word, try my best to eat well and sleep well, not to fall into darkness when I wake up every day, not to be completely depressed before going to bed (I really can’t not be depressed at all), I&#39;m still waiting quietly, waiting for everything to get better. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I was very young, I watched many people singing on TV, saying with sincere blessings that tomorrow would be better. I was too young at that time and didn’t know how to sing. I know why people have expectations about whether tomorrow will be good or not. At that time, I felt that today was good enough, and as for tomorrow, never mind it. But now I understand, because today is so difficult, I can only have hope. So I also told myself that tomorrow will be better. If it is not better, then wait for the next tomorrow. This is not deception, but hope. Only in this way can we continue to wait. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Nana&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Su Gengsheng’s column &quot;At This Moment&quot; is updated exclusively on the &quot;ONE&quot; APP every two weeks on Wednesdays. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/Fg_e6teZsb3lZ1QStYtdnAkh6bO8&quot; alt=&quot;Su Gengsheng&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Su Gengsheng&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@ False Su Gengsheng&lt;/span >; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&quot;ONE·One&quot; resident writer. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/article/6088&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Autumn&#39;s pause button&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Su Gengsheng&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/div>; tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Read&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6070&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt; div>;Like a stone&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Su Gengsheng&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading &lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6034&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;The weather is not as expected&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Su Gengsheng&lt;/div >; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2 ,6112)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4008]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4144]]><description>&lt;div>;27 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FjiHgLZhUY-s66R7dFr5NOrpRgsR&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4008&lt;/span>;Photography | Annie Spratt&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;27&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sep. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&quot; Sometimes I worry that you will find out that I am actually very ordinary.&quot;&lt;br />;&quot;Love does not require you to be different.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>