<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[上香许愿的年轻人，在寻求什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3954]]><description> &lt;div>;24 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; xiang asked&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>;Those on What are the young people who make wishes seeking? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; xianganswer&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original- src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgUAyjCNXKLzBuZPvJi_LTmkZcor&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgUAyjCNXKLzBuZPvJi_LTmkZcor&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;Among young people, going to temples to burn incense and worship Buddha is becoming more and more popular. This year, the search index using temples as keywords has soared, and the number of ticket orders for temple scenic spots has also increased significantly. Nearly half of the people who booked temple tickets were born in the 1990s and 2000s. Young people do seem to fall in love with incense. In the Yonghe Temple in Beijing and the Lingyin Temple in Hangzhou, beside the incense burner in the early morning, the blue smoke disperses, and there are young faces bustling around. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What is difficult to understand here is that the era of technology and digitalization has not allowed people to leave the worship of religious theology under the wheel of rationality and scientific civilization. In ancient times, people&#39;s ignorance and inability to control the environment and destiny made them turn to the mysterious natural forces and the protectors of ethnic groups to seek a stable life. However, in the modern era of information circulation and advanced science and technology, they place their expectations for the future on Gods will inevitably appear absurd. Poor knowledge and production tools means relying on the mountains to eat the mountains. Villagers who rely on the sea to eat the sea must pray to nature with the most humble attitude. However, contemporary urban young people already have no shortage of scientific knowledge. They understand the development of religious history and geography. &lt;strong>;The&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;incense&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;on the temple&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;the&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;fire&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;is hot,&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;one&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;A possible explanation is that their prayers are not because they believe that their wishes will come true. In the /strong>;&lt;strong>;ritual, the young&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;man&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;seeks something else. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After receiving his undergraduate diploma, Qin Shanhe did not rush to find a job. Instead, he worked as a volunteer at Wuling Temple in Chengdu for a month. &amp;ldquo;I feel as if I have never faced anything particularly clearly. It seems to be very chaotic. Maybe I feel very clear at the moment when I make every decision, but when I look back after a while, I find that I am in a very chaotic state. Then I wondered if I could find inner peace in the temple, or if I could feel the present moment clearly. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is understandable that young people feel insecure. In rural society, farmers&#39; knowledge is transmitted orally and by heart, and their lives are highly repetitive. They work at sunrise and rest at sunset. We live in an era of advanced technology. Social media brings information explosion and social competition. Everyone is faced with choices from schooling, employment to daily life. Unknown risks are far beyond the control of individuals and may make them feel more Anxiety and loneliness. Many people turn their attention to temples because in the uncertainty of life, temples, statues, and incense burners are stable. When they close their eyes tightly and clasp their hands together, the inner river is calm. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As for faith and superstition, they are not that convinced. &lt;strong>;Burning&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;incense&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;worshiping Buddha is more like&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;one&lt;strong>;for many young&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;people&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; /strong>;&lt;strong>;A kind of religious ritual that is just a taste of&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;stop&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;and uses traditional prayer rituals to bless&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;oneself&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong >;, to combat the uneasiness of reality. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The temple gives people a sense of stability, not just in the incense ceremony. The architecture of the temple, the scale of the ancient pagoda, the wooden materials and the peeling fragments left by the mottled stone carvings carry time and resist time, and they are even the solidification of time itself. This is a field that resists the changes of time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Qin Shanhe recalled that when she felt peaceful in the temple, it was on a balcony facing the mountains and forests. A senior brother suddenly asked her if she had seen clouds. &amp;ldquo;I said I saw it, right on top of the tree. He said, have you seen clouds in your heart? I didn&#39;t understand it at first, but he didn&#39;t say anything and kept asking me repeatedly, &quot;Do you see clouds in your heart?&quot; Maybe I don’t understand that question now, but when I asked that sentence, I felt very calm, very calm. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a modern society where many feel disconnected from their traditions and roots, temples, incense burning and other religious rituals provide young people with a connection to their ancestors, culture and traditions Opportunity to reconnect. Although we live in an era of highly technological advancement, basic human needs – to find meaning, connection, comfort and belonging – still exist. In the temple, in some subtle movements, ancient rituals separate the restless heart from the uncontrollable anxiety of life, and regain the connection between people and their roots and their own bodies in traditional experiences. Qin Shanhe learned two words in the temple called &quot;Jue Guan&quot;. At first, her understanding was to perceive and then observe, until a senior brother taught her to practice &quot;walking&quot;. &quot;The posture is actually a bit strange. I closed my eyes and walked, and it seemed to be straight. Then Brother Meixia asked me, &quot;Do you feel your feet?&quot; &amp;rsquo;He asked me to put all my feelings on my big toes, then my heels, arms, calves... After the walk, my whole body was shocked. The calmness I felt at that moment was very strong. It makes people feel more peaceful than hearing the sound of knocking wooden fish and chanting sutras in the temple. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The world is huge and unknowable. For thousands of years, humans have been trying to grasp the world and combat the uncertainty of the universe in a philosophical or scientific way. Modern young people are sober. Nietzsche has already said &quot;God is dead.&quot; Burning incense and worshiping Buddha in the temple is not for a definite answer or a happy result. What the young people believe in is not gods. The faith holding incense candles may be what Spinoza calls the &quot;divine necessity&quot; bred in all things. With a sincere awe of the unknown, what they want to grasp is a sense of belonging connected to a cultural context, or just an inner firmness - in fact, when asking the question, the answer is already there&lt;/strong>; &lt;strong>;Own&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;’s&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Heart&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;s. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Li Jialong onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see @ONE Studio’s pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FsJ4zRKtgiPcZPX7NH9nY4eUAlFU &quot; alt=&quot;xiang&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;xiang &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Boring xiang Occasionally write some short words&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td >; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt;/td >; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3941&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What &quot;folk metaphysics&quot; have you seen? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3952&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What small decisions have you made that changed your life? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3954)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 06:25:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[情人如期相爱直到分开]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6141]]><description> &lt;div>;24 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Zhou Hongxiang&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data -author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FlyFJ_kv17uuQVkCStywXS_yK3Pe&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FlyFJ_kv17uuQVkCStywXS_yK3Pe&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the intersection between ideal and reality, there is no intimate relationship based on daily necessities. When love begins, From that moment they were destined to separate. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is always this kind of love, breaking up, making up, breaking up, making up again, coming and going, dividing and reuniting, starting over and over again, Two people go back and forth in a circle, today for this reason and tomorrow for that reason. The two people seem to regard love as a game. It seems that every time they break up and disconnect, there is always a turning point. It seems that every cold war is just to prove that the other party is still there. Love, love constantly consumes a lot of time between two people. Every time they reconcile, they can&#39;t help but wonder if this is the last time they reconcile. Is there a next time? Another time is absolutely impossible. . But there will always be a next time, as if time has never moved forward. Some couples have become accustomed to tolerance and tolerance, and have become tired, and quarreling has become a boring pastime. It’s not that they don’t want to, but they are lazy, but they still enjoy it. People who play the game between breaking up and reconciling are trying to show that love is still flexible, as if loose feelings are a kind of lack of love. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The most protracted long-distance relationship Xiaoxi has ever experienced was for four years, and then it turned into a foreign love. Going from a different place to a foreign country was like walking through an entire forest with great difficulty, only to find that there was another one in front of it. mountains. Compared with love in the same city, being in a different place will amplify all the worries of human emotions, as if an inadvertent neglect will become the original sin. What are you doing, why aren&#39;t you replying to my message, how could you not look at your phone, who are you with, why aren&#39;t you sleeping yet? A series of questions turned into some kind of pressure, and finally the trust between the two of them was smoothed and shattered, turning into shiny glass shards scattered on the floor. The biggest opponent in a long-distance relationship is not the lover, but oneself. Internal friction is everywhere, and emotions come back intermittently. When the emotions are high, they will really provoke the relationship themselves. When do you have to regard love as everything you have? At this time, you can feel a strong sense of security when the other person is next to you, but across the screen, everything becomes cold. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xiaoxi was originally a teacher in her boyfriend&#39;s TOEFL training class. When Xiaoxi was 25 years old, she was with 20-year-old Lex. At that time, Xiaoxi completely thought that as long as the other person pampered her enough, she would have the most perfect love. Quarreling is a very normal thing. Maybe because of the slightest dissatisfaction, Xiaoxi will find fault with Lex for being inconsiderate in the relationship. Lex has not had a good relationship with his sister, but he is very serious about learning that he should take responsibility in love. Responsibility, care, care, tolerance, love. At that time, Lex was about to go to the United States for a short period of time on exchange. Fortunately, the time was not long, and there was plenty of time to come back. Just like what Miriam Yeung sang in &quot;The Rare Guest&quot;: Why are boys so virtuous, unable to bear the cessation of desire? Being young should be willful, going out should be fun, and being in love is like driving across the border. After Lex went to the United States, he couldn&#39;t help but be tempted and met a younger girl. His love, which seemed to be in danger, was saved under Xiaoxi&#39;s forced control. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That was the first time Xiaoxi proposed breaking up. Lex immediately realized the seriousness of the problem and the shelf life of love was still there. He immediately bought a plane ticket from the United States and rushed back overnight to seek peace. Xiaoxi chose to avoid seeing her. After prolonging the cold period, Lex stood under Xiao Xi all night, and finally impressed Xiao Xi with his sincerity. This was a breakup that forced the relationship between the two to warm up. At least it made Xiaoxi realize that he loved her and could immediately buy a high-priced ticket to come back to see her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The most affectionate time I have seen them was when Xiaoxi leaned on Lex and said she wanted a glass of milk. Lex actually went downstairs and bought a carton of pure milk and came back and poured it into the cup. , heated in a microwave and served to her. In what we think is Xiaoxi&#39;s &quot;work&quot; and Lex&#39;s &quot;passing&quot;, the two have reached a certain balance. Then for a long time, Lex returned to Chengdu, while Xiaoxi was in Chongqing. The less than two-hour high-speed rail journey made this love that seemed to be in a different place but actually not far away move in a better direction. Distance creates beauty, and each has its own uniqueness. Each has its own space and the freedom to live its own life. When I want to, I just need a high-speed rail ticket and put more energy into my work every day. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But love that seems to be calm and step-by-step is often turbulent. Xiaoxi always has troubles at work, and her daily life also has Lex&#39;s blind spots. Because they don&#39;t live together, they often talk to each other. The two of them chat with each other at different frequencies intermittently. Aries women have the drive to talk when they have something to say. , but the Libra man has always been practicing Tai Chi in self-tangle. This accumulation of subtle contradictions finally broke out on a large scale one day. Xiaoxi thought that Lex didn&#39;t understand her. She didn&#39;t know why she wanted to have a long-distance relationship. Why? You can&#39;t find a boy in Chongqing to get married and have children, but you have to spend time with a brother who is six years younger than you. Lex&#39;s immaturity in relationships will eventually use his considerate ways to make Xiaoxi change his mind. If you feel that the frequency is different, then I will listen to you. If you feel that you want me to be by your side, I will appear in front of you immediately, Lex Too young, he thinks that the solution in all love is &quot;together&quot;, and &quot;together&quot; seems to be the most powerful cardiotonic. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But is this true? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two people will still quarrel, have discord, and question whether they love each other enough, but they seem to be learning in this relationship and how to love each other. Breaking up, making up, breaking up, and making up again, each time within a week, the two of them are like a new couple, forgetting the past, it’s not that Aries women don’t like to hold grudges, but they value the present more, as long as you still love me , I am willing to move forward. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But as time went by, Xiaoxi began to think deeply about the nature of love. Of course, companionship is the foundation, but on a deeper level, partners have the ability to solve problems. Being together is not the way to solve problems, but it can really help. She sees the essence of life clearly. Young boys will give you sweet things, but this kind of sweetness is just a spice in life. When Lex was about to finish his four years of college, the problem really emerged. He had to work, make money, and officially enter the society. When he was still in school, he would go to Chongqing every weekend to sing, sing, play board games and play scripts with Xiaoxi. When he was thinking about which city he wanted to work in and how to take a step forward, Xiaoxi of course She unconditionally supported his progress, but Lex said, if I decide to go to the United States to work at my dad&#39;s company for two years and then come back, can you wait for me? This question made Xiaoxi a little overwhelmed. The parting came so suddenly and unexpectedly. She originally thought that he would at most find a decent job in a foreign company in Chengdu, but she did not expect that he would decide to go to the United States. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What can we do? The domestic employment situation is not good, Xiaoxi has reached the marriageable age again, and her family is asking a lot of questions. After four years of dating, whether they should get married or not, given Lex&#39;s current situation, the marriage may have to be postponed again. After meeting Xiaoxi&#39;s family, Lex gave Xiaoxi enough confidence. He said that after he went to the United States to work hard for two years, he would marry Xiaoxi when he came back. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Because they have had experience in foreign countries before, the two of them did not feel out of place. Because of the time difference, Xiaoxi always got up and got ready for work, while Lex was about to fall asleep after a busy day. The frequency of their videos is not high, and they are still very decent in that they only pursue quality and not quantity. Two years can be said to be a long time or a short time, and summer turns to winter in the blink of an eye. Half a year has passed. At a wine party one day, Xiaoxi was still praising Lex to his friends that he had matured a lot. Compared to four years, The boy before who had never seen the colorful world outside, he finally began to take responsibility, but he just wanted to think about it in his own mind, and it was really not appropriate to say it out loud. Xiaoxi had just returned home after drinking when she received a call from Lex overseas. Lex collapsed and said that he hoped the two of them would end it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The breakup came so suddenly just because Lex felt that he couldn&#39;t hold on anymore. Working in the United States was more stressful than he imagined, a strange environment, no close friends, a lover who couldn&#39;t hug him, and a long time. After getting off work, I returned to my closed home and looked at the bustling lights of Manhattan, but it had nothing to do with him. Lex suddenly said that he felt a lot of pressure when he thought about getting married after returning to China. He fell into a panic about the relationship between two people who could not see each other for a long time. Xiaoxi comforted him earnestly, hoping that he would wake up from the comfort, but Lex&#39;s willingness to break up was so determined that Xiaoxi had to suspect that he had met someone new in the United States. The distrust between the two people once again amplified. After a burst of rage, Xiaoxi said, whatever you want, do whatever you want. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The cold war has been a normal way for the two of them to deal with it, but this time it lasted longer than usual. Xiaoxi didn’t wait for Lex’s apology, and Lex didn’t wait for Xiaoxi’s sue for peace. Late at night, the two of them They are all analyzing their long-term relationship with their friends and have never really lived together. Marriage will be a greater test for the two of them. Lex cannot imagine it and can only admit defeat. Xiaoxi called him one afternoon when she couldn&#39;t help but told Lex very rationally that she could give up her job and go to the United States to be with him. The two of them could start over and everything could go back to the beginning. When Xiaoxi made up his mind to save this relationship, Lex only replied, &quot;Why bother?&quot; Although you don&#39;t say it, you always feel that I am naive in your heart. Now I am twenty-three and you are twenty-nine. In fact, we have always wanted different things. Just admit it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xiaoxi couldn&#39;t believe that the boy she had loved for more than four years finally dismissed her with just &quot;I&#39;m tired&quot;, just like she couldn&#39;t believe that when she looked back on the love between the two, she never They lived through any episode of firewood, rice, oil, salt, sauce, vinegar and tea, but only endless food, drink and fun. They found the balance of love in their happy life, but they never thought about this kind of relationship that is not based on material foundation. From the beginning, Shaky. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xiaoxi packed up the things that Lex left at her home and sent them to the United States. When asking for the address, she found that Lex had deleted her. A friend shared Lex’s depressed playlist with Xiaoxi, but Xiaoxi didn’t listen at all. He didn&#39;t care about those bullshit songs. When Lex uploaded photos of watching the sea at the beach, Xiaoxi had already fallen asleep peacefully. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xiao Xi said that I despise this man, how could he be so cowardly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two days later, Xiaoxi wondered why he still hadn’t grown up after so long? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xiao Xi wants a mature relationship, a love that takes care of her but can also take responsibility for her, but does such a luxury exist in the world? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lex added Xiaoxi back the night she was drunk. He typed several lines on his phone and deleted them all. After thinking about it, he didn’t know how to start. Speaking of those words, whether to redeem or formally say goodbye, I didn&#39;t want the relationship to end unclearly, but in the end, Lex could not find a natural beginning to the paragraph, so he simply deleted Xiaoxi again. In the minute when they were most likely to get back together, Lex finally chose to leave quietly. He looked at all the photos of Xiaoxi and him, carefully looking at each one several times. He was still too young, and he just wanted He wants sweet company, wants to see her acting coquettishly and pretending to be angry, wants the surprise of being able to appear next to her right away with a ticket, but he can&#39;t do this anymore, the company&#39;s various reports need to be handed in tomorrow. He also has to prepare for an important meeting the next day. He hasn&#39;t learned anything yet and is afraid that he will make mistakes at work. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Winter in Chongqing is coming again. When she gets up in the morning, Xiaoxi is going to find some thick clothes to wear. When she was going through the cabinet, she found that the scarf Lex gave her last Christmas was still hanging there. The big brand&#39;s logo was clearly printed on it. She had obviously not worn it twice. She remembered that it was Lex&#39;s pocket money given to him by his father. He saved it and bought it. At that time, he still had enough living expenses to take her to stay in expensive hotels and see the best night views. But she clearly didn&#39;t want these. She just wanted to take him home to meet her parents and hear his seriousness. It&#39;s enough to say that you want to marry her. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Li Jialong&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see @ONE Studio’s pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FnG6mnVK6opY4g75Tw-7h415dwbd&quot; alt=&quot;zhouhongxiang&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;zhou hongxiang&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@zhouhongxiang&lt;/span>; &lt; /div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Young writer, representative works &quot;Famous Fair&quot; and &quot;They Are Burning&quot;&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot; OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6123&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Crazy Love Practice&lt; /div>; &lt;div>;Text/ Zhou Hongxiang&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td >; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6095&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Memory is often in vain&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Zhou Hongxiang&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Read&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6079&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot; >; &lt;div>;Breakup is a galloping return&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Zhou Hongxiang&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt; td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6141)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt; /table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 06:25:08 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4035]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4176]]><description>&lt;div>;24 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FkJm1ZKh2NyZ-V-z4prFyaGT17j6&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4035&lt;/span>;Photography | Daiga Ellaby&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;24&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oct. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p >;Don’t ask me what my plan is: Breathing, doesn’t it count as one? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot; color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 06:25:08 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>