<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[你的「长远之物」是什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3915]]><description> &lt;div>;20 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Question from ONE Editorial Department&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>; What is your “long-term thing”? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; ONE Friendly Answers&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FqG5f9aRJpd8cEDTRtwfmP3SYhn-&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FqG5f9aRJpd8cEDTRtwfmP3SYhn-&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style =&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Everyone must have something &quot;long and far&quot; that belongs to him. If everything in his life, Positioning is all temporary, including temporary career, temporary interpersonal relationships, and temporary food, clothing, housing, and transportation, and his heart cannot be at peace. &lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;Good Xie Xiang&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;I will always support Bayern Munich. I started to like Bayern from the age of 7 when I watched football with my dad, and before I knew it, I was already a 20-year-old Bayern fan. Even though I can&#39;t watch every game now due to work reasons, I always spend part of my day paying attention to the latest news about Bayern. I think it has become an inseparable part of my life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@Kujira&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;You are still young It&#39;s not big enough, and I can&#39;t think of anything that can definitely be &quot;long-term&quot;. If I have to say, maybe it’s just curiosity about everything. If you lose your curiosity about the world, life is just waiting to be wasted time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@西川&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jay Chou s song. When I was a child, I listened to the tapes she bought over and over again at my cousin&#39;s house. Now I go to listen to Jay Chou&#39;s concerts all over the country. Unknowingly, I have liked it for nearly twenty years. It is really a long-term thing that spans most of my life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@duolemei-&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Now I rarely read anymore. But I will never forget &quot;How the Steel Was Tempered&quot;. I read it many times when I was a child, and I thought Paul was really awesome. I was in adolescence when I read &quot;The Diary of Anne Frank&quot; and bought it with my little pocket money. At one point she shed tears. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@Amber didn’t meet the little bug&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;Running. The only habit that has persisted for many years. Now, except when it rains, I run for about half an hour every day. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@hottydog&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fishing. I’m talking about my dad. Apart from eating and sleeping, he basically sits and fishes by the river in the park every day. It feels like he has really dedicated his body and soul to the river. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@Lucy is not a babydog&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Esaon&#39;s singing has accompanied me through many stages in my life and given me a lot of strength when I needed it. I listen to it during breaks at school and on the subway when commuting to work. Going to see his concert with my roommates in college is also the best memory. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@ VeteranRiven&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;The small gold pendant given to me by my grandpa has been worn for more than 20 years. Now I occasionally see it when washing, and it reminds me of my grandpa. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@sssyi&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grandma put Family photo album in the closet. In the past, when I went home to visit her during the winter and summer vacations, my grandma would take out this photo album and look at the photos of my childhood with me. Later, when I was working out of town, my mother started to take out our family photo albums when she came home during the Chinese New Year and reminisce about the past with me. I think that one day in the future I will do the same thing as them. The time and memories contained in a photo album will be my long-term possessions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@Candy&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ginkgo tree. When I was eight years old, the school organized a voluntary tree planting event, and I planted a ginkgo tree. Somehow I felt that my fate was entwined with the fate of the tree, and I visited it often. Later, it grew into a big tree. When I was in a bad mood, I would go there and lean against the tree in a daze. I even told it about my troubles. Gradually, I felt that it was not only a friend, but also another form of me in the world. Ginkgo can even live for thousands of years, and it can stay with me for a lifetime. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@ Midnight Visitor&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Previously It was music, then it was movies, then it was a stable weekend break, and now I find that it is having a good body. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@在线 shopping 小savvy&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Parental encouragement. As I got older, I suddenly discovered that every time I felt like giving up on something, it was my parents’ encouragement that gave me the strongest support. This would be the most important thing for me. In the long run, I will even pass it on to my children. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@a piece of fried pork chop&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; For me, it&#39;s &quot;growing young&quot;. Because I think the character Fa Xiao is a person who exists in the overlapping area of ​​kinship and social relationships. There are many things you can’t say to your family, not even to your lover, or to your children, but you can tell them about novels. For many things, friends will mind, colleagues will mind, and even family members will mind even more, but Fa Xiao will understand. Sometimes I feel that Fa Xiao is like the NPC who dominates your plot line in the game. No matter how far you run on the map, he will be there when you come back. No matter how many levels you have upgraded, he still has the same tone towards you. . Growing up makes people feel at ease, growing up makes people feel relaxed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@los santo modified car king&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;A person&#39;s beliefs, such as promoting the rule of law and seeking freedom. There are so many things you can do as a lifelong career. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@ a worker in a law firm in Beijing&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Language learning, even the mother tongue, can be learned endlessly, and can be regarded as a hobby and fixed as a part of life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@Polyhedron&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fitness. As long as you persist, satisfaction will fill every corner of your life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;@hasaki&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt; /div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Li Jialong onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For information about the call for papers, please see the @ONE Studio pinned on Weibo. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8 &quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Complex The cutest people in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3910&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Do you really want to resign? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3912&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;How to face dissatisfaction with yourself? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3915)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[他去买肯德基]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6096]]><description> &lt;div>;20 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;文／西瓜&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FiWPNmYRXA8KR5XnTR2Wp3g3mQ_S&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FiWPNmYRXA8KR5XnTR2Wp3g3mQ_S&quot;>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Due to a chance Internet connection, a married man met a mysterious woman. Marriage is like working at the bottom of the sea for these people, and they need a break to breathe fresh air. In this article, Ximai uses a large number of environments, trivial matters and dialogues to create a confused and peaceful situation for everyone, and brings the character&#39;s perspective into the experience. Ordinary and want to make waves, everyone is nailed to the cross with red and white rose thorns for others to examine. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was going to buy two hamburger sets, but adding ice to the Coke would be too cold, so he would not add ice. Anyway, he just ate a lot of boxes. She ordered small watermelons for takeout. We were probably not too thirsty, so we just ordered them a la carte. She just said she was a little hungry, her tone full of complaints, so he volunteered, got up from the bed, and went downstairs to buy something to eat. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was not familiar with this area, so she pointed it out to him in detail using the map on her mobile phone. Here, there, the traffic lights, People&#39;s Square, and the Liberation Monument, it sounded like it only took a few turns and it was not far away. Originally, there was a snack street downstairs of the hotel, with a row of rice noodles, beef noodles and spicy hotpot, but at 1:30 in the morning, only KFC was still open. She wasn&#39;t sure. She said she didn&#39;t come here often, but he could tell she was lying. The hotel&#39;s WIFI connected automatically, and it wasn&#39;t surprising to her that the bathroom shower had hot and cold settings reversed. He had no desire to expose it, and it was still very early before dawn. , when he came back after buying food, they still had plenty of time to communicate. On the premise of not sleeping, of course he had no intention of sleeping. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before going out, he asked her if she was going. She turned over on the bed and patted her exposed thighs from under the quilt. Those two thighs were so slender that they were consistent with her calves. When he pressed up and stroked her up and down, it felt like he was holding someone&#39;s ankle. He was too rough. After all, she was too thin. He might have hurt her, pulled a tendon, or sprained her hip after all the tossing, but she would still be unable to get out of bed. He found reasons for her and tried to understand her as much as possible, a stranger he met for the first time. He suddenly felt ridiculous and said to her, you are so lazy. She laughed loudly, leaning on her elbows and crawling to the bedside. There was her black rectangular handbag, covered with diamond patterns. He recognized the brand, it was from Issey Miyake, and his wife also had it. Before the quarrel last month, he spent three Bought for her for fifteen hundred dollars. She took out a cigarette from it. He didn&#39;t like smoking, but he pretended to have this need and asked her for one. She handed it to him, turned on the lighter, and lit the flame for him. Then he leaned against the bed, folded his arms, adjusted his smoking posture, and turned on the TV. There were some movies on demand on the channel, some of which they had discussed passionately on Douban. He looked at the thigh that was still outside the quilt, and wanted to ask her to put on some clothes. After a while, he would knock on the door. The door was at the end of the corridor, the most hidden one, but there was a black surveillance camera on the ceiling of the door frame. He was afraid of her. was photographed naked. He couldn&#39;t be so considerate and caring. There was no need for it. He took a puff of his cigarette and let her see it. She responded with a smile and chose a European movie on Chesil Beach. After leaving the door, he threw the cigarette he had only taken a puff into into the trash can close to the wall of the corridor. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The pedestrians on the road seemed to evaporate in an instant. When checking in, the streets were bustling with people. He was surprised by the prosperity of this small county. She couldn&#39;t stop talking like a tour guide. Introduce your hometown. She welcomed his arrival, and he was like a surprise seed dropped from the air, taking root deeper and deeper step by step. Looking at the empty city again, the dim light from the street lamps enveloped his looming shadow. It followed him, crouching on the dark pink tiles that looked the same on all city sidewalks. He was in a daze, like an ordinary walk after dinner. He walked a little faster. His wife was holding the golden retriever Lele who liked to defecate in the grass. If he took a few more steps, the accusations from his wife would follow, and he would not There is no real care or concern. He turned around and saw a taxi with an unfamiliar license plate approaching from the end of the road, honking its horn at him, Xiang J. Only then did he regain his composure. He looked at his phone. At 1:50, he opened the map and entered KFC. The nearest one was 1.3 kilometers away. Even though she had shown him the detailed route with her fingers, he didn&#39;t trust her. He never trusted anyone and just said, &quot;Okay, okay.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He walked out of the snack street, passed by a gold shop, a small supermarket, and a fruit shop, and stood at the crossroads. According to the navigation prompts, he should walk towards the upper left. There is a Home Inn on the diagonal side of the road with a very eye-catching yellow sign. When he and his wife travel, they often stay in Home Inns. Because the prices are relatively cheap, they can invest more money in travel and buy local specialties. The key is local beer. His father-in-law likes to drink beer and claims to drink beer here. He has drank special beers all over the country in his life, and his wife and he have been helping to realize it. He also thinks it is very meaningful. Every time he goes on a business trip, he still thinks about beer. Maybe before flying back tomorrow, he would buy two bottles of local specialty beer at the airport supermarket and send them back. He comforted himself, feeling that he was doing well to a certain extent. My wife is saving money in other aspects, and she has secretly saved a sum of money. It cannot be said that she is secretly. She will hint that she has some money, which is reserved for the future. It sounds like a rainy day plan that is too realistic, and she also buys Some insurances, serious illness for the elderly, peace of mind and accidents, including business trip insurance for him who often travels abroad. He always nodded expectantly and had a full sense of participation, even though he didn&#39;t think about the future at all and felt it was meaningless. His wife thought about it I had already thought about it. They don&#39;t have sex at the Home Inn. In her opinion, it&#39;s just a place to rest and settle down after a day of fun, so that they can continue to visit some internet celebrity check-in spots the next day. She even prepared a travel sleeping bag, spread it out on the bed, and crawled into it. She said, do you know what kind of person sleeps in this bed, how many people have slept with it, and how do you know whether underwear has been boiled in the hot water kettle? He nodded and agreed with her, his agreement almost becoming his character. After his wife went to bed, he tossed and turned next to the sleeping bag, looking at the woman who was binding him like a silkworm chrysalis. His body became inexplicably hot. He climbed out of bed, went to the bathroom and sat on the toilet, anxiously searching for short videos and some explicit scenes. The hint of brushing aside aroused his unspeakable depression. Frosted glass partitions, pink tiles, residual water droplets on the tiles, heavy and restrained breathing, he finished quickly, turned off his phone, closed his eyes, fantasizing about another woman lying on the bed, immersed in the few minutes after orgasm in the aftermath. Then he tiptoed back and climbed into bed, purring as he pretended to fall asleep earlier than she did in the sleeping bag. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The phone prompted a voice prompt, please turn around here and go straight for 500 meters. He had already passed the intersection and was standing in front of the Home Inn. He leaned forward and looked inside. The waitress was lowering her head at the front desk, sorting something. There was a thick glass door between them. He thought for a moment, pushed the door open and stood in front of the service desk. The waitresses were not pretty, but their makeup was very delicate, as if they had just been put on before the night shift, but they all looked the same, making it hard to remember, probably because of their uniforms. The waitress asked him what he needed. There were not many rooms left, only one double room and one standard room. He seemed to have forgotten what he came out to do. He looked through the glass door again, looked at the intersection, and asked her, can your kettle cook underwear? The waitress suddenly became embarrassed, at a loss and unable to answer. She seemed to have never encountered such a situation. In fact, he didn&#39;t either. He turned around and looked at the changing red numbers on the elevator screen at the end of the hotel, 4, 3, 2, 1. The door was open, but there was no one there. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She sent a message and asked where he was. She was starving to death. He just continued walking towards KFC, and the waitress welcomed him to visit next time. He suddenly felt that what his wife said might be right, because the embarrassing expression of the waitress just now showed the truth of the matter. He was also glad that he was not trying to take advantage. He was currently living in the Furman Hotel, which was thirty floors high. Xiaoli was lying in the room at the end of the corridor on the seventeenth floor, without any clothes on, waiting for him to buy back the hamburger. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They met in the Douban group. The name of that group is Can’t Sleep What Are You Doing? There was no need for review when he entered. Xiaoli was going crazy, posting topic after topic. He was curious about how explosive she was. She patiently responded to each topic with her emotions. Just out of curiosity, she actually exposed herself on the Internet during a sleepless night. Xiaoli, 27 years old, lives in a small county in a third-tier city. She experienced a disgusting love relationship that ended with the man engaging in prostitution. She regards emotions as an invisible physical disease. She tries to operate on herself at night when she can&#39;t sleep, and invests in it. A closed bar has a litter of puppies in the backyard, which can barely provide food and clothing. He added her as a friend, and she unexpectedly made a voice call and scolded the man. He just listened without any wrong thoughts. At that time, he was still trying to squeeze into the sleeping bag wrapped around his wife, trying to occupy a warm space. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He replied to Xiaoli&#39;s message and was almost there. She replied, what did you do at Home Inn just now? He was suddenly startled and turned on his cell phone in a panic to search for my friends. Xiaoli&#39;s head was hanging above the three-dimensional sign of Furman Hotel. This was his initiative to make it easier for him to get off the plane and find her. He calmed down and replied, &quot;I went to the toilet.&quot; She replied, Oh. He had thought about it. If she asked again, he would go to the waitress and ask her to testify that he didn&#39;t do anything in the Home Inn. He had no one there and no one else. But Xiaoli didn&#39;t reply. . Yes, how could she be like his wife. He calmed down and continued walking, and sent another message to Xiaoli, two beef burgers, a large potato, a corn cup, Coke hurts the body, let me see if there is anyone selling water. He continued to walk a few steps, and the message came back, Xiaoli said, whatever you want. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2008, Beijing held the Olympic Games. He and his wife were both in school and found out that the school was selecting volunteers who could go to the Olympic venue. She had never been to Beijing and felt that the opportunity was rare, so she asked him for help. He asked her relatives who were teachers in schools. The selection criteria could be changed, but height was a mandatory requirement. He replied to her, and regretfully, the relationship became familiar. She is not tall, but she is very lively and always jumps like a bird. They went as tourists during the holidays, and he accompanied her around the Water Cube, Bird&#39;s Nest, and Wukesong Stadium until late at night. They excitedly ended the day&#39;s trip and stayed in a small hotel in the alley. The small hotel was already of the best standard. She didn&#39;t care what was in the kettle. She immediately drank half of it, then took off her clothes and lay on the bed. He stood stiffly, as if he was about to participate in some sport, and everything was ready. Come on, she said, if you can&#39;t be a volunteer, then we&#39;ll be mobilizers. He was amused by her, suddenly felt itchy all over his body, and immediately climbed into bed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He didn&#39;t think about it anymore. He kind of hated the sticky and familiar feeling in the long river of history. There is no sense of intimacy in the environment around him now, and the unfamiliarity he sees is swallowing up his original feelings bit by bit. He should no longer think of anything from the past. The part of his brain that belongs to the memory of the original world should shut down, completely. Downtime. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There were many people in KFC. He stood in line behind three young people. It had been about ten years since he last bought fast food. After getting married, his wife did not allow him to eat it. If the person in front moves one step, he will move one step. When it was his turn, the waiter indicated that he could order food using his mobile phone. He looked up at the numbers on the electronic screen and was told that the meal code was called. He looked at it in surprise and asked the waiter, is the KFC here so high-end? The waiter said it was the same across the country. He put away his surprise and felt that he was very rude just now. He imagined that if he lived here, he would like to eat KFC every day. As far as the current feeling was concerned, he was happy. The meal he ordered has been packed, and the Coke has been replaced with bubble milk tea. He sent a message to Xiaoli, saying that he had bought it and would go back immediately. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He walked back quickly. This road was more familiar than before. The streets had been modeled in his mind. His pace became steady and fast. When he passed by the Home Inn, he didn&#39;t even look at it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When the door opened, she was indeed standing naked, looking at him up and down, making him feel very embarrassed even though he was wearing clothes. I thought you were flying back, she joked. He smiled, which I couldn&#39;t bear to part with. What else do you want to do? she says. He thought for a while and said, I still want to do it. She laughed, took the packing bag, turned around and walked to the bed. Her butt is narrow, her skin is fair, her back is well-defined and full of bones. He followed up and patted her butt, and she turned her head and rolled her eyes at him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They have never had a formal meal together, and he is not here to eat. They both understand that eating is just to replenish energy and maintain passion. He now suddenly wanted to know more about her. After that voice call, she deleted all the topics. When he asked about those bits and pieces of real life again, she said that she was drunk at the time and just made up the story. The more mysterious she was, the more infinitely attractive she was. He saw her sitting on the edge of the bed, twisting her legs together like two snakes, with a small black mass at the corner and two pointed breasts upturned. She took a sip of milk tea and wanted to say something, but didn&#39;t, and then ate French fries. The movie is already halfway through, and the male and female protagonists are quarreling. They have seen it many times thousands of miles apart. People who love each other eventually part ways, and the tumor of love cannot be cured. What&#39;s your name? he asks. The question was asked directly, and the real name was like a key that could twist each other away. Xiaoli swallowed the fries and said, My name is Hu Lili, what, do you want to marry me? He didn&#39;t expect her to say that, and he said, yes. My bride price is very expensive, she said. Is a meal of KFC enough? he asks. Hu Qian picked up the fries and threw them at him. He seemed to see her smile, and they both knew it was nonsense. He also thought, who knows if she has a husband. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He waited for her quietly, and she ate a lot, finishing both burgers. He hadn&#39;t eaten anything, he wasn&#39;t hungry, and he was getting more and more anxious as he waited. She noticed it, adjusted the bed, and tried to pull him to lie down. She also took out two cigarettes, but she didn&#39;t light them. He kept staring at her without clothes, and he felt a little tired of looking at her. He turned his eyes to her face, and a strange feeling came over him. He looked at her bangs and eyes, her nose and mouth. He didn&#39;t know how to describe it. He had never seen it before. He was just venting and it was not very good at all. Care about what she looks like. Now, as he undressed, he stared at her face, getting serious. After a long time, he came to the conclusion that she was a living person, and he was frightened by this conclusion. Do you have a wife? she asked. He trembled all over, and his pants seemed to be moving up again. Who has that thing, he answered immediately. She chuckled, how many have you talked about? He is very good at this question. He and his wife have talked about one, but he always talks about seven or eight on social platforms, and then makes up a bunch of romantic, sad, pitiful and embarrassing plots. He doesn’t want to let Others think he is very simple, and his experience is too simple, so simple that it makes him false. He said, seven or eight, just women. Hu Lili giggled, you liar, she pointed at his crotch. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was a little angry. He was making up a series of names in his mind to prove that the seven or eight women he had had were real. He even made up occupations for them, such as nurses, doctors, Teachers, civil servants, new employees of street offices, online ride-hailing drivers, etc. But he seemed to find that this was not what she suspected, and he didn&#39;t want to continue. Then I&#39;ll go, he said. OK, then go, she said. He got dressed and stood in front of the bed. She lit one of the cigarettes and held it between her fingers. They all watched the cigarette butts burning and the smoke drifting away seductively. He couldn&#39;t bear it, he muttered a few unformed words, took off his clothes and rushed forward. He was determined to fight a tough battle. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Same as the previous time, he felt good about himself, Hu Lili was not interested, and the two of them were a little bored afterward. He took the initiative to take out a cigarette from her Issey Miyake&#39;s handbag, and then leaned on the bed to smoke. Just now he felt his finger was pinched, so he went back to take it out again and took out her ID card. Her name is Wang Li and she is seven years younger than him. She grabbed the ID card and said, what are you doing! He said he quit, he was tired. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He could guess that she was a liar, so he didn&#39;t show too much surprise. He actually didn&#39;t care what her name was, and he wasn&#39;t going to marry her. Of course, he was also a liar himself. He felt that this was really tiring. He thought about it and asked her, have you ever been to this hotel with anyone else? She said, no. He then asked, does the kettle in this hotel not boil underwear? She smiled and said, what are you thinking about. At this moment, he had already lit a cigarette for himself, handed another one to Wang Li, and said, at least it had the word &quot;丽&quot; in it. Wang Li laughed and said, I searched for you. My wife works in a government agency from nine to five, but you, running around, don&#39;t have much achievements. He said, you were pitiful at first, but I really believed you. Wang Li said, who is not pitiful? He went on to say that the dog was real and the boyfriend&#39;s prostitution was fake. Wang Li said that the dog is fake, the cat is real, the boyfriend&#39;s prostitution is fake, and the ex-husband&#39;s prostitution is real. He touched the cigarette held in Wang Li&#39;s fingers with the cigarette handle and said, &quot;I don&#39;t have any wine, so I&#39;ll make do with it.&quot; Saoirse Ronan was having her last argument with her boyfriend on the beach. The wind brought the fog, the waves shrank, and the waves became dull. Wang Li turned off the TV and stopped the argument on the coast. She said, how many movies have we watched together? He didn&#39;t take out his phone and opened Douban to confirm. He casually said that there were about sixty or so. Wang Li said, of the eighty-seven films, two of them have not been finished. You said you had an impromptu meeting, so I guess your wife is looking for you. He didn&#39;t reply. Only the flames of cigarette butts were burning in the room, like two stars hanging in the sky. Wang Li continued to say, just keep on vacation, how can there be so much meaning? After today, it is just past today, and it is just past today. He agreed with this point. Looking at Wang Li leaning on the bedside, he felt that she was gradually becoming more three-dimensional, but the fear that came with this shattering of strangers quickly expanded. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After smoking the cigarette, he walked into the bathroom and closed the door. The sound insulation effect was surprisingly good. He turned on the shower and sat on the toilet. The bathroom decoration style of this hotel is very cold. The walls are made of gray tiles with dark patterns. The showerhead and faucet are all black. The bath towels and towels are placed on the holder. They are still unused and are clean and tidy. He closed his eyes while listening to the sound of rushing water, and thought of another woman lying on the bed outside the door. This woman also went from blurry to three-dimensional, and then blurry again. Finally, he unexpectedly thought of his wife, and was shocked. , opened his eyes and looked at his phone. At 3:26, he realized that he was very tired and wanted to crawl back into bed and sleep for a while. He continued to click on his phone, and there were several messages sent by his wife in the evening. His plane had not yet landed at that time. He was thinking of replying a few words, but he fell asleep before he could think of the content. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When he woke up again, he was already lying on the bed. Wang Li got dressed and dressed herself up in front of the mirror. She put on lipstick and powder, and was putting on contact lenses for herself. She stretched out one of her eyelids. He stood up, his eyes were round inside, and he looked a little scared. Why are you going? he asked her. I&#39;m working, why don&#39;t you support me, she said. After she put on the clothes, she didn&#39;t look particularly thin, but was somewhat substantial. She was now a real person. His conclusion was more firm. She was even a little good-looking. He couldn&#39;t tell. It wasn&#39;t the difference between wearing makeup or not, but probably her age. question, he thought. He took a nap and his mind became clearer. He said, are you mine now? She turned around and said, what are you thinking about? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He pulled back and leaned on the bed to look at her. He felt quite happy. He was trying to think of a way to keep this feeling of pleasure for a long time. The only way was possible. It&#39;s just a divorce. After he had this idea, the first thing he thought of was his father-in-law. He thought that he would still buy wine when traveling and deliver it to his home. Wouldn&#39;t it be childish? He doubted himself. Judging from the fact that he has only been in love once, he will not take the initiative to consider divorce. There is no such thing as a breakup in his concept. He is completely unable to cope with it. But now that he is being pulled by a stranger, he has no desire to go back. . He just thought of a way to maintain a sense of pleasure, but he didn&#39;t necessarily implement this method. He knew that he couldn&#39;t do it. He felt his own selfishness, so he said to her, I will send you wherever you work. Of course Wang Li refused, and he didn&#39;t ask again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At dawn, she deliberately kept her distance and became much colder. She always looked at her mobile phone. He got out of the quilt and hugged her from behind. She yelped and tried to push away. He felt a certain impatience and cried inexplicably. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When she saw his tears, she calmed down and lowered her head to look at him. what do you mean? she says. Tears are too cheap, especially when it comes to two liars. She is inexplicably calm. He actually couldn&#39;t explain clearly. It seemed that once she left, he would burst the dam, but why did it burst? He hasn&#39;t cried in ten years, and his shell has long been extremely hard. His mood is as stable as a century-old bastard, and he has always made people feel calm and reliable. Suddenly, it was over. He hugged her body tightly and pulled her into his chest. Did he want to have sex with her again? He thought that he had sex with his wife half a year ago. She would plan the day, clean herself, clean him again, lay out the sheets and quilts, as if it was a religious ceremony, and she could only move on fixed mats. During this period, she would remind him whether he had crossed the line and whether the bodily fluids would be poured out unnaturally. He was nervous and like a machine without emotions. She didn&#39;t know when he had been like this from the beginning or whether he had been like this from the beginning. He said no. clear. Or maybe she lied to him? Her name is not Wang Li, and even her ID card is fake. She doesn&#39;t have any job. She is going to the next hotel. This seems to be her job. He doesn&#39;t like it. He hopes that she can find a serious job and not be too tired. , she was so thin that it was impossible for her to do hard work and move anything. He could pick her up after get off work, pick her up every day, and go eat at KFC together. The KFC here allows you to order via mobile phone. The order code pops up on the electronic screen, and the waiter can prepare the meal in less than two minutes. He feels magical. Or maybe this is not his city. He doesn’t know the aunt selling tofu puffs on the street corner. He doesn’t know how much apples cost per pound here. There are several parks where you can walk, and you can take a few buses to the commercial center to see them. How much is the house price here? Can he afford another house? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thinking of this, he seemed to have merged into her life, like a baby who had made a mistake, sobbing with all his strength. She leaned down and kissed his tears away. He stood up and went to bite her lips, but she didn&#39;t refuse and made him lipstick all over. They all laughed. She reapplied her makeup and said that she was going to be late for work. It would take an hour to get there from here, and he had to let her go. He asked her to say that she loved him. She giggled and said it twice as if coaxing a child. He was content. He made up his mind, he wanted a divorce and crawled out of his body bag like a chrysalis. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After Wang Li left, his thoughts became even stronger. He couldn&#39;t tell where the conflict between getting closer and leaving came from, but he just had to do it. For the first time, he felt that he was beginning to control himself. He made a detailed plan. At this time, Wang Li turned into a vague concept in his mind and began to lose focus. Before he got on the plane, he sent Wang Li a message asking her to wait for him, but she did not reply. His excessive enthusiasm did not dissipate for a long time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the days after he returned, he had been making plans. His wife was waiting for him to pick her up. He forgot what they had argued about before, and she returned to her parents&#39; home. But it wasn&#39;t important anymore. Wang Li&#39;s enthusiasm was fading, and he was a little anxious. He sent a text message, but she didn&#39;t reply until two hours later, which was tepid. His mood was very chaotic. He was pacing around the room. He learned to smoke one cigarette after another. He wanted to pick up his wife tomorrow. No, not to bring her back, but to talk about it. He couldn&#39;t wait. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He called Wang Li, but she didn&#39;t answer. He looked at his phone and saw that it was midnight again. Maybe she had fallen asleep. He hadn&#39;t figured out how to tell his wife yet, but if that didn&#39;t work, he would show off his cards and tell her about having sex with Wang Li. He thought about it and felt a little proud. He knew that this emotion was wrong, but he couldn&#39;t restrain it. He tried to lie down and sleep, but insomnia struck him. He opened Douban on his mobile phone and found that the group was still there. He left messages one by one after Wang Li’s new topics, but unexpectedly found that someone had already commented on them. She talked with her in a playful tone. The man replied and turned off the screen. His stomach growled and he was hungry, so he went out to look for food and thought of KFC.他在手机地图里搜索，最近的一家1.8公里，这里他很熟悉，他手动调整路线，把距离缩短为1.1公里，他出门了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他想好了，要买两个牛肉汉堡，一份大薯条，一个玉米杯，一杯奶茶，他上次什么也没吃，这回要吃个够。路上他继续给王丽打电话，嘟了几声没有人接，点开信息，十分钟前收到回复，王丽说在加班，明天再联系。他低头看着人行道的瓷砖，安下心来，得过且过，生活不过如此。等明天把想法跟王丽说说，不会太久，他知道手续怎么办，那些睡不着的夜晚他都查过，王丽也曾经试探过，界限在哪，彼此也都清楚，生活即将重新开始，豆瓣和网络终究要落到实处，他体会过实处，王丽的身子骨是软的，她同样不期待但积极的态度确实在无形中感染他，他决定就明天，把什么都摊开来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;肯德基里只有两个人在吃饭，他走到柜台前，服务员给他示意手机点餐，他说，全国都这样了啊！他的语气没有一点惊讶，倒是很骄傲。服务员点点头说，是的。他打开点餐软件，和点餐软件放在一起的是查找我的朋友，他下意识点进去，看到小丽的头像在那家他去过的如家酒店上方悬挂着。他关掉软件重再进入，头像还在那。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;愣了几秒，服务员说，先生，要不要我帮您操作。他小声嘀咕，你说，烧水壶里会煮内裤吗？服务员皱起眉毛前探着身子，没听清他说什么，但还是礼貌地回复说，是的，先生，全国都这样了。他回过神，咯咯笑了起来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;责任编辑：梅不谈&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;征稿信息见@ONE一个工作室置顶微博。更多编辑部的有趣日常请关注小红书：ONE一个编辑部。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FlR5Z0EII4KoZAiklg49yN-v3fdm&quot; alt=&quot;西小麦&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;西小麦 &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@西小麦打字中&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;一个写字的。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;关注&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;相关推荐&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6004&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;摩天轮&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 西小麦&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6095&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;怀念时常徒有虚名&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 周宏翔&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6096)&quot;>;点击可下载ONE一个app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4001]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4135]]><description>&lt;div>;20 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FkXgsq4BxYwisg01fYrHWTlSI8lM&quot; alt=&quot;首页图&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4001&lt;/span>;插画| 赵珂萱&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;20&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sep. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;生活就是一场有很多规则，却没有裁判的比赛。&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 20 Sep 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>