<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[你把梦想藏在哪里了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3972]]><description> &lt;div>;9 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; ONE Studio Question&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p >;Where have you hidden your dreams? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Zhu Deyong replied&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FuH8wDlpBC8fQg1yqTh1g9Dk3miY&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FuH8wDlpBC8fQg1yqTh1g9Dk3miY&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Nana onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Deyong&#39;s Q&amp;A column &quot;Me≠We&quot; is exclusively updated on the &quot;ONE&quot; APP. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmPuzv4rbuXt8DD2ZiWPWVY5GDQ3 &quot; alt=&quot;Zhu Deyong&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Zhu Deyong&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;Weibo@朱德yong&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style =&quot;&quot;>;Cartoonist. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Question and Answer&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/question/3964&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;How long do you think the shelf life of sincerity is? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3958&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Is it okay not to grow up, boss? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3948&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What was the last time you cried? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3972)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[意外]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6155]]><description> &lt;div>;9 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Yi Chaonan&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt; img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgAWbElPw4tTcfqDK2dAgfOzkOv&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgAWbElPw4tTcfqDK2dAgfOzkOv&quot;>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Perhaps we all have relatives like this: some are admitted to college, some are Those who are from technical secondary school or junior college will inevitably be compared among relatives. A promising future does not depend on academic qualifications. It may be reflected in attitude, way of thinking, endurance and perseverance, etc. This article tells such a story. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Until the accident in 2016, we didn’t have a good impression of Zhao Jie. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Several relatives on my mother’s side live close to each other. When we were young, the children of our generation all had a good relationship, except Zhao Jie. He is the second eldest child in the ranking, four years younger than the eldest, Jiang Yichao, and three months older than me. Ordinarily, he and Jiang Yichao are both boys, so they can play together better. In fact, Jiang Yichao has the same bad temper as me. Grandma said, if you and two devils get together, who can have peace in the whole family? After finishing, he turned around and praised Zhao Jie. Look at our second boy. Sooner or later, he will see you. He is solid and does not cry or make trouble. It will save you more worry. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhao Jie is the son of his second aunt. The second aunt had been weak since she was a child and could not keep the baby alive after marriage. At that time, people were reluctant to spend money on serious hospitals and would rather believe in rural folk remedies. The second aunt went to the hospital after losing three children in a row after her home remedies failed to work. She already had habitual miscarriages. The doctor advised that if you really like children, you can’t adopt one. After struggling for another two or three years, the light of hope gradually disappeared. The couple was ready to adopt a child, but they became pregnant with Zhao Jie. I didn&#39;t have high hopes at first, but I unexpectedly saved the fetus through careful care. It is said that Zhao Jie was born weighing less than five pounds and weighing like a small mouse. He was born with insufficient physical strength and his cry was weak. It was not easy to get a child. The second aunt and his wife were afraid that something might happen, so they would follow them wherever they went. They would not let him do anything and would not let him move. They wished they could tie a rope to his trousers, so Zhao Jie developed the &quot;unnecessary and lively&quot; attitude. character. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Everyone said that Zhao Jie’s ability to come out of his second aunt’s belly alive was a blessing from heaven, so it’s understandable that his parents should be worried. But sometimes he looks unsociable and listless. Grandma turns her back on the second aunt and complains to others. The second boy is too lifeless. Although Xiaochao and Xiaoyu are noisy, they are still children, and they only look like children when they are noisy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ordinary children like me and Jiang Yichao, who could not score above 95 in the exam, were beaten and scolded. If you dare to fall below 90 points, your entire vacation will be ruined. If you don’t have pocket money, if you have a little bit of fun, your parents will whisper a few faint words of ridicule, saying that you can’t study well and you are very enthusiastic about doing things that are not famous. It was also mixed with some cold violence, which was more terrifying than being beaten and scolded. When I came to Zhao Jie, my grades have been stable at 60 or 70 since the first grade of elementary school. Jiang Yichao spoke, which was enough to at least cut off two of my dad&#39;s belts. However, the second aunt is always very proud. My Jeva is 67 in Chinese and 69 in mathematics this time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For this reason, Jiang Yichao and I were often jealous of Zhao Jie when we were young. What a fate, we were reincarnated into the second aunt&#39;s house. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhao Jie’s substitute teacher saw that his grades were always at the bottom, so he talked to his second aunt and his wife. The words were polite at the beginning. Children&#39;s education cannot rely solely on schools and teachers. Parents should also provide more guidance at home, so that children can grow better and faster. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My second uncle said that my child’s brain is innate, he can learn whatever he wants, and too much help will only encourage the child to grow. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The teacher was stunned. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The second uncle went on to say, besides what good academic performance is, I think many people who were good at studying when they were young will not be the same when they grow up. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The teacher came back to his senses and told the truth. It would be fine if he was the only one who was worse. The problem was that such a rat-shit type of student would bring down the performance of the whole class, the whole grade, and even the whole school. level, have you ever thought about this? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The second aunt sneered, &quot;Come on, let&#39;s go. Our school is at that level. Is it my child&#39;s turn to bring it down?&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In this way, Zhao Jie became the public enemy of the teachers. She didn&#39;t do anything to him, she just ignored him openly and treated him like nothing. Zhao Jie was a man of temper and didn&#39;t say anything. The second aunt and her husband were vaguely aware of it but didn&#39;t take it seriously. For a long time, they told everyone they met that the teacher wanted to talk to them, but they were taught a lesson. By the time he realized something was wrong, it was already too late. Zhao Jie said he didn&#39;t want to go to school. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;No one seemed surprised that Zhao Jie dropped out of junior high school. But he is less than 15 years old, so what can he do if he doesn&#39;t go to school? According to my uncle and my father&#39;s wishes, they could send me to a technical school to learn things like car repair, cooking, hairdressing, etc. If I have a skill, at least I won&#39;t be hungry. The second aunt and her husband also planned this. After that, he said that the child’s personal wishes must be respected. Four elders gathered around Zhao Jie to do ideological work. No matter what you learn, you can&#39;t let this life be ruined. Zhao Jie just smiled and said nothing. My uncle has a bad temper. He is planning for your future and your whole life. Why are you laughing at such a serious matter? Zhao Jie stopped laughing and still didn&#39;t speak. The second aunt is trying to smooth things over, but Jeva is not good at expressing herself. Let’s just say, he just listens. If he has an opinion, he will speak it out, right Jeva? Zhao Jie nodded warmly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The adults talked to each other and discussed the matter of choosing a school and a major. After saying that, he turned to look at Zhao Jie, who was already playing a game with headphones on. My dad had a slow temper and glanced at me without saying a word. My uncle couldn&#39;t hold it back, so he immediately stood up and walked over. Before he could say anything while taking off his earphones, the second uncle quickly stopped him. His children are like children. They don&#39;t want to cause trouble and just like to have fun. We adults can just discuss it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My uncle did not expect this to be the case. He held the earphones in his hands and was stunned for a moment. It would be wrong if Zhao Jie put them back on, and it would be wrong if he didn&#39;t put them back on. My dad said leisurely while blowing smoke rings, now I don’t have to respect his personal wishes anymore? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The second aunt immediately got angry. You two are elders, why are you trying to get into trouble with a child? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My father and my uncle were worried about Zhao Jie&#39;s future. They came to the door with enthusiasm and wanted to help solve the problem. As a result, the three members of the family were poured a basin of ice water on each person, which made them feel cold. Go back and tell your grievances to my mother. My mother will tell you why my mother and I advised you not to get involved in this matter in the first place. Why can&#39;t you see it? The baby was spoiled by those couple! I had to mess around blindly, but fortunately I have come back to fight against you now. Otherwise, believe it or not, if you interfere here and there, you will definitely become enemies in the end. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My uncle is very stubborn, let’s see what you say. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My mother raised her voice to suppress my uncle. What did I say? Let’s put it bluntly, aren’t the children in technical schools all trash who were kicked out of the school, smoking, drinking and fighting, how many are good? With Zhao Jie&#39;s small mind and body, it doesn&#39;t matter whether he learns skills or not. If something happens to him when he is bullied, you can see that the second sister will bite back and fight you two. Don’t listen to your advice, don’t listen to your advice, and yet, people have already fallen out with you, yet you still don’t believe in evil? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What my mother said is true. Because of this matter, my second aunt actually became estranged from my family and my uncle&#39;s family. Zhao Jie didn&#39;t go to technical school either. Grandma said that the second aunt felt sorry for Zhao Jie because he was too young and she was worried about sending him to a technical school. I also saw that Zhao Jie loved watching martial arts movies, so after much deliberation I sent him to a martial arts school in the suburbs. The school offered half a day of cultural classes and half a day of martial arts training. At least junior high school classes will not be left behind. The second aunt thought so, but after half a semester, Zhao Jie became so thin that he was as thin as a skeleton. The second aunt felt compassion again, so she stopped going to the martial arts school. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhao Jie is at home, and his second aunt is still proud of himself. A young man of this age can disappear all day long and make trouble everywhere. But our Jeva is different. Just stay indoors and watch TV, so you don&#39;t have to worry. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grandpa commented that at the age when she should be struggling, she was living like a retired cadre, how could she have the nerve to show off. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since grandpa can’t stand it, Zhao Jie is the only one who accompanies grandpa to play checkers, chess, and two-player poker. For those who don&#39;t mind the afternoon, Zhao Jie was sent to his grandfather&#39;s house by his second aunt. Although he said he was spending time with the elderly, he was still afraid that Zhao Jie would get sick from being bored at home alone. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grandpa is naturally happy. Jiang Yichao left for college, and he was not used to being anywhere. When Zhao Jie came, he just filled this gap. However, within a few days of being happy, I started to worry about my grandson. What will happen to this good child if he is left idle like this? I took Zhao Jie out with me from time to time. I went to flower, bird, fish and insect markets for the elderly, calligraphy and painting exhibitions for children, and more advanced ones such as the Youth Science and Technology Grand Prix. Grandpa was holding on to some luck - maybe Zhao Jie would be able to discover some unusual talent in his hands. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On this day, the grandfather and grandson went to a venue in the southern suburbs to watch a network design competition. Halfway through the car ride, Zhao Jie pointed out the car window and asked, &quot;Why is there so much smoke when burning?&quot; Grandpa took a look at the crematorium, what do you mean it was burned? Zhao Jie said, Oh, the crematorium, do you have to carry it here and burn it after you die? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Elderly people are sensitive to death, can they listen to this? The relationship between grandfather and grandson, which had been close for less than a month, broke down on the spot. Zhao Jie was sent back to his home and once again lived the life of a retired veteran cadre. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The summer vacation will soon come, and the results of the high school entrance examination will be announced. I followed in the footsteps of Jiang Yichao and successfully entered the key class of the city&#39;s No. 1 Middle School. When grandpa talks, Xiaochao and Xiaoyu make people worry-free. You younger ones should learn more from your elder brothers and sisters. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The middle brother Zhao Jie was omitted for no reason. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The second aunt heard somewhere that driving an excavator makes a lot of money, no matter ten thousand or twenty thousand a month. This time they didn&#39;t ask for Zhao Jie&#39;s opinion and sent him directly to a technical school to learn how to excavate. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When the family heard the news, they inevitably used Jiang Yichao and Zhao Jie as positive and negative teaching materials to educate us. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jiang Yichao went to a key university and was already very proud. However, with Zhao Jie setting him off like this, he was like a proud man at home. He himself was not polite, with his tail raised to the sky, and he always lectured me with the air of a veteran, who was already overwhelmed by high school life. &quot;Third brother, please work harder. In today&#39;s society, if I can&#39;t get into college, I will be stuck for the rest of my life.&quot; But it’s over. Look at your second brother. The sentence added at the end, &quot;Look at your second brother,&quot; makes people feel very uncomfortable. I thought to myself, how interesting would it be for you to pull your ass and compete with someone who is inherently inferior? But in fact, I am also very afraid. I am afraid that if I make a wrong step at this time, the road ahead will be difficult every step of the way. I don&#39;t want to end my life so early. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At that time, I didn’t know that the path of life, regardless of right or wrong, was mostly difficult. I was frightened by what everyone said about Zhao Jie&#39;s future, which was already several times inferior to others even before he arrived. So while sympathizing with Zhao Jie, he also worked hard to avoid becoming Zhao Jie. This is what adults want to see. Whether I want to hear it or not, news about Zhao Jie is constantly reaching my ears. The excavator is not that easy to drive. In the human society, you have to be smart wherever you go. Zhao Jie is not good at it. He will not flatter the master when he goes on a construction site internship. In the past few months, he has not entered the cockpit more than ten times. But he also has poor self-control and is addicted to the Internet. He spends all day and night playing games in Internet cafes. His health was already weak, and his second uncle was afraid that he would eventually develop a fatal disease if things continued like this, so he took him home to support him. But Internet addiction is so easy to overcome. I heard that there were times when my second uncle had no choice but to accompany Zhao Jie to an Internet cafe to play games. My son was working hard in front of the computer, and I moved a stool to sit behind and watch. The father and son stayed up together all night long. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During this period, the second aunt took the initiative to restore the previous intimacy with several families. She also began to complain a little when she mentioned Zhao Jie in front of everyone. My mother refuted her, saying that Jeva was spoiled by you and your brother-in-law. If the second aunt doesn&#39;t recognize him, why should we spoil him? You all know that he is innately incapable of withstanding beatings. He cannot be beaten gently or hard. He is not as strong as you guys. If he disobeys, he will be served with a belt and a stick. How can he not be successful? My mother said that if you can&#39;t stand the beating, there are education methods for those who can&#39;t stand the beating. You can&#39;t just let him go as he pleases? The second aunt asked back, how do we still need to educate her? She has said everything that needs to be said, and her words are all worn out, so how do she still need us to educate her? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My mother wanted to say something else, but my grandmother blocked her with a look. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shortly after this, Zhao Jie ran away from home. No news at all. The second aunt and second uncle searched aimlessly for a few days, and were wondering whether to go to the police station to report her missing. They received a message from Zhao Jie, a classmate, saying that he was in the provincial capital and was applying for a job as a dishwasher in the back kitchen of a hotel. , let the family not worry. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It’s just nonsense. The second aunt fell seriously ill and became even weaker. I burst into tears in front of my brothers and sisters. What did I raise? I raised a wolf with a big tail. He doesn&#39;t do the errands arranged for him well and goes out to wash dishes for others. He has never washed a single dish for me at home, but instead goes out to wash dishes for others. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My uncle said, if it doesn’t work, we should find a way to arrest the person. If the excavator doesn’t work, it is at least a technical job, and there is no future for washing dishes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The second aunt shook her head, forget it, I have seen through it, he just doesn’t want to make life easier for me and his dad. I don’t care what he likes in the future. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grandma curled her lips, I’m afraid it’s not that you don’t want to take care of it, but that people grow up and have their own ideas, so you don’t want to take care of it, right? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My uncle was talking, and my parents were disciplining us at that time. Whoever made a mistake would not be beaten all over the floor? The only second child is as sick and weak as Lin Daiyu. Not to mention beatings, the whole family dare not say a word loudly in front of her, so she is used to bad habits. Now she&#39;s fine, she gave birth to a son and gave birth to a replica, dedicated to treating her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before I was admitted to college and left home, my grandparents planned a family dinner. Grandma was a good cook, but as she got older, my mother was afraid that her body wouldn’t be able to handle such a chore, so she asked her aunt and aunt to help her do it. Everyone in the family agreed, and the second aunt came out and said that Zhao Jie had done a good job in the kitchen of the hotel and learned some skills. Now that his sister was admitted to college, it was a great thing, and he also came up with a job. If you don&#39;t have the strength, why not let him be the chef. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is a problem for my parents. Don&#39;t let him do it. It&#39;s my nephew&#39;s wedding and it&#39;s a family dinner. It doesn&#39;t make sense not to give him a chance to try it out. Let him do it, that&#39;s not the way he behaves. If he can&#39;t bear it, or if the food is hard to swallow, it will make a happy party look neither yin nor yang, which is not good. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the end, it was my mother who spoke. The young man has been training outside for a year and must have learned something. He only spoke this way when he was confident. Let him come if he wants to, and I&#39;ll watch from the side. How could I be wrong? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before that family dinner, we had not seen Zhao Jie for more than two or three years. For a moment, he didn&#39;t recognize it. He was much taller, stronger, and darker. There was no trace of frailty on his body. Jiang Yichao wondered to me, you said he stayed in the kitchen all day long, why did he still get dark? Could it be that fluorescent lamps can also make people tan? After Jiang Yirui heard this, she ran to ask Zhao Jie what her brother had said. Jiang Yichao was frightened, thinking that Zhao Jie was angry. People just smiled, who said they only stayed in the kitchen? We go out to deliver goods and purchase goods. Sometimes we don’t have enough manpower and we have to go out to deliver food under the sun. Jiang Yichao shook his head after hearing this. It&#39;s too hard. If it were you, you wouldn&#39;t be able to persevere. The sense of superiority in his words was not hidden at all. Zhao Jie stopped talking, put on an apron and entered the kitchen. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the banquet started, Zhao Jie has been busy in the kitchen. His craftsmanship is really good, he mixes meat and vegetables well, and he prepares the dishes quickly. In the middle, my second uncle asked him to come out and toast me with a glass of wine. When I think of him again, I don’t know when he has gone. At that time, the family dinner was coming to an end, and my uncle frowned. There were so many elders here, and it was not polite to leave without saying hello. The second aunt said coquettishly, you were drinking when you said hello, and you didn&#39;t even raise your eyebrows. He was still in a hurry to go back to the hotel. The uncle snorted and continued to punch his uncle. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grandma went to the kitchen to serve soup. When I came back, I was full of praise for Zhao Jie. He was a capable young man and cooked decently. He also cleaned up the kitchen for me before leaving. Okay, I think this guy is very good. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My dad is drunk, so what’s the use of looking after him? We’ve watched this kid grow up, he’s not reliable. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My uncle also drank a lot and kept echoing that his good performance today was temporary. His brother and sister have all gone to college, but he is the only one who has no future. It is impossible to do such a small thing well. A useless person. Why didn&#39;t he come to the table? I know I&#39;m embarrassed, but it&#39;s a pity that it&#39;s too late! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I don’t know how the second uncle and my uncle got into a fight. By the time I reacted, my second uncle was already holding a kitchen knife in one hand. Fortunately, there were many people trying to stop the fight. Jiang Yichao and his aunt hugged his uncle&#39;s waist, his aunts and uncles dragged his second uncle, and my father grabbed his knife-holding arm with both hands to prevent him from moving. This prevented the matter from further deteriorating into social news. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jiang Yirui and I stood against the wall and watched. Finally, she praised in my ear, Niuxi, sister, the dinner party at my brother’s college was so bland as water, but there was no such dramatic tension as yours. Cowhide! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This farce has subsided and it is getting late. After sending off the uncle and second uncle&#39;s family, the other elders stood up to say goodbye one after another with awkward smiles on their faces. Grandma grabbed grandma&#39;s hand, her face full of shame, what a shame! I made you laugh, my mother-in-law. Grandma shook her head repeatedly. We are all a family and we don’t say such out-of-the-way things. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is how the second aunt and uncle&#39;s family became enemies. During those two or three years, the two families never appeared at the same time when visiting relatives during festivals or birthdays. I heard that once my aunt moved to a new house, she neglected to treat the two families at the same time. As a result, my uncle and second uncle met in front of the hotel. When the two met, they thought that my aunt wanted to be a peacemaker and persuade them to make peace. They immediately turned around and headed back home. After that, no one dared to bring up the matter of persuading peace. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the eyes of everyone, although Zhao Jieren was not present, the family dinner was ruined because of him, and the feud between the two families also started because of him. The elders who were already dissatisfied with him didn&#39;t say a good word when they mentioned him, as if he was a lost star. And I, who was originally full of sympathy for him, became completely disgusted with him because the family dinner held for me was interrupted. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The accident happened after Qingming Festival. One month before the Qingming Festival, news came from my hometown that the county development zone had taken a fancy to the land where my family&#39;s ancestral tomb is located and allowed the tomb to be moved. The village party secretary belonged to the same family as my grandfather. He called my grandfather and told him that the site for the new tomb he had chosen personally was absolutely fine. But to be on the safe side, people who are out of town might as well go back and take a look. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Firstly, my mother’s family are superstitious and believe that the feng shui of the ancestral graves will affect future generations; secondly, I want to take advantage of the fact that the old graves are still there before moving the graves, so that the whole family can go back to worship their ancestors. So we discussed collective action. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At this time, almost four years had passed since the uncle and second uncle had a bad relationship. During this period, I went to college until I was about to graduate; Jiang Yichao insisted on finding a job outside of college after graduating from college, but his uncle and aunt refused to listen and had no choice but to let him go; Zhao Jie met a good master in the hotel where he was admitted and learned more skills. , after being introduced by the master, he returned to a local three-star hotel to work as a chef. The hotel is less than half an hour&#39;s drive from home by bus, but Zhao Jie still chooses to stay and go home for the holidays. The second aunt still praised me as usual, saying that my son is very filial and knows that I am not in good health. He still wants to come back to me after running around and learning skills. Uncle sneered, deceiving himself. There are so many hotels in the provincial capital, and the treatment is much better than ours. If he had to run back, he would probably offend people outside and be unable to survive. Of course, no one dared to leak any information about this to the second aunt and second uncle. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So when my uncle approached my dad about renting a minivan and sharing the gas and tolls equally among the four families, even though my dad knew it was much more cost-effective than driving each family back separately, he was still very hesitant. My uncle said, I know what you are worried about. They are all relatives. With broken bones and tendons, there is no obstacle that cannot be overcome. What&#39;s more, it&#39;s been so many years. Don&#39;t worry, I will never make trouble. Even if he makes trouble, for the sake of my parents, I, as the eldest, can tolerate it. My dad thinks about it, no matter how old he is, he should be safe. Then agreed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At that time, Jiang Yichao was working overtime and could not go back. I&#39;m busy with my graduation project and can&#39;t go back. Zhao Jie works in a hotel, so statutory holidays are not valid for them, and they cannot go back. Everyone is here except the three of us. I heard that although my uncle and my second aunt didn&#39;t talk to each other all the way, they got along fairly smoothly. After the family was busy with their business, they also took some free time to visit a newly built scenic spot in the nearby mountains for a day. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The accident happened on the way back on the highway. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first person to receive the call was Jiang Yichao. Then there&#39;s me. When the ambulance arrived, the second aunt lay on the stretcher, woke up from the frightened coma, and asked Jeva where she was. Only then did Jiang Yirui remember that she had forgotten to notify Zhao Jie. The order of arriving at the hospital was exactly the opposite. Zhao Jie arrived first, then me. The things that need to be dealt with are very complicated - those who go into the operating room, those who stay in the hospital for observation, those who get stitches for wounds, those who put in slings, and even the doctors, nurses, traffic police team, and the person who was knocked unconscious while sitting in our car. The neighbor boy had almost settled everything, and Jiang Yichao showed up. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That was the first time for a few of us to take on responsibility. When Jiang Yirui called me, her voice was vibrating. I rushed to the hospital and saw that the elders were badly injured, with blood everywhere they looked, moans in their ears, and they were confused, standing there not knowing what to do. Zhao Jie, on the other hand, did not lose his mind. He first arranged for Jiang Yirui to send his frightened but uninjured grandparents and cousins ​​home. He also took me to cooperate with doctors and nurses to arrange examinations, infusions, and payment of various fees for the elders. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was like a robot, following Zhao Jie in confusion all the way, doing whatever he ordered me to do. Zhao Jie saw that I was distracted, so he comforted me when he had some free time. At this juncture, we must not be reckless or stupid, we must be smart. I said I wanted to, but I couldn’t do it. Zhao Jie said, if you think you can&#39;t do it, you really won&#39;t be able to do it. You have to tell yourself that you can do it, keep saying it, and many times you can actually do it. you try. I said you, a semi-illiterate, understand psychological suggestion? After saying this, I realized I had made a mistake and mentally slapped myself. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhao Jie was generous and said disapprovingly, &quot;I don&#39;t understand what psychological suggestion is.&quot; All I know is that since I was little, everyone around me, especially my parents, has said that I can’t do it. My health is not good, my study is not good, no one expects me to do things, and my words are not on point... I also feel that I am not good. No matter what I do, my first reaction is that I will definitely not be able to do it. There was a time when I was obsessed with playing games. Actually, it wasn’t because the games were so fun. It was the first time in that game that I felt like I was pretty good. In order to prove myself, I even took my dad to an Internet cafe to watch me play, but he couldn&#39;t understand. He sighed and told my mother that I could forget my last name when I played games, and I was destined to be a useless person in this life. My mother didn&#39;t shy away from me. From then on, she told me all day long that she was a burden and causing trouble for herself... So you ran away from home? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hmm. I want to give myself some credit, and also want to see if I can do it without relying on my parents. It&#39;s hard to be alone outside. Every time I can&#39;t hold on, I tell myself over and over again in my heart, you can do it. If you hold your breath again, you will definitely be able to do it. When it doesn&#39;t work, cry and sleep for a while, then filter it out as an accident, and only remember the things that can be done in your mind. So I persisted. Slowly I discovered that I was actually not as bad as everyone said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said, this is psychological suggestion. Although you have never heard of this theory, what you do is the explanation of this theory. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I am also lucky and meet good people when I go out. Willing to teach me, willing to give me a chance. Later, I said to myself less and less about whether it would work or not. I no longer needed it. Originally, I thought I could go home now, but... Zhao Jie curled his lips and shook his head, &quot;No, if I go home for a long time, I have to start everything over again.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This was the first time I had such an in-depth conversation with Zhao Jie, and I felt mixed emotions after listening to it. The elders were considerate of his inherent shortcomings and seemed to be indulging him, but in fact they were using another method to discriminate against him and ignore him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Being in the hospital, there were many things waiting for us to deal with. He didn’t have enough time to talk to me in too many details, but I could imagine how lonely and helpless he felt during those years. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said, brother. That was the first time I called him brother. I said, brother, thank you for telling me this. I will try this method you taught me now. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was very tired, and I kept hoping that Jiang Yichao would take over quickly so that I could be relieved. But Jiang Yichao was late, so I had to hold on. After talking to Zhao Jie, I escaped from the mood of dependence and felt some strength in my heart. I think people have to start to accomplish something independently from some point on. And this time that belongs to me has arrived. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhao Jie walked away to do other things. I no longer looked forward to Jiang Yichao’s arrival. I told myself that I could do it alone. I can do it, I can do it. My brain, which had been dormant for a long time, started to work again. I used the energy to cope with the exam to cope with the current situation, comfort the groaning elders, and move between doctors and nurses. It was not a smooth process, but it was completed successfully. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jiang Yichao’s performance after arriving at the hospital was not much better than mine. Hearing that his parents had gone into the operating room, even though I reassured him that the problem was nothing serious, he still couldn&#39;t help but his eye circles were red and his legs were shaking. When he inspected the other elders lying on the hospital bed with hanging bottles, their clothes or pants were stained with unknown blood, and his whole body began to collapse inch by inch from the top of his head. Although he was standing against the wall, his spirit couldn&#39;t resist gravity and kept sliding underground. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although the second aunt is not seriously injured, the second uncle&#39;s injury is no less serious than that of the uncle. Zhao Jie witnessed his father being pushed into the operating room, covered in blood and crying. But when Jiang Yirui heard that Zhao Jie rushed to the hospital, after a brief surprise, he quickly entered a state of high speed. I also watched him working from morning to night, without even having time to take a bite of food. Seeing that Jiang Yichao was in trouble, I directed him to go to a nearby supermarket or restaurant to buy some food. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jiang Yichao nodded, okay, I&#39;ll go out and get some fresh air. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For some reason, I suddenly felt a strong desire to win for Zhao Jie. I tried to steal Jiang Yichao. Zhao Jie had to deal with so many troubles and arrange so many things throughout the day. Your tone, you&#39;ve only been here a while, and you can&#39;t stand it when you haven&#39;t done anything? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jiang Yichao shrugged his shoulders and curled his lips disapprovingly, &quot;Your second brother came out to join the society before graduating from junior high school. Do you think it was for nothing?&quot; People who have never seen any big scenes are not like you and me. We are nerds who immerse ourselves in studying. When we encounter this kind of thing that does not rely on brainpower and relies on brute force, we stop. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brute force? I looked at him, you know how troublesome and trivial all these things are, and it takes no time to sort out the priorities. If you have an unstable temper and a lack of organization, you simply can&#39;t do it. You eat ready-made, don&#39;t know how to be grateful, and are you still here in a weird mood? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jiang Yichao looked impatient, &quot;Oh, no need to show off your merits. I know you have worked hard and tired. I am far away.&quot; I would have rushed here if I were... He suddenly stopped talking and said, &quot;Forget it, I&#39;ll buy you something to eat.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I turned around in confusion and saw Zhao Jie coming this way. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jiang Yichao couldn&#39;t accept from the bottom of his heart that I said Zhao Jie was better than him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My father and my uncle had a fractured right arm and a fractured right leg. They watched how Zhao Jie was busy before entering the operating room. After coming out of the operating room, I heard my aunt, who only suffered some skin trauma, and my mother, who had a slight concussion, praising Zhao Jie. My dad couldn&#39;t help but sigh, who would have thought that at the critical moment, it would be Jeva who would take the trouble for us. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My uncle and second uncle were seriously injured and were placed in the same ward after the operation. My aunt went over to visit and heard the doctor say that the operation was successful, and she breathed a sigh of relief. He took Zhao Jie&#39;s hand and said, &quot;Thanks to you, our whole family is here today.&quot; Zhao Jie smiled, what my aunt said, you don&#39;t mean thanks to me, it should be said that the whole family today is all thanks to me. A wise remark immediately relaxed the sad and tense atmosphere, and we laughed. The aunt was angry and poked Zhao Jie on the forehead with her finger, saying that you were fat and you were breathless! The nurse frowned. The patient should rest and the family members should not make any noise. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The uncle looked back on what happened. They are afraid that if they leave late, they will encounter the traffic returning from the holiday, and the traffic jam on the road will cause panic. So I got up at around four o&#39;clock in the morning and set off back before six o&#39;clock. My dad felt sleepy halfway through the drive, so he switched to my uncle to drive. It didn&#39;t rain when the two of them were changing shifts. As they crossed the Qinling Mountains, the rain gradually became heavier. When they were about to get off the highway, a cat, dog or something suddenly appeared in the middle of the road - my dad said it was thrown by the car in front. Plastic bag - It was raining so hard that no one could see it clearly. My uncle turned the steering wheel quickly. The road was slippery in the rain and the tires of the rented minibus didn&#39;t grip the road very well. As soon as it slipped, I quickly hit the isolation strip in the middle of the road. &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jiang Yichao and Zhao Jie went together to negotiate compensation with the car rental company and insurance company. When he came back, Jiang Yichao complained impatiently. I was impressed by his patience. If he hadn&#39;t been persuading me, I would have started working with those people long ago. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although it was an accident, the accident was caused by my uncle after all. The financial situation of the second aunt&#39;s family is not good. Although they have medical insurance, the second uncle&#39;s injury is serious, and the expenses besides surgery and hospitalization reimbursement are not small. My uncle took the initiative to bear the expense. My family and my aunt&#39;s family are in better condition in all aspects, and the expenses are not big. Considering that my uncle was also seriously injured, the two sisters did not ask him to bear more. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition to my family members, there was also an outsider in the car on the way back that day. A neighbor from the same clan in my hometown found his uncle on the day of ancestor worship and told him that he had found a job for his son in the provincial capital and asked him to give his son a lift. There were extra seats in the bus, so my uncle agreed without hesitation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That boy also came out to work after graduating from junior high school. He was about seventeen years old at this time. After the accident, there were no obvious signs of injury on his body, and the doctor&#39;s examination said there were no abnormalities in his physical signs. However, he remained unconscious for some reason. Zhao Jie was afraid that something might have happened, so he took his phone number and notified his parents. His parents wanted to pay for the fare, but were too embarrassed to say so. After a while of hesitation, Zhao Jie understood the other party&#39;s intention and promised to pay the round-trip fare, and then the couple set off. The boy woke up once and chatted with Zhao Jie. Maybe he had similar experiences of dropping out of junior high school to seek a future, and the two chatted very happily. After chatting for a while, the boy said he was sleepy again and fell asleep. He didn&#39;t wake up until his parents came. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Early the next morning, the boy&#39;s mother called Zhao Jie, shouting that something serious had happened to her son. I saw Zhao Jie&#39;s expression was wrong, so I followed him over. Halfway there, Jiang Yichao and Jiang Yirui also followed me, saying that the family was not well-informed and difficult to deal with, and his father was worried, so he asked me to follow him to see if he could help. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I entered the door, I saw the boy standing perfectly still, and there was nothing wrong with him. Zhao Jie greeted him, are you awake? Before the boy could respond, his father said, &quot;You broke the parts in my son&#39;s head, and you told us it was fine.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhao Jie said, did the doctor check and say everything was fine? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Why are you okay? His father yelled, &quot;My son is an out-and-out rural boy, but you have knocked him into Mandarin. How can I say he&#39;s okay?&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We looked at each other in confusion. Jiang Yichao asked, Uncle, if you speak more slowly, why don’t I seem to understand? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他爸操着一口浓重的方言说，我儿又不是没出过门，原先走得再远，回来一口土话从来没串过味儿。这好噻，被你们一撞，今早醒了张口跟我摆八频道（指方言味浓郁的普通话）：爸，妈，你怎么在这里？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;头回听说这种事，我和蒋一超对视一眼，忍住笑背过身出了病房。蒋一超意思这事麻烦，我们在这七嘴八舌会添乱，不如让赵杰一个人处理。说完拽着我往回走。虽然不情愿，但想到我妈还没到医院来接班，我爸没人看顾，我得过去守着，就跟着蒋一超走。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;赵杰处理这件事，从一开始蒋一蕊就跟着。事情的后续是赵杰带着男孩从头到脚做了个全身检查，没毛病。医生讲，身体机能没问题，大半是小伙子受了惊吓，心理上发生了些医学层面无法解释的转变，不碍事。老两口半信半疑，但儿子虽然满口塑料普通话，其他方面确实没有异常。都是老家邻居，且小伙又和赵杰加过微信，真有事儿我们跑不掉，这才作罢。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;二哥做事挺体面，蒋一蕊说，哪儿来那么大耐性哄得那一家人没脾气。又问大家，你们老说二哥先天不足，可除了学习不好，我咋没看出来他哪儿不足啊？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她以为赵杰出去了才有这一问，谁知赵杰只是去门口叫护士，扭脸回来刚好怼上这话，在场的人难免尴尬，赵杰倒是一副无所谓的样子打趣，这不是吃的好喝的好，先天不足的后天又给补回来了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;趁二姨夫被推出去做理疗，蒋一超问，他是本性就这么温和，还是多年来在家里风评太差，现在有了逆转的机会，刻意压制脾气在人前卖好？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;舅舅冷言冷语，花的不是自己的钱，放我我也脾气好。见我在场，又找补，不过这次杰娃的表现确实意外，让人刮目相看啊。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从医生说舅舅和二姨夫手术顺利没有危险的那一刻起，蒋一超显然从心理上也度过了危险期，对看护和照顾这种事不经意间透出一些疲乏和厌倦。工作电话一个接一个，去趟楼梯间接，少则十来分钟，多则一个小时才回。没两天，他电脑也带进医院。舅舅想喝口水，他捧着电脑说稍等。这一稍等，就是半个多小时没动静。最后还是隔壁陪床的家属看不过眼，帮忙给舅舅喂了水。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;赵杰是另一个风格，处处细致体贴，像个拿了高薪的护工。舅舅难免抱怨，一样都是儿子，杰娃咋那么耐烦，那么孝顺。这抱怨给蒋一超开辟了一条解脱之路&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;你说我不行，我还不奉陪了。借着领导来电话，说有事必须回公司处理，干脆跑路。前前后后加起来，他在床前伺候了不到五天。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蒋一蕊还上学，蒋一超一走，和舅妈换班照顾舅舅的责任就落赵杰肩上，舅舅面子上挂不住，解释说，年轻人工作要紧，超儿那毕竟正规大公司，事情多任务重，没那么长时间假。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;二姨笑着抬杠，嗯，只有你家蒋一超正规，我们家赵杰嘛，从小就是个不正规的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;舅妈见气氛不对，连忙跳出来圆场，你别跟他一般见识，他这是儿子跑了，自己给自己找个台阶下呢。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我妈知道我临近毕业事情多，见蒋一超跑了，就催着我也走。我又多待了两天，看她和我爸相互能照应过来，也就返校了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;赵杰老在医院耗着，一大家人除了二姨问他，你天天在这，酒店愿意？其余再没人问过一句。并非大家不好奇。我妈讲话，正当用人的时候，蒋一超溜了，你也回了学校，能顶事儿的就剩个赵杰，可不敢多嘴，不问没事，一问万一他也跑了，眼下这情况咱指望谁去？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从事情随后的发展来看，赵杰也没想要保住工作。他伺候舅舅出院那天，舅舅才终于卸下没人照顾的担忧问了句，你耽搁这么久，工作咋弄的？赵杰说，想自己干，辞职了。考虑手头资金有限，想先去夜市摆摊。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;舅舅打电话问我爸，夜市摆摊啥意思？卖个惨让我投资他开店？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我爸没言声。舅舅接着说，我就寻思这段时间，这赵杰表现好得也有点过分了，怕不是老二给教的？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我爸还是没言声，回头找我妈商量，说既然大哥撬开了赵杰的口，恐怕你二姐一家不久就要试到我们头上来，万一他们真借钱，咱是借还是不借。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几家亲戚相互电话打了个遍，一方面确实意外赵杰那一个多月在医院的表现，也感激他的付出。另一方面又担心那只是表象，是为借钱做铺垫。所谓江山易改本性难移，小学都学不到人前去的赵杰，那脑子能做成什么生意？钱借给他岂不是打水漂？生意赔了本，必然还要借第二回&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;可，谁家钱也不是大风刮来的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还没商量出给赵杰这个钱到底是借还是不借，赵杰的夜市摊已经准备就绪，要开业了。摊位是通过他朋友介绍，从熟人手里接过来的，大多数东西都现成的，需要新置办的设备、用具他在医院陪床时找空当也置办妥了。甚至连帮手都是在医院寻摸的&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;那位被撞成普通话的搭车男孩。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这里头还有一段插曲。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;二姨一听赵杰找那男孩打下手，当即把头摇成个拨浪鼓，不行不行，他怎么样我不知道，他那父母太难缠，你又不是没应付过，别跟那家人往一块儿粘？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;赵杰不以为然，他是他，他父母是他父母。再说了，他父母当时的表现也不算过分，他们的本意不是占便宜，只是怕吃亏。人生在世谁不怕吃亏，只不过他们没文化表达不好，容易让人误解成难缠。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;二姨细想这话颇有道理，便不再阻挠。后来这番话又辗转落到舅舅耳朵里，舅舅听罢沉吟，有文化的人也不见得有这么豁达的心胸啊。那是舅舅第一次公开表达对赵杰的赞赏。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;跟谁也没张口，赵杰夜市照样开了摊，长辈们之前的种种揣测和提防立刻显得狭隘，尴尬。但谁也没说破，假装没过这回事。我妈和小姨一人给赵杰包了个两千块的红包。舅舅五千。赵杰有些推辞。二姨劝他，拿着，你姨你舅家里有，这仨瓜两枣的算啥。你舅撞车这么大的事，不是你顶着，谁知道一家人得落下什么病根。何况&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;这话我本来不该说，但不说我心里不舒服，你爸身体本来挺好的，这一撞给撞垮了，咱家以后可全靠你。现在你干事业，你舅别说出点儿血，他就是晚上闲了去给你帮忙都应该的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我舅没反驳。他说二姨话虽刺耳，也是实情。从此以后，这一家三口生活水平是上个台阶还是下个台阶，全看赵杰表现。造成这种境况，说里面有他的责任，不为过。所以他不但没反驳，回过头还吩咐蒋一超，让他以大哥的身份给赵杰再补个红包。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;长辈们不知道的是，赵杰摆夜市这个想法的落地，正是我和蒋一超促成的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;赵杰工作那些年虽然攒了些钱，但真要像像样样地支个摊子，还差点儿。这是我俩医院走廊闲聊时顺嘴提的，他说过去就算了，但我记在了心上。我没钱，蒋一超有。我给蒋一超打电话深谈了一次，把赵杰之前在医院跟我说的那些关于心理暗示的事复述了一遍。最后我说，识人要靠自己的眼睛，不能依赖别人的嘴巴。就我跟赵杰相处的那一个星期，我觉得他做事有条理有分寸有毅力有耐心，很可靠。他现在想自己做点事，我们当老表的，举手之劳，能帮帮一把。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;隔天蒋一超回我话，说他能拿出三万来。我说足够了，以后赵杰生意要做起来，能还上他自己还你，要生意做砸了还不上，那时候我上班也挣工资了，这个帐我认。蒋一超有点生气，景博宇，你把我当成什么人了？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;赵杰脾气好，人又活泛会来事儿，做饭手艺也是经过考验的，夜市生意没多久便走上正轨，做得风生水起。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2019年年初，他租了间100来平的商铺，开上了正规的饭馆。门店装修、租金、进货等等一系列投资把他多年来的积蓄花得一光二净。但这次没人再质疑，到处都是支持的声音。几乎每个人都坚信，和之前摆夜市一样，这次开饭馆也很快就能回本见利。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;凡事有意外，谁能料到，投资还没回本，疫情来了。一开始大家都天真，以为两三个月就恢复到日常生活，谁料中间起起伏伏，翻翻覆覆，一折腾就是三年。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那三年里，三天两头封禁，店里没有营收开不出工资，伙计们走得七零八散。赵杰凭着自己的进货渠道和跟管理部门打交道攒下的人脉，在封禁时拿到义工卡，可以自由出入。他当过采买团团长，做过送货工，不能堂食但可以打包的那些半紧不松的日子，他挂上外卖，有时一个人在店里忙活，打扫卫生，洗菜，摘菜，备料&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我和蒋一超也不好过。被封困在家的日子里，看不到前路，看不到希望，只看到自己的焦虑和不知道在为什么而奋斗的空虚。降薪都是能接受的挫折，被裁员，或公司倒闭才是真正的噩梦。那些艰难时刻，放眼望去，似乎每个人都跟我们一样孤独，无助。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;忘了是谁提议的开个多人视频，一开始就我和蒋一超、赵杰，晚上连线各自说说最近遇到的好玩的事。我们小心翼翼地避开一些词语，比如倒闭，崩溃，下滑，亏损等等，聊得很拘谨。有一次蒋一超说这样没意思，我们就踩雷吧，哪里是雷区咱往哪儿去，让它爆个痛快。我们第一次开诚布公地聊起焦虑，未来，迷茫，抑郁。解决不了问题，但敞开说可以释放内心的紧张。我觉得没那么孤独了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;后来蒋一蕊也加入。我们有时视频一开一整天，不一定聊天，只是开着手机放那里，各做各的事。蒋一蕊夜里写作业会忽然唱起歌，或忽然骂起娘来。有一回我做PPT头昏脑涨，手机里赵杰炒菜、切菜叮叮咣咣，我大喊，赵茄子你搞菜能不能小点儿声？蒋一超莫名其妙，抬起头嚷我，姑奶奶你又啥毛病犯了，正画图呢吓我一跳。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;后来赵杰说，有好几次，他一个人在店里忙，猛然间就像回到了小时候，四面八方都是质疑，好像连老天都在对他说，你不行。甚至不惜以一场疫情来警告他，你不行。这种时候跟自己说你能行，说多少遍都不管用了。他说他没多少文化，遇到这样大的挫折，除了怨天怨地不知道还能从哪里找原因。然后他想到了我和蒋一超，两个最初支持他的，有文化的人。连上视频才发现，有文化的我们所陷入的，是和没文化的他一样的困境。他很高兴，虽然不道德但他很高兴，原来这次不行不是他的问题。在成为有用的人之前我们是废人，在成为有用的人之后我们也有可能被一个大浪再次打成废人。他说非常感谢在那个时候，我们相互之间没有猜忌地拉住了彼此的手。最孤独绝望的时候，如果不是那一个又一个视频电话的陪伴，真诚的倾吐，他坚持不到最后。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我没有你们想象中那么有毅力，赵杰对我们说。是现实逼得人不得不坚持。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谁又不是呢。蒋一超说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022年底，封禁政策总算彻底放开。三年来，搭车小伙对赵杰不离不弃，封禁稍有放松就去店里帮忙，每每从老家过来，父母都会让他给赵杰带些自制的土特产。店还在，老伙计也在，赵杰说，留得青山在，不愁没柴烧。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2016年那场意外之后，当大家说起赵杰，没人再提先天不足这几个字，他成为一个可以被拿到正常标准下比较的普通人。疫情三年多少饭馆倒闭，而他却凭一己之力保住了店铺。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;二姨再次骄傲起来，养孩子，学上得好不好不是首要的，还是要看家长怎么教育。你看我们家赵杰&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;责任编辑：梅不谈&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;征稿信息见@ONE一个工作室置顶微博。更多编辑部的有趣日常请关注小红书：ONE一个编辑部。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpKk5N9eg_v2zyAkX7XPWYqc8YtG&quot; alt=&quot;伊朝南&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;伊朝南 &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@伊朝南&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;我是我的障碍，也是我的通途。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;关注&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;相关推荐&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6122&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;较量&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 伊朝南&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6081&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;禁忌&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 伊朝南&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6155)&quot;>;点击可下载ONE一个app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4051]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4193]]><description>&lt;div>;9 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fh1VMjqBt4IyHkXG0dWG11gmNUKz&quot; alt=&quot;首页图&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4051&lt;/span>;摄影| Tim Foster&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nov. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;大海或许让每条海岸都以为海是特地为它而来。&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>