<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[人为什么会沉浸于回忆过去？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3926]]><description> &lt;div>;5 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Qingshan Asks&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>;Why do people Will you be immersed in reminiscing about the past? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Simple psychological answer&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FryVjmusW5B-vwspoSZK7miJqim7&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FryVjmusW5B-vwspoSZK7miJqim7&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt; br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Defenders and opponents of memories are often at loggerheads. Defenders believe that memories always have a charm. In memories, my late grandfather’s cooking was the most delicious; Friendship is the purest; the cartoons I watched in my childhood and the games I played are all classics, so superior to those that children like now that I don’t know where they are&lt;em>;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/em>;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;The opponents retorted like this: The world has always been a mess, but at that time you were naive and your senses had not yet been opened, so you could follow any bad drama with relish. Some people were able to do it then, but not now. Some people were there then but are no longer there now, which adds to your illusion. Now you are complicated, suspicious, and picky. You resist instinctively and are often unhappy because you know better. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;So, why do we like to recall the past? Are memories really that good? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;1. In the past, we kept photos, but our memories are beautiful selfies. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We Memories of past experiences and events are called episodic memories. &lt;strong>;People often believe that the episodic memories they recall are accurate and true. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But this is not the case. From the time we remember something to the time we recall it afterwards, errors may occur at any point during the entire process. &lt;/strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The theory of reconstructed memory tells us: &lt;strong>;Recall is when we reconstruct a certain episodic memory&lt;/strong>;, and this process will be affected by many influences. Such as personal perception, imagination, memory of external objective facts, beliefs, social influence, etc. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For example, popular culture always tells us that it becomes harder for us to relate to the people around us as we grow up, so when we recall our childhood friendships, all we remember is eating potato chips with our friends. When I drink Coke and play games, I imagine that the relationship at that time was more &lt;em>;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/em>;purer&lt;em>;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>; than it is now. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Our brains will selectively forget the childish quarrels and undisguised malice in childhood relationships, and strengthen those &lt;em>;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/em>;Sharing snacks is a good friend&lt; em>;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>;a beautiful moment. &lt;em>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Also, our brains make up fiction when we only really remember certain aspects of something that happened in the past,&lt;/strong >;That is, using existing knowledge that has nothing to do with the event itself, &lt;em>;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/em>; automatically completes &lt;em>;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>; this memory, making the reconstructed memory more complete and coherent. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So in the process of reconstructing our memory, we often &lt;em>;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/em>;remember things that are wrong&lt;em>;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>;, or even far from the truth. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2. Things are still there, people are still there, but years are gone&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Reminiscing about the past is not only Missing a certain memory itself may also mean missing certain states of oneself&lt;/strong>;. There are some friends around me who always miss their student days and are always envious of those friends who are still in graduate school. There are also some married friends who always miss their single days. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What happened cannot be reversed, and the past cannot be turned back. &lt;strong>;Relative to the present, the past is an eternal loss. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When we grow up, we lose the carefree and relaxed feeling of not having to plan for the future when we were young; after working, we lose the winter and summer vacations of our student days, and those with friends. The time spent hanging out on campus with nothing to do; after getting married, we will also lose the freedom we had when we were single and in love, and shoulder many responsibilities that must be shouldered. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When we lose someone or something we love, it’s easy to get wrapped up in their memories. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;People who often recall how wonderful the past was are also remembering in this way a past that will never come again and has been beautified by our brains. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And this is exactly what those who oppose memories are wary of, Iori Iori&lt;/strong>; wrote on Weibo &lt;strong>;&lt;em>;@&lt;/em>;:&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;Li Ruotong appeared on TV with the sculpture, and Zhu Yin also appeared with the donkey. &quot;I Love My Family&quot; is going to be made into a big movie, so I have mixed feelings. I don’t want to see beauties languish, and I don’t want to see cold rice cooked again. Let the 1990s leave. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;3. Be cautious when immersing yourself in the past&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since our memories are unreal, the past has been lost Life, then the question arises: Is it necessarily bad to always miss the good past? Will there be any benefit? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The benefits are there, but they need to be treated with caution. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;em>;a.&lt;/em>;Notice the way you remember the past&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As we reminisce As a way of thinking about life, recalling the past can be beneficial to us when we ask ourselves what meaning our past experiences have brought to our lives. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, many people miss the past because they are comparing it with the present and are dissatisfied with the status quo, thinking that &lt;em>;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/em>;the past was much better than the present&lt;em>;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>;, &lt;em>;&amp;ldquo;&lt;/em>;Old times are life&lt;em>;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em>;. &lt;strong>;Researchers point out that remembering the past in this way does not bring any benefits to physical and mental health. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;b. Notice how often you miss the past&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;em>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em >;The frequency of recalling the past also needs to be controlled to achieve a balance between memories and reality. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;c. Notice if you feel uneasy in your attachment relationship&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past, studies have shown that nostalgia It can relieve some negative emotions, such as loneliness, emptiness and boredom, etc. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, a recent study pointed out that whether nostalgia can alleviate negative emotions is also related to the social relationship in which the individual is located. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Take the emotion of sadness as an example.&lt;strong>;For those who are insecure and lack confidence in social relationships, nostalgia cannot help them get over sadness very well. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;4. Memories are the embrace that we will eventually let go of. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So, if you find yourself I am immersed in the memories of the past and find it difficult to extricate myself. What should I do? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We may need some &lt;strong>;mindfulness practice&lt;/strong>;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mindfulness is a mental process. In this process, our thoughts will be brought back from the irreversible past and uncertain future to the here and now. We will feel more clearly that we are living in the present moment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The editor used to like nostalgia. Later, I suddenly discovered that the candied haws in old Beijing in my memory may be hard to find, but the newly opened hot pot restaurant on the street is also very good. When I was a child, it was wonderful to eat watermelon with a fan blowing in the hot summer, but now, in this hot summer, as long as I let I turn on the air conditioner and I think everything I eat is delicious. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Hold the memories tightly, you may get short-term comfort and warmth, but we all know that any hug in this world will end in letting go. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Li Jialong onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see @ONE一 for the call for papers information The studio pinned it to the top of Weibo. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FrAgJlwkHJ83vofVTBgwOc1o1VK -&quot; alt=&quot;Simple Psychology&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Simple Psychology&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>; Committed to providing high-quality psychological services and content. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Question and Answer&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/question/3919&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Why are some people afraid of praise? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3892&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What is an unequal intimate relationship? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3926)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[孤儿院]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6111]]><description> &lt;div>;5 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Two Old Bad&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FnyemXuNU76BHrxURW0A89_T1t5j&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FnyemXuNU76BHrxURW0A89_T1t5j&quot;>;&lt;/div >;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;This is a cemetery for young people. Some people are struggling. Some people sink, some people fall. A few years later, a children&#39;s paradise was built, and all memories were forgotten like a dream. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;That incident happened when I was fifteen years old. It was like a dream, and I couldn’t tell whether it was reality or fiction. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I first entered middle school, I was very confused. After a summer of absence, many people who were inconspicuous in elementary school suddenly became famous people. They smoke, drink, fight, go to game halls and billiards halls, have unwiped noses on their faces, and behave like adults. My mother always taught me to study hard and stay away from them. But it wasn’t long before I became one of them. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is related to an experience in primary school. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I was a child, there was a coal factory near my house. There was a red brick chimney in the coal factory, about twenty or thirty meters high. The exact number is unknown. The chimney is equipped with a U-shaped wrought iron ladder, which is section by section. From a distance, it looks like a zipper. When I was eleven years old, while the old janitor was taking a nap, a few boys of similar age and I sneaked into the coal factory to practice courage. The method is very simple, just climb up the chimney along the ladder and come down from the top, that&#39;s it. I know I&#39;m afraid of heights. I went to a classmate&#39;s house who lived on the sixth floor. When I stood on the open balcony and looked down twice, I would feel dizzy. But I was even more afraid of being regarded as a coward, so I gritted my teeth all the way up and held on to the handrail, not daring to look down. I was the second to last one to finish the climb. After I came down, I fell on the coal pile nearby, which caused a few laughs and curses. Two children were timid. One slipped away halfway, and the other climbed a third of the way. He lost his grip and almost fell. He didn&#39;t dare to go up again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The child who gave up halfway was later responsible for running errands and carrying backpacks. We played football, arrested people, and rode horses to fight. He could only watch and not participate. The child who slipped away in the middle was even worse. Several people threw him into the latrine of the school toilet. The teachers were helpless until the excrement master came and picked him up with a long excrement spoon. After picking him up, the teachers took him to the playground, took off his clothes, connected a leather tube, turned him in circles and poured water on him, and rinsed him for a long time. Not long after, he transferred to another school and his whereabouts were unknown and no one asked about him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later, this scene often appeared in my dreams, and the protagonist became myself: covered in shit, standing naked on the playground, and everyone was pointing at me and laughing. Every time I wake up, I feel lucky that I didn’t lose my chain that day when I climbed the chimney. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is why I took the initiative to become a ruffian. In fact, I just don’t want to be cornered, have my money taken from me, get punched a few times, and then leave in despair. Just like I don&#39;t want to be thrown into a pit. I would rather let someone else suffer this, even if the cost is becoming an abuser. Thinking about it later, I realized that I was still practicing courage in essence, but in a different form. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The situation exceeded my expectations. In the first two years of junior high school, I followed a group of gangster friends and ran rampant on campus. Many people are afraid of me. In their eyes, I am an out-and-out hooligan. In fact, I only take action when there are many people on my side. The funny thing is, this actually brought me some unrealistic reputations, and when other people heard about these reputations, they would be even more afraid of me. I feel like I am the fox riding the tiger, but no one knows I am a fox. No one knows that even tigers are made of paper. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among the ruffian friends, Wang Zhao and I have the closest relationship. We were classmates in elementary school, and it was Wang Zhao who took the lead when we threw people into the latrine. He has a bad temper, and a look or a brush against his shoulder can be a reason to take action. He is a very good fighter and knows exactly where his fist hurts and where it doesn&#39;t. Wang Zhao said that these were learned from his stepmother. His father was a lawyer. When he first remembered, he drove his mother away and lived with his stepmother. The stepmother always carries him in secret and often pinches or pinches him secretly. Wang Zhao was not convinced and always fought with his stepmother. At first, he was too young and couldn&#39;t beat his stepmother. Over time, he slowly figured out some tricks. For example, hitting the corner of the eye or the bridge of the nose will make the person unable to open their eyes and unable to fight back. For another example, hitting the ribs and lower abdomen will cause short-term breath loss and make it difficult to recover. The stepmother gradually couldn&#39;t defeat him, and finally disappeared one morning, taking away all the cash in the house. Life became even more difficult. His father began to drink heavily and lost his job. He would often break into the room drunk, curse and carry him to the living room, and beat him severely. Wang Zhao said, it doesn&#39;t matter, sooner or later the old bastard will know how powerful he is. When he said this, he had just obtained a Japanese tanto from other places and was waxing the blade with a focused expression. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Every time Wang Zhao mentions his dad, I will think of my dad. When I was a child, he often took me to pull briquettes. When he went there, he rode a tricycle with my mother and me in the bucket. When he came back, he carried briquettes in the bucket. I rode in front and they pushed behind. Passing by a cooperative on the way, there was an old lady selling candied haws at the door. My dad would buy two candied haws, and he and my mother would eat one, and I would eat one myself. My dad was originally a lathe, working in a belt factory. After I was laid off, I bought a second-hand Xiali and rented it out. I traveled under the stars and moon every day and often came home in the middle of the night. In early 1998, he fell ill and went to the hospital to find out he had advanced liver cancer. The doctor asked him to be hospitalized, but he was unwilling, saying that he was not as comfortable as at home. So I went home and went to the hospital regularly for chemotherapy. My hair fell out quickly and my eyes turned yellow like a Persian cat. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That summer, during the summer vacation after graduating from elementary school, I swam in the Children&#39;s Palace. I just swam back and forth, and when I looked up, I saw my dad standing on the edge of the pool, smiling at me. He was wearing dark blue khaki work clothes, with thick black hair, fair skin, and the jaundice in his eyes was gone. He looked only in his thirties. I said, Dad, are you okay? He nodded and said, son, you swam well. I&#39;m very happy because he seldom praises me. He also said, son, study hard and become a college student in the future. Don’t be like your father and have no future. I nodded and said, Dad, come down and swim for a while? He said, no, just swim, dad is gone. After that he left. After swimming for a while, a neighbor hurriedly walked in and called my name into the swimming pool. I swam over and held on to the shore. The man said, &quot;Your mother asked you to go home quickly. Your father passed away.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Back to the topic. Wang Zhao had a girlfriend named Lulu, who was one year older than us and a repeater from another middle school. She was also the direct cause of that incident. Lulu likes to wear high heels and clothes that expose her navel. She likes to wear lipstick, earrings, and dark eye shadow. She dyed her hair blonde and sat on the back seat of Wang Zhao&#39;s Suzuki motorcycle. When the wind blew, it was like a burning flame. Wang Zhao said that they met in the billiard hall, and Lulu borrowed time from him and went back and forth, which was a matter of course. After they got along, they hung out with us in the open air, got into fights, and liked to kick people in the bottom with the small heels of their high heels. To be honest, I kind of hate her. Although she is very beautiful, she is a stinky idiot who opens her mouth and shuts her mouth. She is not like a girl. I also heard some rumors that someone saw her in front of a private clinic. I heard that the clinic specialized in abortions for underage girls. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the second half of the third year of junior high school, Lulu passed by Sanluju Middle School and was accosted by a few gangsters. She refused, but her attitude was not good, and a conflict broke out between the two parties. The other party relied on the large number of people and slapped Lulu twice in the mouth. Lulu immediately put down her harsh words and told the other party not to leave if they had the guts to do so, and to come back to gather the troops and prepare to fight to the death. There are thirteen of us in total. Before setting off, Wang Zhao asked us to take our guys with us. He took the Japanese tanto with him, wrapped it in a layer of newspaper and pinned it to his waist. I took off the newspaper and tried it with my fingers. The blade was sharp and could easily penetrate a person&#39;s body. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Spring had just begun, everything was coming back to life, and the days were gradually getting longer. I don’t know why, but I suddenly thought of death, my dad, and my mom. At this time, my mother should be on the street, cleaning the streets while dodging passing cars. She worked in the same workshop as my father. After she was laid off, a relative introduced her to work as a sanitation worker. She had no establishment and was paid according to her work. When my father was alive, he often told her jokes. My mother loved to laugh, and she had two beautiful dimples when she smiled. In my impression, they rarely quarreled and always had the same position. My mother would definitely not agree to anything that my father would not allow. After my dad left, someone advised my mom, who was only in her early forties, to take a step forward. My mother refused, saying that the child was still young and she was afraid that I would be wronged. Later, she seldom smiled, maybe because she understood my various performances in school. Maybe it&#39;s because my dad is dead and there&#39;s no one to tease her anymore. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thinking of this, I suddenly felt a cramp. When I was approaching Sanluju, there was a public toilet on the roadside. I ran to the door of the public toilet and told Wang Zhao, &quot;You go first, I will chase you later.&quot; Wang Zhao cursed and said, &quot;I&#39;m lazy ass.&quot; Lulu glanced at me and followed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I arrived at the entrance of Sanluju Middle School, I saw them all squatting on the ground with their hands on the back of their heads, including many wearing Sanluju school uniforms. The police lights flashed, two police cars parked nearby, and several police officers patrolled back and forth, kicking someone in the butt from time to time. Wang Zhao saw me and winked at me, telling me not to go there. Lulu was also looking at me with complicated eyes. I turned and left. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later I heard from Wang Zhao that the police did not give them any trouble. They stayed at the police station for half the night, confiscated all the weapons, notified the school and parents, and then released them. This is what he told me before leaving school on the day he was expelled. All participants were punished, including major demerits and probation. Because of Lulu, Wang Zhao is considered the organizer, so his crime is naturally increased. After that, I didn&#39;t see them for a long time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In April, most of the gangsters participated in the recruitment and left the school. I was preparing to take the high school entrance examination and rarely got together with them. When I met them occasionally, I just said hello. When I first entered middle school, my grades were pretty good and I was at the top of my grade. After taking the exam, the teacher said that my foundation was still there and that I didn’t need to think about going to a key high school. I would work hard in the remaining time and there wouldn’t be a big problem in my high school. A friend who is a ruffian said, &quot;You are awesome. You can&#39;t tell, but you are still a good student.&quot; I thought of the child who was thrown into the latrine again, and said, you are the damn good student. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Not long ago, Wang Zhao came to see me for the last time. During that time, I stayed up late every day, reading books and doing questions, desperately trying to find what I had left behind. My family lives on the second floor. At about 11 o&#39;clock in the evening, there was a roar of motorcycles downstairs. After a while, someone threw stones at the window. I looked down through the window and saw that it was Wang Zhao and Lulu was there. My mother is next door and has already gone to bed. She has an early morning shift tomorrow and will be cleaning the streets before five o&#39;clock. I tiptoed to the door and was about to go out when I heard my mother cough. After waiting for a while, I heard no other sound. I gently closed the door and walked out. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I went downstairs, I found that I still had the Walkman in my hand. My mother bought the Walkman so that I could practice my English listening without having to turn over the tape. I had used it to listen to music before, but recently I had to straighten it out. I told Wang Zhao, why are you here so late? Wang Zhao sat on the car seat and threw me a cigarette. There were some bruises on his face, and there was a bruise on the corner of his right eye and a big bump. Let the old bastard come out and stay with you for a while, he said. I glanced at Lulu on the back seat of the motorcycle. She was wearing a short skirt and her long legs were wrapped in black stockings. She leaned back and rested her arms on the seat cushion. I said, it’s almost the second model and I still have to review. Lulu said, do you have money? Get some and we&#39;ll leave as we speak. I ignored her and looked at Wang Zhao. Wang Zhao said, I will pay you back later. I said, no money. Lulu snorted. I said, I really don’t have money, why don’t you ask someone else. Wang Zhao said that he had gone to several people and scraped together three melons and two dates, but it was not enough to cover the night in the Internet cafe. I don&#39;t want to dwell on this issue anymore, saying, where are you going? Internet cafe? Lulu said, do you care? I said, you are fucking addicted, am I recruiting you? Lulu got out of the car, rolled up her sleeves and said, Damn, you idiot is still going strong. Wang Zhao shouted, &quot;Stop fucking.&quot; Lulu crossed her arms and turned her head to the side. We all fell silent. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After a while, Wang Zhao sighed and said, forget it, think about it again, the worst is that I will sleep on the grave. Lulu said, Huh? I remembered one thing. There was an abandoned garden to the west of Marco Polo Bridge. There was a small building inside. It seemed quite big. It should be okay for a night. Wang Zhao said, what kind of abandoned garden? I said, I know, it was an orphanage, but it was later abandoned and I heard it was haunted. Wang Zhao said, have you been there? I said, my father was buried in Taizi Valley, and I passed by there when I was sweeping his grave. Lulu glanced at me. Wang Zhao said, OK, go and have a look. I said, you go ahead, I&#39;m going back. Lulu suddenly snatched the Walkman from my hand and said, let’s go together. I stared at her and said, give it back. Lulu raised her head with a provocative smile on her face. I glanced at Wang Zhao and gave up the idea of ​​grabbing him head-on. I said, stop making trouble, I still want to review. Lulu said, stay with us for a while and we will send it back to you later. Wang Zhao also said, let&#39;s go and change our minds. I really want to say, fuck you, I don’t want it anymore. But I really couldn&#39;t bear to part with this big item like a Walkman, so I had no choice but to give in. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That place is about ten kilometers away from my home. Wang Zhao rode the bike, Lulu sat behind him, and I sat behind Lulu. Lulu hugged Wang Zhao&#39;s waist. I didn&#39;t want to hug Lulu&#39;s waist, so I had to put my hands on my legs. Passing a section of dirt road in the middle, I almost got thrown off, so I subconsciously grabbed Lulu&#39;s shoulder. She looked back at me and said, idiot, hold on tight, I won&#39;t save you if you fall. I said what nonsense. But his hands were still on her shoulders. Lulu&#39;s shoulders were so narrow that I could even feel the outline of her collarbone. There was a strange fragrance on her body, I didn&#39;t know if it was perfume, but the wind blew it into my nose. A strange thought suddenly occurred to me, hoping that Wang Zhao would keep riding like this and never stop. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;About twenty minutes later, we turned into a dark path. There were no street lights, it was dark on both sides of the road and nothing could be seen clearly. After a while, the orphanage appeared in the front right, with walls extending to both sides, and the wrought iron gates were half open and half closed. Entering the yard, there was a four-story building in front of him. The car lights hit the wall, like a giant mouth ready to swallow everything. The ground is covered with gray stone bricks, most of which are cracked to varying degrees. When you step on them, they will suddenly sink, as if some mysterious mechanism has been activated. Weeds grew wildly in the gaps between the stone bricks, and the clumps stood upright and swayed in the wind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said, this place is too deserted, let’s find another place. Wang Zhao has turned off his motorcycle and is walking towards the building door with Lulu. Lulu said, this idiot is scared. I said, I&#39;m not a coward, I don&#39;t have a flashlight, I&#39;m just blinding myself, if I get bumped, why bother. Wang Zhao took out a lighter, lit it and said, &quot;Come here, let&#39;s go in and take a look first.&quot; After saying that, they walked into the small building, and I had to follow them. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The structure of the small building is very similar to that of a hotel, with each floor looking similar: a long corridor in the middle, and rooms of more than ten square meters on both sides. There were some desks and chairs left on the first floor, scattered in several rooms, covered with thick dust. There are a few empty rooms on the second to fourth floors, and the other rooms seem to be dormitories. Most of them have bunk beds. Judging from the area, they can accommodate up to four people. Most of the windows were empty. As I walked through the small building, gusts of cold wind blew through me from time to time, making my back feel tight. Cartoon patterns are painted on the walls of some rooms, and a group of children are running on the green grass, chasing the sun. Large areas of wall paint peeled off, some children had no heads, and some were missing arms and legs, which looked very strange. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We picked up a notebook on the ground. The kraft paper cover was badly worn. I picked it up and flipped through it, and on the first page there was a crooked line: I am six years old, and my mother asked me to keep a diary. Both writing and memorizing are marked in pinyin. Continuing to scroll back, most of them record the content of daily life, using a mix of Chinese characters and pinyin. Sometimes they write about how delicious my father&#39;s cooking is, sometimes they write about going to the park with my mother, and sometimes they simply write about the weather that day. When I turned to the middle, there was a page that read: My father drank and beat my mother. My mother cried and I was scared. Starting from this page, almost every page begins with the same sentence: Dad drank and beat Mom. Turn to the last page and write: Mom is dead, he is the devil. The word &quot;Devil&quot; is written in a large size, and there is no mistake in it. The back was gone, and all the pages were torn off, leaving only jagged tear marks. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After walking around the small building, we returned to the door. There were no ghosts or moths, and I secretly breathed a sigh of relief. Wang Zhao said, yes, it’s no problem for one night. I said, do you really plan to live here? Lulu said, why don’t you live here and live at your house? I said, what about tomorrow? Wang Zhao said, we will talk about tomorrow tomorrow. I nodded and said, take me back. Lulu said, we are not leaving, you can go by yourself. I said, it was agreed just now. Lulu made a surprised expression and said, idiot, you really believe it. Wang Zhao also said, why don&#39;t you leave, I have the cards, and the three of us will fight the landlord. I suppressed my anger, stretched out my hand and said to Lulu, &quot;Give me the Walkman, you two just stay alone.&quot; Wang Zhao said, do you really plan to walk back? I said, I have to go home. Lulu threw her Walkman to me and said, &quot;You can leave if you can. It will be dawn when we get home.&quot; I turned around and left. Wang Zhao grabbed my arm and said, &quot;Okay, let&#39;s do this. I want to poop now. You can wait a while and I&#39;ll take it back to you after I poop.&quot; I thought about it and said, OK. Wang Zhao looked around and ran towards the back of the small building. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lulu and I sat on the steps at the door waiting for Wang Zhao. We sat on one side and ignored the other. I looked up at the sky. There was no moon. The sky was not black, but a dull blue. Lulu suddenly said, was it you who called the police last time? I turned to look at her. She said, we were all injured that time at Sanluju, but you were the only one who was fine. I said, don&#39;t talk nonsense. If it weren&#39;t for the stomachache, I would have folded it. Lulu said, you really think of us as fools. I said, what do you mean? She said, I asked the police, and they said it was a half-grown man who made the call. His voice hadn’t even finished yet. Who else could it be besides you? I said, maybe it was the other party who reported it, and I was scared. Lulu said that the Sanluju gang was also arrested and none of them ran away. Is he sick? Call the police to arrest him? I can&#39;t argue with that. After a moment of silence, I said, I shouldn&#39;t use the knife. She said, admitted it? I gritted my teeth and hummed softly. Lulu looked at me for a while and said, Damn, it’s really you. what did I say? She said, the police didn’t say anything. Use your brain, can someone tell me? Idiot, I lied to you. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I stood up and stared at Lulu. She raised her eyelids and said, what do you want to do? In fact, I didn&#39;t know. I couldn&#39;t move forward or retreat for a while, and I was frozen in place. Lulu waved her hand towards me and motioned for me to sit down. She said, stop fucking pretending, don&#39;t you dare touch me. I still stood and said, that&#39;s not necessarily the case. She sneered and said, I know you don&#39;t want to see me, and to be honest, I don&#39;t want to see you either. You are different from us. I said, what&#39;s the difference? She said, just like that time in Sanluju, both sides had knives. If they really took action, something would probably happen. Thinking about it now, I&#39;m really scared. But when I went there, I didn&#39;t think about this. I only had one thought in my mind: kill them. When something happens, it happens, and I may regret it, or I may not. Anyway, I can&#39;t think about that much. You are different. I have observed that you are measured and never do anything dirty. I&#39;m sure you are not the kind of person who is willing to take risks. To use an analogy, it&#39;s like a dog squeezed into a wolf&#39;s den. No matter how you grin, you&#39;re still a dog. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was speechless and looked at Lulu again. Her eyes were shining brightly, like two X-ray lamps. She lit a cigarette, took a puff, and continued, &quot;There&#39;s nothing wrong with you doing this. On the contrary, it&#39;s quite enviable.&quot; I said, I don&#39;t understand. She said that there are worries only when there are concerns. In short, I guess you called the police based on your feelings and no evidence. I said, so you have been targeting me today? Lulu smiled and said, yes, if Wang Zhao hadn&#39;t been soft-hearted, he should have let you walk back and exhausted yourself, you stinking idiot. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was not angry, but had a very strong desire to communicate with her. Before today, I hardly knew her. I only knew that she was Wang Zhao&#39;s girlfriend, a girl who was full of foul words, dressed in avant-garde clothes, and was riddled with rumors. I have never had a serious chat with her, including Wang Zhao, including those ruffian friends. I have always been pretentious and looked at them with a critical eye. It wasn&#39;t until just now that I realized how ridiculous I was. It only took one metaphor to expose my hypocrisy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said, have you ever thought about the future? Lulu said, what future? I said, it’s impossible to hang around for the rest of your life, there must be a way out. She said that she had never thought about it and was too lazy to think about it. I said, sooner or later we have to face reality. She said, idiot, do you know what reality is? I said, of course I know. When I get into high school, then get into a good university, and find a good job, my mother won’t have to sweep the streets, and my father will be able to rest in peace. She shook her head and said, no, this is your reality, not mine. I said, what is your reality? She said that when I was three years old, my parents went to Guangzhou to buy color TV sets and died in a car accident. The bodies were not taken to Beijing and were cremated on the spot. What was sent back to Beijing were two jars of ashes, which were buried in Taiziyu. I live with my grandparents, and they don&#39;t care much about me and can&#39;t control me. Two years ago, I got a boyfriend. He swore to me that he would marry me in the future, which was actually a fart. But he didn’t understand at the time, so he confessed to himself. Then I got pregnant and the man ran away. I had an abortion and took a year off from school. When I went back to school, I couldn&#39;t keep up, and I had no intention of learning anymore. high school? University? It&#39;s not what people like me can think about, this is the reality. After Lulu finished speaking, she smiled at me. It wasn&#39;t her usual smile, it was a helpless and tired smile. I wanted to say a few words of relief, but no matter how I organized the words, they felt inappropriate, so I had to remain silent. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A gust of night wind blew by, and I shivered. Suddenly I remembered that Wang Zhao had been gone for a long time, and it wouldn’t take that long to pull a string. I said, he won&#39;t be lost. Lulu also felt something was wrong. She looked behind the small building and muttered, &quot;It&#39;s not that bad.&quot; She called Wang Zhao twice at the top of her lungs, but there was no response. She turned to me and said, &quot;I&#39;ll go take a look.&quot; I said, I will go too. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We walked around to the back of the small building. It was no different from the front of the building, with stone bricks, walls and weeds. There was no sign of Wang Zhao. I sniffed hard, but there was no smell, only a gray smell unique to ruins. I was afraid that Wang Zhao would suddenly jump out and scare people, saying loudly, &quot;Stop fucking hiding, I&#39;ve already seen you.&quot; Except for the clicking sound of the soles of the shoes on the stone bricks, the surroundings were as quiet as a tomb. Lulu walked to a wall and suddenly said, look. I took a closer look and saw that a piece of the wall collapsed, revealing a gap and a dense forest outside. Lulu said that this fool might have felt embarrassed and ran inside to pull him away. He was quite thin-skinned. She shouted a few more times into the woods, but there was still no response. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lulu rubbed at the gap, walked out of the wall, lit a lighter, and walked deeper into the woods. I said, it&#39;s too dark inside, why don&#39;t I wait for him here. Lulu didn&#39;t even look back, saying you don&#39;t need to go, I&#39;ll just go. To be honest, the unfamiliar environment in the dark did make me hesitate. While hesitating, Lulu&#39;s figure had disappeared deep into the woods. An inexplicable feeling of fear instantly surrounded me, as if I had been abandoned. I quickly climbed out of the wall and chased in the direction of Lulu. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After walking through the woods for a while, there was still no sign of Lulu. The leaves were rustling, and I began to worry that I was the one who had lost my way and would never get out. Suddenly there was a thud from the front, as if something heavy had fallen into the water. I moved forward in search of the sound and ran to the place where the sound came from. My foot slipped and I almost fell.视野一下开阔了，眼前突然出现一片湖面。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;湖的面积很大，漆黑浑浊，深不见底。脚下是一道很陡的斜坡，大概三米多高，一直向下延伸到湖里。光线昏暗，地势的陡然变化极难察觉。我马上明白了，露露可能是掉下去了。我看着湖水，水面上的涟漪在逐渐褪去。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;夜风森森，周围杂草丛生。我站在陡坡上，喊了两声露露和王钊的名字。我的声音嘶哑，干裂，听起来笨拙而空洞。湖面已经归于平静，像是从未有人落水一样。我想，王钊或许也是这么掉下去的，或许所有人掉进湖里的过程都差不多：从某个陡坡上不慎滑落，发出咕咚一声，从远处听，像是一块无足轻重的石头，而非一个活生生的人。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我转身走回树林，想要找根长一点儿的树枝。我知道这是徒劳的。不知道湖的深度，普通树枝根本捅不到底，即使有足够长的树枝，也无法承担他们的重量。我只是觉得，我必须做点儿什么。虽然，他们掉进湖里不是我的错。我完全可以转身离开，不会有人知道我来过。走回家可能需要很久，几个小时，甚至整整一晚，但肯定能够走到。也许到家时，会正好撞见我妈，不过无所谓，她只会骂我几句，顶多打我几下，绝不会真的伤害我。我不该为此负责任，就像露露说的，这就是现实。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;可我无法说服自己独自离去。他们不该被淹没在这个地方。我只想找到他们，和他们一起离开。于是我走出树林，回到陡坡边缘，犹豫了一下，一个猛子扎进湖里。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;湖水真凉啊。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;冰冷的湖水刺痛着每一寸皮肤。我艰难地睁开眼，四下昏黑，目不视物。我开始向湖底下潜，我知道，王钊和露露就在那儿。我感受着他们同样的环境，感受着同样的黑暗，孤独和绝望。也许他们挣扎过，奋力上浮，又被迫沉底，如此反复数次，筋疲力尽以后，只能随波逐流。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;游了一会儿，我感觉快要憋不住气了。然后，我看见了他们。一个，两个，接着是第三个和第四个。无数尸体戳在湖底。有我认识的人，也有我不认识的人。这里就像是一座坟场，少年的坟场。他们的脸发出幽暗的青光，神情空洞，脚埋在松软的泥土里，只露出半截被水藻缠绕住的小腿，好像已经和环境融成了一体。我想要伸手抓住他们的手臂，但滑如泥鳅，根本无法攥紧。肺快要憋炸了，湖水开始从牙齿的缝隙灌进嘴里。我的身体不受控制地上浮，眼看着他们离我越来越远。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;浮出水面时，我大口呼吸着空气，挣扎着爬到岸边。我躺在地上望着灰暗的天空，头脑中空白一片。那里没有王钊和露露。我安慰自己，已经尽力了，有些事情并非我能改变。我强打着精神爬起身，沿着来时的路返回。湖水坠在身上，仿佛有千万斤重量。终于挪到大路旁边，我再难坚持，趴倒在柏油路面上。我又想起了我妈，不知为什么，此时此刻，我非常想念她。意识逐渐变得模糊，朦朦胧胧中，似乎听见她在呼唤我的名字。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;醒来时，我躺在家里的床上，已经是第二天傍晚。我发着高烧，头脑昏沉，如同刚从一场噩梦中醒来。我妈没去上班，留在家里照顾我。昨天晚上，我出门时她就醒了，一直站在楼上看着我们。本以为我会很快回去，没想到我坐上了王钊的摩托车。她骑着自行车一路追赶，像没头苍蝇一样在卢沟桥附近转了两个小时，最后才在大路旁边发现了晕倒的我。我妈哭着说，你要是有个三长两短，妈也不活了。我也哭了，说妈，你放心，以后我一定好好的，不让你担心了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我没跟我妈说过湖底尸体的事儿，因为我也分不清，那到底是真实的还是虚幻的，所以只能说自己是不小心跌到了湖里。高烧持续了三天三夜。病好以后，我顺利考上了本校高中，毕业之后进入一所知名大学就读。过了几年，那座孤儿院被拆掉了。原址上盖起一个度假村，里面有座巨大的水上乐园，很多大人带着孩子去玩儿。湖底尸体好像一直没有被人发现过，也许真的只是个噩梦吧。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上大学时，我见过王钊和露露一次。在公共汽车上，看见王钊骑着摩托，叼着烟，露露仍然坐在后座。两个人的头发都染成了紫色，如同两个幽灵，从窗外一闪而过。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我不喜欢紫色，紫色是孤独的颜色。 &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;责任编辑：李嘉龙&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;征稿信息见@ONE一个工作室置顶微博。更多编辑部的有趣日常请关注小红书：ONE一个编辑部。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmeP5rZ0UGuNGbmhXfqoEh6dpKK5&quot; alt=&quot;二老坏&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;二老坏 &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;人如其名&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;关注&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;相关推荐&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6091&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;新衣&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 馨乔&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6111)&quot;>;点击可下载ONE一个app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4016]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4152]]><description>&lt;div>;5 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fmx1_M1pHmZNQ2UBRPwKWO_KzPhw&quot; alt=&quot;首页图&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4016&lt;/span>;摄影| Liz Sanchez&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;5&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oct. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;有的人精于计算，有的人勤于劳作，怎么选择都不错。判断得与失的时限大概要拉长一些，或许是一辈子。&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 05 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>