<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[你上一次迅速融入新环境的社交手段是什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3984]]><description> &lt;div>;21 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Sleep more comfortably&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p >;What was the last social method you used to quickly integrate into a new environment? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Li Meili&#39;s answer&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FizuQeyIWF_yGb1qW2-uziefF-9V&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FizuQeyIWF_yGb1qW2-uziefF-9V&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Smoking&lt;/strong>; was my first &lt;strong>;&amp;ldquo;sacrifice&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>; in the workplace. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is a bad habit that is harmful to the body, especially since I am a girl, and the social comments are even more unfriendly. But at its initial starting point, I was actually very pious, motivated, and even brave. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2014, I switched jobs to a leading social media marketing company in the industry. At that time, &quot;new media&quot; was not as sophisticated as it is now. It was a new industry that was truly created out of nothing, and naturally it did not spawn so many scammers and tricks. Everything in a new company is new, especially the people. There is a group of young people gathered within the company, including Douban celebrities, Weibo jokesters, and big bosses from 4A companies who are optimistic about the new industry. In short, everyone looks like they are growing up without restraint. We have no hierarchy or weakened system. Everyone only cheers for the content. Whoever has the most explosive creativity must be the well-deserved King &amp; Queen this month. In short, in the new circle of colleagues, people are only divided into &quot;really interesting&quot; and &quot;boring&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I am eager to integrate into the new environment, but it is very slow. I am always slow to talk about things that everyone is talking about. During team building, everyone shows off their talents, but I am the only one who is worried. I even secretly regretted that when I was a child, my parents should have put a gun on my head and asked me to learn an electronic keyboard or something else. At least I could show in the &quot;talent show&quot; that I was a person who had a life besides work. Fun people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While others are singing and cheering, I am cautious. I hate myself for being cautious. I am so boring! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;I want to be bold! I want to relax! I want to behave like everyone else, I am an uninhibited and dissolute young man! So, let me smoke! &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I joined in every work break, everyone gathered in a small group, stood around a small smoking stove, and puffed away. As for socializing, this is how it is often played in TV and movies. Come on, click on it, and life can be breathed in and spit out instantly. All gains and losses, grievances and grievances are nothing! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Successful. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 24-year-old’s social skills worked. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I quickly became involved with all the company smokers. Everyone yells at each other to go to the balcony to rest. A cigarette seems to be the best time to socialize, not too long or too short. If you are embarrassed, just stay silent and pretend to be busy, and time can quickly slip through your fingers. In short, everything seemed to become easier in the smoke. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later, I continued this habit of maintaining social contact for a year or two, and then it stopped working. With the ban on indoor smoking, smoking has become an uninhibited thing. I began to find that the smoker culture was gradually losing its effectiveness.&lt;strong>;It had some loopholes and bugs. It evolved from &quot;I joined on my own initiative&quot; to &quot;I can&#39;t refuse&quot;. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It’s a bit like social networking. I used to take the initiative to join a bureau because I was too eager. Later, I couldn&#39;t refuse, because everyone was standing there, and you seemed a bit pretentious when you shook your head. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I gave this thing too much meaning, but in fact it has no meaning at all. Social networking is just the accumulation of time, waiting for a breakthrough point, or it will always be indifferent. When I was young, I longed to be playful, interesting, and different. As I grew older, I discovered that smoking was a habit that was &quot;harmful to health&quot; written on the cigarette box (that huge sentence). It was a switch for emotional stress. When combined with deep breathing of nicotine, it was easy to create the illusion of relaxation. Holding the cigarette in your hand is like a declaration of &quot;I&#39;m not afraid.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The excitement in youth can be very lively no matter what. Smoking is fun, complaining is fun, talking about emotions and sharing secrets are fun. They dispersed as they grew up. Smoking was to avoid the crowd. Keep everyone far away and never get together again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sharing secrets is pretentious, and complaining too much can turn into a monster that extorts emotional value. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In short, the &quot;social charm&quot; slowly dissipates. &lt;strong>;Social interaction consumes people. &quot;Social interaction&quot; will gradually return to calm as you grow up. Talk about things when you have something to do. Let me wait quietly alone when there is nothing to do. It is best to eliminate ineffective social interactions and resume recharging. The way. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Friends, it is best not to smoke, at least it is useless for social interaction. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Nanaonewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see @ONE Studio’s pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. &lt;/p>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Question and Answer&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3982&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;At what point did you become an adult? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3981&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What worries does &quot;E-man&quot; have? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3980&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Have you ever been &quot;emotionally blackmailed&quot;? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3984)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[反正最后每个人都孤独]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6171]]><description> &lt;div>;21 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Zhou Hongxiang&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data -author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fp3U142QdrebnzcocBCp3pgDaiKe&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fp3U142QdrebnzcocBCp3pgDaiKe&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The conversations between Akai and I were interspersed between reality and imagination, and love was at this moment There are endless possibilities. After the story is told, we still have to face loneliness, but in the end everyone is lonely anyway. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He fell in love with her at the first sight. This kind of love seems a bit cheap in the eyes of most people, because they don’t have After the test of time, they don’t even know each other well. They don’t even know each other’s financial income, family situation, love experience, and zodiac signs. Falling in love with someone just based on their face is very abrupt and impulsive. However, this kind of relationship often doesn&#39;t last too long, and may even be fleeting after a passionate late night, but he still feels that it is worth a try. He hadn&#39;t liked someone for a long time, and there were quite a few people coming and going around him. He spent enough time on the possible ways to make lovers, and finally found that other than ordinary people who were not attracted to him repeatedly. Entering his life, the rest of the time is spent alone in bed thinking about the emptiness of life. So, love is love, why not, what are you waiting for if you don’t seize the opportunity? On this night, he would struggle for more than five minutes, watching the other person&#39;s eyes in the box where the glasses were being exchanged to see if there was any possibility of them falling on him. When his friends were squeezing towards the center one by one, he chose to get closer to her. Everyone was a little drunk at that time, listening to the organizer introducing so-and-so, so-and-so and so-and-so. Everyone added each other on WeChat, but he was not interested in these people. When it was her turn to pick up the phone, he seemed frightened. The people in the box were still singing sad love songs, but they were communicating privately on WeChat. , he could feel the desire in her heart, let&#39;s call it the reaction of the moment of being loved. This reaction was strong and ready to come out. As long as he said a few more words, they should be able to go home together after the show. But after all, he didn&#39;t say anything out of the ordinary. He just expressed that he was bored at the bar and wanted to go out to take a breather. He asked her what she usually likes to do, and then teased other people present, including of course his friend, and even some who were off-key. song. She smiled on her phone, with a smiling expression, and then sent some cute emojis. Finally, he asked, are you single? The other party hesitated for a moment before replying, &quot;Yes, otherwise.&quot; He said, what a coincidence, so am I. It was almost clear, but there was a bloated uncle between them. The uncle was burping while eating the fried chicken and popcorn on the plate. She kept looking down at her phone, and he was looking at her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is a scene from a novel that I made up. It is not necessarily a fiction. It certainly contains a lot of scenes that I have observed in real life. This is similar to It is related to Akai. The story was originally his, but I made some fictional processing. After listening to my description, Akai said, no, it’s not the other way around. It was me who added the WeChat message next to her, but it wasn’t me who took the initiative to send her the message, it was she who sent it to me. She said that the wine shop was boring and stuffy, and she wanted to go out to take a breather. She glanced at me after sending the message, and then walked out first. I probably wanted to follow her out at that time, but the people next to me were pulling me to drink. And it was too obvious to go out together. There was no way I could do that kind of thing. After she left for a while, I made an excuse to go out to the bathroom. I ran to the terrace at the gate and saw her. She asked me if I wanted to smoke. We could have chatted for a while. We could have talked about anything. I liked her, but we couldn&#39;t fall in love. Love was too hasty. There must be an emotional foundation, and I was stuck in time, mentally calculating how long it would take me to pee, how long it would take to walk from the box to the toilet, how long it would take to wash my hands, and how long it would take to vomit while drunk. I couldn&#39;t waste too much time. Outside, otherwise disappearing into the box together will definitely attract people&#39;s attention. In fact, I didn&#39;t smoke or talk too much to her. I drank some wine at that time. I could ask her what her plans were after the show, but if I asked, our relationship would only develop into a one-night stand. There was nothing else, so I didn’t ask. But I asked her a question, I said, since it&#39;s so boring, why don&#39;t you just find an excuse and leave first? She took this as a hint that I would leave here alone with her, and then said, that would be a good idea, and asked me if there was anywhere I wanted to go. I said there is not much place, maybe we can go hiking. I thought I was crazy at that time. I said go hiking and she said yes, but I obviously said it casually because I had drunk too much. In order not to be embarrassed, I added, but the scenery may be better when climbing during the day, and then They smiled at each other. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I asked him, have you returned to the box? Or really just let go and go with her. At this time, the story should have a turning point, but he asked me, if you were to write a novel, how would you continue writing it? I lit a cigarette, thought about it, and asked him, what do you like about her? Akai said, feeling, isn’t liking just feeling? What else could it be? Sometimes you always think that you want to like a good-looking person, or someone with a great temperament, but when you really meet the person you like, you find that the person is actually nothing, just a feeling that moves you, is very comfortable, and you are willing Talk to her, you want to know more about her, you may even want to get close to her, touch her, feel her, what else? I said, at that time, the person organizing the game should have called you and asked you where you were. You wanted to continue talking to her, but had to go back, but you made an appointment with her the next day. Maybe we&#39;ll meet again on the weekend, but when you return to the box, she&#39;s back too. Sure enough, someone made a joke about you, but this joke made you both uncomfortable, and even had the opposite effect. Now You felt that someone there started to speak very rudely to you. You may not have thought that that person was actually texting her on the phone. When you just wanted to take action, you actually had some plans in mind, but she After responding to you and ignoring him, he became unbalanced in his heart and began to insert songs like crazy, rejecting every song you ordered. You were so stupid that you didn&#39;t even know why he was targeting you. When you figured it out, you felt a little proud, the kind of heroic victory. But on the weekend, she didn&#39;t go to your appointment, and she didn&#39;t reply to any of the messages you sent. Of course, she did reply later, but He postponed it to the next day, saying that she was too busy and would make an appointment alone when she was free. In fact, she went on the date that day, but not with you, but with the person who was targeting you. After the date, you did not have sex with her out of politeness, but the person who was targeting you got there first, and after returning home I sent her a message and invited her out for a supper. Of course something happened after the supper. It might have been hugging and kissing, or of course it might just be sex. In short, they were dating every night after that, but you had no idea. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Akai heard this, he took a sip of coffee and said, you are really good at telling stories, but you are completely different from reality. I really admire you. His imagination is worthy of being a writer. In fact, that night, she suddenly told me the story of her ex and her on the terrace. She said that there was a boy who chased her crazily before. She had no trust in relationships at all, and even thought about every subsequent incident. She just wants to have fun, but that boy is really nice to her. If the sweetness of ice cream is 100, then the sweetness of their relationship must be multiplied by 2. But the big problem with this kind of boys is that they don&#39;t really want to go too far with you. When they realize that your relationship is developing into a long-term daily relationship, they will immediately withdraw. This may be a common case in regular relationships, but she just muttered and told me the whole love process, saying that after that, she completely lost confidence in men. When I heard this, I thought I should leave. It had indeed been too long, and I thought it was a rejection. But she said, that person was in the game today, and she just wanted to make him angry, so she called me. Came out together. She kept delaying my time, hoping to disappear long enough for the boy to send a message asking her where she had gone, but we had been gone for twenty minutes and no one asked where we had gone. I felt taken advantage of and was very angry, but she suddenly said something to me, do you know what she said? Use your novelist&#39;s imagination. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I shook out the ash from my cigarette and suddenly thought of a girl I dated some time ago. She asked me out repeatedly for a long time, late at night. She would video chat with me because I lived very close to the company where she worked at that time. Sometimes she would come over to eat hot pot or Japanese food with me early after get off work, as if she only liked these two foods. To a certain extent, I felt that we were in a love relationship, but no one broke that relationship. Until one day, after we finished eating, she said she wanted to take a walk by the Liangma River. As we were walking, she suddenly said that she had been troubled recently. I didn’t know what she was troubled about. I only heard her suddenly say that she doubted her. The person I was dating cheated on me. At that time, I was walking on the road carrying a beer, and suddenly I had the urge to throw the beer into the river. Who? Cheating? Is she serious? Then she told me all about her relationship in the past six months. I calculated the time I had known her and found that our relationship almost overlapped, so I was thinking, what have I been doing during this time? ? She looked very distressed, as if she hoped I could enlighten her, and I said, let&#39;s break up. After she finished speaking, she looked at me with strange eyes and asked, do you think breaking up is the only way to solve the problem? I said, do you like him? She said she liked it. I said, what&#39;s going on between you and me? She said as if she didn&#39;t understand, &quot;With you?&quot; Don&#39;t you like me? So I wanted to get in touch and try it out to see if we were a good fit. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This experience is really sad and ridiculous, but I don’t think it’s surprising that it was exactly the same as Akai’s feelings at that time. I don’t know if that girl said exactly the same thing as my girl, but I tried Imagine some different words appearing in Akai&#39;s story. I looked at Akai’s dumbfounded expression and said, she won’t want to hold your hand and walk back to the box together in the end, right? If you agree, then you are really a coward. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Akai asked me if I still had cigarettes. I shook my head and found that I was empty. He said, this story must have a different ending. I imagined all kinds of possibilities until Akai said that she asked me if I could go down to the box and help her take a look at what the boy was doing. At the time I thought I should refuse, but out of curiosity who the boy was, I agreed. She described her boyfriend&#39;s appearance to me and showed me the boy&#39;s photo. When I saw that ordinary appearance, I even doubted whether he really appeared in the box tonight. I promised to help her go down and have a look, but I didn&#39;t go into the box. I told my friend who was organizing the game that I had something to do and I had to leave first. Then he asked me jokingly if I was dating someone, and I said Yes, then I changed my mind and deleted that girl. When talking about this, Akai said, this is my recent relationship story. It can even be said that it is only a story without feelings. I finally believe in the so-called love, which is the rippling of hormones in that second when I meet you. It’s so hard to like someone who likes you again. I have been single for three years and five months. Every time winter comes, I think I am going to fall in love. Every time I meet someone I feel like, I think I am going to fall in love again. But in fact, it is not only difficult for me to meet the right person, but it is also difficult for people who are separated from me to meet the right person. Do you think it is possible for people to meet the right person in the end? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I finished smoking my cigarette, and then I remembered the night when I was walking along the Liangma River with that girl. I was carrying the can of beer, and suddenly it felt a little heavy. I wanted to find a trash can to throw it away. Then I heard her say, can you meet my boyfriend? Just the three of us having a meal together. I said, what’s the meaning? She said that this would make him feel threatened. Now he just feels that he is too safe in the relationship. I said, OK. Then she started planning the schedule, and then sent me the address of a certain restaurant. She kept praising me along the way, saying that it would be great if her partner was as considerate as me, and it would be great if her partner liked her as much as I do. At the end, I suddenly stopped and said, give him a call now. She asked me what to do? I said, let me have a word with him. She suddenly looked at me with hostility, and then said, don&#39;t be crazy, call him now, he will definitely break up with me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said, yes, let’s break up. Wouldn’t that be good? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said, you must be sick. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Of course the night ended on an unhappy note. She took a taxi and left early. I walked alone for a while by the Liangma River. My cigarettes were gone, just like now. But now Akai could go with me to buy a pack, so I didn’t have to walk a long way alone. It’s been a long and empty road. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Li Jialong&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see @ONE Studio’s pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FnG6mnVK6opY4g75Tw-7h415dwbd&quot; alt=&quot;zhouhongxiang&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;zhou hongxiang&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@zhouhongxiang&lt;/span>; &lt; /div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Young writer, representative works &quot;Famous Fair&quot; and &quot;They Are Burning&quot;&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot; OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6156&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Likes that are never together &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Zhou Hongxiang&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6141&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Lovers love each other as expected until they are separated&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Zhou Hongxiang&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6171)&quot;>;Click You can download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4063]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4206]]><description>&lt;div>;21 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FkZJv5FSz7O4HAut1Ncquan_XaUH&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;VOL.4063&lt;/span>;Photography | Giang Nguyen&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;21&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nov. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;At that time I really want to like someone, but I don&#39;t particularly need &quot;someone&quot;. I just want to &quot;find someone randomly&quot; and spend all my feelings and pocket money. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot; color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>