<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[「E人」有什么烦恼？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3981]]><description> &lt;div>;18 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; It’s not that hard to ask&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>; What worries does &quot;E-man&quot; have? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Xiaoxia A&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original- src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FjqKyML99nRnmsEY_ejQXZppLf7u&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FjqKyML99nRnmsEY_ejQXZppLf7u&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;When I saw this question, I had three question marks on my head. E person, a happy puppy who can sing &quot;Say Goodbye to All Troubles&quot; with the store clerks in Haidilao, a social gangster who can eat well wherever he goes, what can E person be called a social terrorist? trouble? After interviewing some of my E-person friends, they really do, as follows. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;1. Being bored&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;in&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;home&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;meeting&lt;/strong>; >;&lt;strong>;Death&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, socializing&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;makes me feel alive&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I was locked down at home due to the epidemic last year, I didn’t feel much inconvenience , do nucleic acid as the situation arises. Anyway, even if the lockdown is not enforced, I don’t go out very much. Home is the most fun place. If you don’t have to worry about food, drink and can surf the Internet, it won’t be a problem if you don’t go out for a month. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But for E people, not giving out is like extinguishing the light of hope, strangling the fire of desire, leaving only sin and losing the soul. It is better to eat without meat and live without bamboo than to go out and socialize. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After being banned for a month, an E-person friend went on a revenge trip after being unblocked. He socialized wildly in a youth hostel, yelled at anyone he caught, and even the most talkative boss didn’t talk to him until the end. Talking to her, friends from all over the world would hide when they saw her, and she was too lazy to open her mouth until the end of the conversation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said that if she didn’t go out for more than two days, she would feel abandoned by the world. Even if you go for a spin downstairs, it&#39;s better than staying at home all the time. Only when I go out and communicate with others can I feel alive. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If learning to be bold is a lifelong lesson for person I, then &lt;strong>;learning to enjoy solitude is a game that person E urgently needs to clear&lt;/strong>;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2. Be angry at yourself for not&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;living up to your expectations&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; strong>;&lt;strong>;I-people friends&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is a saying that introverts don’t make friends, they will only be adopted by extroverts. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Is it possible that extroverts will sometimes be angry with these people? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The friend E mentioned above met a shy boy while traveling to Spain. This boy wanted to take off his shirt on the beach, but was too embarrassed to do so because he was afraid of the glares from people around him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She showed the courage of a reliable elder sister: Please, no one is looking at you. Don&#39;t be afraid, I will take off my shirt and only wear a bikini to accompany you. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This boy was encouraged to be brave and let go. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said that’s great. I’ve always wanted to go square dancing. I’m sorry. Can you dance with me next time? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her: What are you afraid of? You don&#39;t have any audience. Your mother was pregnant for ten months and gave birth to you, not so that you should care about other people&#39;s eyes. Even if someone looks at you, they will only think that you are brave and doing something they dare not do. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When you go out shopping, you just quietly tug on the sleeves of E person’s friends and secretly signal that there is a handsome guy five meters in front of you, and they dare to rush over and ask for WeChat to kill you. E person,&lt;strong>;can be said to be for. Their i friend is heartbroken&lt;/strong>;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;3. It’s tiring to be in a hot spot every day&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;. &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;It’s hard to find a like-minded partner&lt; /strong>;&lt;strong>;’s&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although the E people’s energy is comparable to a social nitrogen pump, according to them, being in the field every day is quite tiring. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another E friend was invited to a barbecue by a small group of three people one day after joining a new company. After integrating in, she became the organizer because her E was too high. Who has children to take care of at the party, who likes to be late, who is more introverted and needs more care, who can&#39;t drink while driving, they have no idea, they are responsible for the organization and planning and the one-stop round-off service. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In social situations,&lt;strong>;everyone assumes that the E person plays the role of icebreaker. It seems that if the venue is not enough for the guests and the host to enjoy themselves, the E person has not done his job well. As the i person&#39;s savior, procrastination nemesis, and difficulty in making choices Syndrome Gospel&lt;/strong>;People with E sometimes feel a little helpless because they are burdened with too much expectations and cannot quietly hide in a corner to drink a glass of ice water. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As for finding a partner, regardless of EI, it is recognized to be difficult. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But for E people, finding a partner with whom they can take risks and experience the world seems to be more difficult than finding a match in the secular sense. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I came across a short video before, which can be called an i-person horror film. A girl passed by a Xinjiang barbecue restaurant, made eye contact with the owner, started twisting her neck on the spot, invited the owner to join her, and the two danced in the street Xinjiang dance scares me to death. Is this level of extroversion real? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Perhaps people E have the same scary moment. When they see friends of person i being forced to apply for a card by the clerk at the shampoo shop but unable to say no, they will ask God. Are these levels of introversion real? Then he rushed up to me without hesitation and said, &quot;She said she wouldn&#39;t do it, so she&#39;s going to sell negative reviews again&quot;! &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Mei Butan onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the call for papers information, please see @ONE Studio pinned on Weibo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fr5zkCli70LJvQLn5MtEV9_mpyGS &quot; alt=&quot;小夏&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;小夏&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;Public account@小夏小下&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style= &quot;&quot;>;Ugly appearance and dull mouth. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Question and Answer&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/question/3980&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Have you ever been &quot;emotionally blackmailed&quot;? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3975&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;The Year of Walking: How did &quot;relaxation&quot; become a luxury product? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3981)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 06:25:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[明天的事就交给明天的我]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6168]]><description> &lt;div>;18 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;文／ONEFriend&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmRj98WzaxV-4Dqp0zm9WN7SLM2J&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmRj98WzaxV-4Dqp0zm9WN7SLM2J&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Mei Butan onewenzhang@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Some sentences have been deleted. If you have any questions, please contact the editorial department on WeChat: oneapp2020 . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8&quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div >; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;The cutest people in a complex world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>; Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6160&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Later, the knight was no longer brave&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Text/ONE friend&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/article/6153&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Give yourself back to yourself, give you back to the sea of ​​others&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/ONE friend&lt;/div>; &lt;/a >; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6168)&quot; >;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 06:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4060]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4204]]><description>&lt;div>;18 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fq1o5M2--EENSfTAkT-lZ7-E_P67&quot; alt=&quot; Homepage picture&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4060&lt;/span>;Photography | Memories on 35mm&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;18&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nov. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/ div>; &lt;p>;For the woman injured by flowers, spring is not her real enemy. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 06:25:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>