<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[你做过哪些改变人生的微小决定？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3952]]><description> &lt;div>;23 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Question from ONE Editorial Department&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>; What small, life-changing decisions have you made? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; ONE Friendly Answers&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Ftm1nC5ipl0RUne-HqGd-AdDUnN7&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Ftm1nC5ipl0RUne-HqGd-AdDUnN7&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Every seemingly insignificant decision is a butterfly, when it flaps its wings, destiny The trajectory of life has quietly changed. Maybe we should pay more attention to the little things now, maybe that is the beginning of a wonderful fate in the future. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&quot;When I was eight years old, I agreed that my parents would have one more child at home&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Because of this incident, I found that I could have a companion for everything, and I no longer had to worry about what to do by myself. We grew up together, and it seemed like nothing could separate our families, or us. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Dream, 22 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;&quot;Resigning to take the postgraduate entrance examination in 2020&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Because of the epidemic, I resolutely resigned to take the postgraduate entrance examination. It has been more than two years since I graduated. I prepared for half a year and failed to pass the exam, but my life trajectory has changed. I returned to my hometown, a small city, and settled down there. I was no longer a wanderer. Although the ending didn&#39;t quite match the beginning, I&#39;m really glad I made the decisive choice at that time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Slowly, 27 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;&quot;I first tried writing poetry nine years ago&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later, some of my poems were published in local magazines, some were submitted to one, and some It was used as a copywriter by some literary and artistic online stores. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Jin, 27 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;&quot;Hospital Physical Examination&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To be precise, it is not the kind of routine physical examination performed by the unit. It is when you get the physical examination report after the physical examination at the unit and decide to go for a re-examination. It’s time to start sorting out your life based on your true physical condition. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;WiFi, 35 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt; strong>;&quot;Start keeping accounts and record the flow of funds&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I can save money to buy myself a tablet and travel to Qingdao with my friends. At the same time, I can have more confidence to enjoy more good life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Stefan, 21 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;&quot;I changed the form for changing my major&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I originally wanted to change my major to Chinese medicine, but my parents and friends persuaded me, so I finally filled out the Western medicine clinical form because I have been learning Chinese since I was a child. Very poor. Now I am doing well in clinical studies. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Yi Hao, 21 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;&quot;Delete short video apps such as Weibo and Douyin&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Every day I can feel the sense of freedom that my soul has returned to me and I am no longer trapped by the algorithm. Enrichment and satisfaction, learning more knowledge every day, which has not been packaged by the Internet. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Biscuits, 37 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt; strong>;&quot;My good friend who was in the same dormitory in college was going to take the teacher qualification certificate exam and asked me to accompany her.&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After graduating from college, I didn’t have a job that I wanted for two years because I had a teacher’s book With the qualification certificate in hand, I accidentally took the teacher&#39;s exam and now I am a gardener who accompanies the growth of the flowers of my motherland. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Beibeibei, 31 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;&quot;I used more snacks in my professional course homework in college&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One of the professional class assignments used more snacks, and I was praised by the teacher. I was dragged into the studio to work by the teacher, and later other teachers praised me. My classmates recommended each other, participated in many competitions, and won many awards. Gradually I gained confidence and successfully passed the postgraduate entrance examination. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Eating grapes without spitting out grape skins, 24 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Cross-examination Psychology&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Actually, my life has not changed for the better, it has just gone towards another path that I never thought about. I saw new scenery and new people, even if I was more unhappy, this may be the biggest and last bravery in my life, and it may also be the only decision to not talk about reality and only talk about ideals. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Xi Xi, 24 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;&quot;Be a volunteer at an exhibition&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I was in college, I became a volunteer at an exhibition. Because there were only a few classes a week, the organizer asked if there was anyone who could I went to work to help out, and later met my current boyfriend, and my expected life path completely deviated from that. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Ye Zi, 26 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;&quot;Read a few pages of a book before going to bed, and go to sleep when you don&#39;t want to read it.&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I don&#39;t end the day with my mobile phone. I sleep peacefully, accumulate some knowledge, and have a peaceful mind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Kafka in the mountains, 40 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Serving as a soldier&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It allows me to go to college for free, allows me to upgrade to a bachelor&#39;s degree without taking the exam, and allows me to have my own money to go out and pursue the freedom I like. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Chunfeng, 21 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt; strong>;&quot;Watched a movie &quot;Bottom Hot Girl&quot;&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I chose to study law when I was in high school, and now I am studying law in the fourth department of a 211 fifth college. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Xiao Wu, 20 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt; strong>;&quot;I signed up for a ballet dance class when I was in fourth grade&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was present at the elementary school, junior high school and high school art festivals, and performed at school celebrations and various evening parties, although I did not take a professional path. , but it gave me great confidence. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Traveling Lilith, 21 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p >;Responsible Editor: Zhou Ziheng onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This Q&amp;A is collected from the WeChat Moments of the ONE Editorial Department. To participate in the collection, add the Editorial Department WeChat: oneapp2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8 &quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Complex The cutest people in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3950&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;The five most important things to do &quot;together&quot;&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/ div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail( 4,3952)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[家的构成]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6131]]><description>&lt;div>;23 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Yi Chaonan&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt; img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgqFfPh5lepDmfyTpe57HSbiiBVJ&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgqFfPh5lepDmfyTpe57HSbiiBVJ&quot;>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Many things in this world are not black and white, especially life. So many principles sound correct, but cannot be implemented because the complexity of people&#39;s emotions is ignored. While climbing up to admire the chrysanthemums on the Double Ninth Festival, it also gives us the opportunity to think about the contributions of the elderly and the composition of the family. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My aunt’s eldest son is the tenth among the cousins. When the tenth brother was young, his parents were busy with business, so he was sent back to his hometown to live with his grandparents. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If you ask me, how happy I am to be able to live with my grandparents all the time without being disturbed by my parents. However, the tenth brother was not satisfied. One time, my aunt went back to her hometown to visit him and he wanted to follow her, so she advised him, &quot;It&#39;s the same with my grandparents.&quot; &quot;It&#39;s different,&quot; said the tenth brother: &quot;The love of grandparents is different from the love of parents.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is what my grandmother told me when I went to visit her. Grandma said: &quot;You see, it is difficult to take care of this child now. The children of our time could not say such things.&quot; Whether it’s your grandparents, your parents, they all love you, so what’s the difference? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I thought about it and said, &amp;ldquo;There must be some differences. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I was a kid, my parents were also in business. But I am not as lucky as my tenth brother. No matter how busy my parents are, they still want to keep me by their side. I&#39;m very troubled, to be precise, very annoyed. I didn&#39;t like them much at the time. They control me, restrain me, and beat me. Sometimes they can&#39;t stand me. I don&#39;t understand, since everyone is annoyed with each other, why bother to take me with you? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Compared with my parents, my grandparents were so nice. They let me sleep when I was lazy, eat delicious food as much as they wanted, and they only shamed me for wetting the bed but did not scold me. Grandma is always kind to me and always responds to my requests. Grandpa had such a hot temper, but he never laid a finger on me. I would simply like to stay with my grandparents forever. If not, the next best thing is to stay with my aunt. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My aunt is so kind. She cooks delicious food in various ways, teaches me this and that, chats with me, and tells me very trivial things, whether I understand or not. Although my uncle is a bit annoying and always makes fun of me, he has to go to work and doesn’t have much time at home so I can ignore it. If that doesn&#39;t work, you can just make do with your grandparents. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grandpa is very strict and is not allowed to talk nonsense or use chopsticks while eating. Grandma is also very strict. She always makes me study. When I get up in the morning, she doesn’t help me put on my clothes and shoes. She always makes me do it myself. But when I go out to play, my grandma will tell my older sister in the yard to take good care of me. Around them, at least playing is very free. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Anyway, don’t be with your parents. In addition to controlling me and not letting me go out to play freely, my mother was also too fierce and beat and scolded me frequently. My dad is gentle and doesn&#39;t hit me, but sometimes he can be cold and violent and ignore people with a straight face. Grandparents and aunts don&#39;t have these problems, and they get along easily. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Children always like easy people and things. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I forgot which song sung, children are a sweet burden to their parents. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I was a child, I only saw the sweet part of myself. Now that I have become an adult, my eyes have come to the part that burdens adults: When chatting, I always hear my colleagues say how their sick children spend time in the hospital from midnight to early morning, how many connections they have made and how much money they have spent to send their children to a good school. When you come home after a tiring day at work, you still have to help your children with their homework. On weekends, you have to attend various tutoring classes. The parent group messages are as important as the work group. The instructions of your children’s teachers are as irreversible as those of your direct leaders... ;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Every time the winter and summer vacations come, colleagues with children fall into different levels of troubles one after another. There are elderly people who help take care of the children, and they are afraid of taking them back to their hometowns and infecting their children with bad habits in rural areas. If there is no elderly person to help take care of the child, I have to contact the child care class early, and I am afraid that the teacher of the child care class is not responsible enough. Their happiest moment was the day or two before the end of the winter and summer vacations, when they were relieved, relaxed and happy, as if they had gone through all the hardships and finally came to the end of a large project that was so heavy that it would cause collapse. stage. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;It’s the beginning of school! &amp;rdquo;That’s what moms and dads say. This is not surprising. However, one time in the elevator, a grandma said to her neighbor: &quot;It&#39;s good to wait until school starts, and I want to send my little ancestor back to his parents.&quot; &amp;rdquo;I immediately remembered the days when I was sent to my grandma&#39;s house and my aunt&#39;s house to spend the winter and summer vacations when I was a child... I always thought that I was loved by everyone and that every family looked forward to me. Is it possible that when I leave my parents during the holidays and return to my parents during the holidays, the person who protects me actually feels relieved every time I leave? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I don’t dare to think about it, don’t think about it, I can’t think about it anymore, if I think about it more, I will just hurt myself... So the lyrics also changed in my heart-mdash ;&amp;mdash; Are children a sweet burden to parents? Whether it&#39;s sweet or not depends on the situation, but the burden is pretty certain. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Parents are the direct bearers of all the burdens that come with their children. A generation apart, grandparents are no longer the front-line responsible for financial pressure and parenting planning. Elderly people have more emotional space to enjoy the energy and cuteness of children. Therefore, their love is looser and lighter, not as pressing and stressful as their parents&#39; love. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But at the same time, the love of grandparents is not as &quot;one&#39;s own&quot; as the love of parents. When I was a child, I naively thought that my grandparents’ home, my aunt’s home, and my grandparents’ home were all my homes. Until one day I accidentally realized that the family that only consists of my parents and me does not need to be restricted by attributive words. When I say &quot;go home,&quot; everyone knows where I am referring to. There is no need to specifically say that I am going back to my parents&#39; house. However, the homes of grandparents, grandparents, aunts and uncles must be specifically designated. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I am in high school, but due to student status issues, I need to transfer back to my hometown school. My parents bought a house in our hometown county two years ago. The house is next to the school and opposite the county hospital. Before school started, the family was very busy. Aunts, uncles, grandparents were all here. I took it for granted that my grandma would stay and take care of me and live with me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One day, my father seemed to accompany my aunt to the hospital for medical treatment. I was sorting out books in my house and heard my uncle and grandma talking quietly in the living room outside. The general meaning is that it is unrealistic for my parents to abandon their business and come back to take care of me, and it is also unrealistic to just focus on business and leave me alone. Based on my uncle&#39;s understanding of my father, he must be very conflicted. He wanted to talk to grandma, but he was afraid that if grandma didn&#39;t have this plan, he would be embarrassed. My uncle suggested that grandma take the initiative and speak clearly, so as to help her son and daughter-in-law relieve their worries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Finally, my uncle whispered: &quot;Since you have this intention, then take the initiative to say it.&quot; It&#39;s two different things if you take the initiative and agree to it after he proposes it. What&#39;s more, the character of your son and daughter-in-law can make your work in vain? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My heart sank as I listened. What I thought was a matter of course turned out to have the word &quot;help&quot; in it. But I almost immediately accepted this small calculation, and then felt warm in my heart, thanking my uncle for standing in the middle and helping my dad make peace. In this way, I can live with my grandma in a natural way, without being restricted by my parents. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, the good days of freedom only lasted for one year. During the summer vacation of my freshman year of high school, my mother left her business and came back to take care of me personally. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;My son/daughter has given birth to a baby, and you won’t help take care of it? &amp;rdquo;This is a common phrase used by people when their parents are about to become grandparents. The word &quot;help&quot; shows a subtle layer of human relations between the old family and the small family. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition to not directly bearing the burden, when parents upgrade to the level of grandparents, their temperament changes with age, which is also a reason why grandparents&#39; love is more tolerant. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My mother had a firecracker-like temper when she was young. She was super fiery and extremely tough as a mother. I was often frightened by her and dared not get close to her. Instead of looking for reasons within herself, she went to cry to her grandmother and tell her that I was kissing her and my aunt, but not her. Later, some big changes took place in the family, and after years of hard work and worldly events, my mother&#39;s personality changed a lot, and she began to learn how to introspect. Now that she is a grandmother, from what I have observed, she is quite kind. You will be proud of your granddaughter&#39;s outstanding appearance, or you will be extremely proud of her smart actions or heart-warming words. Occasionally, I was bullied by my granddaughter, but I had to swallow it, and only later complained to my sister-in-law. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sometimes when I look at their grandparents, I think of my grandma. Grandma is no longer here. I can&#39;t help but wish that time would go slower, the children would grow up slower, and the grandparents would grow older slowly. But time will not stop. One day, my little niece will miss her grandma just like I miss my grandma now. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My tenth brother and I are quite different in age, so I don’t know him well, nor how he gets along with his grandparents, or how he gets along with his parents. When my grandma said that my tenth brother wanted to live with his parents, my first reaction was how sad his grandparents would be if they found out. But I think our luck is the same. We can weigh, compare and choose between the two kinds of love. Fortunately, I know that not everyone has such an opportunity. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I was a child, I was chatting with my classmates. This classmate said that I didn’t have a grandfather, and that classmate said that I had met my grandma. I secretly thought in my heart that my grandparents are here, and all my family members are here, how perfect it is. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I didn’t know at that time that the next step to perfection is to continue to lose and become incomplete. The person you love the most will die of illness. If you don’t have disease, you will die when you get old...and under the impact of reality, people will have no choice but to lose part of their innocence, just like I will, at a certain moment, lose all the people who have taken care of me. I woke up from the fantasy that all my homes were my own. This is probably the unavoidable sobriety and slight sadness in adults. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A person will change from a child to an adult, and from an adult to an old man. In our context, the child&#39;s task is to learn and deliver a report card that satisfies adults. The task of adults is to make a living, provide children with a better educational environment, and create a stress-free old age life for the elderly. What about the old man&#39;s task? Apart from helping to take care of the grandchildren, society seems to have no more requirements for the elderly. The old man&#39;s task...to ensure his own good health and not cause trouble to his children? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Our family is the kind of family that interferes a lot in personal affairs. It&#39;s the same on my father&#39;s side, and it&#39;s the same on my mother&#39;s side. My parents had conflicts. If my father felt that he was being reasonable, he would go to my grandparents for comment. My grandparents scolded my mother, and they returned home to continue their lives. If the mother thinks she is responsible, she will ask the grandparents to comment. The grandparents gave Dad a lesson, and the two of them continued to live their lives as usual. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I was in college, my parents once had a serious conflict that led to divorce. My aunts took my mother to me for comment. At that time, I thought I understood a lot of truths. In life, happiness is the most important thing. If a husband and wife are not living well, why should they be tied together? I gave a simple suggestion: stay away. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Everyone was silent. This is obviously not the result everyone wants. It is also obvious that people will not just look to me for comment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later, with my grandmother’s persuasion, the divorce was temporarily put on hold. Grandma reasoned with me and said everything was for the integrity of the family, for me and my brother. I don&#39;t understand it very much. I have more reasons than she does. For example, adults should not use children as an excuse to maintain their marriage. Life is not going well, I just say it&#39;s for the sake of my children, and I fool around with everything, so I keep fooling around for the rest of my life. In the end, if there is any dissatisfaction, everything will be blamed on the child, and a painful drama of &quot;how much have we sacrificed for you&quot; will be staged. The child just has no right to speak, and the child should not bear such responsibility. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grandma said earnestly: &quot;Have you ever thought that if they get divorced, you will have no home.&quot; They are still young and will definitely start their own families after the divorce. Will your siblings have a good life in the future? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;How can I listen? I said, &quot;If they get divorced, it&#39;s not certain whether our siblings will have a good life.&quot; But no matter what the reason, no matter who you are for, you should not sacrifice your own good life. Besides, if they make trouble like this, how can we have a good life? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grandma sighed: &amp;ldquo;You are too young and don’t understand many things. No matter how dilapidated your home is, no matter how hard it is, as long as your parents don&#39;t divorce, it will still be your home. Once they break up, it won&#39;t be that easy when you regret and want to put them back together again. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was young and energetic at the time, and I hated this rhetoric. My opinion is that most of the elders are pedantic and live their lives with outdated values. They love whatever they want, I can’t say it, and I can’t hide from it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, my grandmother passed away. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before my grandmother passed away, several families had constant gatherings and met frequently. In the year after my grandmother passed away, except for the Chinese New Year, there were no daily family gatherings. Some time ago, my ninth cousin got engaged, so the whole family got together in a relatively neat manner. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past, we used to get together whenever there was nothing to do. I always thought that because everyone lived close by and they all loved having fun, it was natural for them to get together. Take it for granted. Now that we can&#39;t get together, we realize that we can get together because the old man is here and the cohesion is there. The old man is no longer here, no matter how close the distance is, the things that should be dispersed will still disperse. My heart is inevitably empty. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What I lack is of course not those meals, but the lively reunion. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I have lived alone for many, many years and have always been proud of my independent and calm life. It was only in the year after my grandmother passed away that I realized that people like me, who have lived in an environment where families support and tie each other since childhood, essentially like to be complete and reunited. That home where I can go back at any time, where I am bonded with each other and lively and bustling, is the foundation and nourishment for me to grow independently. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I watched &quot;Gravity&quot; before, and someone in Douban Film Review interpreted the traction line between the heroine Sandra Bullock and the earth on the poster to symbolize the umbilical cord between the baby and the mother. People are constantly trying to escape gravity and fly farther into space, but they still have to return to Earth in the end. Our dependence on the earth is an invisible umbilical cord. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The extended family behind me is my earth. When I was young, I longed for farther and broader places and tried every means to escape. I really went out, from emotions to body, but I unconsciously came back again and again. I have always thought that home is the most stable place and is always there. All I need to do is not forget the way back. After my grandparents passed away, I realized for the first time that the road is always there, but home is not necessarily there. Now my grandmother&#39;s death has once again made me realize that the umbilical cord of a big family is not our emotions, but the elderly in the family. When the old man passed away and the umbilical cord was severed, the gravitational pull for our return disappeared. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Someone once broke the news about &quot;Walden Pond&quot; and said that Thoreau sometimes couldn&#39;t stand the loneliness and would sneak home at night to eat cookies and meet his family. I used to sneer at this kind of gossip, thinking it was just a typical case of mutual jealousy among literati, or a dark speculation about people with high spiritual qualities. I don’t think so now. Now I think that if the news is really better, it will add a bit of human touch and human fireworks to Thoreau. No one can live on an island. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So in recent years, when I think back to my parents’ divorce, I have a different perspective. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;People who really make up their mind to divorce will not go around looking for comments and advice. This is one of them. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The second point is somewhat selfish. But as my grandmother said, it was a lucky thing for my brother and me that my parents were not divorced. At least in our memories, home is a complete concept and has not fallen apart. In other words, what I object to actually protects us to a certain extent. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is the gap between theory and reality. Many things in this world are not black and white, especially life. So many principles sound correct, but cannot be implemented because the complexity of people&#39;s emotions is ignored. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grandma may not know as much theoretical knowledge as I do. But when it comes to discerning people&#39;s hearts and understanding of the world, I&#39;m far behind. Now I understand a little bit, but grandma has no chance to know that I understand. This is the case with many things. As I grew up, I slowly changed my views and opinions. I wanted to tell my grandma, my aunt, and my father. I understood, but I had no chance. They have all been dead for too long. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is called regret. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some people say that growth is continuous accumulation. In my opinion, growth is also constant loss. Accumulation may not necessarily lead to results, but loss is the only way to go. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Mei Butan&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see the @ONE studio pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FpKk5N9eg_v2zyAkX7XPWYqc8YtG&quot; alt=&quot;伊Chaonan&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;伊Chaonan&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@伊Chaonan&lt; /span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;I am my obstacle and my path. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/article/6113&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;The Burden of Reunion&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Cheng Huizi&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr >; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Read&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6023&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div >;Great Heat&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Written by Wang Xiaofeng&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6131)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank &quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt; /a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4034]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4172]]><description>&lt;div>;23 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fv24QYoV7uAo7W6efO-4WpUylnFk&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4034&lt;/span>;Photography | Bilgin&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;23&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oct. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;That paragraph The feeling is dead and that&#39;s the only reason it&#39;s so good. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>