<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[哪些信号，意味着这份工作不能再干了？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3956]]><description> &lt;div>;25 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Question from ONE Editorial Department&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>; What are the signs that you can no longer do this job? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; ONE Friendly Answers&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FvOJvWsLZeFP3wSqGXU8NFUByVxQ&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FvOJvWsLZeFP3wSqGXU8NFUByVxQ&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot; font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The idea of ​​​​resigning is either an immature impulse or a reflection after careful consideration. The following &quot;signals&quot; may help you make a clear judgment. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In clinical work, we will always encounter some unreasonable patients. When you patiently explain the current condition and the treatment required, the patient casually says, &quot;Do you want to charge more?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;I think what Baidu said is different from what you said! &quot;What&#39;s more, some people slap you in anger. Not only do you have to endure it, you also have to apologize to others. This is how the original kindness of doctors is worn away.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Medical staff｜Ni Dongqing, 30 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When work takes up most of the day, and you find yourself returning to work after less than 12 hours of rest; when you continue to fall into depression and other emotions that are easy to cry, and you feel disgusted with work; when the person you yell at every day is always the person at work. People and things, the former quiet female college student has become a shrew who can curse on the street... The most important point is that when you find that none of your colleagues around you are what you want to be, whether it is career or Personally, you&#39;re good to go. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Bank employee | Dirty, 23 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. Frequently start talking about your work to the people around you, sometimes chattering endlessly, regardless of whether the other person wants to hear it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2. If you continue to deal with work while taking a break, you will have no life, lose yourself, self-doubt or even deny yourself in the long run. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3. I started to pay special attention to the opinions of my colleagues or leaders, which put me in a situation where I needed to constantly prove myself, and I always felt that I was not perfect enough. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Teacher｜Menghuameng, 25 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I have been working in a market dried fruit store for almost a year after graduation. The store was opened by a partnership of three people, which means I have three bosses. This boss said, &quot;You should do this.&quot; The other boss came over and said, &quot;No, you should do this.&quot; This is really annoying. Later, I only listened to the more authoritative one among the three of them. The other two bosses saw that I was more strict in control and the accounts in the store were very clear, so they gave me small shoes. Really, what a headache. When two bosses are targeting me, I feel very uncomfortable. I am not a human being inside and out. Others will distance themselves from you and try to curry favor with the two bosses. well. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Dried fruit store accountant｜At the time, 23 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1. The leadership does not pay attention to it and misses the promotion many times. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2. Falling into interpersonal difficulties and not having a harmonious relationship with colleagues and superiors. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3. The company plans to lay off employees, there is negative news about the company, it is slow to recruit new people, and the prospects are bleak. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4. The leadership has no ability and vision, PUA employees, employees often work overtime, and the company&#39;s management is poor. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5. When the value is underestimated, quickly change jobs and leave. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Work confidential｜Mickey A-Nian, 22 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;The more beautiful and complex the scene, the more energy and time it takes to complete it. When the word &quot;pass through&quot; flashed through my mind, I felt that it was time for me to take a break. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Wedding planning｜Pu Pu, 24 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;If you are not happy and have so many things to do that you don’t know where to start, then just don’t do them at all, which is the tactic of “procrastination”. It&#39;s all a trivial matter as big as sesame seeds, but picking up sesame seeds all over the ground is so overwhelming. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Warehouse staff｜Lazy, 36 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;As a programmer, in the initial stage, when you have learned everything about the company and there is no momentum for a salary increase, you can run away. Because the salary will double in one jump. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Programmer | Xiao Kongya, 24 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;1. Promise to be promoted, but then give up without informing or communicating in advance. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2. The immediate supervisor has PUA behavior, and (you) communicated with the higher-level supervisor to no avail. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3. Started to suffer from insomnia frequently. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4. The company’s performance deteriorated, bonuses were cancelled, income dropped sharply, colleagues resigned without compensation, and things became more and more complicated. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5. There are more ineffective meetings in the company, but no one cares about business revenue. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6. Begin to cancel benefits, take unpaid leave, and work from home. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The above is the state of my last company when I left my job. In the end, there was no toilet paper left. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Accountant | Mamie, 32 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Salary cut, bad working environment, and lack of learning. If two of these three factors are involved, you can consider running away. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Automobile manufacturing | Coltsfoot, 28 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;I have nothing to do during working hours, but I have to work overtime and attend meetings. There is absolutely no room for improvement. My boss plays with his mobile phone like a high school teacher. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Editor | astron, 24 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;1. Wages cannot be paid on time, more than 3 months. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2. Finance staff started to leave their jobs. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3. Some leaders are disgusted and suppress themselves. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Company lawyer｜He An, 28 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When you feel like you are surrounded by evil spirits. (Just kidding, let’s be serious: when your body has recurring problems and you can’t find any major problems even if you go to the hospital, but it’s just not good, that’s when your body is sending a signal to let you go.)&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Content Editor｜Cat who loves milk tea, 30 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When When a job only provides output, no input, and completely takes up personal time, you should give up. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Kindergarten teacher｜Linda, 28 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;There are three most important points in work: 1. Money; 2. Interpersonal relationships; 3. Work content. If two of these three points change, you can run away quickly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Stomatologist｜Yang Guling, 27 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;Generally speaking, when the business of a freelance partnership studio is relatively good at the beginning, everyone is discussing technical and operational matters. When one day your boss starts telling you that life is not easy and starts complaining to you, you will know that it is time to resign. Because there is a high probability that your salary will be reduced after a while. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Manicurist｜Manicurist Banban, 29 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;The problem with interpersonal relationships is greater than the work itself, so there is no need to continue. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Operations | Hermione, 22 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;The current job makes you &quot;sick&quot; all the time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For you, the most painful thing may be waking up in pain in the morning, taking the bus or subway to go to work with the same mood as visiting a grave. You are always listless when you go to work, and you have to procrastinate after work. Going home with a tired body, this job may have made you &quot;sick&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Cost clerk | Wainan Street, 22 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Nana onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This Q&amp;A is collected from the WeChat Moments of the ONE Editorial Department. To participate in the collection, add the WeChat account of the Editorial Department: oneapp2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8 &quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Complex The cutest people in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3954&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What are the young people who make incense and make wishes seeking? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3952&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What small decisions have you made that changed your life? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3950&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;The five most important things to do &quot;together&quot;&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/ div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail( 4,3956)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[游向何处]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6139]]><description>&lt;div>;25 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Xingxingchen&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgX3MyhPljdXTXM4I_4M6Sphp_7r&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgX3MyhPljdXTXM4I_4M6Sphp_7r&quot;>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Our understanding of work is the two points and one line of commuting, and the direction of clocking in. Nine to five, there are rules and restrictions. And a more liberal workplace group is emerging. They are called &quot;digital nomads.&quot; Let us follow this article into their lives and explore with the author, where will life go? &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When most people’s lives have been alienated into two points and one line between company and home, a new group is trying to combine the points and lines in life. Extended into a face--digital nomad. With the maturity of the Internet and online collaborative office tools, geographical location is no longer an obstacle to people&#39;s work communication. &quot;Digital nomads&quot; rely on the Internet to complete their work, breaking the strong correlation between work and work location. While working remotely, they also have the freedom to choose where they want to live. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;How do digital nomads who rely on the Internet but wander around the world live? Some people started a new life in Dali, and at the same time, they planned to &quot;escape from Dali&quot; again with their friends. Some people moved from Beijing to Chengdu and experienced the easy but difficult life through &quot;geographical arbitrage&quot;. It is also a profound experience, and there are also people who constantly jump out of the surface of the world and complete interesting jumps from city to countryside, from online to offline, and from virtual to real again and again. Among them, freedom, freedom and escape have become key words. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;SIDE A&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Freedom: go at any time, stop at any time&lt;/strong>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;Life in Dali is still very &quot;volumey&quot;. Comparing the &quot;involution&quot; in the company and this self-involution, Nian feels that there is a clear difference between them. &quot;The endless overtime and endless meetings in the past There are too many, and your actual effective working hours are very short. In the long run, it will be difficult to bring anything valuable to yourself. But now when you work, you have stronger self-motivation, and you don’t have that feeling of consumption. On the contrary, you will There is a sense of progress. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmCXDY79mbZ5x3gJ58XrAvl8OGTL&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot; http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmCXDY79mbZ5x3gJ58XrAvl8OGTL&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;i>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i>;&lt;div>;Photographed by Nian: Coffee in Jizhao&#39;an, located halfway up Cangshan Mountain Pavilion&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For Nian, the sense of progress stays in the middle of the night, and of course he has to do something more meaningful during the day. In addition to working together, this group of &quot;digital nomads&quot; in Dali also do more activities outside of work - for example, when they work until noon, they will sit on the grass by Erhai Lake. Play Frisbee or skateboard, or find a time when the weather is good, and climb the mountain together with your computer on your back. There is a beautiful temple in the mountain. A vegetarian meal will be provided at noon, so everyone will climb up the mountain to work. After the meal, they will sit on the side of the mountain chatting and drinking coffee. Time passes very slowly. Some people will choose to work for a while, while others disappear into the forest and wait until the sun is about to set before going down the mountain together. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even if you don’t look at Nian’s life in linear time, you can get some answers by looking at the space she and her friends live in. The &quot;digital nomad&quot; community in Dali where she currently lives has, in addition to shared office spaces with mobile workstations, more than a dozen fully furnished single apartments. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition, there are independent kitchens and laundry rooms. The activity space on the first floor is used for weekly salon sharing sessions, and the dance studio is where Nian teaches everyone how to dance every night. , there are guitars, pianos and drums in the piano room next to it. It is the best soundproof place in the entire space. In addition to playing music freely there, if someone needs to conduct video conferencing or online classes relatively quietly, there will be Done in that room. &lt;/p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgNdGgVaY3x7wEU_ry2YSwVJ7Xxz&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FgNdGgVaY3x7wEU_ry2YSwVJ7Xxz&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;i>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i>;&lt;div>;Photo by Nian: The digital nomad community and shared office space she founded in Dali &lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition to these clearly divided spaces, there is also a large and open rooftop on the second floor. From there, they could see the color of the lake which was not completely hidden in the mountains, as well as the primeval forest surrounding the lake that blocked the sky from the sun. The Erhai Lake was not far away, and they often spent an entire afternoon here. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For Nian, diversity of identities is an important condition for her to become a &quot;digital nomad&quot;: in addition to her identity as an independent designer, she has multiple labels, and is a food blogger on Dianping. The owner is a travel blogger on Mafengwo. In addition to undertaking design work for different communities, he also does a lot of content creation and space operation work. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition, experience seems to be more important. I took an improvisational drama class with Yang Mengen in Beijing, organized a ride on Hainan Island with my friends, tried a talk show, and worked as a volunteer teacher. Recently, because there are too many tourists in Dali, they are planning a new &quot;wandering plan&quot;; , preparing to escape to the next new place - &quot;Things that I wanted to do before but didn&#39;t have the opportunity, time and energy to do have been gradually realized by digital nomads in the past two years, including being able to work in different places. It&#39;s a very interesting thing for me. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In her opinion, the definition of &quot;digital nomad&quot; is inclusive and rich. &quot;No one has the right to define &quot;digital nomad&quot;. It is a very flexible one.&quot; The concept emphasizes your own control over time, space, including the rhythm of life. For example, some friends have temporarily settled in Dali and have not started traveling. Are they not digital nomads? Actually, no, because if you want to leave, you can always collect your things and leave the next day. I can go at any time and stop at any time. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;SIDE B&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sense of dissociation: depth and detachment&lt;/strong>;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;Megan moved to Chengdu last year, and her situation has always become a little unpredictable every morning. Sometimes she starts from Qingcheng Mountain, and sometimes she has not fully woken up from the wine stall the night before. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After three or four years in Beijing, moving to Chengdu seemed to be a matter of course. Suddenly one day, she discovered that her friends began to gradually leave Beijing, Shanghai and Guangzhou and move to Chengdu and Dali. The brands she used to cooperate with also began to gradually move out to Wuhan and Chengdu. Even the bands she liked no longer &quot; &quot;Beidiao&quot;, but chose to stay in the local area. A certain band she has always admired is now also in Chengdu, living in the same community as her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After coming to Chengdu, the sharp drop in the cost of living made her realize the convenience of &quot;geographic cash-out&quot; in the concept of &quot;digital nomad&quot;, whether it was rent, parking space, etc. Whether it’s the daily necessities such as eating, taking taxis, etc., the cost of living here is more than half lower than in Beijing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I am relatively lucky, and my income may be a little higher than that in Beijing, Shanghai and Guangzhou, so when I arrive in Chengdu, I feel that everything is too cheap and I can live very comfortably here; and I am going to Europe now , Africa, I often go there for more than half a year. If I&#39;m in Beijing, the house will be empty and 20,000 yuan a month will be wasted there. But in Chengdu, you don&#39;t have this pressure. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition, the free state of a &quot;digital nomad&quot; allows her to experience the city more truly. This experience is not limited to living here, but can relax and Freely shuttle through the streets and alleys of the city, you can go deep in slowly and get out quickly. &quot;Many people who want to come to Chengdu think that they can enjoy the kind of urban life here. But if you work in a company, it is nothing more than moving from the high-tech zone in Beijing to the high-tech zone in Chengdu. There are high-tech zones in every city. They&#39;re all the same, nothing special. &amp;rdquo;Being a digital nomad provides her with the opportunity to experience the city. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;ldquo;I get up in the morning or noon every day and work in the afternoon. I don’t work long hours every day, but I am more focused. I close the computer after about two hours. The rest of the time is very busy. I collect information sporadically, read books, surf the Internet, take notes, and then exercise. In the past two years, I have been playing tennis and practicing yoga regularly. I exercise very regularly, and I basically exercise for an hour or two every day. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At night, life becomes richer—this reggae-leaning club hasn’t closed yet, and the vinyl in the store over there has been put up. The underground clubs are not just about pure disco dancing, but also discussions between musicians and art exhibitions on various themes. The cultural atmosphere in Chengdu makes her feel relaxed and fashionable. &lt;/p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgQ-BjYTYCTE5VgkStzSavUnKCOM&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot; http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgQ-BjYTYCTE5VgkStzSavUnKCOM&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce. com/Fk0oOZ2dYiGNRtGPQWzKTAiBtlwy&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fk0oOZ2dYiGNRtGPQWzKTAiBtlwy&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;i>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i>;&lt;div>; Photographed by Megan: Her travels in foreign countries&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition to staying in a certain place for a while, more often than not, she has been on the road, and traveling has always been with her occupies a large proportion in life. During the riots in Cairo, there were gunfire in the morning, in the late night when people were singing on the streets of Mexico, and in the &quot;barter&quot; market in North Africa... they all left her footprints. These constantly changing flows give her a unique wanderer temperament. She travels to different countries and cities all year round, and her relationships with various groups and individuals are distant and indifferent. This is what she likes most. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;My relationship with everyone is very indifferent, and I will not respond like a close friend to others. Because I am always away, it gives me a lot of freedom and I will not interact with others. People come very close. Once you get too close to someone, there will always be a lot of right and wrong. I have a very good friend in Chengdu. We play together every day. But tonight, for example, everyone is drunk. I don’t have to help you, and you don’t have to do anything to me. I’ll just take a taxi and leave, and there won’t be any &quot; Sticky greetings like &quot;Are you home? Am I home?&quot; I like this kind of relationship that does not require excessive dependence, and the personal space and freedom that comes with it. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;SIDE C&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Escape: leaving is inevitable&lt;/strong>;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;Moving from the bustling metropolis to the countryside is not only for the purpose of &quot;geographical arbitrage&quot;, but also for the possibility of close contact with nature. While connecting with the earth, you feel a relative tranquility and a complete natural experience. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wu Jianying recently lived in Xu&#39;aodi, Wenzhou. This 800-year-old Wenzhou ancient village provides the best example of being close to nature. The village still retains the traces left by the previous dynasties&amp;mdash ;—Wenyuan Courtyard, Juren Mansion, Wu Ancestral Hall, and around the village, there are continuous bamboo forests and tall and tall ancient trees. The cobblestone stone road extends from the entrance of the village to the depths of the dense forest. &lt;/p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgXUy_WkbG71GvCGS8BR-xWmGag1&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot; http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgXUy_WkbG71GvCGS8BR-xWmGag1&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;i>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i>;&lt;div>;Photographed by Wu Jianying: Xu&#39;aodi, Wenzhou, where he is currently located Ancient Village&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The AIMKIDS platform he founded recently cooperated with Xuli again, inviting artists, designers, architects, picture book authors, copywriters, etc. to the countryside to carry out a A mountain class about &quot;the best education is in the countryside&quot;. In the morning, he would visit the entire village with foreign or local children, introducing the layout of the village&#39;s former military champion&#39;s residence, the history of the Zhongxun Temple at the entrance of the village, or the cultural meaning behind a certain stone threshold. While walking, you should remember these small details so that you can draw the entire village in the &quot;Cognitive Map&quot; course later. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At other times, he would sometimes fetch water, take a walk, chat with the children, or learn to make mung tofu with his aunts. After that, he started working online for the previous AIMKIDS Apply for and design NFT based on children&#39;s paintings in the &quot;My Home in the Metaverse&quot; international youth design competition. &lt;/p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpZ4E4nSibCqtNZLKyHqKEl4isnc&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FpZ4E4nSibCqtNZLKyHqKEl4isnc&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;i>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i>;&lt;div>;Photographed by Wu Jianying: &quot;My Home in the Metaverse&quot; he planned ;International Youth Design Competition&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rural life is a &quot;complete natural experience&quot; for him, &quot;Here, you You can see the sunset from sunrise, from the hot summer to the sudden heavy rain, the sound of frogs and the chirping of insects after the rain. Your connection with nature is in a complete state, making it easier to perceive the entire environment; and in In the city, your experience is very easy to be cut into pieces. Going to and from work is cut into sections, and all kinds of information are filled in between, which will make your perception of space very weak. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But for Wu Jianying, living in the countryside is just one of many choices. He left home to study since high school, and went to Taichung to study. He went to university in Taipei, and then went to Paris. He traveled to many European cities, went to Africa to see animals, gave a lecture at Harvard, and lived in Manhattan and traveled long distances in China. Each one was special, and these experiences made him feel that &quot;leaving is inevitable.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I feel that I need an action like leaving in my life. Leaving is a kind of detachment and sorting out things, just like when you are swimming, you lift your head and take a breath of air before entering. in water in order to transform into another state. &amp;rdquo;In this state of constantly leaving and engaging, his identity is constantly changing, including artist, designer, university professor, manager, and entrepreneur. But what he likes most about being a &quot;digital nomad&quot; is It has an important relationship with the &quot;sense of escape&quot; he emphasized. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I cannot stay in one space forever. It is similar to the state of &quot;monad nomadism&quot; mentioned by Deleuze. This nomadic state actually sets a tone for you and the world. It has always been a relatively detached relationship with the land and certain identities. Although you will be affected by it, you can break free. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This kind of jumping out that often occurs is not only reflected in geographical space, but also in what he does and the difference between virtual and real experiences - he provides children with They create international design competitions, make different artworks, drawings or designs. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the one hand, he enthusiastically embraces various emerging digital tools and networks, and enjoys the &quot;collage art&quot;-like gathering and dispersion brought about by virtual space; at the same time, he I love real life and the long shots in Hou Hsiao-hsien&#39;s movies, because &quot;the complexity of information is generated through the language of the lens, thus containing more content. I need to feel this reality.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But he does not move just for the sake of moving. In this metaphor of living like a herdsman chasing water and grass, there seems to be a compulsion to work hard for life. &quot;In fact, what it embodies is The positive meaning, for me, is a movement for self-realization, for a better experience, and to enjoy life. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In fact, digital nomads are gradually growing as a new group. At the beginning, this concept actually referred to high-paid Internet employees from Silicon Valley and Wall Street&amp;mdash; &amp;mdash;After they started working remotely, they slowly moved from San Francisco and New York to Bangkok and Lisbon...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the homeless group began to further expand, it no longer specifically refers to &quot;coders&quot; , those who focus on design and content creation have also begun their global &quot;wandering&quot;. In a sense, it seems to mean that we can break away from the organization to a certain extent, gain flexibility in time arrangements, freedom of work location, and considerable remuneration, and regain the freedom to enter life. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Zhou Ziheng&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This article is selected from the [NYLON Nylon] official account&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FhmWISjmLN6dMYPFmqAMyRsG6bHY&quot; alt= &quot;Xingxingchen&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Xingxingchen&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@Moridioteslress&#39;s bottom of the lake&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>; Nonfiction writer. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/article/6134&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;My genius girlfriend&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Xingxingchen&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr >; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6139)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt; /div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4036]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4177]]><description>&lt;div>;25 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FhgkziXIQMjFlWHs1rjmgQKl35gy&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;VOL.4036&lt;/span>;Photography | Dori Bano&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;25&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oct. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;No matter how good the memory is Pain, it belongs to the past, it is gone, why do we still cling to it and let it represent us? This is who we are, and therefore, we suffer. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>