<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[害怕失去，是一种喜欢吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3995]]><description> &lt;div>;2 Dec. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Asked anonymously&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>;Fear of loss , is it a kind of like? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Hong Sangda &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fl3cQu7ZXwCkbCnUGyi-h8yLejq_&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fl3cQu7ZXwCkbCnUGyi-h8yLejq_&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt; br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In relationships,&lt;strong>;the stronger the feeling of worrying about gains and losses, the closer it becomes to an instinct and the further away from pure love. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is like, &quot;The other party will not agree to get married unless he gives enough 188,000 yuan as a gift&quot;, and &quot;A man will go out to find a young lady after getting married.&quot; The former is a female animal The instinct to obtain resources from a partner, which is the instinct of male animals to widely spread genes, cannot be said to be pure love. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In my opinion, jealousy, testing, worrying about gains and losses, etc. in love are close to the nature of the above situations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fear of loss is also a self-preservation instinct in love. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Why do some people become particularly worried about gains and losses as soon as they fall in love? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;1.&amp;nbsp;Fear engraved in female genes&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Generally speaking, in long-term relationships, Girls are more worried about each other&#39;s change of heart than boys. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This situation is caused by the different genetic characteristics of both parties. From the perspective of evolutionary psychology, the best reproductive strategy for male animals is to &quot;remain stable in one object&quot; &quot;While investing in their parents, they also make short-term investments in other animals of the opposite sex.&quot; Therefore, as the time spent together increases, boys are more likely to be less attentive to their partners and start to pay attention to other opposite sexes around them. For female animals, on the contrary, their best reproductive strategy is to &quot;continue to monopolize the parental investment of an object&quot; in order to ensure that their offspring can survive. Therefore, they will be more cautious and worried about their partners. The other party reduces its investment in itself because of the potential partner, or simply gives up on itself. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One wants to monopolize, while the other can’t stop seeking outside. The two instincts compete with each other, and women become increasingly anxious and worried about gains and losses. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2.&amp;nbsp;Attachment patterns formed in early years&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Worrying about gains and losses is not the prerogative of women. Men may also worry about losses. each other, and this is closely related to each person&#39;s attachment pattern. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The attachment pattern is formed in early interactions with the mother. A mother who can steadily provide love and care can cultivate a child with a full heart. This is called &lt;strong>;Secure attachment&lt;/ strong>;; A mother who is emotionally unstable and likes to lose her temper with her children is likely to cultivate children who worry about gains and losses. This is called &lt;strong>;anxious attachment&lt;/strong>;; a mother who is emotionally indifferent and resists taking care of her children is likely to cultivate children who are anxious about gains and losses. Children who have no emotional needs and like to be alone are called &lt;strong>;avoidant attachment&lt;/strong>;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The anxious attachment type accounts for 19% of the population. This type of people were often threatened by their mother’s abandonment when they were young - &amp;mdash;&amp;ldquo;If you don’t obey, I won’t want you.&amp;rdquo ;, they have had relatively strong separation anxiety since they were young, and when they grow up, they will bring this insecurity into their intimate relationships, constantly worrying that the other person will no longer love them, and worry that the other person will interact with other people of the opposite sex outside. For this reason, they often lose their temper to attract the attention of their lovers. In the eyes of their partners, these actions are just unreasonable manifestations. They will also make the other person unable to feel the nourishment of love and being loved, and feel that such a relationship is just a mutual relationship. consumption. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;3.&amp;nbsp;Excessive emotional investment in your partner&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is another situation that will lead to If one party in a relationship is concerned about gains and losses, that means he or she has invested too much emotion. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I often say that deep love will not last long, but wisdom will be damaged. If a person continues to invest one-sidedly in a relationship, and it is not proportional to what he gains, then he will be more worried about whether the relationship can last. To give an inappropriate example, if you invest a lot of money in a certain company, are you also worried about their business conditions, or even afraid that they will go bankrupt? The same is true for love. Once the other person chooses to leave you, it means that all your previous investment in time, energy, feelings, etc. is wasted. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This situation more often occurs when the hard values ​​of the two parties are not equal. If the other person&#39;s conditions are obviously better than yours, you will have a sense of unworthiness, &quot;I am so lucky to meet such a partner.&quot; &quot;They are the ceiling of my mate selection. I can never lose them.&quot; ;, the more you think this way, the more cautious you will be in treating this relationship. Moreover, in order to make up for the value difference in this relationship, you will be in a low profile, provide emotional value to the other party, and make the other party happy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The more you do it, the stronger your sense of investment will be, and the greater the damage to you once the relationship breaks down. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When the relationship shows such a background, it is difficult to get involved with words like &quot;like&quot;, because what dominates the relationship between you is no longer &quot;appreciation&quot; Emotions such as &quot;love&quot;, &quot;gratitude&quot; and &quot;satisfaction&quot; are instead &quot;fear&quot;, &quot;suspiciousness&quot;, &quot;grievance&quot;, &quot;dissatisfaction&quot;, etc., and internal friction is greater than nourishment. , entanglement is greater than determination. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If you want to obtain pure love, it is important to choose the partner as well as personal cultivation. Only when you are self-sufficient can you love others more freely. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Mei Butan onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the call for papers information, please see @ONE Studio pinned on Weibo. The official WeChat account of the editorial department: oneapp2020. Regularly publish Q&amp;A collections, give away books and peripheral gifts, readers are welcome to add. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fh_rAFN3IDcz2KT6BHHjGoD051Ge &quot; alt=&quot;Hong Sang&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Hong Sang&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Psychology Consultant, WeChat public account: Hongsang&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -- >; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span >; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3991&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Reading a lot of books can change your life. Is it a scam? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3988&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What I need VS what I see | Can the Internet really satisfy us? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3995)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[看看年少，再挥霍一次]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6186]]><description> &lt;div>;2 Dec. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;文／ONEFriend&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpwdscnjmtORmuGynbld5UlfPWNE&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpwdscnjmtORmuGynbld5UlfPWNE&quot;>;&lt;/div >;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Mei Butan onewenzhang@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For information about the call for papers, please see the @ONE Studio pinned on Weibo. The official WeChat account of the editorial department: oneapp2020. Regularly publish Q&amp;A collections, give away books and peripheral gifts, readers are welcome to add. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8&quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div >; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;The cutest people in a complex world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>; Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6178&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Make a piece of snow and kiss the earth&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Text/ONE friend&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/article/6168&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Leave tomorrow’s affairs to me&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/ONE friend&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/div>; td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6186)&quot;>;Click to Download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4074]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4218]]><description>&lt;div>;2 Dec. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FtNZnpVV8vEzzE3GcarkoxUmk4y5&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;VOL.4074&lt;/span>;Photography | Leyla Qəhrəmanova&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;2&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dec. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Once a person dies I can&#39;t help myself, I can only think more openly. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 02 Dec 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>