<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[什么是“有意义的迷茫”？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3938]]><description> &lt;div>;9 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; It’s not that hard to ask&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>; What is “meaningful confusion”? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Hong Sangda &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FnTCSMYoC2tDTAYjO4-SGEHxtb_7&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FnTCSMYoC2tDTAYjO4-SGEHxtb_7&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt; br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;If you feel confused, it means that you have begun to feel that something is wrong with your current life. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some people are never confused, and their requirements for life are particularly simple. They only need to clock in on time and clock out at the same time every day. They don&#39;t care what they do during working hours or whether they are on the path they want. Anyway, work is just selling labor time. Since I have packaged and sold it to you, it doesn’t matter what you do. Time is not wasted if it can be sold at a price. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Back home, I have no plan for life, and I don’t do anything with long-term rewards. Anyway, my day at work is full of meaning. After work, I just want to have a good rest, catch up on TV dramas, and binge-watch. Short videos, playing games, as for the major issues in life - falling in love, getting married, having children, life achievements, etc., don&#39;t think about it for now. Anyway, the ship will be straightened out. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Are these people dissatisfied with life? Yes, if you ask them this question, they will say: the salary is not high enough and the vacation is not enough. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Once you start to feel confused, it means that you are fundamentally different from them. In your heart, you don’t want to live a life like a pig pen. You don’t want to be the same as all other living beings. You want to discover yourself. , live yourself. But now, you still have no direction at all. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;You clearly feel that something is missing in your life. You may not know what it is, but you at least understand that it is not money and leisure time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It can be said that confusion is the beginning of exploration and the beginning of change. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;In fact, the most desolate &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; attitude is not to be in &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;confusion &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; , hesitant to move forward, but as if being beaten with chicken blood, full of energy, focused on&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;rushing forward, everything you catch is an opportunity, everything you see is an opportunity. Target. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This kind of anxious state like a headless fly is called premature closure of self-identity in psychology. That is to say, without enough thinking and exploration, you prematurely identify your own personality, identify with a certain goal, and then plunge into the corresponding field wholeheartedly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I have really seen too many people who only have enthusiasm and some start-up capital, and then study hard, take various business classes, learn about success, and listen to various big names analyze the trends and success of entrepreneurship. The essence of it, and then almost crazyly getting to know top people from all walks of life, flattering, trying to please, trying to get into their circles, struggling for a group photo with friends, buying a lot of books without even reading them, but learning the industry slang After learning a lot, I thought I had accomplished something. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the end, these people often want to do too many things, but fail to accomplish anything. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Moreover, even if they succeed, they may not be able to agree with themselves from the bottom of their hearts, because everything they do is based on identification with external opinions, and they just follow what others say , just reproduce the successful process once according to the rules summarized by others. You followed the trend and opened a hot pot restaurant. Is hot pot really what you want to do in this life? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Calm your mind &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Come &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; because the most valuable thing is not the hard work, but the pious dialogue with one’s own heart. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are many people who work hard. If you look at the office buildings in Shenzhen at 11 o&#39;clock in the night, or at the gathering place for Internet celebrities in Hangzhou, each one of them will be flying. And when you see these people working hard, you actually feel embarrassed - everyone is obviously struggling, but I am the only one lying down here, and I am separated by them again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are at least two &lt;strong>;thinking misunderstandings&lt;/strong>; in such self-talk. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;First, you are not lying flat. &lt;/strong>;If a person is lying down with guilt, then he is not lying down, because people who really lie down will not reflect on themselves. They will only think that their current life is very good. I don’t. It is necessary to think about some more things that are available and not available. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And you are just at a low point in your life. You need to settle down for a period of time to find your true direction while restoring strength in your heart. What I fear the most is that I can’t even calm down, and I feel guilty even when I rest. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Second &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;, &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;You are not on the same track as everyone else, and there is no way you can compare. &lt;/strong>;If you feel that you are greatly separated by others, then there is only one possibility, that is, you agree with other people’s rules of the game and force yourself to be on the same track as others. This track It&#39;s called - being richer than others and having more status than others. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even if you succeed, you will not be rich in your heart, because from the bottom of your heart you don’t feel that the first priority in life is to make money. You just want to live a good life and live yourself. And the more you identify with the values ​​of the public, the farther away you will be from your true self. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;So, what you want is not struggle, but introspection. There are so many people who are struggling, but there are very few&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;people who know how to introspect&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cherish the time when you are confused, because when the day comes when life forces you to gear up and move forward, you will no longer have the time to calm down and think. . While you are still confused, do more things that you really want to do, but may not produce any utilitarian gains. Do more things that are not for pleasure, but that you truly agree with your nature. You can assume that if I have entered a communist society and can survive without much labor, what will I do with the extra time? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Don&#39;t worry, you will find the answer. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Mei Butan onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the call for papers information, please see @ONE Studio pinned on Weibo. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fh_rAFN3IDcz2KT6BHHjGoD051Ge &quot; alt=&quot;Hong Sang&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Hong Sang&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Psychology Consultant, WeChat public account: Hongsang&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -- >; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span >; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3936&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Why is it so difficult to &quot;reject&quot;? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3931&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Young people vs. the workplace, who has rectified whom? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3938)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[学以无用]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6121]]><description>&lt;div>;9 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Palace Master Bing&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt; img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fuo3zzp78XZSUlWHG_fGO5bnFbah&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fuo3zzp78XZSUlWHG_fGO5bnFbah&quot;>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the long years of more than eighty years, grandma has made great achievements in career, life and family. Continuously plays the role of being abandoned. Looking back from this moment, my grandfather’s life was indeed glorious, but my grandmother’s “useless” time was equally magnificent. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the day she was diagnosed with cervical cancer, my grandmother started writing her autobiography. Because I couldn’t type, I helped her input the manuscript into the computer and became the first reader. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I had just won a composition award in the city that year, and I was quite young and frivolous. Whenever I encounter words or phrases that are not beautiful enough, I always try to give them some pointers. For example, she wrote that the process of her grandfather&#39;s pursuit of her was &quot;asking for instructions early and reporting later&quot;, that &quot;the situation was very good&quot; when they planned to get married, and that after the marriage, her grandfather regarded her grandmother&#39;s words as the &quot;highest directive.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For me, who grew up reading &quot;Youth is a bright sorrow&quot;, it is really boring to write about love without writing about the spring breeze and autumn moon, and without using the metaphors of overlapping chapters to make the words colorful. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grandma was annoyed by my nagging, so she decided to learn Pinyin and computer by herself. Although she learned it with difficulty, my grandmother used her one-finger Zen skills to type extremely slowly. She often wrote a manuscript in an hour and took two hours to complete the recording. When I went home to recuperate between chemotherapy treatments, I saw my grandma playing with the keyboard like a turtle, and I couldn&#39;t help but do it myself. Unexpectedly, before I opened my mouth, just as I was approaching her computer, my grandma stopped me from looking at it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At that time, I thought my grandma was dissatisfied with my advice on her writing style. Many years later, I realized that my grandma could not tolerate anyone&#39;s advice on her love. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grandpa and grandma’s love began in Russian. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grandma has learned a lot of useless things in her life, and she has the best command of Russian. But even though it was a skill learned at a young age, when grandma was old, her only function was to use her uvula to imitate car horns to amuse children. If I hadn&#39;t met my grandpa, maybe even this function wouldn&#39;t exist. Maybe God arranged for grandma to learn Russian in order to let her meet grandpa. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Back in 1959, the first industrial oil erupted from Well Songjisan, and Daqing Oilfield officially entered production. Two years later, my grandfather retired from the army and became one of the first officers to aid the construction of Daqing. As more and more people gather in Daqing, this small village that was used for hunting by the Mongols hundreds of years ago has become an independent district. The government plans to build schools, hospitals, and even department stores here. This is finally no longer a wasteland with more rigs than people. In addition to the comrades who fought together in the oil fields, many young and fresh faces began to appear on the streets. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My grandmother is one of them. It was 1964, and the slogan &quot;Learn from Daqing in industry&quot; was in full swing. Daqing became a city more fascinating to young people than Beijing and Shanghai. After graduating from the Teachers College, my grandmother set off from Henan to join her uncle who worked in Daqing and became a Russian teacher in a middle school. My uncle is a lively person, and he often held gatherings with fellow villagers during his years in Daqing. It was at such a gathering that my grandfather, who was also from Henan, met my grandmother for the first time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That year during the Laba Festival, my uncle held a banquet for guests. After three drinks, someone among his comrades began to play the accordion, and everyone sang Soviet songs along with the music. When &quot;Katyusha&quot; was sung, the eyes of several strong young men in the room fell on my grandmother, the only young female guest. Grandma wrote in her autobiography: Those men are all like hungry wolves seeing meat, but I want to show them who is the real wolf. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She asked her comrades to accompany her again, stood up and sang &quot;Katyusha&quot; solo in pure Russian. In those years, the Soviet Union was still the big brother in Europe and Asia. If a person was proficient in Russian, it was as if he had an all-powerful backer, and in the eyes of others he always seemed a little more proud. Sure enough, after grandma finished singing, the frivolous eyes of the men suddenly turned into respectful ones. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grandpa arrived at this time. As usual, grandpa was still the last one to leave in the unit on Laba Day. After listening to his grandmother&#39;s solo outside the door, he applauded her along with the crowd, then took off his cotton hat and quietly entered the house. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the narratives of grandma and mother, grandpa is always very busy at work. At first, grandma regarded this as an advantage and felt that grandpa was motivated and responsible. Later, when we lived together, this advantage turned into a disadvantage. Later, my grandfather passed away in a hurry. Regardless of the advantages and disadvantages, they all became regrets buried deep in my heart. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In short, when I was young, my grandfather impressed my grandmother with his sincerity and thirst for knowledge. After being introduced by my uncle, my grandmother officially became my grandfather’s Russian teacher. I think that in my grandfather’s heart, Russian was not only a language for finding a good future, but also the bright and bright Bragi of my grandmother, the drunken evening breeze in the suburbs of Daqing, and all the unknown romance and tender dreams. He wanted this dream to last longer, so he proposed to his grandmother. Grandpa promised that he would take grandma to visit the Soviet Union if he had the opportunity after marriage. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was also bad luck. Soon after the marriage, relations between China and the Soviet Union were sour, and the honeymoon trip to the Soviet Union came to nothing. By the time Sino-Soviet relations eased, my grandmother was already pregnant with my uncle. The uncle&#39;s arrival not only ruined grandma&#39;s honeymoon trip, but also messed up her work. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the time when she was pregnant and had her baby, a new batch of middle school students had begun to learn English, and Russian teachers were ruthlessly eliminated. Although my grandfather had already risen through the ranks and became a high-ranking official in the cultural department at that time, he refused to establish relationships with his grandmother. In other words, he felt that it was enough for his grandmother to be a woman who supported her husband and raised her children at home, and there was no need to go to school to show off. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grandma, who was extremely enterprising, approached the old leader of the school and begged hard, and got a job in the logistics department. Grandma felt that as long as she stayed in school and learned English well, she would still have a chance to be a teacher. Even though she was now changing from the person holding the chalk to the person delivering the chalk, she always felt that this was temporary. Until she got pregnant with my mother again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My grandfather did not care about the family. When my mother was born, he was promoted and transferred to the education department. Grandpa was very happy about the birth of his two children. He felt that both of his children were prosperous in officialdom. Although his grandmother&#39;s career was sacrificed because of this, he felt that it was worth it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, in my grandma’s view, the birth of her two children made her completely disappear from her original industry. The skills she relied on for survival could no longer help her make money. No matter how good she was at writing in chalk, After using it, she lost her job. Although some people would say that being a housewife also has a great job, grandma is not willing to accept it. Although her husband has been promoted steadily and can support her and the children, she has no sense of security, especially when learning a new foreign language. She feels like she has been abandoned by the times, but she cannot tell anyone about this feeling. There was no time to even say it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To say postpartum depression may be a bit hypocritical, but more of a sign of exhaustion. When my uncle was a child, he always cried for no reason at night. He finally exhausted his patience and coaxed him to sleep, and my mother started to have a high fever again. The winter in the Northeast is very cold, and after countless trips back and forth between home and the hospital, my mother’s tonsils were removed. Later, due to excessive injection of antibiotics, the mother&#39;s hearing in her left ear was irreversibly damaged. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grandpa blamed the child&#39;s illness on grandma&#39;s poor care. After a big quarrel, grandpa found a young nanny from the countryside. In my grandfather&#39;s opinion, the nanny was diligent and obedient, and was much easier to get along with than my grandmother, a senior intellectual. But in the eyes of grandma, the existence of the nanny is a humiliation to herself by grandpa. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The arrival of the nanny not only did not ease the family relationship, but also aggravated grandma&#39;s anxiety. Grandma felt that not only had she lost to her grandpa in her career, but now she was not even as good as a nanny. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nowadays, heroines and independent women are advocated. Grandma’s change in mentality resonates with many modern people. However, forty years ago, Grandma’s negative emotions could only be interpreted by family members as difficult. The bad conduct endured. After my uncle and mother became more sensible, they began to find ways to avoid the moody grandma, and grandpa came home late more and more frequently. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But you can still hide away for a while. During the Chinese New Year, families always get together, and New Year reunions in the north always involve making dumplings. Kneading the dough, cutting the stuffing, wrapping it into balls and cooking it in a pot, it seems like a simple process, but grandma always fails to do it well. Grandpa always complained that the skin was too soft and not chewy enough, and the filling was not fragrant. My uncle and mother always eat one or two and then have the rest. This kind of harm to the family gave grandma a huge sense of grievance. In her later years, she still wrote in her autobiography: &quot;I have learned many things in my life, but I can&#39;t cook.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Of course, grandma’s statement that she can’t cook is a bit exaggerated, she just doesn’t do it well. As a Henanese who has lived in the Northeast for half his life, my grandmother did not know the two major pasta skills of making dumplings and pancakes. It was okay to forget that the dumplings she made were unpalatable. If she was asked to pancakes, she would often make them raw. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sometimes I can’t help but think that my grandma is such a smart person. She can even learn Russian with hundreds of changes in the gender of words. With just a piece of dough, How can it be difficult to keep her? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Perhaps it’s not that she can’t learn it at all, but that she never wants to learn it. It seems that as long as she learns how to make dumplings and pancakes, she has admitted that as a woman, she can only serve the family. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I guess my grandpa probably thought about this in his later years, so when he was approaching retirement, he suddenly became more family-oriented. He no longer criticized his grandmother’s cooking skills, and even took the initiative to buy her many Russian novels. But my grandmother felt that her life had been wasted, and those Russian novels had never been read until I grew up. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My grandfather was diagnosed with liver cancer when he was sixty years old and passed away within three months. As soon as my grandfather passed away, my grandmother decided to leave Daqing. Thinking back to thirty years ago, my grandmother was inspired by the times and came to a completely unfamiliar city with passion, hoping that she could apply what she had learned. Thirty years later, she felt that the city no longer needed her, or in other words, the city had no longer needed her. She has not left for a long time, just to serve her family and her man. Now that the man has left, she is relieved. Whether it was her love for Daqing or her love for grandpa, grandma felt that she had achieved the best that a woman can do. For the rest of her life, she wanted to live for herself. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My grandma used the money left by my grandpa to choose two cemeteries on Wanshou Mountain next to the Longmen Grottoes in Luoyang, one to bury my grandpa and one to keep for myself. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the two years after returning to Luoyang, my grandmother lived a life of indulgence and confusion. She smoked, drank, dyed her hair red, traveled around on the large inheritance left by her grandfather, and even went on a few blind dates, leaving a few photos with strange old men. She was tossing herself desperately, trying to grab something from this messy life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She is free, but also old. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;None of the old men who dated grandma really touched her heart. Perhaps she still couldn&#39;t let go of the futility of her studies. When she was young, she could blame everything on her husband and children. But now that the lady is gone, the beauty is old, and love and hate have returned to dust, what else can she do except go crazy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But this madness did not last long, and the great layoffs in 1998 ushered in. History moves forward, but it repeats itself in cycles. Just like my grandmother in 1968, thirty years later, my parents were also in the dilemma of using their knowledge to no avail. They graduated from prestigious universities and worked in the country&#39;s top machinery factories. They obtained cadre establishment in Luoyang at a young age. Just when they thought their future would be bright, the factory could no longer pay basic wages. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Perhaps it was obvious to bystanders that when faced with the plight of her children, grandma showed unprecedented calmness and courage. She told her mother that if there is no hope in a city, leave decisively and go to a place with more opportunities. With my grandmother’s support and encouragement, my parents dared to make up their mind to leave Luoyang and go to Shanghai. Many people who were laid off at the same time as my parents are still in Luoyang. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The story later turned out to be bright and clear. Under the guidance of my grandmother, my parents found new jobs in German companies and Taiwanese companies respectively, and reaped the dividends of the development of the city of Shanghai. Grandma also seized the opportunity of the times and bought houses everywhere in Shanghai. Through the appreciation of real estate, she indirectly multiplied the assets left to her by her grandfather many times and completely achieved financial freedom. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many years later, when my grandma came into my life, she was already an amiable old lady. From her face, you can&#39;t see any unwillingness, although she is different from the common old ladies in life. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If we must find one temperament in her that matches her autobiography, it would be her love of learning. She seems to use her limited life to learn infinite things. Even things that seemed useless to me, such as beads, harmonica, and silk screen flowers, she learned with gusto. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I remember that every weekend when I was a child, my mother and I would accompany my grandmother to the Shanghai Bookstore to buy the latest handmade books or CDs, and then go to the small commodity market in the Chenghuang Temple for wholesale. Return a pile of colorful beads or silk screen. Grandma&#39;s hands are like a fertile land. If you scatter those crude materials, lifelike peonies, lilies, peonies, or sparkling tissue boxes and gold bags will grow on these hands. Soon, the house was filled with grandma’s colorful handicrafts. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As my grandmother’s skills improved day by day and the storage space at home became increasingly tight, my grandmother allowed my mother and I to give away some of her early works. It happened to be a school charity sale, so I took twenty silk-screen flowers, thinking that if I couldn&#39;t sell them, I would give them away, but they were all sold out in less than half an hour. A silk screen flower costs five yuan, twenty flowers is one hundred yuan, half an hour earns one hundred yuan, one hour earns two hundred yuan, if I sell for eight hours... then wouldn&#39;t I become a success? The richest elementary school student in the world! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I told my grandma about my genius idea, but she laughed loudly. She ridiculed me: &quot;Little ancestor, even if you can sell it, I can&#39;t do that much!&quot; &amp;rdquo;After saying that, she showed me her tools: three pairs of pliers with different functions, a stack of plastic sleeves for twisting flower petals, wires of different thicknesses and colored tape wrapped around the wires, and nylon wires tied by color. net. Not only are there many tools, the process of making wire mesh flowers is also quite complicated, and sometimes you even prick your fingers on the wire. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It turns out that the birth of beauty requires so much trouble and even pain. Looking at my grandma’s old hands and imagining the hardships those hands had endured, I couldn’t help but ask: “Since it hurts so much to make silk screen flowers, why does grandma still do it?” &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Because grandma likes to make flowers. &quot;She spread her fingers and showed off in her smile, &quot;And after getting calluses on her hands, she didn&#39;t feel the pain anymore.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Then what are these silk screen flowers used for? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As soon as these words came out, grandma’s smile disappeared instantly. She paused for a moment and suddenly became very serious: &quot;Sometimes, people do not necessarily do things for the sake of being useful; things that are done for the sake of being useful may also become useless; usefulness and uselessness are not decided by ourselves. . &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I nodded pretending to understand, completely unaware of the rugged thoughts behind these words. When I understood that what my grandmother meant was English and useless, I was already very old, and English was no longer useful. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I was in the third grade, my mother didn’t know whether she was tricked into attending a lecture by an education and training institution or accidentally entered an online chicken baby forum. She suddenly became worried about my promotion to junior high school. She took me to the Children&#39;s Palace to sign up for a bunch of interest classes. Since she and my father had to work during the winter and summer vacations, the burden of accompanying me to classes fell on my grandmother. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among the many interest classes, calligraphy is what I hate the most, but every time I go to a calligraphy class with me, my grandma is the most excited. Unlike sports such as dance and martial arts, calligraphy is a class in which parents feel the strongest sense of participation. This is not only because the calming effect of calligraphy is closer to adult preferences, but also because the ink used in calligraphy is a very dangerous weapon in the hands of children. , teachers alone cannot control it. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fortunately, I started learning late and had already passed the extremely destructive age, so my grandma was able to fully emulate my teachings when she supervised my writing. After attending two classes with me, grandma went to Fuzhou Road to buy another brush, dipped it in my ink, spread it on my paper, and became classmates with me. Soon her handwriting surpassed mine, and her passion for calligraphy was a hundred times greater than mine. A week before the start of school, I asked the teacher for leave because I didn&#39;t have time to make up for my summer homework. Unexpectedly, my grandmother went to the teacher alone to teach. From then on, I didn’t know whether it was my grandma who practiced calligraphy with me or me who practiced calligraphy with my grandma. Until now, more than ten years after I gave up calligraphy, my grandma still keeps in touch with the teachers at the Children&#39;s Palace and communicates from time to time. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When you grow up, it is inevitable that your grandmother will be obsessed with calligraphy. Just like making silk screen flowers, calligraphy is also an art that realizes elegance in boredom and integrates perfection in detail. In the early days of learning calligraphy, I couldn&#39;t help but feel frustrated when I looked at the crooked strokes on the rice paper and my nails stained black with ink. These dirty marks mark my childish stupidity. It is cruel for a child who is new to the world to face his own stupidity. But my grandma is tougher than me. Those old rice papers filled with waste words are like the calluses planted on my grandma’s knuckles by the iron wire. She believes more than anyone else that one day undefeated flowers will bloom on this bleak ruins. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was this spirit that made my grandmother a natural scholar. She is always focused when studying, as calm and composed as a well-trained warrior. She is not afraid of failure, or there is no failure in her eyes at all. All tests will eventually turn into bullets in the magazine and become her key to defeating time. arms. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Time decayed her body. Cancer first took back her uterus, radiation therapy destroyed her intestines, and an accidental fall shattered her hip joint, which had to be replaced with cold metal. Now she is so old that she can neither see nor move her legs. She can no longer make screen flowers, write calligraphy, or travel around. But every sunny day, she must let her uncle push her to the garden of the community. Play the harmonica. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Whenever the melody of &quot;Katyusha&quot; flows out from my grandma&#39;s piano, I seem to follow the sound of the piano and return to the Laba sixty years ago, to the place where my grandpa and grandma first met. that night. The north wind lifted her braid, and the heavy snow lit up her eyes. In the vast wilderness, grandma sang melodiously. She was truly a fearless lone wolf. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At that time, her life had just begun. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Li Jialong&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see the @ONE studio pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FpeR0h0SvASC3l3Ve3XoN3pkxB9z&quot; alt=&quot;Palace Master Ice&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Palace Master Ice&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;Weibo@宫主Bing&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Writer, his representative work is &quot;No Way to Say Goodbye&quot;. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/article/6116&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;The book-losing incident in 2009&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Article/Who&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/div>; tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Read&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6119&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt; div>;Huisheng Temple&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Ahu&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot; text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6121)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4020]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4161]]><description>&lt;div>;9 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fu4U19W3sKhfjKJnDIHCRn9PN6fg&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;VOL.4020&lt;/span>;Photography | Jake Nebov&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;9&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oct. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;The human heart is easy to understand It goes to death and silence, and after the suffering, it is rebuilt, agitated for a while, and then becomes numb again. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 09 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>