<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[我的父母要是这样就好了]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3960]]><description> &lt;div>;30 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Question from ONE Editorial Department&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>; What are the little things you always wished your parents would do? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; ONE Friendly Answers&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgbsfYkw2Q7wyS6C5oK3SfZnxW8J&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgbsfYkw2Q7wyS6C5oK3SfZnxW8J&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot; font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;We have received selfless love from our parents, but we have also experienced unspeakable grievances. They are first-time parents, and we are children who only get one chance to grow up. If you want to talk about your concerns about your parents, you can tell them to ONE friends in the comment area. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I once suggested that my parents buy a house in a small town. My mother said something that I will never forget: &quot;Buy in a town.&quot; Isn’t that good for you? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(89, 156, 215);&quot;>;I hope:&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;They can ask me if I have been hard at work recently. Thank you for your hard work. Ask me if I am tired. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Idealism, 27 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; My parents were a little biased. They bought a jade pendant for my one-month-old brother and then asked me what I wanted. I said I wanted a skateboard, but they didn&#39;t buy it for me, and they didn&#39;t buy me a jade pendant either. Although I was in the third grade of elementary school at that time, I really remember it very clearly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(89, 156, 215);&quot;>;I hope:&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;When I am bullied by others, my parents Not to accuse me, not to ask why others bully me, not to bully others. I feel really sad. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Xiao Xiao, 22 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Their casual concern had always been with their younger son. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(89, 156, 215);&quot;>;I hope: &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;They can take care of me more, instead of just saying &quot;I don&#39;t understand&quot; and leave the choice to me, and then use some prejudice to judge my final choice. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Metalworking internship in the afternoon, 22 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;They like to judge based on a single value. For example, if you get up at eight in the morning, they think you are &quot;lazy&quot;. If you don&#39;t make a lot of money, you are useless. If you don&#39;t work according to their expectations, you are not doing your job properly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(89, 156, 215);&quot;>;I hope:&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;1. Learn to &quot;let go&quot; and let the child go Treat them as independent individuals; 2. Don’t compare your children with other people’s children; 3. Spend more time on yourself and don’t pay too much attention to others. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Linda, 28 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although They keep saying that I am not as good as others, and when I reach the age, I should find a boyfriend and get married...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(89, 156, 215);&quot;>; I hope: &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;They can eat on time and not stay up late, because my parents are busy with business. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Wang Tonton, 23 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Because I didn&#39;t achieve the desired results, they blamed everything on my lack of effort. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(89, 156, 215);&quot;>;I hope: &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;They can understand my unhappiness and unhappiness. Studying in the evening every day is really tiring (manually wronged). &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Partly rainy, 16 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;My parents are separated. I have never dared to face this matter. I just pretend that they are still together. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(89, 156, 215);&quot;>;I hope: &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;I can travel with my parents every year , take a photo with them. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Li Gan, 24 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; My legs are relatively thick, and my parents are always used to comparing them with other girls, saying that my calves are so thick, while their legs are very thin, like bamboo poles, and my legs are like elephant legs. So when I grew up, I never wore short skirts or shorts, mostly wide pants. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(89, 156, 215);&quot;>;I hope:&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;Mom can buy more when she buys food portion so that she could eat it herself. Because she is very frugal, when buying meat buns and other things, she will only buy for her children, not herself. I also always say, buy an extra portion so you can eat it too. She would say she didn&#39;t want to eat. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Si Si, 23 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; When I was eighteen years old, I had a skill I wanted to learn. When I told my parents about it, all I got was negative. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(89, 156, 215);&quot;>;I hope: &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;They can recognize my efforts and growth over the years, See the change in me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Yu, 28 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Me I especially don’t like traveling with my parents. I feel like a little pendant next to my parents. I have no emotions and don’t look like an independent person. When I was traveling when I was young, my father and stepmother scolded me for half an hour in front of a bus of tourists because of a bottle of water. Even though I was very young, I still had self-esteem. This happened all the time when I went on a trip, and even now I still resist it when I grow up. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(89, 156, 215);&quot;>;I hope: &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;My dad can remember what I said and don’t grow old They used &quot;I don&#39;t have time to remember useless things&quot; to prevaricate me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Counting sleeping sheep, 19 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;My parents have always been very dissatisfied with my college entrance examination results. They would always say, &quot;Oh, you can do whatever you want if you get a few more points.&quot; When I really want to get out of such a shadow, I am always reminded of my unbearability, accusing me of not working hard and letting them down. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(89, 156, 215);&quot;>;I hope:&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;My parents will praise me more, or don’t have any There are too many demands, just hope that I will grow up to be a happy adult. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Qiqi, 21 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; When my parents fight, the kids get involved. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(89, 156, 215);&quot;>;I hope: &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;They should apologize even if they are wrong, I am right You can also praise and don’t belittle your children. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;A Qing, 24 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; They started telling me since I was little: If you don’t learn these skills well, your future mother-in-law won’t like you in the future. First of all, housework, cooking, etc., these skills are skills for an individual to live an independent and happy life, and have nothing to do with future mother-in-law. Secondly, why did you treat me as an &quot;outsider&quot; in the family when I was so young? Why didn&#39;t you tell me this to your elder brother and younger brother, but only to me and my sister? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(89, 156, 215);&quot;>;I hope:&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;Parents know and tell us how old we are from an early age There are physical and emotional changes that occur with age. These are normal phenomena. You must learn to feel and accept yourself. Another very important thing is not to shy away from sex education, whether it is for boys or girls. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Classmate Zhuzi, 24 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; My parents once randomly gave away my toys, clothes, dolls, etc. (my things) to others as favors without my knowledge. My family of origin is a grudge that I can never let go of, especially when I grew up and lived on my own, far away from my parents and everything in my native environment. When I saw how other normal parents treated their children, I realized that my parents were not incompetent. They know how to be parents, but they really don’t love me. I couldn&#39;t forgive, but resentment was useless. I kept convincing myself to move forward. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(89, 156, 215);&quot;>;I hope:&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;My biological parents will never disturb my peace now life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Meow Meow, 28 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; My parents would inadvertently compare myself to others. When they make a mistake, they are unwilling to apologize and choose to be vague. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(89, 156, 215);&quot;>;I hope:&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;Parents can not be so &quot;arrogant&quot;. Take the initiative to contact me and share your life instead of letting me wait passively! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Eleven, 20 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; I once had a very cute dog, but because my parents didn’t agree, they secretly gave it away when I was in school. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(89, 156, 215);&quot;>;I hope:&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;Parents will not turn the dining table into a court of justice, no matter what The conversation eventually turned into scolding me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Qingtian Xiaoxu, 19 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;My parents changed my name when I was eight years old, saying they wanted to change my personality or something. It felt like my parents had denied me even though it was only eight years of my life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(89, 156, 215);&quot;>;I hope: &lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;Accompany me to go to the provincial capital zoo. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;fujisan, 24 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At When I graduated from college, my second sister was still young. I have been unemployed at home for more than a month. They usually go for a walk in the fields after dinner, and only occasionally call me. I’ve lived in my teacher’s house since elementary school, and in middle and high school. In fact, the school has an open day for parents every week, but my parents seem to have only come once and brought some food. Although I don’t like drinking milk, I see many parents bringing it by the carton. It is precisely because I was not at home often and was raised by my grandparents when I was a child. In fact, my parents don’t even know what I like to eat. Although I don’t care about it now, I’m not picky about food either. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(89, 156, 215);&quot;>;I hope:&lt;/span>;&lt;/strong>;There seems to be no hope. After work, I would go home once every two months on weekends, and my mother would give me hot milk for breakfast, which seemed to make up for the regrets I had at that time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Le sinnone, 22 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Responsibility Editor: Nana onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;This Q&amp;A is from the ONE Editorial Department WeChat Moments solicitation. To participate in the solicitation, add the Editorial Department WeChat: oneapp2020. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8 &quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Complex The cutest people in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3729&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;How to transcend your original family and live like someone other than your parents? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3960)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[一片]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6143]]><description> &lt;div>;30 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text／April&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data -author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fluk3i-iklToc_NsXHIOagQgB-77&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fluk3i-iklToc_NsXHIOagQgB -77&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Life can be divided into many slices, for those you love, People are always more willing to share the best part and hide the rest. When the heroine met Lister, who was engaged in hospice care, in the hospital, the relationship ended at the beginning. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I originally thought, if someone asks &quot;What do you like about Liszt?&quot;, how should I try to describe him as a job? Ordinary, ordinary people with ordinary life and everything. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But before I could think of an answer, Liszt disappeared from my life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last autumn, late at night, a good friend suffered from acute kidney stones. It was already past 3 a.m. after I went to the hospital to settle her down. It’s rare for me to stay awake at this point, so I still didn’t feel sleepy, so I simply took my phone and jacket with me and decided to go to the first floor of the inpatient department for a drink. Probably due to the general trend of aesthetics, the tables and chairs in the restaurant on the first floor are all gray and white Ikea style. There are two vending machines at the end of the hall, with small bags of potato chips, chocolate bars, and milk of different flavors. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The coffee machine is on the other side. There are only a few overhead lights on in the restaurant. It is not clear whether the indicator light of the coffee machine is on. Apart from me, there were less than 5 people in the whole restaurant. Most of them were resting on the table. They were probably family members who came to the hospital to stay with me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Perhaps due to professional habits, I can always find very few people reading paper books in the crowd. Especially since there were only a handful of people in the restaurant that night, I immediately saw a fruit green copy of &quot;Ordinary People&quot; spread out on the table diagonally opposite the coffee machine, with the cover facing up. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liszt is the master of this book. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I use &quot;Can the coffee machine be used?&quot; ” started a conversation with him, even though there was a khaki paper cup without a logo or lid next to &quot;Ordinary People&quot;, which contained a small half cup of Americano. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Oh, yes. But at this point,&quot; Liszt clicked on the screen of his phone and glanced at the time, &quot;I guess there is no more milk, so I can only serve American style. &amp;rdquo;I squatted down and took out a paper cup exactly like his from the cabinet, and also drank an American cup for myself. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the early hours of the morning, this different schedule from daily life inspired me and made me feel that everything was reasonable. So I took the initiative to ask him: &quot;Do you think Connell likes Marianne? Or does he just want to sleep with her?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liszt was obviously caught by my senseless question and the question itself. He was stunned for a while and said, &quot;You mean this book?&quot; The two protagonists here? Connell and Marianne? &amp;rdquo;He subconsciously picked up &quot;Ordinary People&quot;, looked at the cover, and then looked at me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I could feel his embarrassment. I should have stopped there, but I continued to ask, &quot;So which one do you think it is?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later, when Liszt and I talked about the conversation that day, he always wanted to summarize, &quot;Without Sally Rooney&#39;s book, you should He wouldn&#39;t take the initiative to talk to me either. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He works in a service company that provides hospice care for critically ill patients, and his responsibility is to read a passage to the patient lying on the bed. &quot;Read everything...&quot; I have read &quot;A Dream of Red Mansions&quot; several times. The original plan was to read to the grandma only the story of Baoyu and Baochai getting married, and the story of Daiyu&#39;s death. After listening to it, grandma said, I want to hear again Baoyu’s first meeting with Daiyu. There are also people who want to listen to &quot;Pride and Prejudice&quot;, but they want me to read English, but I can&#39;t. Oh, I remember one that impressed me deeply. I wanted to hear about a Japanese writer named Banana. She wanted to hear about the story about a girl who took a taxi from Izu in the middle of the night and gave a boy a fried pork cutlet with topping. That part of the meal. This girl was very young and suffered from a blood disease. When I went to read this story to her, she had no energy to speak, but I could see her crying. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That night in the hospital, Lister introduced his work to me like this. I didn&#39;t think there was anything bad about this job at all. On the contrary, when he mentioned &quot;pork cutlet rice&quot;, I saw him smiling as if he had remembered something, and I felt a soft place in my heart. Was hit all at once. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But I didn’t say anything at the moment, I just held the paper cup and took a big sip of coffee. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The sky in the early morning of autumn is dark blue. Near sunrise, the distance slowly fades into crimson, and then into highly saturated orange. Through the large glass windows of the restaurant, seeing such quiet colors makes it easy to get closer to the people who are looking out the window together. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Do you still have work today? I mean, wait until daybreak. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Well, yes. At 7:30, an auntie wanted to listen to me read some Shu Ting before entering the operating room. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;But aren’t you...hospice care? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Yes, this aunt doesn’t have much time left. It doesn’t matter whether she does the surgery or not. She just wants her daughter to feel at ease. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Then let’s have breakfast together. It’s 5:30 now.” I raised my wrist and glanced at the watch. “I’m going home and bringing a few changes of clothes for my friend.” , and then bring you a sandwich. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;That’s fine. I almost finished reading &quot;Normal People&quot; when you came back. &amp;rdquo;I&#39;m not surprised at all that he didn&#39;t raise any objections. We, who probably hadn&#39;t slept all night, and the few remaining people in the restaurant were enveloped in an atmosphere where everything we did was reasonable, even if there was one We wouldn&#39;t be surprised if a zebra and a giraffe kissed in a restaurant. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first time I heard about Frenchtoast was in Naoko Takagi’s manga. At that time, I had just joined the publishing house and had just started living alone. I had a great interest in cooking. enthusiasm. &quot;Dip the cut-off toast pieces evenly into the milk and egg liquid, put them into a frying pan with butter on the bottom, and fry over low heat until golden brown,&quot; Naoko Takagi introduced it this way. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That morning I fried two slices of toast for Lister, sandwiched bacon and cucumber between them, spread a layer of peanut butter on them, cut them in half and wrapped them in greaseproof paper. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Liszt was two-thirds of the way through the meal, the anesthesiologist in the operating room called and said that the aunt who asked him to read poems was not in good condition and could not be operated on, but she insisted on lying on the bed. On the operating table, after listening to Shu Ting&#39;s poem. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Then I’ll go. Then you...&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Me? I happened to check on my friend and she was almost awake. &amp;rdquo;After saying this, I immediately realized that what Liszt wanted to ask was not where I was going next, but whether I would contact him again, and if so, how to contact him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The courage I had been given in the early hours of the morning a few hours ago was dashed away by the traffic on the way back to the hospital in the morning. But a frail life was still lying in the operating room waiting to listen to Liszt reading Shu Ting for her. I didn&#39;t have time to think about whether I was not reserved enough, so I took out my phone, unlocked it, opened the dialing interface, and crossed the paper bag with the sandwich on the table. A thin book of Shu Ting&#39;s poems, &quot;Ordinary People&quot; with the cover facing down, and two paper cups that I didn&#39;t have time to throw away last night, I handed them to Liszt and said, &quot;Leave a phone number.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I didn’t know how he would respond, so I left my number. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When we met again, my friend had been discharged from the hospital. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We arranged to meet at the subway station near the hospital, and he arrived before me. We haven&#39;t seen him for about a week. He had a haircut and was wearing dark gray sweatpants, a navy sweatshirt, black sneakers, and a cardboard box under his arm. He was standing next to a pile of shared bicycles near the subway entrance, with his back to the direction I came from, his head lowered and looking at his phone. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;hey. &amp;rdquo;I tapped his shoulder lightly with my index finger and found a line of very small CALIFORNIA on the lower right corner of the sweater. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Here it comes,&quot; he locked the phone screen, threw it into his trouser pocket, and then handed me the paper box, &quot;This is for you.&quot; &quot;I subconsciously reached out to take it, but he took it back and said, &quot;I&#39;ll take it first, Shen.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What do you want to eat? &amp;rdquo;We walked down the stairs side by side and walked towards the entrance of the subway station. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;It’s okay..., ah, but,&amp;rdquo; He turned his head and smiled at me - the same smile as when he said &amp;ldquo;pork cutlet rice bowl&amp;rdquo; &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;ldquo;You girls hate it when boys say, &quot;Anything is OK,&quot; right? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I don’t seem to have thought about this issue. &quot;As I answered him, a solution quickly and automatically formed in my mind: &quot;How about you go to my place? There is a really delicious takeout place near my house.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Ha,&amp;rdquo; he was obviously a little surprised by my proposal, but he didn’t shirk it, &amp;ldquo;So what kind of takeaway is it? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Ah, that is a pretty small Italian bistro. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Let’s go then. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;It is a collection of plays by Lai Shengchuan. &quot;Liszt was sitting barefoot and cross-legged by the floor-to-ceiling glass door between my living room and the balcony. He probably noticed that the silence between us lasted for a while, so he picked up another topic. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;In that box, I gave it to you. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At that time we had already finished the takeout. We ordered Neapolitan pepperoni pasta, creamy mixed vegetables, and a 9-inch Margherita pizza. I took it out of the refrigerator and kept it for a long time. two cans of coke poured into glasses. Excessive intake of carbohydrates made me sluggish, and it took me a while to think, &quot;Oh, that box, the box in the subway station.&quot; &quot;But I had no intention of getting up to open it. I sat on the other side of the glass door and said &quot;thank you&quot; to him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;By the way, &quot;Ghost House&quot;, do you remember it? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Remember...? &amp;rdquo;I picked up the cup and took another sip of Coke. &amp;ldquo;That story about the boy who made cake rolls at home? &amp;rdquo;I searched hard in my mind, and there were too many novels and movies with &quot;ghost&quot; and &quot;home&quot; in their names, but I intuitively felt that this was the one he was talking about. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Yes, yes. I thought of this when you just suggested coming to your house. Let me read you a paragraph.&quot; He shifted his weight to his left leg, reached into his pocket with his right hand, took out his cell phone, and tapped the screen a few times quickly. I noticed that the way he typed was different from mine - he held the screen with both hands and tapped the screen alternately with his thumbs - this gesture was very much like he was seriously replying to a work message. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;&amp;lsquo;When I am invited by a boy who lives alone, I always don’t know how to answer. But this time I thought, because he said it, he must have meant it literally, and the apartment he lived in seemed to be very close. There was an incredible brightness and gloominess about him, just like the misty sky in the middle of winter, which was half cloudy and half clear. This made me reluctant to like him. Because I was completely incapable of feeling that all-too-precious, run-based frenzy and excitement between young lovers. &amp;rsquo;&amp;rdquo;After reading this short paragraph, Liszt put down his phone, changed his posture, stretched his legs, and looked at me with an expression as if he was waiting for me to say something. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You haven’t dared to like me yet? &amp;rdquo;Although my thoughts were still confused, somewhere in my heart reminded me that this sentence was the secret he hid in this passage. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was noncommittal. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The night did not end with a muddle-headed lovemaking like the two characters in &quot;Ghost House&quot; did. We talked a lot more, mostly about the patients he met, until I started yawning frequently and he suggested leaving. We packed up the takeout boxes with me, and when we said goodbye at the door, he changed the big garbage bag to his other hand, as if he could easily turn his watch back to the moment when he read &quot;The House of Ghosts&quot; - -The discussions about life and death in the middle were like No. 12 Grimmauld Place, which was hidden between two houses in Harry Potter and folded up with a &quot;ding&quot; sound. ;&amp;mdash;He answered my question and said, &quot;But I still really want to like you.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I can’t say what attracted me to him, but I did fall in love with him. We often dated in the hospital restaurant. I brought a book manuscript to be edited, and he brought a book that the patient wanted to read. When he came across something I had not read, he would read a few passages to me in a low voice, such as &quot;Divorce&quot; by Lao She. &quot;, Acheng&#39;s &quot;Venice Diary&quot;, and even &quot;Private Life in the Soviet Union during the Stalin Era&quot; - I would not take the initiative to read them, but I listened to him read them. After work, he sometimes stayed overnight at my house and sometimes went to his house. Apart from this, we almost never appeared together on other occasions as a couple - not even the restaurant where we often order takeout. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This kind of relationship is something I have never had in my previous relationships - it seems that it was only when I was studying in the hospital restaurant, and when he used to put his arms around me before falling asleep - ;We are lovers in the true sense. But the weird thing is that I don&#39;t doubt the relationship between us, and even proudly confirm to myself &quot;I am in a very good relationship&quot; when we are alone. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That Friday, my work ended early, so I packed two boxes of fried pancakes and went to the hospital without sending him a message. When I was approaching the inpatient department, I saw Liszt sitting by the flower bed downstairs with a middle-aged man. Liszt was carrying a plastic bag containing an ultrasound report, and the middle-aged man was holding a large bag of medicine in his arms. The middle-aged man&#39;s appearance clearly shows that he is financially strapped. He looks like he is physically and mentally exhausted from taking care of a seriously ill patient at home for a long time. So I reflexively thought that this was another family member of &quot;Party A&quot; of Liszt, so I walked forward without hesitation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I got off work early! Sorry to bother you. &amp;rdquo;The following sentence is for middle-aged people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liszt saw that my expression was not as excited as I expected, but instead subconsciously took a step back. The middle-aged man looked very calm, and he naturally set his eyes on me. During our brief look at each other, I found that I could not decipher his emotions. He looked at me with a mixture of &quot;I know who you are&quot; and &quot;But I don&#39;t care who you are&quot;. Such calm indifference made me very uncomfortable. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;This... my girlfriend. &amp;rdquo;He said to the middle-aged man. Turning to me again, &quot;My dad.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I tightened the bag of fried food in my hand, and his expression accurately conveyed the message that he did not want to meet his father and I at this moment in the hospital. I looked away and didn&#39;t move or speak. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Oh, hello. You guys chat, I&#39;ll go up first. ” Liszt’s father grabbed the report bag in his hand and left without looking back. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Is it still American? &quot;Liszt squatted down and reached for a paper cup in the cabinet. &quot;Well,&quot; I took out the wet wipes and wiped the table, and opened the bag of fried food. Apart from this sentence, after his father left, he only said, &quot;Let&#39;s go to the restaurant.&quot; Just like that night at my house over pizza, he was free to fold for a while so that meeting his dad never happened between us. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Ah, the fried bottom is not even crispy anymore. &amp;rdquo;I poked it with my chopsticks, not knowing whether I was pretending to cooperate with him easily or waiting for him to speak on his own. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;It smells good. Give me some vinegar. &amp;rdquo;He pushed the coffee in front of me and picked up a pair of chopsticks. His tone, demeanor, and the way his upper body leaned forward slightly and his chest pressed against the edge of the table all told me that he was ready to join me in a passionate discussion about how delicious the pan-fried buns are. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But he just didn’t mention his father. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When working in a publishing house, it is inevitable that you will encounter authors whose manuscripts have been declined. Although the rejection letters are all sent to the authors&#39; mailboxes in the form of emails - most of them will not reply to us - there are still some very persistent authors who will come to the door in person with their works. The usual procedure for handling this type of situation is that after the author explains his intention, the front desk informs the editor. The editor will ask the editor who is not busy at hand to go to the reception room to receive him politely. &quot;The attitude must be firm, otherwise he will still be there tomorrow.&quot; Come on, do you understand? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I am always worried that I will be assigned to deal with such a situation, because I cannot bear to repeat the words of rejection on my lips in response to what others have spread out in front of me. The embarrassment of trying to regain your respect after your self-esteem is frustrated. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liszt commented enthusiastically in front of me that &quot;pork stuffing is more delicious than shrimp stuffing&quot;, as if he didn&#39;t want to admit that the indifferent and slightly rude person in front of the flower bed just now was. My father&#39;s Liszt reminds me of those cramped authors in the publishing house&#39;s reception room. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So I decided not to mention it until he took the initiative to talk about it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After that day, we still dated as usual and took turns spending the night at each other&#39;s houses. However, when he said &quot;I am in the hospital&quot;, I would not continue to ask &quot;What did I read today?&quot; , because after meeting his father, &quot;He is in the hospital&quot; to me is like an opaque white barrier he has put up between us. There seem to be countless small squares on the barrier. He is in the hospital. In the box in the upper left corner, it may be reading &quot;Afternoon on Granthans Island&quot; to a terminal breast cancer patient. In the box in the middle right, it may be a family member of a patient who died of renal failure. I would like to express my gratitude to him for his previous work, but there are always a few pieces in these grids. He must be taking care of the owner of the ultrasound report that day in the ward - maybe his grandparents, maybe his mother, I can&#39;t help but Know. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My question is tantamount to deliberately using a sharp weapon to break this barrier. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In mid-November, my colleagues from the publishing house gave me two experience cards for an improvisational performance workshop. It was a recently opened studio. Two or three In one hour, under the guidance of the performance teacher, you will complete an improvisational performance based on a specific theme. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;A colleague gave it to me. Shall we go play some other time? &amp;rdquo;I took a photo of the experience card and sent it to Liszt. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;What a bourgeois entertainment.&quot; This message was followed by a simple and honest smile, and we made an appointment to go together next weekend. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although I don’t want to admit it--but I am just like those boys who think that by taking their girlfriends to watch romantic movies, they can change their minds--I do have a voyeuristic mentality. , hoping that through this performance, the barrier between us and him will be eliminated. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before going out, I changed out of my brightly colored sweater and skirt and wore a black turtleneck sweater, light blue high-waisted jeans, and a brown canvas bag that I often use to carry manuscripts. , go to the subway station to meet Liszt. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You look like a female reporter in French movies from the last century. &amp;rdquo;Liszt commented like this after seeing me. I felt very useful and suddenly felt excited. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The subway was not too crowded after lunch. We stood side by side in the middle of the car. When the subway was running, in the dark track, we could clearly see each other in the windows. His dark red sweatshirt and my black sweater were almost swallowed up by the dark background, but I could still see his facial features clearly, and I also saw his reflection on the window accurately sending a smile to my reflection. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The improvisational performance workshop is in a semi-sunken basement. The lighting and ventilation are not satisfactory, but the empty stage and the messy metal armrest seats under the stage Coupled with the yellowing lights, it looked a bit like an audition scene for a film crew. In addition to Liszt and me, there were two other young boys. They were already sitting on the chairs closest to the stage and were talking eagerly. Obviously, the arrival of Liszt and I did not arouse their interest. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Considering that none of you have any experience in acting, today I will give you four more everyday scenes. The four of you will discuss it and choose one from them. Then you will need to cooperate and continue to improvise the performance of this scene. ,&quot; After the workshop teacher gave a brief introduction, he handed each of us an A4 paper with four sentences on it, &quot;1. The wall clocks showing Toronto time and Osaka time in the hotel lobby suddenly stopped, waiting for check-in&amp;nbsp ;的客人还没发现&amp;rdquo;、&amp;ldquo;2.诗人独自一人站在湖边大声朗诵&amp;lsquo;草色烟光残照里，无言谁会凭阑意。 &amp;rsquo;，几位游客注意到了他&amp;rdquo;、&amp;ldquo;3.两对新婚夫妇在希腊某个小岛上一起蜜月旅行，正在商量晚餐吃什么&amp;rdquo;和&amp;ldquo;4.独居的男青年忘带钥匙，恰好整栋楼停电，决定步行下楼找物业帮忙开锁时，碰到了邻居&amp;rdquo;，&amp;ldquo;给各位一刻钟时间简单商量一下选哪个场景，我们就可以开始了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;这句诗&amp;hellip;难道有什么深意？ &amp;rdquo;两个男孩中其中一个穿着牛仔外套的最先开口。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我去，我完全不懂唐诗啊。 &amp;rdquo;另外一个黑色帽衫接话。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;这个好像，可能，貌似，是，柳永？ &amp;rdquo;牛仔外套边看手机，说话的音调不自觉地变高了，我和李斯特面面相觑，也接不上话。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;哦，柳永不是唐朝的吧？选这个的话，是要做诗词鉴赏了？ &amp;rdquo;黑色帽衫挑起了眉毛。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;那不然新婚夫妇？我们正好四个人？ &amp;rdquo;牛仔外套边说边抬眼望向我和李斯特，好像突然意识到了表演也需要我们两个的参与。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我觉得可以，总比诗词歌赋好。你们两位看有没有什么意见。 &amp;rdquo;黑色帽衫马上又接上话。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我和李斯特交换了一个眼神，刚刚在地铁上轻盈的快乐，好像已经飘远了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;那就这个吧，&amp;rdquo;我朝着两个年轻男孩的方向点了点头。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;牛仔外套和黑色帽衫就希腊的小岛上会不会有中餐厅开始了争论，一个斩钉截铁地说有，另一个非要查手机确认。一直没有说话的李斯特突然站了起来，&amp;ldquo;这本来就是虚构的故事，而且我们也不一定非要去中餐厅吃饭吧。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;行，那我先拍个照，你们往这边坐一点可以吗？对对，我拍完就可以开始了。 &amp;rdquo;黑色帽衫的男孩对着观众席的位置拍了几张，我顺着他取景的方向看过去，只有几把凌乱的扶手椅而已，但午后的光线确实还不错。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;原本以为他们还需要时间来决定谁演其中的一个妻子，黑色帽衫就已经很自然地入戏了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们商量好，直接从在餐厅坐下点餐开始表演，工作坊里的表演老师坐在台下，身体前倾，认真地看着我们。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们几乎同时举起了刚刚发的那张A4纸，假装是餐厅的菜单。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我要一个圣托里尼番茄煎饼，一杯希腊咖啡。 &amp;rdquo;牛仔外套率先完成了点餐，紧接着用极小的声音说了句&amp;ldquo;刚刚在知乎上查的&amp;rdquo;。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;老公，那你也帮我点一下吧。 &amp;rdquo;黑色帽衫大概是想模拟一个娇妻的嗓音，但反而听起来更加奇怪了，我感觉得到李斯特和我一样，都在努力憋笑。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我要一个希腊沙拉吧，&amp;rdquo;我说完后，也像他们一样放下了A4纸。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;那我&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;A4纸挡住了李斯特大半张脸，他好像真的在研究一本厚厚的菜单一样，停顿了几秒，最后决定&amp;ldquo;我跟你一样&amp;rdquo;。我一点都不意外，因为他确实会像这样，在一些需要决定吃什么、咖啡要什么口味之类的场合，完全失去主见。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你们明天准备去哪里玩？ &amp;rdquo;牛仔外套一只手撑着头，对我和李斯特发问。黑色帽衫交换了一下翘着的腿，也在等我们回答。李斯特看了看我，假装整理一下桌上的桌布，我在脑海中飞速搜索除了&amp;ldquo;圣托里尼&amp;rdquo;以外的地名，刚要开口回答说&amp;ldquo;我们想去看看格兰汉斯岛&amp;rdquo;时，他沉静、从容地接了一句&amp;ldquo;我们明天准备返程了&amp;rdquo;。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大概是计划好的台词突然没办法接上了，牛仔外套和黑色帽衫的惊讶完全展露在了脸上。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我们，&amp;rdquo;我扭头望向李斯特，&amp;ldquo;是明天就返程吗？ &amp;rdquo;那一个瞬间我感觉自己是真的和他在异国旅行，我兴致盎然准备探访一些景点时，他却突然告诉我今天就是我们旅程的最后一晚。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;抱歉明天不能跟你们同游了，我爷爷生病了，情况不太好，得赶回去。 &amp;rdquo;这句还是对着他们说的，他并没有直接回答我刚刚的问题。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;哦这样，那你也不应该跟我们道歉吧，这是你和她的蜜月旅行，是吧。 &amp;rdquo;黑色帽衫挺直了后背，马上接上了话。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;爷爷生病了？ &amp;rdquo;意识到我们还在扮演新婚夫妇，我咽回了&amp;ldquo;你爷爷&amp;rdquo;，拿起刚刚那张A4纸开始对折。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;黑色帽衫和牛仔外套似乎很满意我们有一个可以继续的话题，他们应该还沉浸在&amp;ldquo;另一对新婚夫妇因为行程产生了分歧&amp;rdquo;的戏码里，我却无比清醒地意识到，李斯特并不是在演戏。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;脑溢血，就是中风。昏迷挺久了，家里有点不想继续住院了，但我不同意。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;工作人员扮成餐厅服务员，把事先准备好的餐厅道具&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;几个放了食物模型的白色餐盘、刀叉和4个玻璃杯一一摆在我们面前的桌子上，同时给我们的杯子里都添了水。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;能真喝嘛？ &amp;rdquo;黑色帽衫小声嘀咕，工作人员轻微点了点头，退回了舞台后面。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;老人生病确实比较麻烦，但这也是没办法的事。 &amp;rdquo;牛仔外套拿起刀叉，假模假式地在食物模型上比划了几下。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你们可以去看看格兰汉斯岛。村上春树写过的。 &amp;rdquo;这其实是我知道的为数不多的希腊岛屿，所以脱口而出。仅凭上次在医院和李斯特爸爸碰面，我单方面认为他并不想继续就此讨论，所以决定替他换一个话题。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;村上春树&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;是不是写什么森林的，挺黄的。 &amp;rdquo;黑色帽衫自如的表情让我分不清他是真的这么认为，还是只是在塑造他扮演的角色。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我不同意也没什么用，住院加上陪护的开销不是我一个人能承担得了的。所以我爸爸很生气，他觉得我在做梦，真以为自己已经在这里站稳脚跟了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;又一次折叠。我们明明可以就《挪威的森林》好好聊下去，再讲讲村上春树的一些游记，轻松、体面地完成晚餐部分的表演。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;牛仔外套和黑色帽衫显然愣住了，索性不开口了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;那所以&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;我也没有想好自己到底想问的是什么，如果沉默是有形状的，那此刻它从对面的两人那边被送到我面前，又被我递给了李斯特。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;所以才会在医院碰到我爸爸。 &amp;rdquo;他说完后低下头，拿起了面前的玻璃杯。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我在想，是不是大家演着演着，演到最后，都开始分不清哪句是台词，哪句是对方真心想说的话。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那天的即兴表演还是以黑色帽衫和牛仔外套的争执草草结束了，表演老师点评说了些什么我也没有听进去。黑色帽衫留下了在场所有人的联系方式，包括我和李斯特的。但我内心深处总是认为，他这么做只是出于礼貌。因为从一开始，我就感觉得到他们在面对我们时那种微妙的轻视。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;晚上就看到了他发的动态，9张图，全部做了黑白处理，其中就有我看到他拍的那张观众席，还有两张是现场工作人员模糊的剪影，最后一张是他们的自拍。文字是用英文写的易卜生最知名的两句语录&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;至少从知乎上看是这样的。即兴表演、剧场、黑白的光影、加上英文，整条动态都构筑了一个审美高级又极具文化内涵的下午。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;只是我和李斯特被排除在外了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;几个月之后，朋友第二次肾结石发作入院&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;距离李斯特离开已经过去了一段时间。我没有向他追问原因，但隐隐知道，一定和那个下午有关。帮朋友搬东西去病房时，碰到了原来和李斯特经常联系的医生，他说有一个李斯特落下的文件。 &amp;ldquo;可能是之前他读完书忘记带走了，护士看到了，就帮忙收着了。但我们一忙就忘记了，要不你带给他吧。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文件装在一个快递纸袋里，纸袋已经被撕开了，被压得平平整整。是一份遗体捐献的确认书。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我突然意识到我不曾真的了解他，和他共度的时间也只是他人生切片的其中之一，但可能是他尽力拿出的最好的一片。 &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;责任编辑：舟自横&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;征稿信息见@ONE一个工作室置顶微博。更多编辑部的有趣日常请关注小红书：ONE一个编辑部。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FoSUhogtB_tNIsneKD20hYfXutUb&quot; alt=&quot;April&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;April &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;普通写作爱好者。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;关注&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;相关推荐&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/3547&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;云泥&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 班宇&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6143)&quot;>;点击可下载ONE一个app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4041]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4184]]><description>&lt;div>;30 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FhC6IJhb5GJ4kcBDQzMC8MKSqSvw&quot; alt=&quot;首页图&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4041&lt;/span>;摄影| Ariel&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;30&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oct. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;我对你透露一个大秘密，这是人类最古老的玩笑。&lt;br />;往哪走，都是往前走。&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>