<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[一周的心情｜本周小记精选]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3913]]><description> &lt;div>;17 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Question from ONE Editorial Department&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>; It&#39;s been a week, how are you? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; ONE Friendly Answer&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1 ;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Another week has passed, and life may be destined to be busy, but ONE friends may wish to take a break here and observe the scenery of life elsewhere. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fhijhvn3tgF-MEIt156LgxWucE60 &quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fhijhvn3tgF-MEIt156LgxWucE60&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src =&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Firafp4RvF4RTZFfEBWMYMEtlsLm&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Firafp4RvF4RTZFfEBWMYMEtlsLm&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fo9e5FMC3ivkarC8s6iX4HPIttsX&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fo9e5FMC3ivkarC8s6iX4HPIttsX&quot;>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Ftk6bms4ExxMdk3CD8cLKf2GPjwE&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image .wufazhuce.com/Ftk6bms4ExxMdk3CD8cLKf2GPjwE&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Ft8cto2ma2r4ykknk7_GknW9YXsa&quot; data-source =&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Ft8cto2ma2r4ykknk7_GknW9YXsa&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http:// image.wufazhuce.com/FqHB_5yV8fGIxry326M9KQ1n6NnI&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FqHB_5yV8fGIxry326M9KQ1n6NnI&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FsgnSPuMH059R4zpu1swN5d6Zfh4&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FsgnSPuMH059R4zpu1swN5d6Zfh4&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot; false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FuAC6lwN-M8liXnX728aGLNbWgZK&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com /FuAC6lwN-M8liXnX728aGLNbWgZK&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fs6PvNkQUiMBfhuhJMRt3YdqGaQV&quot; data-source=&quot; &quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fs6PvNkQUiMBfhuhJMRt3YdqGaQV&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image. wufazhuce.com/FlDp5icDHKindQJi6IoONo-1YBRL&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FlDp5icDHKindQJi6IoONo-1YBRL&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author= &quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FopmL4VBqgz7nKrhz7NR0ysh6scz&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FopmL4VBqgz7nKrhz7NR0ysh6scz&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable =&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmVAdaDbJht-WyHP0To7dfsEYh9S&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce .com/FmVAdaDbJht-WyHP0To7dfsEYh9S&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmPe7BbQ0GHdKeyuI2hcpruYCFbu&quot; data-source =&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmPe7BbQ0GHdKeyuI2hcpruYCFbu&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http:// image.wufazhuce.com/Fj7u6spFByOiRfnNPCXvSZlNRn8S&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fj7u6spFByOiRfnNPCXvSZlNRn8S&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fgx6JJVAnnpOeWjPzMGW7LVjbDmS&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fgx6JJVAnnpOeWjPzMGW7LVjbDmS&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br >;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Zhou Ziheng onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Click on &quot;that pen&quot; below the date signature on the homepage, Leave your life moments and your emotions that cannot be expressed clearly to others in the tree hole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8 &quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Complex The cutest people in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3905&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;My mood of the week | Selected notes of the week&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, 3913)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 06:25:11 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[医生总在黎明时到来]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6094]]><description> &lt;div>;17 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;文／深宇&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data -author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FrUPsO2vXWKoD1KWp74y74hZ6lRy&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FrUPsO2vXWKoD1KWp74y74hZ6lRy&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;When a teenager who is tired of studying and pretending to be sick meets a doctor who is only interested in profit, what will happen between the two of them? Tango? Perhaps there are countless people who have gone crazy. The so-called normal life is only determined by who is better at pretending. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If everyone is more or less similar to some kind of animal, Zeng Qin initially left me with Her impression is similar to that of a mare - she is quite tall, with long and thick black hair tied into a ponytail on the back of her head, swaying from side to side as she walks; her fair, vibrant skin is wrapped in plump Physically, it&#39;s as elastic as milk pudding. She is not the kind of beauty who is stunning at first sight, but there is always a hint of smile at the corner of her mouth, making her whole face full of mystery. When she walked towards me from the end of the corridor where the psychological consultation room was located, against the light, her whole body seemed to be enveloped in a circle of golden light. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was seventeen years old at the time, and I was trying every possible means to escape from that key middle school that kept students like poultry. I am a sponsored student, which means that my family spent a lot of money to allow me to go to school there. Since the fifth grade of elementary school, I have lost interest in going to school. I never do my homework, and I always copy other people&#39;s work for exams. Being late and skipping classes are commonplace. But until high school, I still couldn&#39;t escape school. The reason is simple. As a teenager and a half-year-old, if you don&#39;t go to school, you have nowhere to go. You have nothing to do, you are not wanted, the door of the world has not yet opened to you, you are not welcome wherever you go. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When you are tired of the short-term liberation brought by playing truant and the lengthy reprimand you will face afterwards, the only way out now is to drop out of school. I have never wanted to accomplish something so sincerely. From the first to the second year of high school, I have exhausted all the methods that a high school student can think of in his limited experience, and in the end I had to pretend to be sick. Dizziness, insomnia, forgetfulness, bad temper, and severe anorexia...these symptoms clearly gave him the appearance of a mental disorder. At this moment, Zeng Qin appeared. This young woman, who had just graduated from medical school less than a year ago, seemed to play the role of a psychologist in the life of the world-weary boy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strictly speaking, Zeng Qin is not the kind of harmless and charming girl - there is always a cold intelligence on her face, which often makes it difficult when dealing with others. Perceived oppression. But men would always be attracted by some of her casual expressions or movements. Look at her small face like a pit, with slender eyes and upturned eye ends. Her hair was as black as if it had been soaked in ink, making her skin appear fairer. Such a woman seems innocent, yet has just the right amount of cunning, and is fully aware of her own charm. They always looked at her as if they were staring at a fruit that was about to ripen, round and heavy hanging on the branch, as if they could pick it off just by reaching for it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon when we first met, she sat across from me and observed me for a long time. After watching me fill out two sets of mental status test forms, I lifted up my shirt and auscultated my heart and lung function. After measuring my heartbeat, pulse and blood pressure, I opened my eyelids and used a small flashlight to shine a light on the contraction of the pupils of both eyes. , she concluded that I suffered from a disease that was very rare at the time: depression. She also said that if my disease was not cured, I would not live to be twenty. &amp;ldquo;The only fatal possibility of depression is that it can lead to uncontrollable suicidal tendencies. &amp;rdquo;In front of my parents, she had spoken so plainly that it actually made me embarrassed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I knew what suicide was like, had no fear of it and had no intention of avoiding it, but my parents were visibly embarrassed by having to talk about it in public. My dad took out a handkerchief from his pocket and wiped his sweat - this is his habitual action when he is nervous, embarrassed or even ashamed. &quot;Okay, let&#39;s do this. Let him receive psychological counseling first...&quot; Having said that, my mother obviously lacked confidence. She frowned and asked Dr. Zeng worriedly, &quot;If this treatment doesn&#39;t work?&quot; Yes, do I have to send him to a mental hospital next? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are many people in the hospital, and it is filled with the smell of disinfectant, medicine, blood, sputum, and washed grindstones. If you smell it for a while, you will feel dizzy. I sat in the psychiatry chair biting my nails, trying my best to appear abnormal and turning a deaf ear to their words. I planned to vomit on the spot a few times if necessary in order to get a doctor&#39;s certificate for suspension of study. After the conversation with the doctor, my mother sobbed uncontrollably and my father fell silent. I guess they felt real despair for the first time - this child might be dead. This turned out to be much more serious than I expected. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It can be seen from this that not only do I have no mental problems, I may be more awake than most people. It is said that character determines destiny, which is natural, but who else cares more about my own destiny than me. Seeing me sitting there with an indifferent expression, and gradually starting to get impatient, Zeng Qin finally issued a certificate—I could temporarily take a break from school to recuperate at home, but the condition was that I had to go to the hospital for psychological counseling every other day. Next two hours. This should be the best arrangement I can get under the current situation, and I agree with it silently. Before leaving, I cast a complicated glance at Zeng Qin. She had a confident expression on her face and frequently comforted my parents. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;The mental health of adolescent children must be taken seriously. Now there are some relatively advanced drugs. Let’s treat it for a period of time and then see how it goes. Don’t worry too much. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This hospital is located on a hillside in the southern suburbs, far away from the city. When we went there, we stopped and had a meal. The lamb is said to be delicious. It may not be appropriate to use &quot;we&quot; here, because I didn&#39;t eat mutton or other food in the restaurant, and I only drank a few drinks of water. The explanation is not complicated - I am a vegetarian and plan to stick to this habit for a long time. My parents had no premonition of the coming crisis. They didn&#39;t expect that I would be so &quot;sick&quot; and that I might even commit suicide. They just regarded this as an ordinary outing, so they feasted on three kilograms of mutton in clear soup. and two plates of seasonal stir-fries, with an extra serving of rice. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Our family is very meat-loving. When I was only two years old, I got food poisoning from eating too much fried pork liver. The consequences were so serious that I almost died. In the past, like my parents, I also enjoyed meat, and I was more interested in game, such as muntjac and pheasant. I was also keen to drive to various towns and villages with my father on holidays to buy fresh mountain products. At that time, I had a good relationship with my parents, and people around me liked me quite a lot. In fact, I have been a lovable child since I was a child, I mean when I was still willing to play this kind of role. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since two years ago, I stopped eating meat and refused to eat foods including eggs and milk. Besides making me sick, the smell of meat gave me nightmares. The key high school I attended implemented so-called &quot;military management&quot; on students. Every morning at 6 o&#39;clock in the morning, they gathered in the school playground for morning exercises. The specific content was to run 10 laps on an 800-meter track. If you are late, you will incur more severe corporal punishment, including leapfrog, push-ups, standing, etc. There are various torture methods until all your energy for the day is exhausted. After being a vegetarian for a while, I obviously felt that I no longer had the energy to complete such a huge amount of exercise, so I simply skipped the entire morning class. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since I entered that school, I have suffered from long-term insomnia, along with anxiety, cynicism and other typical rebellious symptoms. In addition, my long-term vegetarian diet has made me skinny, and I am not as tall as the male classmates in the class. , seems to have never developed. When wearing a tight T-shirt, you can see two rows of ribs clearly visible when you move your hands and feet. As a teenager in adolescence, growing up requires a lot of nutrients, but I feel that I need to rely on vegetarianism or similar behaviors to preserve something inside. As for what it is, I can only say that it has something to do with the budding self-awareness. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Countless nights, I lingered on the rooftop of my home for a long time, smoking one cigarette after another, sometimes drinking some beer, listening to rock music with a fierce rhythm, and there would always be thoughts in my mind. Distant imagination about punk. Those young people who are out of touch with the secular world live all over the world. They are young and angry, unruly and brave, and it seems that there are four big words written on their foreheads-&quot;Just disobedience!&quot; &amp;rdquo;But I&#39;ve never seen a living punk, if I don&#39;t count myself. Alcohol and tobacco made me dizzy, and my body seemed to become very light, as if just a breeze was enough to fly me far away. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I shaved off my hair and eyebrows, refused to go to school or speak, started hitting street lights with an air gun, and destroyed trash cans on the roadside...My parents couldn&#39;t figure out what caused this mutation. They thought that there might be too much pressure from study, coupled with the rebellious psychology of adolescence or something, but they didn&#39;t think deeply about it. This is good, it will make me feel more relaxed - even if my dad really cares, I can&#39;t give him any specific and clear reasons for being world-weary. I always remain silent for long periods of time, as if the weariness of life has swallowed up my voice. I don’t know where the violence surging in my heart comes from. I just want to destroy something with simple and crude means, no matter the cost. It&#39;s to destroy myself. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After many inquiries, only this hospital had a psychiatrist - at that time it was still an absolutely new term, and depression probably sounded better than &quot;crazy&quot; or &quot;schizophrenia&quot; &quot;It was a little better, so my parents had no choice but to be a doctor and entrusted me to this young doctor who didn&#39;t seem very trustworthy. Later I learned that Zeng Qin was only 24 years old that year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the psychological counseling one after another, Zeng Qin’s understanding of me continued to deepen, and I also became familiar with various hidden corners of the hospital while wandering around day after day. I know very well in my heart that psychological counseling is useless. It is just a packaged excuse at best. Since I had to kill time anyway and didn&#39;t want to go to school, I had no choice but to go to the hospital. I often had the same dream at that time: a simple swing hung from the air. It was just a piece of wood tied between two ropes. I sat on it and started swinging. The strong wind kept blowing all around, making it difficult to open one&#39;s eyes. When my hands finally lost hold of the rope and I fell off the swing, I fell into the boundless cold and darkness. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The psychological consultation room under the psychiatry department is far away from the outpatient department, as if it is invisible, hidden in a building next to the inpatient department In an independent three-story building. The first floor is the rehabilitation room, which contains various sports equipment; the third floor is the animal laboratory warehouse, which is used to store many human organs and animal carcasses soaked in formalin. On the entire second floor, only the door of the psychological consultation room is open every day. The corridor outside the door is dark and long. There are two low-wattage voice-activated lights on the top, which will suddenly light up with the sound even during the day. Walking to the end, you can see an old-fashioned sink that is half a person&#39;s height. There is a damp mop on it all year round. The water valve is dripping and leaking water, and a group of dark green moss has grown in the corner of the wall. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Everything here seems isolated and divorced from reality, like a forgotten corner of the world. There are several windows open on one side of the wall, and the paint on the light green wooden window frames has peeled off in large areas. When I walk through the corridor to wash my hands, I often see many surgical patients with missing arms and legs or with their heads wrapped, basking in the sun in the small garden downstairs. I have many quirks, and washing my hands every half hour is one of them that&#39;s fairly normal. Whenever she takes too long to wash her hands, Zeng Qin will always poke her head out of the psychological consultation room and say, &quot;What are you doing?&quot; The voice is long and playful, and this is not a joke. Interrogative sentence, because she knows that I will always start to stay anytime and anywhere. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The lives of those injured are very simple. As long as the weather is good and people who can move around smoke and play poker in the sun every day, those minor or serious injuries can be recovered as long as they rest for a period of time without affecting their lives. produce irreversible effects. I&#39;m often curious about the reasons for their injuries. For example, one person&#39;s right hand is missing a finger, another person&#39;s entire leg is covered with bandages, and still others are missing an ear, or one eye is covered with white gauze... The stories behind it should be complicated, and all involve dangers and difficulties that may be encountered in daily life, but the pain of others does not help my current situation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I had to reveal something to Zeng Qin, answer her questions or take the initiative myself, otherwise I would not be able to get the job and my vacation would be over. I have never thought about whether silence is a cause or effect of depression. But Zeng Qin said to me: &quot;You are the only one in your world.&quot; &amp;rdquo;She may have noticed that I have no need to talk to others, unlike my noisy peers. After a period of psychological treatment, if my condition did not improve, I might have to receive formal psychiatric treatment - being tied up like a pig and giving electric shocks. She also felt that the outcome would be too serious. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Every other day, I get up and take a two-hour bus ride to the hospital. I get there just in time for lunch at 11:30. This matter is quite a headache. The hospital has several canteens with different dishes and prices, but none of them have a little bit of meat in them. Zeng Qin did not persuade me to stop being a vegetarian, nor did she say, &quot;It&#39;s okay to eat meat occasionally.&quot; Instead, she prepared a long loaf of bread commonly known as &quot;Caterpillar&quot; made for children with sick children. The filling is cream jam - as a doctor, she is obviously much more considerate than her kind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It can be seen from this that I decided that I like psychological counseling. For things that cannot be avoided, it is better to like them than not to like them. What’s more, Zeng Qin is not unbearable, and he did not impose anything on me. In my little experience in dealing with people, this is indeed a kind of comfort. I often wonder if she thinks I&#39;m abnormal. My rebellion, world-weariness and silence, or maybe she has long been used to it and understands that these are just some fears that adolescent children have about life that must be accustomed to. This is how people grow up, maybe my symptoms were just a little bit more severe. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I am not going to the hospital, I stay at home, sleeping most of the time and reading a small part of the time. I live in a kind of Completely isolated from the outside world. I think this state generally refers to having no sense of direction, in short, no goal. The family struggles that preceded this were difficult and tiresome in retrospect. The arguments with my parents were of no use. The hardest part was getting them to understand a little bit of my intentions. Of course, this is purely wishful thinking, but adults always think that they have mastered the truth for no reason, and it becomes more difficult to communicate. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I have had my own views on life very early. I feel that everything is meaningless, especially in such a small place on the border, where there is basically no choice in life. It&#39;s just a matter of going to school, finding a job, getting married, and having children who don&#39;t know what they will grow into. They have to do whatever they want at any age. This is the case for everyone, repeated generation after generation. Compared to my energetic peers, I definitely seem pessimistic and negative. But what I don’t understand the most is: why should we compare with others? Can’t it be okay if I don’t do what everyone else does? Facts have proven that most people who ask this kind of question are mentally ill, because humans are a group animal, and the main implication in the education we have received since childhood is that &quot;conformity&quot;--the value pursued by the group is always high. Yu He is greater than personal value. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sometimes when I dream about school, there is usually no one else in my dream, but in the dream about school, even myself disappears. A line of sight started from where I once sat and moved forward along the narrow aisle between the desks. There is still unwiped writing on the blackboard, which contains many mechanical measurement units, indicating that the last physics class was my most hated one. After leaving the classroom, my eyes wandered along the empty corridor for a while, and finally I chose to go downstairs from the left staircase. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The light in the corridor is dim, and there are many shoe prints and football prints on the walls at every corner. During class or after school, you can often hear the &quot;bang bang&quot; sound of balls hitting them. But there was silence in the dream. The road leading from the teaching building to the football field also leads to the cafeteria, the school back door, the auditorium, a toilet with more than 20 squat toilets and several teacher residential buildings. On the right side of the road are two tennis courts and some Tall trees. After walking this way, your sight will reach the end of the dream: the flower stand on the east side of the football field. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Judging from the surrounding light, it was probably summer evening. The setting sun gave everything a soft light, and even the low-hanging dark clouds were rimmed with gold. The grass in the football field is lush and dense, exuding bursts of fresh smell, just like the smell that suddenly comes when a watermelon has just been cut. The gaze stays here for a long time, facing the west. Judging from the direction in which the grass blades fell, it was estimated that a strong wind was blowing at the moment. There was no one on the court, and the surroundings were so quiet that it made people feel peaceful from the bottom of their hearts. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later, I woke up from the darkness, lay in bed and thought about the scenery of that school without emotion for a while. Although every dream related to it always starts from the class seat and ends on the sidelines of the football field, my favorite thing in life is not this route and these places. When I was in school, I stayed most often in the cool, quiet, and dark chemistry laboratory on the fourth floor of the experimental building. There is a faint smell of chemicals floating in the air, and there are many haunted legends about it. The administrator is a retired teacher who likes to wear short-sleeved shirts. In his memory, he has become too old to be blurred. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After each experimental class, I took the initiative to stay and help the class representative pack up the equipment, and he was also willing to leave early. Gradually, this job fell entirely on me. The teacher likes to arrange the experimental classes in the last two periods in the morning or afternoon, so that I can stay for a while after school. That building is a rare quiet place in a noisy school. The second and third floors are studios, which are provided to students in the junior high school and high school respectively who are determined to apply for art schools. They also stayed in silence for a long time, and none of them seemed to have artistic temperament. They often looked at the plaster heads with bitter expressions and worried. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later I discovered that another student had similar habits to me. He was short and unattractive. He seemed to be a residential student from a suburban county. He wore school uniforms that were as big as pockets all year round. Sometimes several classes with similar progress in the same grade would do experiments together. It was in such large classes that I discovered that he had an almost fanatical obsession with playing with experimental materials. He had no interest in the icy atmosphere I secretly enjoyed, finding a way to linger because of the chemicals rather than the lab itself. He stayed there more and more often and for longer and longer, secretly tinkering with things, causing me great inconvenience, and soon attracted the teacher&#39;s attention. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Not long after, at the morning meeting of the whole school, the principal announced that all the students in the school who had joined the cult had been found and expelled, and his name was among them. It is said that he has long been stealing dangerous chemicals from laboratories, especially sulfuric acid and mercury. An astonishing amount of reserves were found in a box under his dormitory bed, and he was not known to intend to use them for vandalism, suicide or poisoning. That was in the winter of 1999. With the arrival of the new millennium, the whole world fell into anticipation and panic about the new century. For a while, cults were in full swing. Recalling the lonely and focused figure of the boy alone in the laboratory, it is difficult to imagine that there is a connection between the two. After that, the school&#39;s management of the laboratory quickly became stricter, and registration was required for entry and exit. I have never been to that building again, including during experimental classes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I told Zeng Qin this, the season was already summer. I have discovered a pattern: people are more likely to have mood swings when the weather is hot. There was no need or intention to say something to her, but suddenly I felt like I was ready to talk. The desire to talk to her was like an itch that gradually penetrated deep into my heart. I seem to have some vague feelings for her. When I can&#39;t sleep at night, I often recite her name silently - Zeng Qin, Zeng Qin, Zeng Qin... Thinking back on her face makes me immersed in a secret The happiness is like relaxing in warm water, and those two monotonous syllables are like a spell, which can bring solace to the depths of the heart. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I convinced myself that this sentiment was not excessive - patients have to trust their doctors, right? Unknowingly, she seemed to have become a friend. Even though she was always observing me, my words, deeds, and even my unintentional expressions and spoken words would be recorded. In this doctor-patient game, she acted as an excellent listener. In addition to nodding appropriately or hinting with her eyes that she was listening, she never actively interrupted my story, and often lured me into a private conversation atmosphere. Despite this, the impression I had when we first met has never dissipated - she still makes me feel uneasy, like a time bomb planted around me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I tried my best to ignore these tremors from the bottom of my heart. Although Zeng Qin pretended to be very good, some unintentional expressions were enough for me to realize that she was also performing to a certain extent - between us The contact between them may not be sincere. It didn&#39;t matter, after all, being able to talk to her every other day was a relaxing compensation for my boring and scary life. When my sleeping situation improved, I began to believe in the role of psychological counseling. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The journey to the hospital does not feel long, but it is inevitable to be irritable when returning home. The bus stopped countless times for people to get on and off, and I was the only one sitting there from the starting point to the final stop. This is the last bus every afternoon, a dedicated line from the hospital to the city. The old-fashioned minibus swayed back and forth on the gravel road in the countryside. While feeling sleepy, I managed to look out the window at the farmlands and villages passing by. Many farmers were driving their livestock or carrying farm tools on the field roads. A thin mist seemed to linger in the dusk between the sky and the earth, distorting all kinds of daily scenes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the constant shaking of the vehicle, I often forget where I am. From this moment on, I smelled a strong smell for the first time. It was not pungent but left an accurate and clear impression, as if someone was burning hay nearby - the dry smoke was burning with the flames. A slight &quot;crackling&quot; sound reminded me that I was far away from normal life. I suddenly felt a little annoyed that I shouldn&#39;t have wasted time like this. I also felt more and more deeply depressed that everything I had to face now and in the future was caused by myself. The closer I get to the city, the more irritable I feel. I really don’t want to go home, but where can I escape to? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The most important question right now is: where should I go after the psychological counseling is over? Go back to school and continue to suffer, or look for a way out? Frankly speaking, I have no hope at all for my future life, and I don’t know how to end this huge loss that seems to be lost in the vast ocean. I don’t know whether it’s because I took a lot of drugs or because the anxiety exhausted all my energy. I often fell asleep on the last row of seats without realizing it, until someone kept tapping me on the shoulder and opened my eyes to look at the car. Arrived. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It’s still a long way from home, so I’m used to walking back slowly. The weather is getting hotter and hotter, and it gets dark later and later. The barbecue seller set up a roadside stall, and every street lamp was surrounded by a small group of flying insects. Do they know what they are doing and why they are doing it? The air was filled with a pungent stench, and a river was flowing with black wastewater, with solidified dirty foam floating on it. Soap factories and paper mills are working overtime again, polluting the air and water day and night. The odor produced is a headache and may be harmful to health, but over time, people have become accustomed to it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What about me? As I walked on the dirty and narrow road, I felt an inexplicable hatred for everything. How do these people around me do it so well? Could it be that life looks better in their eyes? What you can see is a mixture of canteens, small restaurants, and hair salons with suspicious pink lights and gauze curtains hanging at the door. Some people have their dining tables set up on the roadside, and their children are running around... They go on like this day after day. One day I lived contentedly and laughed. I want to step forward and take a closer look - is this what life is? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I try to look at these things as objectively as possible, but I still feel resentful. Lying in bed at night unable to sleep, maybe doing something can relieve the pain. What followed was a terrible week of failed negotiations with my parents, endless arguments every day, and late nights of packing and getting ready to go. I don’t know why things suddenly spiraled out of control. After the first phase of psychological counseling, I had to go back to school and had to downgrade to make up for all my homework. When my parents and doctors said this, I was not anxious at all. I always felt that I could figure out a way to deal with it, and my time was just wasted. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Everything is my responsibility. I don’t want to solve the problem, I just muddle along and take it one day at a time. There is one way to get out of here, but where? What can I do? What will you do for a living in the future? ... It is not easy to maintain even the minimum daily life - having a place to live, enough to eat, a job or regular income. Could it be that my mistake was to eat all day long and moan without illness? I feel that the call from the distance I feel, the power to fight against the same life, and such a real and painful faith... are they all hallucinations caused by mental disorder? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zeng Qin called home, and I briefly told her what had happened recently, including my plan to run away from home. Unknowingly, I began to trust her, and at this critical moment, I really needed to consult with someone. She pondered for a while and said, &quot;Well, if you agree, how about I talk to your parents?&quot; &amp;rdquo;In my opinion, the matter may have reached an irreversible point, but as far as the current situation is concerned, the best way is to delay it for a while without hurting the peace. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sure enough, after her communication, things came to a temporary satisfactory conclusion the next day. I will extend my leave of absence from school and continue psychological counseling. Another concession from my parents doubled my inner conflict and pain. I wasn’t sure if I really had depression, but I couldn’t explain the reason why I didn’t want to go to school. That would involve many things. Even if parents pretend to listen patiently, they will not understand. There is only one thing that is very clear. If you force yourself to sit in the classroom, it is a waste of time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Is Zeng Qin the only one who can understand me? Why is she the only one in the whole world who understands my thoughts and cares about my safety? She always had a calm tone on the phone, &quot;One day you will understand that life is serious.&quot; But the most serious of them all? Man cannot choose freely. Family environment, growth environment, and living environment are not things that can be changed just by struggling. &quot;I still can&#39;t understand the cruelty. In her words: &quot;Whatever you have or what you lack, it&#39;s all the same. People have no choice, so they have to live like this.&quot; ” But she didn’t tell me another thing: once someone starts to resist, they find it difficult to turn back.有那么一刹，我真切地感到风暴即将来临，在我的内心也是如此。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;离开学校后，除了班主任往家里打过几次电话，没有任何一个曾经的同学找过我。班主任希望我在家休息时继续进行自学，我可以理解他的一片苦心，但我准备自学的很可惜不是课本上那些东西。直到这时我才发现，在学校混了那么多年，好像竟连一个称得上是朋友、分别之后会想念的人都没有。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;表面上我人缘还不错，学校里有很多人认识我。平时最常跟同桌和后桌的人说话，还不时请他们吃吃喝喝，那几个人成绩相当好，因此也可以把这种交际看成我为了作弊拉拢关系。没有深交，也就不会产生矛盾，处理人际关系最有效的方法莫过于保持距离。但我知道班上那些人在背后都是怎么叫我的，&amp;ldquo;怪胎&amp;rdquo;，&amp;ldquo;疯子&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;肯定还有更难听的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然以前从没跟任何人提起过这些事，但告诉曾琴的时候，我一点儿也不难受，反而有一种清除心底淤泥的感觉。她脸上照旧没有表情，一边记录一边问，&amp;ldquo;在学校你觉得孤独吗？ &amp;rdquo;我告诉她，&amp;ldquo;很少。 &amp;rdquo;但心里想的却是&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;我离开后，那些仗着成绩好就随便孤立和欺负别人的傻逼是肯定不会放在心上的。这没什么要紧，生活中有几个人能大大方方说出&amp;ldquo;孤独&amp;rdquo;这类字眼呢？他们只会觉得你有病。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;雨季就快来了，天空的颜色逐渐变浅，像被稀释过的颜料，呈现一种清澈的淡蓝色。风把积雨云慢慢从山后吹过来，空气持续低压。这段时间以来，我跟曾琴聊了许许多多，生活中的一切都令我焦虑，虽然总试图掩饰，我想她还是早就看出来了。她也许是现在和将来唯一知道我心事的人，但我并不觉得真能和她成为朋友。个中缘由其实不难理解，我们只是医生和病人的从属关系。听我说话时，她脸上最常出现的那种笑，是连微笑者本人都知道是故意的、但又无法止住的笑。也许曾琴对我确实有一些关心，但我弄不清面对我时她究竟是什么心态&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;可能只把我当作研究对象或实验品。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;心理上自我隔离的症状假如超过某个限度，就已经成为一种病态。 &amp;rdquo;她不带感情地建议：&amp;ldquo;也许你可以尝试养只宠物。 &amp;rdquo;面对她时，我常感觉自己深陷在随心所欲的自怜中，既希望从她那儿得到更多关心和抚慰，却又不敢面对内心深处那饥渴的诉求。在这段医生与病人的关系里，我所扮演的角色或许已经近似某种宠物。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在怀疑、背德、依赖和自愧等五花八门的情绪中，我对曾琴的感情日渐复杂&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;它们与任何想说的话相去甚远，就像毫无目的的爱一样令人感到陌生。当与她并肩行走时，我的肩膀能察觉她的发丝拂过时带起的那阵微弱气流，而我们脚上穿的款式相同的高帮匡威鞋，又总在水磨石地上发出微弱而沉闷的摩擦声，那几乎就是从我内心深处传来的，空洞而无望的回响。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第二阶段治疗已到尾声，我异常困倦，不是平时那种熟悉的麻木和沉闷，而是新的排山倒海般的困倦，也许说成厌烦和失控更贴切。刮起北风时，我在空气中、在食物里、在生活的方方面面都可以尝到越来越浓的肥皂味。这有些尴尬，一个人居然不爱他出生和成长的地方，这多少有些不可理喻。但是你知道，假如他连自己也不爱，一切就很好理解了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;每天我都跟自己说，最终的战场在生活中，为了逃脱注定的结果，我已经放弃了许多东西。你能明白这种感觉吗？如果我失败了，这些东西就白白失掉了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我明白。但我还是想问你：既然一切都是你无法面对和解决的，你对所谓的胜利有什么把握吗？你想过还会发生什么可怕的事吗？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我越来越讨厌医院，那些身穿白大褂、戴着口罩、行色匆匆的人总使我焦躁不安，现在他们中的一些好事者已经对我很熟悉。我还知道护士们背地里对我的议论，有几次在食堂她们甚至当着我的面就谈论起来。 &amp;ldquo;那孩子这儿不太正常。 &amp;rdquo;往往是这样一个暧昧的开头，说着一边故作神秘地指指脑袋。围在旁边的一小撮妇女分别发出各种叹息声，&amp;ldquo;瞧着挺聪明的孩子，真是可惜了&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;好像她们头回听说世上有精神病人似的。对这一切我习以为常，偶尔视线交汇还不忘送个会心的微笑过去，然后看她们一脸惊慌地作鸟兽散。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;医院食堂毗邻一片面积很大的平房住宅区，司机、锅炉工、杂工、临时工等等后勤部门的人和他们的家属住在那儿。卫生条件相当恶劣，与医院内部的干净整洁相比如同天上地下。下水口经常堆着腐烂的菜叶和剩饭，唯一的公厕地面屎尿四溢，隔老远就能感到一阵刺激的气息直冲眼睛，路过时你根本不敢呼吸。还有为数不少的肮脏猫狗四处乱窜，生活环境呈现长期缺乏管理和平时毫不上心的状态。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有时我会来这一带转转，为了避人耳目，或被那股子热爱生活的劲儿吸引&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;破败的花台上有许多种在大碗和破花瓶里的植物，还有几丛生长茂盛的美人蕉。那天下午三点多，医院临时通知各科室开会，当日第二次治疗取消。我再次饶有兴味地到平房区转悠。员工都上班去了，除了一户人家传出麻将声外，周遭没有其它响动。火辣的太阳劈头盖脸照着，我有点儿犯晕，耳道深处传来&amp;ldquo;轰隆隆&amp;rdquo;的声音，就像有趟列车正从旁边驶过。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就在这时，我发现了它。这是一只肥硕的土狗，黄中带黑的皮毛粗糙、肮脏，耳朵耷拉着，头部和腹部有几块褐色斑点，丑陋无比。它被一条麻绳拴在某户后院的矮墙边，脖子上没有项圈，我不禁猜测它最终的归宿大概是在一只砂锅里与陈皮、干辣椒什么的待在一起&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;本地一些人有着食用狗肉滋补身体的习惯。我的出现使它大喜过望，拼命摇着尾巴，还发出&amp;ldquo;哼哼&amp;rdquo;声扑向前来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;至今我仍能回想起充斥在那些下午的光线、气味，还有空气中漂浮的微尘和我感受到的一切。对于接下来要讲述的事，我不会进行任何辩解。一场荒诞离奇的戏码即将上演，我打算告诉你的是，人在某些时候对带有毁灭性的行为怀有那样强烈的渴望，自己根本刹不住车&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;他们非做不可。为了平复内心的焦灼和厌倦，他们什么都可以牺牲。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我不止一次带着零食去跟那条土狗玩耍，时不时在它身上毛多肉厚的地方踢一脚，也会捡一兜小石子，在两米外向它投掷&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;它给我的感觉像一个人或某些类型的人，每次看到我时，那双三角形的小眼睛里总透露着期待、谄媚和讨好。它知道取悦我能换取食物，尽管它并不确定我是否喜欢它&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;这份圆滑的市侩太使人熟悉了不是吗？不少人就是这样泯灭本性地生活着，就连一条狗都比我了解在社会上混需要掌握的技能。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;所以我必须到那个后院去，那儿有使人眩晕的太阳、令人厌恶的动物和皮毛的臭味在召唤我，还有现成的工具和仿佛专为我的精神解脱准备的一切东西。只需跳过墙去便能跟映照出内心全部丑恶的动物周旋，我排斥和唾弃它一如厌倦整个尽管恨却离不开的世界。对已被黑洞侵蚀的心灵而言，这未尝不是一种拯救，那种迫使自己直面内心讨厌之物的行为似乎能带来扭曲的愉悦&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;谁也别同情我，我根本不在乎自己的感受。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;每次在烈日下与那条狗玩闹，我没一会儿便汗流浃背，心跳声大得几乎震破了耳膜，眼前逐渐模糊，两只手还无法控制地颤抖&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;这是药物的副作用吗？食物总能轻易使它得意忘形，仿佛我已经成了它最好的朋友。它惺惺作态地扭动着肥硕的身体，摆出一副小狗崽似的天真模样，向我哼哼唧唧地撒娇，一边大声招呼我跟它玩一边摇尾乞怜&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;这些令人作呕的丑态无不使我的恨意日渐膨胀起来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关于我当时的处境已经说得够多了，到第二阶段治疗结束前，我明显感到事情出现了偏差，也许跟那些药有很大关系。曾琴给我吃的五种药，都是尚在临床实验阶段、并未批准面世的进口抗抑郁药物。它们可能导致多种副作用，包括但不限于：幻听、手脚麻痹、嗜睡、对肝肾功能尚不明确的影响，视个体差异，还可能出现皮疹、幻觉、肌肉松弛、激素性发胖等症状。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;曾琴没让任何人知道，她正在与外地几家制药公司私下进行合作，而包括我在内为数不多的病人将为药品的上市和她日后发表的那篇研究抑郁症的论文贡献一份临床样本。当然，这些事都是后来经人举报才曝光的。关于那些药物可能产生的副作用，她简要地对我父母做过说明，但他们只关心这药能否治病，还一厢情愿地安慰我：&amp;ldquo;是药三分毒，只要病能快些治好，有点副作用就克服克服。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;表面上我已经可以有效地控制自己的行为，可精神上的失控却愈演愈烈，可怕的白日梦与对生活的仇恨交替折磨着我，但我已经战胜了所有恐惧。眼下我只关心那条狗&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;我不但要成为自己的主宰，接下来还要决定它的命运。看来需要制作一些专用工具了，其中必须有套住嘴的网兜，这样就能大幅减轻叫声带来的困扰；还得准备一块床单，以便罩住它那令人厌恶的嘴脸&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;晚上洗澡时，我频频呕吐，曾琴的脸、父母的脸和狗的脸交织在一起，带来难以言喻的生理上的难受，噩梦般的生活摧毁了我的理智，也让一切逐步脱离了常轨。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;8&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最近与那条土狗对峙时，我沉迷于观察和想像&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;大部分时间都在考虑如何杀死这头还在呼吸的活物。终于离开那儿时，全身肌肉都松弛了，但感觉一点儿也不好，仍旧是灼热、复杂、怪异。当你朝着某个可怕的方向步入越来越黑暗的地方，对状态再进一步分类就很难。自身感觉慢慢简化，最终浓缩成内心深处潜藏着的唯一欲望。假如这欲望得不到实现，世界就会停止，一切分崩离析。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关于如何干净利索结束那条狗的性命，我考虑得不可谓不周到，在记事本里写下各种计划，务求万无一失。但所有计划都是完全可行成功率又不高的&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;它太肥了，还又脏又臭，我不可能沾上血迹再回心理咨询室去洗。于是我明白眼下必须进行克制，不要冒险做出危险的事情。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;计划一：绞杀。 （可行性80%：优点为绳索易携带、实施简便、不造成流血。成功率50%以下。缺点为耗时较长且臂力消耗过多。&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;尸体处理方法：1.原地弃置。2.带走扔掉（太重、不作考虑）。3.附近挖坑掩埋（需带工具、耗时）。4.其它&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;（烧掉？）&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当我看着他们&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;医院内外那些人，心里总是翻涌着一股集合了憎恶、厌烦、愤恨和想要对他们做出可怕事情的念头。那些只在噩梦中才会出现的场景，每天都要在我脑海里实施好几次。因此我知道，假如放弃了对这条狗的最终控制，我可能同时会失去对某样更加危险的东西的控制，那就是我自己。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不久后的一次治疗中，曾琴刚让我服下药没一会儿，便被其他人叫了出去，医院好像在发什么物资，有空的医生可以先去领。她让我躺在心理咨询室那张窄小的床上先休息，又支了个瓷盆放在床边，因为我吃完药后头晕目眩，还止不住地干哕。&amp;ldquo;现在是最后的疗程了，&amp;rdquo;她边观察我的状态边说，&amp;ldquo;这种药的副作用可能会比较强，你忍一忍，我一会儿就回来。&amp;rdquo;又在我前额轻抚片刻，&amp;ldquo;没事，体温正常。&amp;rdquo;医用丁腈手套在我头上留下了冰冷、滑腻的触感，就像有条蛇从这儿爬了过去，接着我便陷入了昏迷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;后来的一切如同梦境&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;我先是搞不清自己在哪儿、在干什么，接着发现头上有帽子，脸上戴着口罩，身上背着一个双肩包。我检查了包里的内容：火柴、绳子、塑胶手套、黑色垃圾袋，还有一瓶75%的酒精。看来一切都已准备齐全，我稳住心神，慢慢横穿住院部前的花园，抄小路进入后门停车场。来到熟悉的矮墙外，看着那头凝聚我日常生活所有压抑、呆滞与麻木的动物正无忧无虑趴着睡觉，一个声音在耳边响起：&amp;ldquo;这是最后一次了，就让一切做个了断吧！&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我跳进后院，狗被惊醒了。看见是我，它脸上露出过分期待的表情，拼命摇动尾巴，丝丝缕缕的口水从嘴角往下滴。此时，头疼得非常厉害，&amp;ldquo;坚持住！&amp;rdquo;那个声音说，&amp;ldquo;就快结束了。&amp;rdquo;看我打开背包，它以为又有罐头，喜悦地朝前扑着。&amp;ldquo;现在用力拉！&amp;rdquo;来不及犹豫了，我一把抓住那根拴在它脖子上的麻绳，用尽全身力气拉，它刚哼出一声便翻倒在地。 &amp;ldquo;马上踩住它的身体！ &amp;rdquo;那个声音继续指挥道，&amp;ldquo;手上绝不能松劲儿！ &amp;rdquo;心跳如雷声般在耳边炸响，透过帆布鞋那薄薄的鞋底，我清晰地感觉到它的心跳也非常剧烈，就像有面小鼓在我脚下无止境地敲&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;ldquo;咚咚、咚咚、咚咚&amp;rdquo;。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;仿佛过了很久，它依然在挣扎。再胶着下去我的力气将很快耗尽，我把绳子绕在手上，用所能使出的最大力气向上猛扯，同时传来两声轻微的&amp;ldquo;咯哒&amp;rdquo;声&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;它的颈骨断开，我的右手也脱臼了。随着巨痛袭来，依然握着绳子的右手再也感觉不到任何生命迹象，脚下是绵软的一堆肉，可以感觉它正在空气中变得僵硬起来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;现在把绳子从它身上取下来，你就可以离开了。 &amp;rdquo;那声音说。四周静悄悄的，这场发生在午后的谋杀行动没被任何人发现。手臂疼得要命，已经开始肿胀起来，我端详着那具散发着臭气的尸体，一种异常的感受突然攫住了我的感官，头部胀痛加重了，汗水顺着脊背往下流，眼前逐渐模糊起来。要是此刻有面镜子，我就能看见那张双眼充血的可怖面孔，浑身散发着笼中困兽般的疯狂。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;尸体怎么办？ &amp;rdquo;我问。 &amp;ldquo;打开你的背包，看看里面有什么好东西。 &amp;rdquo;那声音回答。我从包里拿出酒精，咬住瓶盖拧了几圈后，将无色透明的液体全都倾倒出来，再划燃火柴。火焰窜起的瞬间，我似乎听见它&amp;ldquo;汪汪&amp;rdquo;地叫了两声，也有可能是其它狗的叫声自远处传来。毛皮焚烧的气味令人作呕，其中并未使人察觉到任何感情色彩&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;反正它也活不了太久，现在只不过把死亡稍微提前了一点儿。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那户人家院里的厨房屋顶上铺着油毛毡，这是一种相当易燃的黑色片状物，大风一起，不知道那儿会烧成什么样。但我心里已经没有任何感觉，喜悦、悲伤、忧郁、痛苦、欢快、遗憾、罪恶、解脱&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;什么都没有，甚至连平静也没有，整个人变得空空如也，一如内脏被全部掏空那样。这空虚充其量只会让人有一点儿难受，但我没想到的是，它将使你终生都能感觉到。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我没再回头看一眼，可我能听见燃烧的声音。直至今日，那团火焰仍在我眼前焚烧，&amp;ldquo;劈啪&amp;rdquo;作响，随风飘舞，不一会儿就成了灰烬。这就是是我需要的解脱吗？ &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;烧掉一切，包括自己。直到这时我才发现，大概从很久以前开始，燃烧就已在暗处发生。我点燃无形的火焰，在隐秘的地方烧自己，直至一切终结。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;直到我从病床上醒来，头部炸裂般地巨痛，浑身麻木、四肢无力，发现鼻端插着氧气管，手上还打着吊针。好几瓶大小各异的针水挂在床边的金属架上，喉咙干涸得如同灌满了细沙，我用尽力气想要水喝，却只发出了一阵呻吟。有人把一根吸管插到我嘴里，我不顾一切地吮吸着，没一会儿却又把好不容易喝的水全吐了出来。我再次晕了过去。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那天下午曾琴离开后，我便止不住地呕吐，随后陷入了昏迷，被送到急诊中心洗胃和抢救至今。看来我的身体对她给的最后一种药产生了强烈的排异反应，后来高烧持续不退，我又在医院躺了很久。过往的意识消失殆尽，仿佛做了一个冗长的梦，醒来后却什么也想不起来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;曾琴来看过我一次，没有提起医院家属区发生火灾的事。我终于忍不住问她：&amp;ldquo;那天下午着火了吗？ &amp;rdquo;她神态自若地看着我，反问道：&amp;ldquo;哪儿着火了？ &amp;rdquo;见我没有回应，又自顾自地说，&amp;ldquo;做噩梦了吧？这回你可受了不少罪。 &amp;rdquo;看着她头一次在我面前穿上便装，一身藏青色连衣裙&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;白皙的小腿又细又直，坐在旁边削水果的模样，我们双方都很清楚，心理治疗实际上就到此结束。父母都认为曾医生的治疗成果显著，因为我已经同意接受他们的安排，到乡下另找一所学校借读。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;千禧年那个疯狂迷乱的夏天至此画上句点。我开始写日记，还在其中不少篇目声情并茂地描述了康复后的喜悦和对父母的感激，其中不乏&amp;ldquo;生活重新向我张开了怀抱，我宛如新生&amp;rdquo;之类老派抒情的语句。写这种玩意儿当然是为了给父母看，这要比开口诉说效果好得多。但那个噩梦真的结束了吗？我被治愈了？ &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;你觉得呢？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;9&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;秋季开学后，我重新成为高一新生，在离家百多公里的县城中学开始了住校生涯。每天晚上，我到一位退休教师家里补课，从基础知识学起。一段时间后，成绩有所提高，尽管从来没考进过前十名，但总算离开了年级倒数的行列。补课的老师押对了好几道题，以致高考时我超水平发挥，那年本科录取分数线是480，我考了554，足够在几所过得去的大学选择一个所谓有前途的专业。那会儿金融和贸易最热门，毕业生们趋之若鹜，最后我如愿去了上海某大学网络信息工程专业。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;四年大学生活很快过去，毕业后我顺利留在上海，在门户网站找了份后端维护的工作，美其名曰网络工程师，薪水还不错。青春岁月好像没在我身上留下什么痕迹，我成了符合父母期望的那种人，日后还将过上随大流的生活&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;无非结婚生子、成家立业之类。可想而知，未来我会继续接受父母资助，先在上海外环买套房子，再搭配一辆与收入水平相匹配的车。尽管银行贷款需要花20到30年方能还清，但没关系，人们不都是这样过日子吗？把有限的希望寄托在无限的明天，习惯了就好。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;说到对我青春期影响至深的那个人，我已经彻底失去了她的消息。 2003年，曾琴因长期对患者使用未经批准的药物，加之与制药公司存在利益勾结，经人举报后被医院开除。事情并未就此完结，数名患者服用药物后出现多种后遗症，多个患者家庭联合起诉，她以医疗渎职罪被立案调查。经过漫长的取证和庭审，最终被判归还患者的全部治疗费用，处罚金20万，并入狱三年。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高考结束后的暑假，打听到曾琴正在省第一女子监狱服刑，我跟家里说要出门旅行几天，坐了十几个小时长途车去探视她。那天的事我已经记得不太连贯，就像初次见面时那样，她坐在我的对面，说我有抑郁倾向。她还说，要是我的病治不好，就活不过二十岁。 &amp;ldquo;所以我算是被你治好了对吗？ &amp;rdquo;我问她。她狡黠地笑了，把头凑过来悄悄地说：&amp;ldquo;我知道你是装的，我什么都知道。 &amp;rdquo;我也笑了，&amp;ldquo;那你为什么还给我吃药？ &amp;rdquo;她促狭地挤挤眼睛，&amp;ldquo;你不就是想跟我待着嘛，干脆就演戏演全套。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尽管身在监狱，曾琴给我的印象依然不乏风趣，好像随时都能说几个笑话那样。直到这时，我心里长久的怀疑才终于得到了证实：我跟她恐怕都不是正常人。至于我们俩谁疯得更厉害一些，则已经无法得知。用文明点儿的说法：此事有待商榷。随着年复一年不断增长的生活经验，后来我也明白了一个事实：在整个社会中、在每个人身边，外表看似正常、实则已经疯掉的人数不胜数。所谓正常生活，起决定作用的不过就是谁更会伪装。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;出狱后你打算干什么？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;不知道，也许去哪儿开个小诊所。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我考上大学了，九月就去上海。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;真好，以后别回来了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我给你写信好吗？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;算了吧。跟犯人打交道对你没好处。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我看着曾琴白净红润的脸，这几年监狱生活还让她胖了一些，像是获得了充分的劳动和睡眠，气色很不错。一身蓝底白条的狱衣穿在她身上并不难看，头发剪成了齐耳样式，使整个人外观成熟许多。听说有特长的犯人在监狱里会受些优待，她这种有医疗背景的估计用处更多。看起来她在这儿过得还行，但就算有什么难处，她也不会告诉我。我始终猜不出这究竟是个怎样的人，在那张似笑非笑的脸背后，到底隐藏着多少秘密？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;可我在她面前却无法遁形。她一直都知道这个坐在对面的男孩正用一种不可想象的方式爱着她；她明白他剃光头发和眉毛只是幼稚但勇敢的反抗；她了解他喜欢听摇滚乐，是反旗乐队的忠实拥簇；她理解他决定吃素，想要离开学校和家庭的想法；她知道他没有朋友，身陷孤独，心中总是暗藏压抑，涌动着无边的愤怒。她看见了他的一切，还想办法帮助他争取了一点儿时间，以便他能挣扎着离开水面呼吸几口&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;尽管这没什么用。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;探视结束时，她爽快地站起身，笑着跟我说再见。这是我最后一次见到她。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这已经是许多年前的事了，可能根本不是发生在我身上的事，或者我已经忘掉了，也许只不过是我听说的。我只是无法忘记那个夏天&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;真正的我存在于世的最后一个夏天。我以为我爱上了曾琴。可是，这对她并没有什么意义。很遗憾，这不是你以为的那种爱情故事。生活的真实性体现在很少会有美梦成真，人们一旦失散就是永远的别离，命运普遍如此。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;每隔一段时间我会往监狱写一封信，主要为了告知她我不断变化的地址和电话号码，她从未回信。出狱后没人知道她的下落。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们过去交谈的内容已经不再重要，重要的是我将借此怀念说话的感觉。每个失眠的夜晚，当我长久地闭上眼睛，在黑暗中呼唤那个名字，我的身体便回应着，渴望着，被一种神秘的怀旧之情牵引着回到过去，而我早已忘了自己还拥有过这样的感情。我的老朋友始终美丽而冷淡，穿着白大褂或蓝底白条狱衣，来到我身边，坐在我对面，嘴角带着微笑，怀有无边的耐心和不多的怜悯，聆听我的忧愁，我的愤怒，我的孤独，我的无助&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;还有藏在那颗怯懦心灵里的卑微的爱。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;只要我屏息敛气地等待，那么无论曾琴在哪儿，或者我又在哪儿，她都将穿着那双与我款式相同的帆布鞋，带着药片、一段交谈的时间和观察实验样本的心情，穿过心理咨询室门外漫长黑暗的走廊，于黎明之前向我走来。那阵脚步声穿越了上世纪九十年代最后的青春岁月，划过千禧年从春到夏的时光，永远、永远地在我心间怦然回响。 &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;责任编辑：梅不谈&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;征稿信息见@ONE一个工作室置顶微博。更多编辑部的有趣日常请关注小红书：ONE一个编辑部。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fm2pdOYl3StianIZjgZGe5iogfz1&quot; alt=&quot;沈郁&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;沈郁 &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;艺术从业者，前媒体人。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;关注&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;相关推荐&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6017&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;昨日狂欢派对&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 沈郁&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/5986&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;隐匿之所&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 沈郁&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6094)&quot;>;点击可下载ONE一个app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 06:25:11 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.3998]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4130]]><description>&lt;div>;17 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FuqjV5rTvh5r4G1blJQsUTTh2i3t&quot; alt=&quot;首页图&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.3998&lt;/span>;摄影| Thom Holmes&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;17&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sep. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;生活是简单寂寞的，劳动是繁重的。但没关系，食物安慰了一切。&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 17 Sep 2023 06:25:11 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>