<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[什么样的童年可以治愈一生？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3917]]><description> &lt;div>;22 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Wild Wolf Asks&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>;What What kind of childhood can heal a lifetime? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Hong Sangda &lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpYWtpyuh9mz5kzrQYG4mhiQ1SBE&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpYWtpyuh9mz5kzrQYG4mhiQ1SBE&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Without leaving any psychological trauma, such a childhood is healing enough. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, in real life, such situations are rare. After all, it is not easy to pass the entire childhood &quot;without injury&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The &lt;strong>;&amp;ldquo;no injury&amp;rdquo; mentioned here does not mean that I have never experienced any injury&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;in the process of growing up, but It is&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;able to&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;use one’s own inner&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;power&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;to digest these injuries without leaving long-lasting scars. &lt;/strong>;This inner strength is called &lt;strong>;&amp;ldquo;resilience&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>; in psychology. Everyone&#39;s resilience has a certain limit. It is like a spring. If the pressure is within the range, it can return to its original state. However, if the pressure exceeds the limit, the spring will be damaged and cannot be restored. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The same is true for childhood injuries. Some small injuries may not necessarily leave long-term effects, but once the frequency and intensity exceed standards, they will leave psychological trauma. Every time I get hurt as I grow up, the old wounds reopen. This is why adults sometimes have ups and downs of emotions when they encounter small things.&lt;strong>;He is not sensitive and fragile, but new injuries awaken old injuries. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Among childhood experiences, the one most likely to cause damage beyond resilience is the influence of parents. If you want your childhood to be free of psychological trauma, it needs to satisfy:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;1. Sense of security: You are worthy of being loved&lt;/strong>;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;In a good childhood, children grow up in an environment where they are loved. In such families, parents often verbally express their love for their children. They do not require their children to work hard or be good. In their hearts, love is the first priority. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They will have regular parent-child activities, and parents will spend time with their children and interact with them, instead of always feeling distant or absent-minded. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, many parents are not good at expressing their love for their children. &lt;strong>;The love they understand is not words, companionship, or support, but demands. &quot;Feng&quot; is to impose their unfinished wishes on their children. They believe that as long as they give their children the best educational resources and train them to the best of their ability, they are good parents and want their children to be successful in the future. , is the best love. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are also some parents who will use abandonment to blackmail their children, hoping that their children will meet their expectations. They will say, &quot;If you continue to disobey me, I won&#39;t want you anymore.&quot; Children who grow up in such a family often have a lonely childhood. They will have strong insecurities under their parents&#39; high expectations and strict requirements, and they need to constantly prove that they are loved. Therefore, in adult intimate relationships, they will frequently question their partner&#39;s love for them, and are always worried that their lover will cheat on them and no longer love them. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Therefore, an ideal childhood environment should be full of love, warmth and support. Parents use words and actions to convey care to their children, provide them with solid support and encouragement, and build a sense of security for their children. In the education process, parents give their children necessary guidance and requirements, while respecting and understanding their uniqueness, rather than resorting to coercion and oppression. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2.&amp;nbsp;A sense of autonomy: You can do what you want&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;A sense of autonomy, simply put, means that&lt;strong>;a person knows that he is an independent&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;person and that he is his own master. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In early childhood, many parents will take care of their children&#39;s affairs. They can&#39;t do this and let me do that. So what can the children do? They can only stay by themselves. This way Excessive spoiling is actually depriving children of their ability to be independent. &lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;The reason why many young people lose their pursuit when they grow up is because they have not been encouraged to pursue it since they were young. Anyway, adults will solve the problems. If I don’t have pain points, I will have no motivation to improve. My only wish is to do nothing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Therefore, a good childhood should help children become themselves. Parents should be aware of their own worries rather than forcing them on their children, respect their children&#39;s uniqueness, allow them to do what they want to do, and help them develop their own interests and talents. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If parents believe that their children will continue to explore, express and understand themselves as they grow up, they will gradually find an identity and life direction that suits them. At the same time, in the process of seeking self-affirmation and satisfaction, gain the motivation to pursue achievements and pursue your dreams unremittingly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;3.&amp;nbsp;Se&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;I&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Effect&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;Ability&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; strong>;&lt;strong>;Sense: You can succeed in whatever you want&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We begin to deal with various problems in early childhood. Different experiences and tasks, this is the beginning of the formation of &quot;self-efficacy&quot;. That is to know&lt;strong>;&amp;ldquo;I&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;can&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;do things&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;well through hard work&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, when many parents see their children showing timid and withdrawn behavior, they want to encourage their children to face difficulties, but as soon as they say it, they turn into harsh accusations and denials of their children: &amp;ldquo; What&#39;s so hard about this? useless! ”, so that the children will become timid and afraid of failure the next time they do anything. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the contrary, if children are given sufficient opportunities for trial and error and experience, they will build a sense of self-efficacy. As an adult, when facing various unknown and potential challenges, I always believe that I can do it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Therefore, a good childhood requires the support of self-efficacy, because when such children grow up, &lt;strong>;they&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;will not&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;because of others Saying&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;oneself&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;is &quot;not good&quot; and feeling&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;oneself&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;is &quot;not good&quot;, no matter what others criticize him , looked down upon him, he always felt that&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;himself&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;was capable&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;4.&amp;nbsp;Optimism: Nothing is past&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;not&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A person will pay great attention to the words and deeds of his parents from childhood, because as he grows up, children rely heavily on their parents as role models and guidance. They observe their parents&#39; words and deeds to learn how to respond to different situations and deal with various problems. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Optimistic parents will teach their children to maintain a positive attitude when facing setbacks. For example, when their children fail in a sports competition, optimistic parents may say: &quot;This is just a game, next time you There will be better performance. &amp;rdquo;Such teaching will help children develop a mindset of self-challenge and self-growth, thus improving their ability to withstand psychological stress. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the contrary, if the parents have a negative mentality and sigh, &quot;Hey, this child just doesn&#39;t have any motor cells,&quot; the children will easily lose confidence and hope, and their personal growth will be hindered. They will often feel that Life is hard, the world is dark, setbacks are common and there is no solution. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It can be said that &lt;strong>;optimism is a life-saving straw in times of adversity. Whether you can survive &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;going on &lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>; all depends on it. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A good childhood is a lifelong psychological capital. If you establish &quot;being loved&quot;, &quot;I can&quot; and &quot; With the belief that &quot;I can do it&quot;, when you grow up, you can trust yourself unconditionally even if you encounter challenges, instead of worrying about gains and losses because of your lover&#39;s words and deeds or other people&#39;s comments, and being emoticon when things happen. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, it doesn’t matter even if you don’t clear your childhood without any injuries. This does not mean that your life will be worse than others. &lt;strong>;We can all be our own saviors at any time&lt;/p>; strong>;&lt;strong>;Lord&lt;/strong>;, save yourself from dire straits without hesitation, as long as you are still willing to heal yourself. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Mei Butan onewenzhang@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For the call for papers information, please see the @ONE Studio pinned on Weibo. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fh_rAFN3IDcz2KT6BHHjGoD051Ge &quot; alt=&quot;Hong Sang&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Hong Sang&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Psychology Consultant, WeChat public account: Hongsang&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -- >; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span >; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3915&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What is your &quot;long-term goal&quot;? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3914&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;A dictionary｜What is &quot;addiction&quot;? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3917)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[晃晃荡荡的人间]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6100]]><description> &lt;div>;22 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Wu Zhongquan&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fqc8sFOS3hKRNqOorIHS2jio33Yf&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fqc8sFOS3hKRNqOorIHS2jio33Yf&quot;>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In a small northeastern town, Brother Chen, who lingers on the edge of society, experiences year after year Pain and laughter swayed through another spring, summer, autumn and winter. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;In the past year, Brother Chen has always asked me to borrow money on WeChat, not much, always twenty or thirty. I began to think that he was short of money to buy a drink, so I didn&#39;t ask any questions and just gave him the red envelope without even thinking about asking for it. He probably didn&#39;t really want to pay it back. But this happened so many times that I inevitably started to wonder, why do I always buy wine in the middle of the night? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So the next time he came to ask me to borrow money, I asked him what exactly he wanted to do. He hesitated and refused to say anything, and even provoked me, saying that if you don&#39;t lend it, you will get it. I really refused to forward it to him. After a while, he surrendered and came back. He said he didn&#39;t do anything but just tipped the live broadcast for fun. I said, which anchor is so attractive? He sent me a link. She was a woman named Dan Mei. She was average-looking and had average beauty. She didn’t have much talent in live streaming. She just chatted and occasionally sang. There were only a dozen or so people in the live broadcast room, but they were quite perseverant and could keep broadcasting until midnight. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brother Chen said that Danmei is not far from him, only seventy or eighty miles away. Because of this distance, he feels closer than those anchors from far and wide. Now he is the top brother on the list. He felt quite proud when he said this, and said that Danmei also said that they would have the opportunity to meet and have dinner together. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I say, be careful of being deceived. You can reward twenty or thirty people through the screen, but it is difficult to say it in person. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He didn&#39;t want to hear this, saying that you don&#39;t know, Danmei is a very good person, and she will definitely not trick me. When I heard this, it was just the talk of a crazy person. The person should have been deluded, but he was too lazy to reason with him. If he believed in something subjectively, he would not be able to explain it no matter how hard he tried. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I transferred another thirty yuan to him, and he sent a thank you emoji, and then added, don’t tell my family about this. I was confused for a moment. Does this mean that he rewards the anchor or instructs me to borrow money? But I didn’t ask, I just replied in a general way, okay, and then helped him hide both things. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brother Chen is my friend from the Northeast. We grew up in a village. He is the third child in the family, and he has two older sisters. When my mother was pregnant with him, she had a lung problem and took a lot of medicine. The medicine harmed the fetus, so Chen brother was lame in both legs when he landed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This lameness is quite obvious when he is a child. Most people can walk when they are more than one year old. When he is three years old, he can barely move by holding on to the wall. When he grows up, the lameness becomes more obvious. You can see a person swaying over, his hands and feet are not very coordinated, as if he is carrying an empty basket at the same time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition to the disability of his legs and feet, he also has a slight problem with his IQ. He has no problem speaking and doing things in life, but he has difficulty learning. He cannot do arithmetic. He always stumbles when reciting texts and writing. No one can recognize it except himself. The teachers all sympathized with his disability and were not harsh on him. The parents felt that they were responsible for the child&#39;s disability and felt too much guilt about him, so they were more permissive, so they stayed in elementary school a few times and barely survived. After graduation, his family followed his wishes and did not continue to send him to middle school in the town. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was left alone and wandered around the village all day long. But how can one wander around all day long? The conditions at home were not very good. As he grew up, he had to find something to do. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The trustee at home found him a job as a temporary worker in a road class. Every day he would carry a shovel and walk back and forth along the gravel road from the countryside to the county town, filling in any potholes he encountered. Big rocks blocking the road were removed. After the rain, the roadbed was not stable, so a few shovels of soil were needed. This job is more suitable for him, because it is almost like wandering. The only difficulty is that the legs and feet are not very good, and it is often dark after going back and forth. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The family felt sorry for him and bought him a bicycle. He practiced hard for a while, but his legs and feet were not in a good place, so he learned it stumblingly. But within a few days of riding this car, the county suddenly started a major infrastructure construction project, and every gravel road had to be built into a cement road. Once the cement road was built and became smooth and smooth, his job became redundant, so his days of wandering around with a shovel were over. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After that, his family asked someone to find him another job, which was also related to highways. He was picking up garbage that fell from cars on the highway. His family took him to the person in charge&#39;s office, but he took one look at him and said no, saying no, his legs and feet were too awkward, so he couldn&#39;t let the car hit him when he got up? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The family didn’t give up. After they came back, they found someone again. This time they went to a construction site to do the watch. They said they didn’t need to wander around, just sit in the watch room. If the dog could talk, he could do it. Especially suitable for him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brother Kechen went away for two days and came back by himself. What about a construction site? It&#39;s just a mining site, in a barren mountain, with nothing built. The dressing room is just like a tent. When you get in at night, ghosts and wolves howl when the strong wind blows. It&#39;s really scary. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The family was not sympathetic to this matter and began to criticize him. Why is a grown man so timid? It is hard to find such a good job anymore. He didn&#39;t reply, just said he couldn&#39;t do it anyway. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After that, he couldn’t find another job. Before the New Year, someone came up with the idea to ask him to go to the county to deliver the God of Wealth. It cost a few cents a piece to buy this thing. No matter which door he knocked on, he would get a ten-eight yuan. Blocky? This profit is hundreds or thousands of times. After hearing what he was interested in, he went to buy a batch of goods, and then went from neighborhood to neighborhood in the county, knocking on doors. He is like a deadbeat. When he knocks someone out, he just says to send the God of Wealth, and he doesn&#39;t say much about New Year greetings. People saw that he was disabled, so they didn&#39;t care too much. They saved ten or eight yuan and made a lot of money in a few days. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But the good times did not last long. When he knocked on the door of a house, the parents who opened the door turned out to be the parents of a primary school classmate whose children had been studying with him a few years ago and had moved to the county. When he saw that he was an acquaintance, his face turned red and he refused to accept the money he was given. He turned around and ran away. When he ran out of the corridor, he threw all the God of Wealth in his hand into the trash can and never gave it away again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He may be discouraged, or it may be that several setbacks have made him feel inferior. When the inferiority complex becomes stronger, it becomes externalized as self-esteem. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The family probably didn’t understand this mentality, so they started scolding him, saying that he made money with his own hands and didn’t steal or rob. What’s the shame? He said it&#39;s not embarrassing, why don&#39;t you do it if it&#39;s not embarrassing? It sounds nice to say that you are going to send the God of Wealth, but in fact it is just to beg for food. The family said that now we are raising you, but when we all die, you will have to beg for food. He said that after you die, I will drink pesticide. My family says why are you so worthless? He said, isn&#39;t this also the case with you? If you gave me a good birth, would I be able to do this? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The family members stopped talking. This seemed to be the source of the matter, but they were not willing to be choked to death like this, so they continued to trace the source, saying that if we had known this, we should have aborted you! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After this quarrel, the family never mentioned finding a job for him again. The two parties reached a certain tacit understanding, and when the topic came close to being discussed, they would avoid it. Just like he continued to wander around the village, bypassing several springs, summers, autumns and winters on his own in a blink of an eye. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A few years later, Brother Chen’s mother’s lung disease became more and more serious. In rural life, the daily cooking and the smoke from the coal stove in winter would cause her to have a severe and persistent cough. So the family rented a building in the county town, a seven-story attic with a roof. It is sloping, and people in the shortest places cannot straighten their backs. Although it is small and cramped, they can still live a city life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For Brother Chen, the most intuitive feeling is that urban life is more lively than rural life. He quickly made some friends. I don’t know where these friends met, but they all have one thing in common, that is, they are unemployed men and are more or less disabled, either physically or mentally. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I met several of them later. The oldest was in his forties. His hands had been shocked with electric shocks and he could not straighten each finger. However, he still liked to fight with landlords. Half of the playing cards he grabbed fell off. Half of them were playing cards and picking up cards at the same time, which was very disturbing to watch. The youngest is seventeen or eighteen years old. He has no physical problems, but has an obvious lack of IQ. He often carries half a pack of crushed instant noodles in his pocket, and he is used to pinching a little and chewing it when walking on the road. He was quite greedy. When he saw people eating, he looked at them and asked if he could give me a taste. If he doesn&#39;t give it, he&#39;ll say fuck your eight generations of ancestors and run away. There is also a young and artistic man who is highly myopic. When talking to you, he wants to get right up to your nose. When he is playing cards, his eyes are glued to the playing cards. He loves to create sketches, and he writes one from time to time, performs it for everyone, and submits it to the county TV program. He has also participated in folk talent shows such as &quot;There Are Literary Artists in Our Village&quot;, but has never been selected. . He also has a cousin who often comes over to play with everyone. He seems to be very smart and always pretends to be cool with his hands in his pockets. Later I found out that he lost part of his finger by kicking his foot. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The strange people often get together and always think they will figure out something big, but in fact they have never thought about anything except drinking. None of them had any money. Occasionally someone would get some money from somewhere and invite everyone to come and have a meal. Most of the places we go to are the self-service lunch boxes that taxi drivers love. They cost ten yuan, two meat and two vegetarian dishes, and there are also stir-fried dishes for three to sixty-nine yuan. A group of people can eat for less than a few dozen yuan. The only thing that costs money is drinking. One person can drink seven or eight bottles of beer, which is too luxurious. Liquor is more affordable. The bulk of the small roast is sold by the pound. A bucket of ten pounds can create light in one meal. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brother Chen is very happy. He has finally found a partner in this world. He must drink five horses and spears every meal. After drinking, a group of people wandered around on the street, walking sideways, so to speak, and no one dared to mess with them. This is indeed true. Anyone who saw this group of strange-looking drunkards would stay away. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But Brother Chen’s happiness did not last long. Drinking too much alcohol is always harmful to the body. One night, he was walking home after drinking too much and fell into a drainage ditch, causing a sanitation worker to He was pulled up and had several stitches on his head. His family scolded him and forbade him to mix with that group of people anymore. He agreed on the surface, but secretly ran out. He couldn&#39;t drink alcohol openly, so he drank secretly, and then returned home after he sobered up. Then one time he woke up in the police station. He was frightened, thinking that he had committed a crime while drunk. After asking again and again, he found out that &quot;there are also artists in our village&quot; who were drunk and were sent to the hospital with cerebral infarction. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mother of a literary artist had been singing duets for two years before, and she traveled all over the country. Later, she got pregnant with someone unknown, and the child was born in confusion. However, the legal provisions were clear, and her son drank like this. Every bastard at the table has a responsibility. So I called the police and wanted to keep it private. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brother Chen asked his family to take it back, and his family discussed it with other people’s families. Finally, they pooled together 100,000 yuan and gave it to the singing duo. She scolded her that this was not enough. My child was paralyzed and would have to serve him like his ancestors for the rest of his life. While putting the money in his cloth pocket, he walked out the door and ran to the bank. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brother Chen’s wine shop and his friends just broke up. Sometimes when they meet each other on the road, they will stop and say a few words, but they never dare to sit down and have a meal anymore, and there is a shadow in their hearts. , everyone is a hidden mine, afraid of destroying themselves again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brother Chen’s family felt that they could not let him continue to hang out like this, and it happened that his two sisters had lived a better life in the past few years after getting married. When I got up, I remembered that this younger brother was also over thirty years old and it was time to start a family. It&#39;s not that I hadn&#39;t thought about this in the past few years, but my family was poor and I was disabled, so it was too difficult and no one dared to mention it. Although I can&#39;t say that I&#39;m very wealthy now, it shouldn&#39;t be a problem to find a well-matched woman with a few flaws. Maybe after he has a family, he will have a sense of responsibility and want to do something more, so that he can support the family by himself. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brother Chen is also very happy. He dressed up neatly and went on a blind date. He has no objection to the tone of the blind date set by his family. If there are flaws, they are flaws. Who can like someone with a full head and full face? Own? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first person brought over by the matchmaker was a woman with mental problems. At first glance, she looked normal, but when she talked, she was in trouble. After a while, she saw a pair of stockings on the way here. He was dressed very energetically. One moment he said that Brother Chen looked like an ox-headed horse face from the underworld. After a while, he talked about his daughter-in-law and her husband removing ashes from the village. After that, he kept looking at Brother Chen and his father, and looked at the whole room. They all looked very embarrassed. Brother Chen was so angry that he coughed. After they left, he said that he would not find anyone with brain problems in the future. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The next person on a blind date has no problem with his brain, but there is something wrong with his eyes, which are crooked. When talking to you, his eyes keep staring at the side, as if there is a soul standing next to him, and he is so scared. Brother Chen doesn&#39;t like it, and so does the family. But before she could express her attitude, the woman spoke first and said, &quot;On your terms, where will I live when I come?&quot; Four people live in such a small place, and it&#39;s crowded and noisy. I&#39;m used to being quiet, but I&#39;m not used to it. He also said that Brother Chen doesn’t even have a serious job, why would he become a drunkard after following him? Then he turned a corner and said, if you buy me a building, it doesn&#39;t have to be too big, just over 60 square meters. If you give me another 100,000 yuan to cross the river, I can consider it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Farewell to this one, and usher in the next one. This woman seems to be a good match for Brother Chen. Both of them have leg disabilities, sequelae of polio, and one leg is as thin as a bamboo pole. She was quite satisfied with Brother Chen and his family, and she spoke sensibly, saying that if he were not such a person and had such a family, you would not be able to like me. This is how the world is, with princes matching princesses, and potatoes stewed with eggplants. . She added that your two sisters and one brother had to insist on giving birth to a boy in those days, and it must have been because they wanted a boy. Now that he has reached this age, Bala insists on marrying a wife. It must be for the sake of continuing the family line. I also like children, so I want to go to the hospital for a check-up in advance. If we can have children, we can stay together. If we can&#39;t, we can separate. Delay the other party. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is a clear statement, and even the secret wishes of Brother Chen’s family that are not in line with mainstream values ​​have been revealed. So the two of them went for a check-up, and the woman took them there. Brother Chen was shy and followed behind him honestly. Seeing that she was talking and doing things in a sound manner, he thought that she would definitely run the family well in the future. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The results came out quickly. The woman was fine. Brother Chen’s sperm motility was too low, making it difficult to get pregnant. Brother Chen felt ashamed as he covered his crotch and made an excuse, saying that he had drank too much in the past few years. But the woman was generous and said that it was nothing. If she was sick, we would treat her. She would stop drinking first and then take medicine. Then I took Brother Chen to a traditional Chinese medicine clinic and prescribed a large bag of traditional Chinese medicine. After boiling it, I put it in a shrink-sealed bag, one bag after every meal. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This medicine is quite expensive, and a course of treatment lasts for half a year. Brother Chen felt distressed while drinking it, but he gritted his teeth and drank it. After drinking, the woman took him to the hospital. The sperm motility improved a little, but it was still low, so he had to continue taking the medicine. Brother Chen’s second sister felt something was wrong and asked if this report was electronic. The woman said no, and the second sister was puzzled, so she kept an eye on it, and secretly took Brother Chen to another hospital for a checkup a few days later. The report came out, and it turned out that there was nothing wrong. Only then did the family realize that they had been deceived by this woman, who was just a Chinese medicine practitioner. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two sisters were so angry that they called the police. The police said that there was no evidence, and besides, the Chinese medicine was indeed aphrodisiac. I consulted a doctor again. The doctor said that the vitality of sperm is just like in life. It is normal to have high and low levels. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two sisters were dissatisfied and took Brother Chen and his two brothers-in-law to find the woman. The woman&#39;s home was in a town in Linxian County. When the five of them arrived, they saw a short mud house with two beds and a blind old lady taking care of a paralyzed old man. Life was really difficult. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The second sister asked, where is your daughter? The old lady couldn&#39;t see her and thought it was a friend who came, saying that my daughter and her partner were traveling. She said that traveling can help you understand your personality the fastest, and if you get along well, you can get married when you come back. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brother Chen is confused, isn’t she dating me? I&#39;m just hanging on here. After saying this, I realized that there were several people hanging on me at the same time. He was not special, he was just one of the people who was deceived. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The second sister kicked over the urinal next to the kang and said, &quot;Fuck you, we&#39;ll come back when your daughter comes back from death.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A few people set fire to the nest and left. A few days later, the matchmaker came to the door with two chickens and said that I was really sorry. I didn&#39;t expect that she was like that. The second sister said she was back? How do you want to solve it? The matchmaker said she was going to sue you, saying that you went to her house to bully the old man and kicked over the urinal. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is the truth, the second sister has nothing to say. The matchmaker then said, how about just forget about it, you will suffer a little loss, she will be a little angry, and the medicine will not go into other people&#39;s stomachs. I think your brother is much better than before. We are both disabled and have a hard time living, so don’t make things difficult for each other. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brother Chen and his family looked at each other and said nothing. The matchmaker said that I will introduce him to you when I meet someone suitable. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As soon as the matchmaker left, there was no news from him. Maybe he really didn’t meet the right person. Brother Chen and his family were discouraged after what they had experienced, and no one mentioned the marriage again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I went back to the Northeast a few years ago to do business, and I met Brother Chen. He picked up the habit of drinking again. He drank white beer mixed with it. Very fierce. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After careful calculation, he is almost forty. The years are fleeting and half his life has passed. I asked him what he was doing recently. He is very proud and says that he is a maknae and goes to the entertainment city every day. Then he took out a card from his pocket. I thought it was a membership card for a high-end nightclub. When I picked it up and took a closer look, I found out that it was a card for recharging currency in a game arcade. The so-called entertainment city was a game arcade in an underground shopping mall with arcades, dance machines, and fishing games. So complete. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I wonder where the money comes from for playing every day. He said it didn&#39;t cost any money. He took the card and saw whoever was fishing had left. He forgot to pay the points, so he inserted the card and the points went to his card. Did I say there are so many people with poor memories? He didn&#39;t say much. Most of them had ten or twenty cents left. If there wasn&#39;t enough for a cannon, they didn&#39;t want it. There were also some who were playing dancing machines. The coins popped out of their pockets and fell under the machine. He would lie on the ground and pick them out, and also charge them into the card. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It turned out to be just picking up bits and pieces. I asked him if he picked up enough every day to play? When he said it was not enough, the boss would sometimes kick him out. After a few kicks, he got used to it and let him hang around. When business was not good, he would gain more popularity and sometimes even give him a few coins to play with. One play. He proudly patted the card again and said that more than two hundred coins can be exchanged here. Can I invite you to play? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I can’t say, this is also the wealth you have accumulated with great difficulty. You can play with it slowly by yourself. I’m afraid I’ll run out of fun for you and I’ll have to top up another five hundred for you. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He laughed and said how could that be possible, and then put the card into his pocket. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I mentioned his blind date again and asked if it never happened again. He shook his head and said that he would never consider getting married in this life, it was not easy to find. He also said that it is not only hard to find people like me, but also men with good arms and legs. There are too few women and they all have to be snatched up. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This sentence reminds me of a documentary filmed by Japan&#39;s NHK TV station, &quot;Chinese Men Who Can&#39;t Get Married.&quot; In the opening scene, an older man from the city went on a blind date to the woman&#39;s house in the countryside. When he got there, he saw a line in front of the door, all men who came for a blind date. Originally, they thought that by searching downwards and reducing dimensionality, they could easily take the initiative in the marriage relationship, but they found that there was no difference between this place and the city. Women became Ip Man, and they all picked out ten. The owner of a massage parlor thought that he had an advantage because he had a shop and a house, but he found that other women preferred to go to KTV with the rich second generation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brother Chen drank too much that day and did two things. The first thing was to hold my toilet and vomit. I don’t know how I got the strength to break the base of the toilet and the filth flowed out. land. The second thing was to ask a philosophical question, &quot;They say women are like water, but why does water always flow to higher places?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was too lazy to tell him that this was natural selection, Darwin. Without strength, there would be no possibility of mating. I don’t want to analyze the imbalance between men and women. Some men are destined to remain single until death. This is too big and he doesn&#39;t like to hear it. I didn’t say anything, why don’t you think about why people would choose you? Can you get under the machine and pick up coins? These words hurt his self-esteem so much that I was afraid he would cry. His life has come to this point because of both innate and acquired factors. He chose a life and unwillingly gave up the marriage he wanted. So I can only comfort him, why do he have to What about marriage? How comfortable it is to live alone. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said yes, yes, it was pretty good and there was no pressure. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past few years, Brother Chen&#39;s mother&#39;s condition has slowly worsened, his father has also suffered from severe diabetes, and the lives of his two sisters have not gotten better. But their life is not difficult. The rural land is contracted and they can get more than 10,000 yuan in rent per year. They also applied for subsistence allowances from the government and can receive more than 1,000 yuan every month. In addition to providing money, the government also built new houses in rural areas. If you get sick, the rural cooperative medical system can reimburse most of the money. He is disabled and gets some holiday money and subsidies of rice, flour and oil during holidays. In this kind of day, even if you never work, you will definitely have basic food and clothing. As long as you don&#39;t have too many desires, your life will be quite comfortable. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But life is always not peaceful, and there are always people throwing stones into the lake. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past two years, Danmei appeared like a thunderbolt and knocked Brother Chen unconscious. I thought their fate started when I asked for money, but it was actually earlier than that. In Brother Chen&#39;s words, he has been protecting her for four years. In the past four years, as long as Danmei started a live broadcast, no matter what time it was, Brother Chen would definitely arrive on time. In the live broadcast room where there were never more than 20 people online, he would stay all night as if he was on duty. The guardian of the land, she broadcast live for six hours, and she stayed on guard for six hours. She broadcast live all night, and he had to keep his phone on even when he fell asleep. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I asked Brother Chen, what do you like about her? He hesitated, as if he was speaking on the Avenue of Stars. First, he said how difficult it was for Danmei&#39;s family. Her father died early and she only had one mother. She also had an unfortunate marriage and divorced. She felt that work was too tiring, so she just It is difficult for a 26-year-old woman to do live broadcasting and work alone outside. I said take it down, that woman looks to be at least thirty-six, and her beauty level can be as high as forty. He said no matter, she said 26 is 26. Did I say you love me so deeply? He doesn&#39;t care whether he loves her or not. She is just a companion. She is such a nice person. Every time I give a reward, I take the initiative and she never asks for it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我大概理解他的心境，他的人生到此，在现实层面找不到任何精神的寄托，于是把一腔的空虚都投射到了那个小小的屏幕上，发束花，发个啤酒，丹妹就会说谢谢臣哥。每次这四个字都会让他浑身颤栗，心里老美老美了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;丹妹这样一个直播间里营造的幻想，让他觉得遇到了一个淳朴的姑娘，不贪色也不爱财，只爱你孤身走暗巷和破烂的模样，他恐怕又产生了对婚姻的向往。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;臣哥那次管我要过钱之后，很长时间都没有再联系过我，我直觉是发生了点什么事，就又主动去问，他支支吾吾了一阵，说他和丹妹见面了。他偷着把家里低保的钱领了出去，跑去了丹妹的城市，和丹妹吃了顿旋转小火锅，喝了杯白的，又喝了两瓶啤的。我问他啥感觉，他说没啥感觉，本人比直播间里差老远了。我说你失望了？他摇头，说人家看到我是残疾人，都没瞧不起我。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我说然后呢？他说没啥然后，吃过饭丹妹有事就先走了，但俩人加了微信。他在那边住了一宿也回家了，家里人发现这事，把他一顿骂，两个姐姐冲过来要把他的手机没收，还要去直播间骂丹妹。他吓得蜷缩在床上，浑身发抖，跟心要裂开似的，紧紧抓住手机不放。两个姐姐看他这样，也心软了，还哭了一阵，说也理解他的心情，但是这玩意用手机看看就行了，别再去见面了，太危险了，咱们村里有个男的就是这样被骗走的，等找回来时身上就剩一件裤衩子了，都瘦得没人形了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;臣哥也哭了，但更多的是觉得逃过一劫。另外家里人也放宽了话，手机上看看是被允许的，他就每日更加沉迷地守护丹妹，有时下了直播还会微信聊几句，视频里喝个酒啥的。这亲密让他心头的幻想越来越重，直到有天失了控。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;丹妹的直播间最近来了另一个大哥，打赏十分阔绰，680的礼物都敢刷，臣哥的三十二十块就退到了次位，丹妹明显和那个大哥互动更频繁了，听说私下里也见了面。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;臣哥心里不是滋味，受不了，越想越来气，有种受了背叛的窝囊和愤怒，之后他喝多了酒，在微信里把丹妹大骂了一顿，甚至上升到了人格的侮辱，说她没了男人啥都不是。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他骂完痛快了，倒头就睡。醒来肯定后悔啊，急忙拿手机看，丹妹已经把他拉黑了。又去直播间，也发现进不去，直播间也被拉黑了。他捧着手机，又后悔又恍惚，四年的守护，就这么轻轻松松地断了，看起来很深的时间羁绊，原来啥都不是。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我不知道臣哥是怎么熬过这段心理重创的，总之他现在已经修复得差不多了，他注册了一个新号，偶尔还会去丹妹的直播间看看，但是不表明身份也不说话，看看就走，像是看一个老朋友，知道你还在过着旧日子，就安心了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;臣哥的日子依旧如故，娱乐城倒闭了，充值卡里还有一百个币子没换出来。他得了高血压，酒也不敢再喝了。母亲的病还在加重，今年下了两回病危通知书，好在都抢救回来了。父亲的糖尿病在维持着，只是夹菜的手越来越抖了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他夏天的时候，因为点小事和家里人吵了一架，自己搬回到了农村住，房子是新盖的，没有纱窗，晚上开着窗户睡觉，蚊子嗡嗡地咬。他睡不着，就起身出门，在村子里来回晃荡，把路过的狗都吵醒了，他一晃荡就晃荡半宿，晃着晃着，就晃荡回了小时候，他觉得还是那时候好，但具体好在哪儿呢？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;是因为从前车马慢，人人都能娶到老婆吗？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;可能是，也可能不是。 &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;责任编辑：李嘉龙&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;征稿信息见@ONE一个工作室置顶微博。更多编辑部的有趣日常请关注小红书：ONE一个编辑部。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FuesooEpr13-iy8Yt-6-tZtu9dZD&quot; alt=&quot;吴忠全&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;吴忠全 &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@吴忠全&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;作家/编剧&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;关注&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;相关推荐&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6085&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;你看世间朗朗有光照&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 吴忠全&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6063&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;永无止境的迁徙&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 吴忠全&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6100)&quot;>;点击可下载ONE一个app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4003]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4126]]><description>&lt;div>;22 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpjjFQSt_35ud4iTyUwZIjzenkfV&quot; alt=&quot;首页图&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4003&lt;/span>;摄影| Laura Paredis&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;22&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sep. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;也许我们无法明白“活着”的意义，但是我们已经为“活着”付出了太多的代价。&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>