<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[一周的心情｜本周小记精选]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3937]]><description> &lt;div>;8 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Question from ONE Editorial Department&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>; It&#39;s been a week, how are you? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; ONE Friendly Answer&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1 ;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The long holiday is over and autumn is getting darker. How are you ONE friends? Listen, there is a new echo in the tree hole. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com /FrJ-1v4Kt-Gbui0r2BbjBUocdy3-&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FrJ-1v4Kt-Gbui0r2BbjBUocdy3-&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data -author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FlX-FKp25F6kwvb32B5JUaD7WjT2&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FlX-FKp25F6kwvb32B5JUaD7WjT2&quot;>; &lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fn2I1BPDbKDv59u-fHSNUi45DS_y&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot; http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fn2I1BPDbKDv59u-fHSNUi45DS_y&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce. com/Fn4XbYS5iSdo2MMACtmxPaN5ZKtn&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fn4XbYS5iSdo2MMACtmxPaN5ZKtn&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original- src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Ft6B9RhYSLGvEQxOWR_KZER8xc21&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Ft6B9RhYSLGvEQxOWR_KZER8xc21&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt; img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FkUHJS8stWJhxmaY5gPgqhwtQPaT&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FkUHJS8stWJhxmaY5gPgqhwtQPaT&quot;>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FjOMjrVQHSafcZ8Y6AnaOQYjnQFi&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http:// image.wufazhuce.com/FjOMjrVQHSafcZ8Y6AnaOQYjnQFi&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fnm5W1INoE-n6k00WeppsyQK9fF3&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fnm5W1INoE-n6k00WeppsyQK9fF3&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src= &quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Ft8r5aCbk4xSxykKaT7hEt3mPofU&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Ft8r5aCbk4xSxykKaT7hEt3mPofU&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data -author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fsi3Nd9o9gF8-ckKVDzjvKzUsj-F&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fsi3Nd9o9gF8-ckKVDzjvKzUsj -F&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FuEQq4vDdparaq958Iu4pcDJt4Rr&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src =&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FuEQq4vDdparaq958Iu4pcDJt4Rr&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce. com/FviCpxvNFfS1hJorLY4Euv6WFf7G&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FviCpxvNFfS1hJorLY4Euv6WFf7G&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original- src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgskYnpWYBYP4kQ9Jd2QEy9MQi7H&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgskYnpWYBYP4kQ9Jd2QEy9MQi7H&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt; img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fnu5wKi55vzgpa6MdNsjOEMg9cSp&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fnu5wKi55vzgpa6MdNsjOEMg9cSp&quot;>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fu_5z8PyuMx91jwhQlWcgONFym4W&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http:// image.wufazhuce.com/Fu_5z8PyuMx91jwhQlWcgONFym4W&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fq5TZAx66jHry4TowV7eL_hsg9D3&quot; data- source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fq5TZAx66jHry4TowV7eL_hsg9D3&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor: Zhou Zi Click onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Click on the &quot;pen&quot; below the date signature on the homepage to leave your life moments and your unexplainable feelings in the tree hole. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8 &quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Complex The cutest people in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3935&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;My mood of the week | Selected notes of the week&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, 3937)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more updates Multiple RSS: &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href= &quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[会胜寺]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6119]]><description> &lt;div>;8 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;文／Ahu&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FlXQZuUGIf79otLdaWJxMZRuUfHm&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FlXQZuUGIf79otLdaWJxMZRuUfHm&quot;>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;My tutor and I sniffed out the theft of Arhat Head during an inspection Based on the truth of the case, we made different choices on whether to report it. Some truths are easy for a three-year-old to understand but difficult for a seventy-year-old man to understand. When morality and interests conflict, you must make a choice with a clear conscience. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;1&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is a high-speed train bound for Shanxi, smooth and comfortable . In the two-seater seat, instructor Jeff Cai sat on the inside and I sat on the outside. The train was traveling along the Sanmenxia Yellow River Ecological Corridor. It was early spring, and greenery was rolling outside the window. Cai Jiefu tilted his head and squinted his eyes, as if sleeping but not sleeping. He had a book called &quot;Residences and Living Forms in the Two Song Dynasties&quot; spread out on his lap. He occasionally opened his eyes and flipped through a page. I tried to chat with him, but he said: &quot;Please sort out the information.&quot; &amp;rdquo;Then he ignored me. After a while, he squinted again. I opened my laptop and started sorting out pictures and information on the restoration of ancient buildings. This time, we will go to Zeshan Town, County C, in southern Shanxi for inspection. The most important object of investigation is Huisheng Temple, an ancient temple built in the Yuan Dynasty. Last year, a heavy rain that had not happened in fifty years caused damage to many old buildings in County C. The foundations sank and the outer walls collapsed. Naturally, the oldest Huisheng Temple was not spared. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At two o’clock in the afternoon, we arrived in Yuncheng. Then transfer to a bus and go to Zeshan Town. The village where Huisheng Temple is located is called Guangming Village. The village chief Li Futian came to the tourist distribution center early to greet him. Cai Jeff is familiar with him. As an expert in the restoration of ancient buildings, he has visited Huisheng Temple several times for investigation. Li Futian asked us to check the situation in advance. Jeff Cai had already communicated with him on the phone, so we bypassed the people from the Cultural Relics Bureau and went directly to the village with him. Li Futian drove a small car with poor performance and didn&#39;t even have a license plate. He said with a smile that he didn&#39;t learn to drive until he was sixty. His son was a car repairman, so he gave him this little broken car to drive and play. The road conditions were not good and there were shell craters. The car bumped, making people worried that it would fall apart immediately. Fortunately, the village is only seven or eight kilometers away from the town and can be reached in just over 20 minutes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Entering the village and passing through the archway with the title of &quot;The First Ancient Village in Thousand Years&quot;, you can see a large area of ​​ancient rooftops from a distance. Due to the high-profile prevalence of local cultural protectionism, people like to think of themselves as &quot;first&quot;. Over the years, I have followed Jeff Cai to visit many such &quot;firsts&quot;, which must be called &quot;thousands of years&quot;. Those who don’t know what is going on usually come to worship. As the car drove in, we finally saw the legendary Huisheng Temple. The first thing we saw was the mountain gate. The temple is located on a high platform with dozens of steps, backed by the towering Zeshan Mountain. The temple is covered with blue colored steel tiles. Li Futian said without confidence that because he had no financial resources to carry out repair work, he could only wear temporary &quot;clothes&quot; for more than half a year. Li Futian is a masonry craftsman and one of the few old men in the village who has the skills to restore ancient buildings. He hopes that our inspection can develop a lower-cost restoration plan and then go to the public for bidding. . But Huisheng Temple is actually in its final years. According to Cai Jiefu, only the dozens of colorful sculptures in the temple still have the appearance and aesthetic value of cultural relics. There are almost no people living around the temple, and the dilapidated houses in the surrounding area have been preserved as landscapes. The gables of the houses are soaked by rain and are in danger. Red signs saying &quot;Dangerous wall, please go around&quot; are hung everywhere. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Get off the car and walk into the mountain gate. There is an old man with disheveled hair sitting high on the stone steps in front of the temple. The old man was twisting the hemp rope, turning the wooden knot like a diabolo under his hand. I heard Cai Jeff said once that the dialect is called &quot;diabolo&quot;. The old man watched us walking up the steps with dull eyes. When we entered the temple gate, he stood up and followed us. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The front hall is the Hall of Heavenly Kings. Going around the cloister of Tianwang Hall is a patio-style courtyard. There are wing rooms on the left and right sides of the main hall, Amitabha Hall, which should be relatively recent additions. The weathering of the bricks is not that serious. There is a tall dead tree in front of the temple. The bark has almost completely fallen off, resembling dead bones. The trunk was split in half, and the curved half had to be supported with iron rods. There are some new shoots at the bottom of the dead tree. Li Futian told us not to get too close, saying it was not auspicious. I laughed in my heart, what age are we in, and we are still so superstitious. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The most valuable colored sculptures are in Amitabha Hall. But there is an iron lock on the palace door, and the key is with the Cultural Relics Bureau. So we had to take a peek through the window hole. But unfortunately, I saw nothing, only the bases of the Buddha statues and Arhats. Because the roof of the temple leaked, the Buddha statues and Arhats were covered with plastic sheets. Li Futian looked quite embarrassed and said, &quot;I have no choice but to put clothes on them.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When we were wandering around the courtyard, the old man twisting the hemp rope followed us almost every step of the way. The soles of his shoes made a &quot;caracara&quot; sound, always attracting my attention. I looked around and found two pieces of iron nailed to the heels of his deformed leather shoes. Li Futian then introduced that he was an eunuch and had some mental problems, so he should ignore him. The words were said in front of people, which seemed extremely disrespectful. The sky was gray, the courtyard was dark and damp. It was a cold spring this year. During my stay at the Tianjing Courtyard, snowflakes began to appear in the sky, and a layer of white soon appeared on the stone slabs. Li Futian looked at the sky, worried that the snow would turn to rain. He was tormented by the rain. Look at the eunuch holding his sleeves up and looking at the sky silently. The two men raised their heads at the same angle, which was very interesting. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After a while, the snow turned to rain as expected, and the coldness penetrated into the breath, which was really sad. Li Futian took us to the concierge to keep warm. There was a strong fire in the room, and the airflow made a sound from the suction tube, like someone gasping for air. Seeing the eunuch follow, he silently opened the stove lid twice and put the kettle on it. While Cai Jiefu and Li Futian were chatting, the old man also huddled by the stove, continuing to twist the hemp rope and tilting his ears, as if listening attentively, and the kettle quickly turned on. The eunuch stood up, walked around the room, and found an iron can. He is looking for tea. Afterwards, he made tea for us and placed three tea bowls side by side on the stove. After the tea was finished, he pushed in our respective directions. This man knew how to treat guests very well. Except for the dull look on his face, he didn&#39;t look like what Li Futian said. Li Futian drank tea with peace of mind, as if the eunuch should serve him. The tea cup is a little dirty and the inside of the cup is full of tea stains. I pinched it, warmed my hands, and put it down politely. It made me uncomfortable to see the eunuch looking directly at me, so I had to pick up the tea cup and take a sip. But he still looked directly at me. It seems that there is something wrong with my brain. It&#39;s understandable for a person with problems to do anything strange. Maybe he&#39;s just curious about my glasses or my hat. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the rain stopped, Li Futian planned to take us back to the village headquarters for dinner. He said with a smile: &quot;It&#39;s not public money to entertain us, it&#39;s a daily meal for our old lady.&quot; You guys have been riding all the way, so let’s deal with it first. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I walked out of the temple gate, I saw that the eunuch was following me. He suddenly walked up to me, grabbed my arm and said, &quot;Baby, can you sit down again?&quot; ? &amp;rdquo;I was startled at first, and then stunned for a moment, because he was speaking in dialect. After a moment of reaction, I understood what he meant. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Futian scolded: &quot;What do you have to talk about with me?&quot; go back! &quot;He then explained to me: &quot;His son died and his head was stimulated. When I see young people, I always want to chat with them. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Futian’s harsh scolding made me disgusted. There was no need for him to treat an old man like this. Seeing the eunuch looking at Li Futian innocently, he put his hands back into his sleeves and silently lowered his head. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the way to the village headquarters, I asked Li Futian, who was driving: &quot;Secretary, how did that man&#39;s son die?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;It’s a long story, I’ll tell you later. It has something to do with Huisheng Temple. &amp;rdquo;Li Futian actually kept it secret. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jeff Cai clicked on me and said: &quot;Young man, you are too curious.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Haha. &amp;rdquo;Li Futian smirked twice. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two middle-aged men continued to chat politely, while I stayed out of the conversation. It was raining lightly, and the rainwater wetted the bluestone road of the entire street. The ancient houses on both sides showed a melancholy that had been peeled off by time in the misty water. On the tall fence, dry weeds are dancing gently in the wind. The dull alleyway echoed with the dull barking of dogs. The village is at the far west end of the village, where there are newly built residential buildings and a busy road passing through. Looking back at the old street, it looks like a small shadow cast by this new world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After entering the village office, Li Futian’s woman had already delivered meals. It&#39;s braised noodles with sauteed seeds, and the toppings and noodles are put in two pots. It&#39;s steaming hot. Li Futian said proudly: &quot;My wife&#39;s spicy noodles are one of a kind.&quot; If you eat it once, you will want to eat it again next time. ” He didn’t know where the confidence came from. The mentor is originally from Shanxi and grew up in Henan. He has a natural stomach for eating noodles. He enjoys noodles every day. He first ate a bowl and then another. He ate so much that he completely lost his self-cultivation. I have a rice stomach in the south. Over the years I have been studying in the north, I have never been used to eating noodles. After gaining weight, I still got used to giving up carbs, so I barely ate half a bowl and put down my chopsticks. Li Futian&#39;s woman was so enthusiastic that she just added half a bowl and stuffed it into my hand. After eating, my whole body felt bloated. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After dinner, it was already dark. Li Futian took us out again and went to the ancient alleys to inspect the houses. Most of the folk houses were built in the middle and late Qing Dynasty. Judging from the degree of dilapidation and the style of construction, it is easy to find the continuity of folk house building. The ancients paid attention to building a century-old residence. An old house always contains the hard work of many generations of the family, blending it together. The foundation of a touching bloodline inheritance. Tall old trees and mottled old stones can best bear witness to the vicissitudes of human life. But all along, I have been relatively repulsive to this kind of emotion. This is completely contradictory. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We set foot on a watchtower. Li Futian pointed at the whole village as if he were pointing a mountain, and said boldly: &quot;Look, it&#39;s beautiful.&quot; It&#39;s so beautiful. Every year, photographers from all over come to capture the scenery. It&#39;s a pity that the repair work has not been able to keep up. There is no way. The maintenance work of the Forbidden City in Beijing costs so much. How can we have any hope when it comes to our little monument? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is already very dark. I no longer wanted to look at the dilapidated scenery, so I had to look further away and look at Huisheng Temple wearing a coat of colored steel tiles. I probably saw the figure of the eunuch, who was sitting on the bell tower at the corner of the temple and seemed to be looking at the mountains behind the temple. There is a tower on the top of the mountain, just a small gray dot against the backdrop of the high-voltage electricity tower. Faintly, I had the urge to get in touch with the eunuch. If an old man who has lost his son really needs someone to sit with him and get some comfort, I would be willing to listen to him. At the same time, I was also a little curious about how his son died. There is more than one ancient village in Zeshan Town. The inspection by Cai Jiefu and I will last three to five days. We should be able to find some free time to look for him. Crazy Wen doesn&#39;t know how to hit people, I&#39;m sure of that. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the evening, Jeff Cai and I checked into the Jardine Hotel in the town. Zeshan Town is located in the three provinces of Rooster, across the Yellow River, with Shaanxi to the north and Henan to the east. In ancient times, it was a wharf and commercial port with prosperous commerce. There are ancient buildings on the street, but now due to tourism development, many antique buildings with the same style have been added, which lacks craftsmanship and is inevitably boring. The Lantern Festival has just passed, and the streets are relatively deserted with not many tourists, but the lanterns are still there and wine flags fluttering in the wind are hung everywhere. There is a Pinya Bookstore downstairs, opened by the hotel owner Lao Bai himself. Jeff Cai is a bibliophile and will never miss a place where he can buy books wherever he goes. In the evening, he went to the bookstore to spend time, bought several out-of-print local chronicles and old architectural atlases, and came upstairs to show off to me, like a child showing off candy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;There are still educated and responsible people hiding in the countryside. &amp;rdquo;He was praising Lao Bai who insisted on opening a bookstore in the countryside. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Early the next morning, people from the C County Cultural Relics Bureau came, and the inspection was officially underway. I visited several endangered ancient buildings, most of which were lackluster in terms of aesthetic value. Being reduced to ruins is still a destination. On the fourth day, the inspection finally ended. But overall, I didn’t have much time for inspections, but more time for dinners. When you go to a place, you will definitely be treated to a high-quality meal by a farmer. People from the Cultural Relics Bureau have always complained that country people are too enthusiastic. Enthusiasm will eventually be mispaid. In the foreseeable future, the ancient buildings in those villages should have no future. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the fifth day, the instructor planned to take a break and sort out the information. From the sound of his voice, it sounds like he will be here for a few days. I am a fast hand at organizing information, and it only took me one morning to complete the work. Jeff Cai gave me half a day off, and I was free to walk around the town as I pleased. I said I wanted to go to Guangming Village and see Huisheng Temple. Cai Jiefu said: &quot;The main thing is to see the old man.&quot; &amp;rdquo;Now that it has been exposed, I can only admit that it is. I&#39;m really curious about how the old man&#39;s son died and how he had anything to do with Huisheng Temple. I will definitely not ask the village chief Li Futian. His hypocritical cadre style is too annoying. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I carried my camera and left happily. I found a boy on the street who knew how to ride a motorcycle and arrived at Huisheng Temple in less than ten minutes. The weather today is really good. Against the backdrop of the blue sky and white clouds, the ancient residences in the village look full of ancient charm. However, the Huisheng Temple, as the main building, looks very awkward because it is wrapped with colored steel tiles. Unfortunately, when I walked into the mountain gate, I found that the temple door was locked. See the eunuch is not here. I walked around the courtyard wall, thinking I could find him, but in vain. I had to sit on the steps of the temple gate and wait. About an hour later, I saw a hunched figure of an old man walking down the road, carrying a basket on his back. I didn&#39;t know what it contained. In order to show my kindness, I got up quickly, walked down the steps, greeted him, and called vaguely &quot;Uncle&quot;, &quot;Uncle, do you still remember me?&quot; I visited the temple a few days ago. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking at the eunuch blinking his eyes, he said &quot;Oh&quot; and said: &quot;Remember.&quot; &quot;I looked at the basket on his back, which contained some broken corn cobs. I said enthusiastically: &quot;Let me carry it for you.&quot; &quot;Looking at the eunuch smiling, his mouth showing ugly gapped teeth, &quot;No, no, you are wearing clean clothes and dirty clothes. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I didn’t force him anymore and walked him up the steps to the temple gate. The temple door is locked with a general&#39;s lock. He took out the key and opened the lock skillfully. We stepped over the threshold and walked in. Seeing the eunuch go to the concierge, I followed him. It was extremely cold in the room, and the chill was coming out. I looked at the stove. The hearth was dark. The eunuch said, &quot;Just stay outside for a while, baby, while I light the stove.&quot; &amp;rdquo;He moved a stool to me and I sat down at the door. He poured me another cup from the thermos bottle and said politely: &quot;Drink some water first to keep it warm.&quot; After giving birth, make some tea. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;It doesn’t matter, you are busy with your business. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking at it now, the old man doesn’t look like a mentally ill person at all. I am even more suspicious of what the village chief Li Futian said. He really shouldn’t comment on an old man living alone like this. As a village cadre, his words are too immoral. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking at the eunuch working in an orderly manner, he stuffed the corn cobs into the stove, ignited it with soft grass, and the fire was quickly lit. He took the cattail leaf fan and fanned it quickly at the damper. There were thick clouds of smoke pouring out of the room. When the smoke cleared, I noticed a group photo on the bedside of the room. It was a young eunuch holding a child. However, there was only half of the photo. The person next to him had been torn off, leaving only half an arm and a sleeve. It&#39;s red. I thought that was probably his wife. I also thought that if I wanted to talk about his son, photos would be a good entry point. After watching the eunuch light the fire, I pretended to ask casually: &quot;The photo is of you when you were young, isn&#39;t it, uncle?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Correct. &amp;rdquo;As he said that, he actually took the photo and handed it to my hand. It seemed that he was happy to continue chatting about the photos. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Why is there only half of the photo? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Hey, I was having a divorce with my baby’s mother back then, so I tore up the photos. I was too young and had a bad temper at that time. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I looked at it pretending to appreciate it, &amp;ldquo;My uncle was quite handsome when he was young. &amp;rdquo;I had to try my best to be nice and lighten the conversation so that the topic could be directed to the death of his son. After hearing what I said, the eunuch grinned and shook his cattail leaf fan even more cheerfully. But the last time I came, the only impression he left on me was dullness and gloom. He said: &quot;Young, you should be like that when you are young.&quot; ” In the photo, he is wearing a red sweater and a trendy hairstyle, and his eyes are full of high spirits. He clumsily held the child and deliberately flashed his shiny mechanical watch. This was a common iconic move for people in the 1990s to express their vanity. My father was like that too. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I pointed to the child in his arms and asked cautiously: &quot;Is this your son?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Correct. &amp;rdquo;It seems that he is not averse to talking about his dead son. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;He was born in 1986? &amp;rdquo;I noticed the words &quot;86 years commemoration&quot; on the photo. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Yes, we were fined for family planning at that time. It&#39;s a pity that after death, there is no one left to establish a household. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;How many years? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;From 2001 to 2023 this year, I think about it...&amp;rdquo; the eunuch rolled his eyes and did the math, &amp;ldquo;it has been twenty years. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;ldquo;That day, I also heard what the village chief said. How did you die? Can you tell me? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;It’s nothing inconvenient, just let the fire burn you to death. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said it so abruptly that it startled me. &quot;Oh...then you only have one child?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;There is a woman above, who is married. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;ldquo;The aunt has left you, and you are left alone. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&amp;ldquo;Correct. There&#39;s nothing wrong with it. Being alone means less trouble. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;We chatted for a while. Finally, I plucked up the courage to ask: &quot;I heard from the village chief that your son&#39;s death has something to do with Huisheng Temple?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking at the eunuch’s eyes, a terrifying light suddenly shot out, but it was fleeting. &quot;He&#39;s talking nonsense, don&#39;t listen to him.&quot; &amp;rdquo;His tone was still calm. Just now, I almost thought I had pissed him off. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It seems that he still has some problems. I am too optimistic. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I continued: &amp;ldquo;When we left that day, you said you wanted to keep me here...?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Really? Forgot long ago. As I get older, my memory is always bad. &amp;rdquo;He didn&#39;t look at me. He was filling a kettle with water and then putting the kettle on the fire. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We were silent for a while. After the water boiled, he made tea like last time. While drinking tea, our chat gradually became smoother. I watched the eunuch talk about his past. He worked as a seaman in the early 1990s, worked as a second mate, and often went to sea with freighters. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;After Hong Kong returned to China, I stopped following the ship. When China joined the WTO, I opened a mill. I remember that year, the Olympic bid was successful. Bin Laden also hit the World Trade Center that year. There were so many things going on back then. &amp;rdquo;He likes to use historical events to illustrate his life nodes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I checked my phone and entered keywords, and found that an Arhat head theft occurred in Huisheng Temple in 2001, so I asked: &quot;Is this also the year the Arhat head was stolen in the temple?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking at the eunuch’s eyes once again radiating a stern and frightening light, “We won’t mention the bad things. &amp;rdquo;He lowered his head and fell silent again. He twisted a piece of hemp rope and started rubbing it. He helped me refill the tea without being polite, and seemed to have forgotten my existence for a while. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I think I must have touched his lightning point. At the same time, I thought, could his son&#39;s death be related to the theft of Huisheng Temple? He said that his son was burned to death. Although it sounded uncomfortable, it was enough to arouse my strong curiosity. My curiosity about special people stems from my experience traveling around with my mentor during my years of study. Most of the time the inspection is boring, and I always use observing people as a point of interest to refresh my mind. I don&#39;t have enough enthusiasm for cultural research and ancient building restoration. When I was an undergraduate, I majored in Chinese painting. Later, in order to be able to find a smooth job, such as entering a university or cultural institute, I took the major of ancient building protection and restoration as a graduate student. If given the chance, I might pick up my paintbrush again. Seeing the eunuch&#39;s face aroused my desire to understand him, and my mind was already starting to wander. The dilapidated ancient temple and the traumatized temple keeper must have an interesting theme. I actually moved myself. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In order to reduce the embarrassment, I stood up and walked around the courtyard casually, admiring the stone pillars in the courtyard. There are carvings on the stone pillars, which are exquisite and detailed. There was an old dog with droopy eyelids lying in the corner. I took out the sausage from my backpack and teased it over. I showed kindness to the dog in order to regain the eunuch&#39;s favor with me. Sure enough, this trick was more effective. He looked at me teasing the dog and had a little smile on his face. We chatted around the dogs. He said that the dog was the offspring of a female dog raised by his son and was now old. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He finally put down the hemp rope, moved his legs with deformed knees, and said, &quot;Come on, doll, let me take you around.&quot; There are many beautiful things in the temple. You big city people don’t like to watch it, but I have watched it for more than ten years, and the more I watch it, the more interesting it becomes. &amp;rdquo;His interest suddenly soared, which caught me off guard. The more I believe it, there is something wrong with his mind. I have to be cautious. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;3&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He took me to the Temple of the Heavenly King first. According to research, this temple was restored in the late Qing Dynasty, and most of the statues inside were reshaped during the Republic of China, and the workmanship was not so fine. Therefore, the value of the cultural relics is not that great. The eunuch looked at him and pointed to the clay behind the statue of the King of Heaven, and said, &quot;This work is too rough. At first glance, it looks like the master is in a hurry to finish the work and want to take the money and leave.&quot; ” He also pointed out to me the hidden name under the base and said, maybe it belongs to a stonemason, or maybe it was left by an unknown passer-by. After years of observation, he has figured out too many secrets about the dead people attached to the statue. This also shows the loneliness of the eunuch. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After that, we walked through the courtyard and he took me to Amitabha Hall. He actually had a &quot;key&quot;, but it was a thin wire. He gently poked the keyhole of the general&#39;s lock, and the lock popped open. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The eunuch said: &quot;None of them knew the lock was broken, and I didn&#39;t tell anyone else. I was the only one who knew.&quot; &amp;rdquo;At this moment, I actually started to admire the eunuch. He is the real owner here. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The pressure from the curved wall almost deformed the door frame. I was worried that the eaves would suddenly fall and hit both of us. I was really afraid to go in. The eunuch saw my hesitation and said, &quot;It&#39;s okay, the four beams and eight pillars will not collapse.&quot; &amp;rdquo;He went in first, and then I followed him in tremblingly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ground in the temple was covered with thick dust, and it felt soft when you stepped on it. Some places have become hardened due to the rain. Looking up, you can still see the gaps in the broken tiles. Only because of the color steel tiles, a few rays of light sneak in from there in a tortuous way. The eunuch suddenly turned back and pushed the wooden door shut. The creaking sound of the door shaft echoed in the hall. Standing in the darkness, with the moist breath wafting around my cheeks, I saw that the eunuch&#39;s face had changed. At this time, I couldn&#39;t help but reinforce his identity as a mental patient, thinking that he wouldn&#39;t do anything unreasonable to me. I couldn&#39;t help pinching the backpack behind me. There was a multifunctional folding knife in the backpack. I have to carry this portable tool with me during outdoor inspections all year round. I can&#39;t explain why I&#39;m afraid of an old man. If he wants to hit me, he is no match for me. But he had no reason to hit me. But dark spaces do trigger bad associations in me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking at the eunuch moving his legs that were unable to move, he walked to the left side of the hall. He took off the plastic sheet covering the Arhat statues. There were nine Arhats of different shapes in a row, but behind them there were two statues of ancient people in ordinary clothes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I asked softly: &quot;Whose statue is that?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The eunuch said: &amp;ldquo;It belongs to a good person who donated merit, and I don’t know who it is. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I took a closer look. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking at the eunuch walking to the right again, he also lifted the plastic sheet covering. There were also nine Arhats of different shapes, but the five Arhats in the back were each different. The neck was severed, and there were obvious signs of repair on it. Thinking about it, this must be the trauma left by the thief. The limited information on the Internet shows that although Arhatou has returned, the thieves have not been captured so far. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The eunuch walked up to a decapitated Arhat and gently touched the crack on his neck. I went to take a closer look and found that a large piece of the back of this Arhat was missing and had not been replaced. It was most likely caused by rough cutting by thieves. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Arhat&#39;s calm expression is in sharp contrast to the destruction on the back of his neck. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;When I have free time, I will talk to him. &amp;rdquo;Looking at the eunuch&#39;s hand sliding onto Arhat&#39;s face, it seemed that he and Arhat had already been old friends who talked about everything, and Arhat was not shy about his touch. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said: &amp;ldquo;He is a gatekeeper. It was carved in the image of the great monk Yu Xian. He was a filial son. The great monk Dao Guangnian stayed here. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It turns out that the eighteen Arhats on both sides of the main hall all have prototypes of the temple, and most of their names are engraved hiddenly under the base of the statues. The eunuch discovered it. But with the passage of time, most of them have been erased, and only a few can still be recognized. It seems that everyone is suspected of self-promotion. The image of the Eighteen Arhats instantly dimmed in my mind. The eunuch told me one by one the names of the prototype Arhats he discovered. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Seeing the eunuch walk to the statue of Amitabha, we removed the plastic sheet covering it together. The statue is very tall, with a painted Bodhisattva on each side, but the color is severely peeled off and looks dirty. However, under the illumination of a beam of sunlight, the three tall statues showed a majestic momentum. The expressions of Amitabha and Bodhisattva are lifelike and moving, and the movements of their palms are also very natural. This is probably the most important reason why Huisheng Temple has been preserved. However, when I looked carefully, I found that there were also defects on Amitabha&#39;s neck, distributed on the left and right sides, each as big as a fist. Come to think of it, Amitabha must have been at the hands of thieves. With such a huge head, they were probably intimidated by its &quot;bigness&quot; and had no choice but to do the next best thing and cut off the Arhat&#39;s head. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I couldn&#39;t help but ask: &quot;Is that also the one left behind by the thief?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Correct. The first year, someone came to steal the Buddha statue, but failed. The next year, someone came to steal the Arhat more than once. First, Li Baoqing died, then Wu Sanniang and his son died, and finally, Meng Laohai also died. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Who are they? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;They are all eunuchs here. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I actually had a little heart palpitations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I am the fourth one to come...it&#39;s not my turn yet. Talk to you, doll. &quot;The eunuch lowered his voice and said, &quot;This temple has some evil nature. If you get involved with it, you will die.&quot; Even if you are not dead, it will still remind you that one day it will kill you. Did you see that? &amp;rdquo;看寺人指了指殿外的枯树，&amp;ldquo;那是棵老树精，害了好些人了，李保庆、吴三娘和她儿子，孟老海都是它害的。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;大爷，咱还是相信科学，不能迷信。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;不是迷不迷信的事儿，真的有那东西，咱在这里说话，它听得见。没事，我不怕，我已经是老棺材瓤子了。李保庆是97年来看寺，98年瘫掉，死了，死的时候说是让那棵树害了病。吴三娘和她儿子是99年住这儿的，第二年，出了盗贼。吴三娘说，出盗贼的那天晚上，这满殿的罗汉都活了，盗贼被吓跑了。吴三娘也病了，也瘫了，没几天也死了。吴三娘死了没多久，他儿子出了车祸，也死了。孟老海&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;也跳河了。我儿子&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;让大火烧了。都死啦，都必须死。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;看寺人的眼里忽然散发出恐怖的光，把我带到弥陀像的背后，指着一处黑暗的角落说：&amp;ldquo;那里放了好大一块磁铁，镇着这里呢，不然老树精就得作怪。你当那抵着树的铁杠是干啥？是导磁用的。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我实在没法儿信看寺人的鬼话。但他有精神问题，我不可能和他去计较。我假装认真地问：&amp;ldquo;我能摸摸吗？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;不信你就去摸一摸。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;于是，我趴下来摸了摸，果然摸到一块石头。我把书包滑到身前，把折叠刀拿出来，往石头上贴了一下，就听&amp;ldquo;当&amp;rdquo;地一声，刀就吸了上去。看来，看寺人并没有说假话。由死亡恐惧而生发的一切连续性事件，很容易杂糅成神秘的故事，塞到一个看寺人的嘴巴里，形成人们对这座破寺的敬畏心理。说实话，我一向对这种充满谣言性质的故事表示警惕。死亡的神秘性自然值得探索，但过度沉溺，很可能演化成病症。比如我身后的这位看寺人，他让死亡恐惧扭曲了心智，相信了由无数嘴巴塑造出来的关于会胜寺的精怪故事。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我捏住了刀柄，试图把刀取下来，但磁石吸力惊人，用指头抠了好半天，才把东西抠下来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我爬起来，发现看寺人已不在我身后。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;大爷？ &amp;rdquo;我喊了一声。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没有人回应。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我绕着弥陀像走出去，殿里也没人。看着那些幽暗里的罗汉像，个个展露出属于人的丰富神态，我不由也感觉出了一丝胆怯。猛然，在罗汉像之后，一个身体蠕动了一下。我的心脏&amp;ldquo;突&amp;rdquo;地一跳。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你在干什么，大爷？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;看寺人的身体拱起，手臂一摆，一只老鼠晃在手中。鸡皮一下爬满了我的手臂。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;抓到了吱儿。 &amp;rdquo;他们这里把老鼠叫做&amp;ldquo;吱儿&amp;rdquo;。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;看寺人提着老鼠向大殿门口走去。他拉开了门，阳光汹涌而入。我抓紧跟了出去，看到看寺人已经把老鼠丢进了作为门海的水缸里。水缸里有水，活老鼠的挣扎激起了水花。看寺人直直地看着，像在欣赏这场小型杀戮。我走过去瞧了一眼，发现里面漂着不止一只老鼠尸体，统统都翻白了肚皮。我顿时感到阵阵反胃，慌忙躲了一边。看寺人却还在欣赏着，直到水缸中彻底没了水花。老鼠是乡下人的祸患，看寺人痛恨老鼠也不足为奇，但有人这样虐杀老鼠，我还是头次看到。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此刻，我只想赶紧离开这里，再不要和老头待在一起。我借口要去村子里拍照，提出了离开。看寺人说：&amp;ldquo;再来，娃娃。 &amp;rdquo;我想，大概率不会再来了，除非修复古建的招标成功。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;4&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我打算去制高点拍拍村子的全貌，于是向寺后的山上走去。但走了没一阵，却误入村子的墓地。我是个方向感很差的人，因为脑子还在回想着看寺人关于死亡的故事，所以迷迷糊糊竟走错了方向。等到意识到的时候才发现离村庄越来越远，甚至连会声寺的山门都看不到了。不得已，又原路返回，回到墓地，认准了相反的方向，这才望到熟悉的景物。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;小伙子！ &amp;rdquo;路旁的田里忽然传来一声呼喊，是个女人的声音。我四下找寻，却没看到有人的身影。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;看哪儿呢？这边！ &amp;rdquo;那声音仿佛从地洞里传来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我循声望去，发现一个女人的头正从排水沟里升起。女人笑盈盈地看着我，说：&amp;ldquo;瞅了你半天了，还真是你啊，小伙子。 &amp;rdquo;竟是李福田的老婆。女人攀着杂草从沟里走出来，臂弯上挂着一个篮子，篮子里装满了新出芽的野菜。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你咋又来了？ &amp;rdquo;她很不客气地说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;啊，我们老师让我来给咱们村的房子拍拍照。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;来了咋不上村部呢？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;就我自己一个人来的，也没想再麻烦村委会。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你为我们村办事，哪算得上麻烦？走啊，家去！也到饭点儿了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一想到大碗面，我的心马上一抖，忙说：&amp;ldquo;不用了，不用了，阿姨，我已经忙完了，就要回镇上。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你车呢？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我没车。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;那你咋回去？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我去找个摩的。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;别去找摩的了。我儿子要去镇上，他接娃放学，捎上你。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我已经非常了解女人的热情好客，也找不到拒绝的理由，只好说：&amp;ldquo;也行。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我随女人去了他们青瓦白墙的新房。房子有上下两层，四合院的格局，在一众低矮的平房中，看起来格外气派。李福田不在，只有他儿子在院里修车。女人对儿子说：&amp;ldquo;鹏鹏，一会儿这小伙子回镇上，你捎上他。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鹏鹏满脸油污，拿白眼球看我一眼，也没理我，便进屋洗漱去了。等他洗漱完，他母亲的饭已摆到了桌上，是红薯焖大米饭，还有大盆的凉拌菜。女人强烈要求我上桌，我撕不过她，只能坐下吃饭。这次好歹有大米饭，终于没有那么排斥了。吃完，带着饱满的肚子，我上了女人儿子鹏鹏的车。鹏鹏一路抽着烟，粗鲁地讲着电话，发出魔性的笑。我像是一件顺便让他带着的物品，毫无丁点儿存在感。路程过半的时候，他才结束通话，问：&amp;ldquo;哪儿来的，哥们？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;郑州。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;不像啊，郑州人也不是你这样。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我是福建人，在郑州读大学。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;这样啊。我说呢。 &amp;rdquo;然后便不再说话。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了填补沉默的尴尬，我问：&amp;ldquo;能问你个事儿吗？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;问，别客气。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;会胜寺是不是一连死了好几个看寺人？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;这你也信？ &amp;rdquo;鹏鹏歪嘴一笑，&amp;ldquo;是，没错，是一个个都死了。但罪名都推到寺里一棵老树的头上，就是一帮人胡诌的瞎话了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;现在的那个看寺人，他儿子是让火烧死的吗？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;可以啊，门儿清。那小子死的时候，我还撒尿和泥呢。倒是听我爸说过，说是他去会胜寺玩，结果让土炸弹没炸冒烟了。当时，看寺的是个叫孟老海的老头儿，寺里的警报器那阵子坏了，老头儿还挺牛逼，自己拿黑火药做了几个土炸弹，夜里安置在院里的过道。结果那小子一进去就中招了，手指一下子炸断好几根。再发现那小子的时候，已经是具烧焦的尸体，就抛在泽山后边的采石场。当时都怀疑是孟老海干的，孟老海还坐了班房。这人气性挺大，可能觉得受了冤枉，从看守所一出来，就跳了黄河。捞了半年，才把尸体找到。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;那孩子是谁烧掉的？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;谁知道。兴许就是孟老海，兴许是别的混蛋。但人是让活活烧死的，这是事实。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;这么惨？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我还能骗你是咋？警察那儿把人给解剖了，说是肺管子都是黑的，说明人活着的时候，还在喘气呢。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我突然很后悔去探问这种可怕的事，真是自寻烦恼，徒然增加一桩噩梦。可事已至此，终止探索又不是我的性格，我说：&amp;ldquo;那会儿去会胜寺拍照，我碰到了那个看寺人，我和他聊了一会儿。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你和他聊能聊啥？一个神经病。 &amp;rdquo;鹏鹏鄙夷地看我一眼，&amp;ldquo;可怜之人必有可恨之处。佛教里不有因果报应？估计是上辈子的业报都应在了他这儿。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我看见他在水缸里杀了不少老鼠。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;操！让你给碰上了。你应该不知道，他特恨老鼠。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;为什么？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;说是他儿子让土炸弹炸掉的手指头让老鼠给拖到了洞里，没找全。听说当时棺材里除了骨灰，就放了一根手指头。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我灰暗的心又蒙上了更重的阴影。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这时，车已到镇子的街口。鹏鹏扬了扬长小胡子的下巴，说：&amp;ldquo;瞧见了吧，前边那个殡葬一条龙就是孟老海儿子开的。想听更多，去问他，我这是二手的故事。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我顺嘴说：&amp;ldquo;那你引荐一下。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;他一般不会和人说那事儿，也不是他妈的啥好事儿。没事儿，带你去会会。 &amp;rdquo;鹏鹏把车开到了店门口，店里有个女人正扎花圈。鹏鹏问：&amp;ldquo;姨，叔呢？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;女人抬头，又低头，不冷不热地说：&amp;ldquo;在里边呢。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;有人找他。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;女人再次抬头，看我一眼，目光暗淡。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鹏鹏介绍说：&amp;ldquo;郑州来的，来给会胜寺拍照的，想问问咱家死掉的爷爷当年是咋回事。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;里屋的门帘荡一下，一个白头男子冒了出来，眼里两道儿冷硬的光，直接射到了我的脸上。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你谁呀？ &amp;rdquo;他冷冷地问。他的白发与他舒展的脸皮极不相称。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我一慌，竟认真做了自我介绍。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;想听故事，去街面上听去。 &amp;rdquo;说完，门帘就落了下去。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他老婆则赔着笑，说：&amp;ldquo;他就这脾气，不用理他。 &amp;rdquo;又看向鹏鹏，&amp;ldquo;鹏鹏，带人家去别的地方玩吧。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鹏鹏看着我，调皮地挑了挑眉毛，&amp;ldquo;咋样？没说错吧。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这小子竟拿我开涮。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;车继续行驶。鹏鹏说：&amp;ldquo;那货受过伤，脾气可怪了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;哪里受伤？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;瞅你还戴个眼镜，就这理解力？ &amp;rdquo;我居然遭到他的嘲讽，&amp;ldquo;不是身上受伤，是精神上的。他坐过两年牢。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;因为什么？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;还不是因为会胜寺盗窃的事儿。案发前几天，寺里警报器的线让人剪了。一开始都以为是盗贼干的，可查到他妈的最后，居然是孟老海儿子孟辉子干的。罗汉头被盗以后，警察怀疑他和盗贼是一伙的。你让谁想，能不觉得他有问题？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;他为什么要破坏报警器？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;孟老海答应去看寺的时候，孟辉子不同意他爸住进去，怕他像上两个看寺人一样死掉。孟老海不信鬼怪，没听他儿子的。他住进去以后，孟辉子总想找个办法吓唬他爸一下，所以就冒充盗贼去剪了报警器的线。他自己是这么说的，但没人信他，结果搞得他爸也被警察怀疑，到处在传，说是孟老海答应去看寺，就是为了给贼行方便。李炳银，就现在的那个看寺的老头儿，他儿子跑去寺里玩，把土炸弹引爆，受了伤，孟老海这对儿混蛋父子很可能误以为把人给炸死了，怕担责任，所以才把人弄去烧了。还有的说，李炳银的儿子也是贼娃子，也和贼是一伙儿的，因为他被炸后第三天就发了盗案，烧死他，是为了灭口。反正说啥话的都有。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;孟老海要是和盗贼是同伙，为什么还要做土炸弹？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;没听说过障眼法吗？不过这事儿真不好说。反正都知道李炳银和孟辉子一直不对付，李炳银觉得孟老海父子害死了他儿子，孟辉子觉得是李炳银给警察递话，诬陷他爸，把他爸给逼得跳了黄河。两家斗了太多年了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;罗汉头最后是从哪里找到的？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;就藏在山上的采石场，离发现李炳银儿子尸体的地方不远。罗汉头还没运走，就让警察给起获了。往后，寺里再没人敢来盗。都说会胜寺太邪性，谁来，谁倒霉，都怕了，都不敢来了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;李炳银是什么时候疯掉的？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;就孟老海跳黄河以后。听我爸说，老头儿尸体弄回村里的那天，李炳银去看了，看完，人就像跳大神一样发癫了。警察起先还怀疑李炳银呢，怀疑这家伙为了报复孟老海，把人给弄死了，结果查了查，孟老海去跳黄河的时候，李炳银一直待在运城干活，压根没作案时间。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;李炳银儿子出事那会儿多大？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;十五六吧，小混混一个，也不去上学，成天泡网吧。 &amp;rdquo;鹏鹏探头一看，&amp;ldquo;靠，到你住的地了吗？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;哦，到了，好像过了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;不早说？ &amp;rdquo;他粗暴地打转方向盘，又开了回去，&amp;ldquo;哪儿？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;怡和旅店。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;车窜出去，&amp;ldquo;吱嘎&amp;rdquo;一声停下。我像被吐在地上，眨巴眼，车便没了影儿。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我回到旅店，蔡杰夫却没在。我打电话问他，他竟去了解州。也没说去做什么，只让我在泽山镇等他，也许明天回来。晚上闲极无聊，我下楼去了品雅书店。老板老白很客气地说：&amp;ldquo;你就是蔡教授的高足吧。 &amp;rdquo;文绉绉的，听着很是别扭。老白穿唐装、绸裤、土布棉鞋，稀疏的头发往后竖着，纹丝不乱，手里&amp;ldquo;卡啦卡啦&amp;rdquo;转动着两个文玩核桃，身后挂满了当地书画名人的字帖，书架旁边的横杆上立一只五彩斑斓的鹦鹉。我们聊了聊天，老白聊到当地风俗，历史掌故，最后聊到岌岌可危的会胜寺。老白感叹世风日下，文化凋敝。但在我的观点里，旧梦就像是滤镜，一切不过是对其&amp;ldquo;拨乱反正&amp;rdquo;功能性的留恋罢了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;5&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;翌日下午两点多钟，蔡杰夫才打来电话，他说不再回泽山，让我直接去运城张孝机场，约定在那里会合，我们飞回郑州。一向对效率社会颇有微辞的蔡杰夫很少坐飞机，这次倒让我有些意外。飞机上，蔡杰夫几乎睡了一路，在快要降落的时候，才醒过来。我很好奇他去解州做什么，他笼统地说：&amp;ldquo;那边有没破获的古建盗案，想让我给些调查建议，看赃物最终可能的流向。 &amp;rdquo;做古建修复工程时，蔡杰夫常常需要一些老的木砖石构件，他经常会跑遍国内各大文物市场。文物市场鱼龙混杂，一旦打交道，不免形成开门揖盗的局面，和警察产生交集也在所难免。我就着他的话说起会胜寺的盗案，蔡杰夫像是没兴趣听，把眼又眯了起来。我没再说，他又说：&amp;ldquo;没事儿，没睡着，说啊。 &amp;rdquo;我说了下去，但他也没什么回应。飞机落地时，他才感叹说：&amp;ldquo;老头儿怪可怜。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;您以前知道这事儿吗？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;失盗的事儿知道，以前新闻上报道过。老头儿子的事儿，这次去解州，才听警察说了。那孩子进过看守所，可能在看守所认识了某个盗贼，案发当晚，他去帮着盗贼团伙踩点儿，才被炸伤。既然人受了伤，带着又是个累赘，许是怕暴露身份，盗贼可能就一不做，二不休了。警察是这么说的。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我内心稍稍得到圆满，至少看寺人的儿子可能不是屈死的了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从新郑机场出来，蔡杰夫让我自己搭车回学校，自己则搭了另一辆先行离去，像是要着急去处理什么事儿。我比较奇怪，因为他很少有这种情况出现。他的涵养没能包裹住他的匆忙和急躁，上车时连公文包都差点儿让车门夹到。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第二天见到他时，严重的睡眠不足导致他脸色暗沉，他平时梳理得很整齐的发型也有些凌乱。他也没督促我去做会胜寺的修复方案，只是当我问他时，他才说：&amp;ldquo;你抽空做一做，回头发给C县文物局。修复工作能不能进行还不一定。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我无从推测到底是何种状况影响了他的精神状况。总之，在此之后的三四天，蔡杰夫的脸上总带着若有若无的忧虑。就连师娘都察觉到了，她打来电话问我：&amp;ldquo;你们蔡师这几天在家话少得很，他是不是在学校有什么事儿？ &amp;rdquo;蔡杰夫至今还是副高五级，学校里不能让他洒脱的问题也就是这种了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我说：&amp;ldquo;没有。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蔡杰夫是性情内敛的人，他不愿说的事儿绝难开口，问了，反而会发脾气。我和师娘都小心翼翼，没敢去追问。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这日，在学生食堂用餐，蔡杰夫端餐盘时，手里的牛皮公文包不小心从腕上滑落，文件散落了一地。我帮他捡文件时，发现其中有张炭笔素描，是个穿和尚服的光头男子。素描是复印过的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;坐定时，我问：&amp;ldquo;这人是谁？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蔡杰夫我一眼，眼里难掩慌乱，说：&amp;ldquo;这几天，你可能也看出我有心事。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我说：&amp;ldquo;何止是看出，是您很明显。师娘还打电话问了我，她很担心。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;是吗？我没留意。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我不好点破他的虚伪。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;原本不想和你说，还是说说吧。 &amp;rdquo;他伸出手指，弹了弹公文包，意指那张炭笔素描，&amp;ldquo;那是会胜寺盗案的嫌疑人。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我一惊。原来，那是张警方的模拟画像。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蔡杰夫说：&amp;ldquo;我看了以后，觉得很像多年前我认识的一个人。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我又是一惊。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蔡杰夫说，上次去解州，其中有个刑警曾参与侦办过会胜寺盗案，刑警听说他近来去了会胜寺考察，就随口提起了这案子。当时，叫孟老海的看寺人供述过一个可疑的人，那人是个和尚，去寺里看过碑文和罗汉彩塑。刑警常年都带着嫌疑人的画像，他便让蔡杰夫看了这一张。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当蔡杰夫看到模拟画像的一刹那，脑海里一下就跳出了那位旧识的样子。那是在2006年，蔡杰夫在帮一个古建修复工程寻找石雕构件，在去南阳镇平县的火车上，正好遇到一个在郑州古玩城做石雕生意的男子。两人在火车上相谈甚欢，便留了电话，之后导师便常去古玩城，帮工程部采购了不少石雕构件。之后的很多年，导师和男子还常打交道。微信流行起来的，两人也互加了微信，不过联系已没那么频繁，因为男子转去开了家字画店。两人渐渐沦为点赞之交。男子就是个光头，头上有戒疤。蔡杰夫记得他说过，他是还俗的和尚。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蔡杰夫学生时期也曾练习过素描，那种对人的骨相和面目的辨识能力始终还在。他问了那位警察，是谁画的这张像。警察说，是西安美院的一位女学生。当年为了破案，警察找了多名画师对嫌疑人进行模拟画像，但都没能得到孟老海的认可，最后找到这名正在度暑假的女学生，画完一看，孟老海说，就是他了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;像是老天写好了剧本，非要蔡杰夫对应到那个人一样。但他没勇气和警察说出来，&amp;ldquo;万一搞错，不是毁人家吗？ &amp;rdquo;那天匆匆离开机场，他正是去郑州古玩城找那人。但那人的铺子已搬迁，去向不明。他心存顾虑，也没敢向谁打听。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蔡杰夫自我开解说：&amp;ldquo;也许只是巧合而已，我不太信一个念过经的人会盗佛杀人。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;那您为什么又那么着急去找他？ &amp;rdquo;我非得戳他的软肋。师娘说，蔡杰夫身上有文人特有的软弱性，我以前没察觉，但现在总算感受到了。他的焦灼恰能够说明他的旧相识很可能有问题，只是他不愿太快承认。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蔡杰夫像是自己也犯了什么错，脆弱地看我一眼，说：&amp;ldquo;我在想，如果他有过作奸犯科的经历，我的手上免不了也过过不少赃物。以前，我拿他当半个朋友相处，我们还聊佛学，论茶道，难道这些全部都要推翻？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;但这是两回事。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;也是。你容我想想，再考虑举不举报。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蔡杰夫再三叮嘱，暂时不要把事儿说出去。作为学生，我只能卑微地承诺，&amp;ldquo;不会。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;四月份，蔡杰夫应一位姓段的商人之邀，去荥阳规划一座老屋的整体搬迁。城市建设规划扩展到了商人的出生地，老屋原本要拆除，但饱含了商人的个人情感因素，因此便想到了曾做过类似工程的蔡杰夫。工程完毕，老段在荥阳一处文化创意园区举办酒会活动，邀请了导师和我参加。座上不少文化名流，许多与导师都有交谊，导师虽不喜这种场合，但有熟人在侧，也还算自在。飘荡的丝竹声中，是典型的中国式酒桌交际。席间，一个光头男人忽然出现在回廊上，抱着拳，冲着吃饭的老男人拱了一圈手。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;王老师，李老师，张老师&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;目光转移中，他发现了蔡杰夫，&amp;ldquo;啊，蔡教授，好久不见。 &amp;rdquo;他像只灵活的兽一样窜过来，用两只手满满逮住导师的右手，用力一晃。那是一双不太好看的手，手背上像是有烫伤的疤痕，或是鱼鳞病之类的皮肤病。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;导师惊悚地看我一眼，忙又看向男子，&amp;ldquo;老常，你好，你好。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;老常说：&amp;ldquo;要不是老段说你今天在这儿，我还不知道你来了荥阳。我不在郑州干了，来荥阳太多年了。石雕生意断了之后，你也不来找我了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你退出古建，步入书画界了嘛。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;哈，是。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;老段说：&amp;ldquo;和你说蔡教授在这儿，你还不信。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;信了，信了。 &amp;rdquo;男子毫不客气挨着蔡杰夫坐下了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我和老段的年轻秘书坐在一处，椭圆的桌边，和他们隔着大概五六个座，几乎算是正对面。蔡杰夫那惊悚的一眼，含义复杂。我盯紧了那颗光头，上面有明显的戒疤。模拟画像上的脸瞬间叠在了那张脸上。老常身材干瘦，但脸盘很圆，很大，皮肤也很白，衬托得一对儿乌黑的眉毛像是悬挂在额头。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;老常捡了几口菜，老段给他倒了茶。老常说：&amp;ldquo;我以茶代酒，敬各位。 &amp;rdquo;老男人们举了杯。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;老常起身交际一圈，最后又回到蔡杰夫身边，说：&amp;ldquo;不急着离开荥阳吗？可以来我店里坐坐，咱叙叙旧。 &amp;rdquo;他把店址告诉了蔡杰夫。蔡杰夫客气地连说&amp;ldquo;好&amp;rdquo;，虚情假意里或许已晃动着斧钺钩叉，拆解着老常作奸犯科的过往。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;老常再次握了握导师的手，他忽然看我一眼，说：&amp;ldquo;那小伙子就是您学生吧？ &amp;rdquo;听口气，老段已知会过他了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我的神经紧了一下。桌上就我一张学生脸，他轻易就将我逮到了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蔡杰夫说：&amp;ldquo;是。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;回头和你老师一起来玩啊。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我点点头，心里七上八下。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;老常走后，剩余的饭局时间像口热锅，焦灼了我和蔡杰夫两个。蔡杰夫没喝多少酒，但脸却红得像烙铁烙过一样。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;6&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我和蔡杰夫并没有去老常的店，那只是客气的虚套。翌日回郑州的路上，我小心翼翼问：&amp;ldquo;老常就是那个和尚吧？ &amp;rdquo;蔡杰夫点点头，给了我肯定的回答。那人名叫常宝林。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们继续聊了聊。我说，还是该把怀疑说给警察。我并没有劝解的意思，仅仅只是建议。我以为蔡杰夫仍会固执下去，但下车时，他突然说：&amp;ldquo;那好吧，那就当回坏人。 &amp;rdquo;他的回应是如此迟滞，以至于让我以为他在自言自语。我很不认同他这种说法，他可以假定老常是个好人，但他首先假定自己是个坏人，这就将自己放在了道德天平分量较重的位置上，简直虚伪。如果老常确实盗佛杀人，蔡杰夫也无法摒弃掉更重的道德负担。我不会去斥责蔡杰夫的懦弱和平庸，但他的所作所为却严重弱化了长久以来我对他积累的尊重。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蔡杰夫终于拨通警察的电话，他先解释了一直没举报的原因。负责会胜寺盗案的是解州刑警马永康。马永康说：&amp;ldquo;谢谢蔡教授提供线索，理解你的心理负担，毕竟是朋友嘛。这个叫常宝林的，我们通过别的渠道也找到他了，盯了也有一段时间了。我们委托荥阳警方去做了暗访，但没有直接证据，也不好说当年的盗案就和他有关。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我看到蔡杰夫明显松了一口气。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不过马永康透露，当年曾从被盗窃的罗汉头上提取过两枚指纹，但荥阳警方收录的常宝林的二代身份证信息里并没有指纹信息，原因是手指烧伤，没有采集到。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;教授清楚他的手是怎么受的伤吗？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;听他提过一次，说是触电。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;是什么时候的事？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;说是小时候。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但马永康得到的信息却是，常宝林的手受伤时间是在2002年左右，那时，他三十二岁。如果具体时间能够吻合盗案发案的时间，这双手受伤的状况就不能简单去看待。作为文物缉私刑警，马永康曾接触不少文物盗窃案例，太多盗贼为逃避追查打击，故意用自残的方式毁掉指纹。如果常宝林曾做过盗贼，他很可能也会采用这种方式。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;挂断电话，蔡杰夫很无力地说：&amp;ldquo;如果年初没去泽山镇，也许根本不会出现麻烦。 &amp;rdquo;他的软弱已经达到让我怒不可遏的地步。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会胜寺的往事梦魇一样落在我和蔡杰夫的日常里，我们不时总会提起。五一劳动节过后，C县文物局给了回复，说是光明村的村长李福田拉到一笔投资，即将展开古建的修复工程。按照约定，我们自然要去做技术顾问。之后，我们数次前往光明村，前后加起来，在那里待了足有一个月之久。那个村子，那座破寺，还有寺里破损的彩塑，以及目光呆滞的看寺人，我们最终都熟悉得不能再熟悉。修复工作完成之后，我竟患上了会胜寺&amp;ldquo;后遗症&amp;rdquo;，具体表现是，总是控制不住地在梦里梦到捉老鼠的看寺人，他被大火烧死的儿子，还有被锯断了脖子的罗汉头。蔡杰夫也患上了&amp;ldquo;后遗症&amp;rdquo;，但他和我的有区别，他在担忧着常宝林的被抓，他每天总要翻一翻常宝林的朋友圈，看看他是否还在更新。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我坚信，会胜寺的盗案终究要在二十多年后真相大白，没有什么力量会将恶的暗流永久包裹在地面以下。会胜寺罗汉脖颈上的伤疤还在，看寺人李炳银的疯病还在，警方的模拟画像还在，常宝林作祟的罪责还在。只要会胜寺还矗立在地面上，人们总会把往事拉到光明的地面上晒一晒。污恶是始终无法蒸发掉的，只会随着时间的积累，沉淀得更加浓黑与顽固。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;暑日，据说河南将迎来史上最高温天气。这天，我去嵩山避暑写生时，微信上忽然弹出一个&amp;ldquo;胜利&amp;rdquo;的表情图案，随后是一条语音信息：&amp;ldquo;常宝林，已带走。 &amp;rdquo;我的心里&amp;ldquo;咕嘟&amp;rdquo;一声，像一口久没疏通的下水道忽然洞开，松懈，污恶一下就缩到广阔世界里去了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;发微信者是刑警马永康。其实我们早就认识了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马永康说：&amp;ldquo;谢谢小老弟。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我说：&amp;ldquo;也谢谢你，没把我搁里边。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他笑说：&amp;ldquo;彼此彼此。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我的脸上也堆叠出最无奈的笑容。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我必须实话实说，我没有遵守承诺，还是就背叛了蔡杰夫。我从没有当过小偷，但针对蔡杰夫，我当了一次。我私自翻了蔡杰夫的公文包，翻出那张模拟画像，拿手机拍摄了下来。在蔡杰夫饱受精神困扰的那些日子里，我跑遍了郑州以及周边的大小古玩城，去寻找一位头顶有戒疤的男子。我去了荥阳，去了一家字画店，当我大概认出我要找的人时，手机很不友好地咬了我的手一下。我查找到解州警方的电话，毫不犹豫拨打了过去。我说：&amp;ldquo;我要举报。 &amp;rdquo;心里同时在想的是，也许会胜寺早就不需要一位疯癫的看寺人了，用无辜者的生命一次次去祭它的腐朽、血腥与诡异，那地方，还是早点儿塌掉算了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;责任编辑：讷讷&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;征稿信息见@ONE一个工作室置顶微博。 For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fh8gokNt2KMRW1BZRFeHvmguxXa7&quot; alt=&quot;阿虎&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;阿虎 &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;编剧，小说作者，现居北京。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;关注&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;相关推荐&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6056&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;杏棉街往事&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 阿虎&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6109&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;最&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 甲或乙&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6116&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;2009年的丢书事件&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 何人&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6119)&quot;>;点击可下载ONE一个app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4019]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4158]]><description>&lt;div>;8 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FiVg2BSBdaXqRQI6YqVp8bLQD8ZW&quot; alt=&quot;首页图&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4019&lt;/span>;插画| 胡一凡&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oct. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;生活是正着来生活，倒着去理解。&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>