<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[你上一次哭是因为什么？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3948]]><description> &lt;div>;19 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; ONE Studio Question&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p >;What was the last time you cried? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Zhu Deyong replied&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpAk0gaZoJ3eKxBEakrGZT55tcht&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpAk0gaZoJ3eKxBEakrGZT55tcht&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Nana onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Zhu Deyong&#39;s Q&amp;A column &quot;Me≠We&quot; is exclusively updated on the &quot;ONE&quot; APP. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmPuzv4rbuXt8DD2ZiWPWVY5GDQ3 &quot; alt=&quot;Zhu Deyong&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Zhu Deyong&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;Weibo@朱德yong&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style =&quot;&quot;>;Cartoonist. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Question and Answer&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/question/3942&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;At which moment did your childhood end? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3932&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What is your comfort in a complicated life? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3916&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What determines the size of your world? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3948)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[我的天才女友]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6134]]><description> &lt;div>;19 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Xingxingchen&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FjavF3mwDbL337mTxHDq-kh6nb7M&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FjavF3mwDbL337mTxHDq-kh6nb7M&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;This article is a work of non-fiction. The author knows an extraordinary female friend who dares to break the rules. She travels all over the world and leads a wandering life. This article records the life journey of the two getting to know each other. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;1. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She often disappears for a period of time, and no one knows where she is. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is often places that you would never expect, such as the long bus ride in Addis Ababa, the mist-shrouded Machu Picchu, the chaotic cross streets of Kabul, the ups and downs of San Francisco, and a place in Berlin. She doesn&#39;t mark the underground bomb shelters, the roads in Reykjavik that all look the same, or the islands whose names she has never heard of. She doesn&#39;t necessarily answer when asked, depending on her mood. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It’s not that she doesn’t care about other people’s opinions at all. On the contrary, she cares a lot about it. She is willing to hide this, which makes her feel safer. She often talks about other people&#39;s comments about her, saying, &quot;I just watch you all day long and have fun all over the world.&quot; After saying this, she will comment to herself, &quot;That&#39;s not the case at all.&quot; But she never refutes it publicly, &quot;Let them I thought it would be better if I played around. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She often falls into some kind of dangerous situation. For example, during the Egyptian riots in Cairo, she watched her girlfriend buy a bouquet of flowers amidst the roar of tanks rolling through the streets on 24-hour TV. Walk up from downstairs; when the U.S. military and the Taliban were rioting in Afghanistan, you swallowed sleeping pills while listening to the barking of dogs and the sound of gunfire. Then when the next morning came, you quickly walked across the noisy and dangerous neighborhood in black and found a hidden restaurant. He ducked into the carpet store; or he went to Tanzania during the epidemic. At that time, one of the only two countries in the world that had not released specific epidemic figures, he searched for those people in the small villages under Mount Kilimanjaro whose origins no one could tell. Jewelry and furniture... these dangerous situations are neutralized by her own dangerous temperament, and then through her nonchalant ridicule, it becomes a kind of relaxed conversation material extracted from rich nutrients. , thus ignoring all the hardships, setbacks and unknown fears or sorrows. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before her last trip to Tanzania, when she left customs at Pudong Airport, the border inspector was confused that she had been to so many dangerous places and asked her, &quot;Did you go to Afghanistan just to get a blanket?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Yes&amp;rdquo;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said while learning, &quot;He looked at me like I was crazy.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In some aspects, she is almost obsessive-compulsive. She must do her best when she wants to do it. It is best to do it best when it looks easy. The lightness of her posture is very important to her. It&#39;s important to say, &quot;If you can&#39;t do it 100%, it&#39;s better not to do it.&quot; For example, she tried writing novels, but she thought they were not good enough, so she put away the manuscripts and continued her business. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She felt that doing business was like a cover-up, &quot;covering up my love for literature&quot;, the kind of cover-up and frustration of simply not doing it when she knew she was not good enough. But now, she seems to be able to slowly accept it all. After all, literature is not that important in front of life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sometimes, she will completely accept her own unimportance. Her Moroccan supplier could not accept that she was dealing with a woman, and he did not believe that the woman standing opposite her was the one who had the final say. “He never thought that I was the boss. He said it, but he didn&#39;t believe it. He thought I was just a secretary and was sent to Morocco to buy goods for him. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This arrogant Moroccan businessman never let her sit down in his office, and was not even willing to move a chair for her, so she stood the whole time while he completed several containers. order form. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When it comes to self-introduction in serious or joking situations, she likes to call herself &quot;the bad guy&quot; or &quot;the blanket seller&quot;. Such self-deprecation makes her feel relaxed and &quot;can be wrapped up.&quot; The shyness of what I really wanted to do. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Actually, what she did was not just as simple as reselling goods from all over the world. How did she combine the patterns on the blankets collected from an African market with the feelings she felt when they were woven in the hands of the workers? Connected with a unique rhythm, she felt that it was some kind of cultural translation; or giving a rather exotic and mysterious name to a certain type of hanging cloth in India - &quot;Mandala hanging cloth&quot; ;, and then compile a set of romantic rhetoric for them. This name was later copied by the entire Internet. In fact, they were just called &quot;Bu&quot; in India. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This story has an even more bizarre follow-up. Because of the super &quot;imitation ability&quot; of Chinese traders, these hanging cloths were later copied by countless small domestic workshops and mass-produced and sold cheaply. , resulting in a serious slowdown in the sales of hanging cloths in many local engraving and dyeing factories in India. The Jaipur Chamber of Commerce in northern India blacklisted her name because she was among the first to import hanging cloths from there and sell them outright. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In &quot;My Genius Girlfriend&quot;, Lenon&#39;s perspective on Lila is just like my perspective on her. She is the genius girlfriend in my life, always in uncertainty, but always able. Escaping from a dangerous situation; at the same time, her brightness and dilemma are so distinct, it&#39;s almost as if she chose all of this on her own. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For me, she is not only an adventurer, but more like a person who is still waiting for something to happen. It does not refer to the mediocre plots, great joys and sorrows, or the narratives of successful people. The climax is something more moving and nihilistic, like under the sun in the Serengeti, &quot;when the sun is particularly strong, a person walking under the sun.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FufthBdB_b63GIzMLFRsp0Jf2q9W&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot; http://image.wufazhuce.com/FufthBdB_b63GIzMLFRsp0Jf2q9W&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;i>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i>;&lt;div>;Iceland&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable= &quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FhCYD43WWaKkrb0ImyyX-f-_bnRi&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image. wufazhuce.com/FhCYD43WWaKkrb0ImyyX-f-_bnRi&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;i>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i>;&lt;div>;Kabul, Afghanistan&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot; false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FrsaEVxJJEsp1H-Y9rwJWr0GI7tN&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com /FrsaEVxJJEsp1H-Y9rwJWr0GI7tN&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;i>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i>;&lt;div>;Tanzania Serengeti&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When her foreign trade business just started, she rented an extremely large apartment in a southern city. One of the rooms was very small, with a mattress thrown on the wooden floor and a mattress on the bedside. There are several books scattered on the low cabinet, one of which is &quot;Other Voices, Other Rooms&quot; by Truman Capote. There is a small window beside the bed. Through that window, you can smell the loneliness. The humid air belonging to the southern city, I lived in this room during my short stay there. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The entire space here is like the messy style of the American &quot;Beat Generation&quot; in the 1960s, with rough walls, exotic printed cloths, and a log table that is almost as big as the restaurant. There are piles of fabrics, scissors and sundries on it, a bathroom half painted with blue paint, and various handicrafts she brought back from all over the world - a Japanese illustrated version of the Heart Sutra, a Moroccan golden chandelier, an African wood carving mask, and a wooden container. The formed platform and the southern tropical plants swaying on it...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unlike the decadent literary atmosphere exuded by the huge space, she did not place the books, but Hide a book in a cardboard box and place it high on the side of the living room. A huge curtain is placed on it, hanging from the ceiling to the floor. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She has never been able to buy a bookcase of her own. In the past, she had no time because she was running around, and later because she kept moving, she seemed to be unable to find time. She was extremely eager to have a study room of her own where she could write with peace of mind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In fact, when she really works, whether it is a dining table against the wall, a small coffee table, or a train, car, or plane traveling quickly, or even the ever-changing cafes, country guesthouses, Five-star hotels, tents in tropical jungles...she can use it to work anytime and anywhere. Perhaps what she really wants to have is not a study room, but a completely independent and quiet space and freedom that exists in her imagination. The free creative time is separated from all kinds of annoying things in real life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She told me on the phone that her friends in this city would only talk to her about lipstick and camera models, &quot;I really can&#39;t talk to them about literature, I don&#39;t understand them at all.&quot; She is very generous. She bought a plane ticket for me, and I happily flew over to see her. At that time, she dragged a stool and stood next to a huge cardboard box to look for McEwan&#39;s novels for me. She pointed at the book and emphasized in a very solemn tone, &quot;You must read it!&quot; A must see! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then we discussed the novels of a newly published female writer, and we all agreed that her writing was extremely poor, but none of us mentioned that we wanted to write it. She sometimes told I talk about business, or things between her and her boyfriend. I don&#39;t speak much, I just listen most of the time. I like to listen to her stories. There are always some extremely magical things in her mouth, with thousands of twists and turns and exciting unfinished things. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was not very comfortable during the last few days there because she mentioned my ex-boyfriend inexplicably--this boyfriend was introduced to me by her after I met him. , he warned me several times, &quot;You must stay away from her,&quot; but then we broke up - the afternoon I left, the weather was very gloomy, and my face looked uglier than the clouds outside. , she observed me carefully, and asked in a begging tone, &quot;Do you want me to send you off?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After I refused, I took McEwan’s novel back with me. I asked for her permission before taking it away. She waved her hand and said, &quot;Take it away, take it away. I don&#39;t have any friends around me to borrow books from.&quot; This sentence made me feel warm and I remembered it for many years. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After returning home, I was inspired, or more directly stimulated, by her independent entrepreneurship. I quit my job and started trying freelance writing. During this period, I finished reading McEwan&#39;s collection of short stories, and I was shocked for a moment. I conveyed my excitement to her in a poor and fierce way, &quot;I&#39;m so awesome. I wrote it so well. How can I write it?&quot; Yes, really awesome...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her reaction to this was relatively indifferent. When I started reading the second McEwan, she started reading Munro. At that time, Munro was in mainland China. It wasn&#39;t as popular as it is now. My first Munro novel was also given to me by her. I have forgotten when and under what circumstances I got this book. Both books have no covers, leaving only the brown and hard cover inside. Book. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Until now, I don’t know what the real covers of McEwan’s and Munro’s books look like, but what is certain is that her recommendation at that time must have been as sincere and effective as ever, almost A kind of compulsion. For me, her affirmation and recommendation are things that must be taken seriously. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I suddenly realized that I unconsciously valued her opinions, which made me feel bored and rebellious. After getting Munro&#39;s book, I briefly read an article and told her, &quot;I can&#39;t understand what she&#39;s talking about,&quot; she replied to me, &quot;I can&#39;t understand it either, but the writing is very good. Munro is so good that you can&#39;t even explain it.&quot; This comment means that she has entered the world of words and is familiar with the beauty of it that cannot be explained to outsiders, but I can&#39;t even scratch the surface. I feel a little angry, so I continue to put it away. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Until the summer of the second year, I had almost no work at hand and slept idle until noon every day. One day, after I was lying on the sofa and couldn&#39;t find anything to kill my time, Open the novel again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She simply underlined or marked some places in the book, and wrote a few words here and there. I paid special attention to these notes, always hoping that when I read that page, I could easily understand the meaning. &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;Sometimes it works, sometimes it doesn&#39;t. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;She still has that strange hesitation and ease, as if she is waiting for life to start again.&quot; This is the sentence that she underlined in the book, and it is also a sentence that I like and yearn for. In this sense, I feel like this sentence is describing her life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This story tells the story of a peculiar woman who, after failing in her family business, sold her house to another person, who demolished it and built it into an apartment, in which she rented a house. And developed an unexplainable relationship with an extremely depressed cleft lip patient. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is a novel that cannot be summarized. This magical woman is always able to maintain a positive and optimistic attitude towards the situations she faces. To pessimists, her naive attitude is almost absurd. This allows her to have a small space around herself to accommodate her simplicity and pride. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;And I prefer another article, which tells the story of a lame woman who took up a married lover. During the decades they were together, she paid for a blackmail. Yu she heard from her lover that he was discovered by a domestic helper of their affair and was blackmailed. Years later, she attends the helper&#39;s funeral and wakes up the next morning to realize the truth of her deception. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So, &amp;ldquo;She got up, got dressed quickly, walked through each room, and told the walls and furniture about this new idea. There was a hole in every place, the most obvious one being in her chest. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;She is bold and childish, and men may be fascinated by her, but then, her recklessness, her smugness - if that is smugness - will make her &quot;People are tired&quot; - This is the sentence that I underlined in this story. To a certain extent, I feel that it also describes my life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But I have not discussed this with her, not only because I am sure that the novel I like seems more ingenious and rough in comparison, but I always feel that it is unclear what the novel is about. The novel is the real novel. At the same time, alongside this craftsmanship, what I didn’t want her to see were my real weaknesses and flaws. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I probably agree with my ex-boyfriend&#39;s comments from the bottom of my heart. She is extremely dangerous. If she discovers such a weakness, you can&#39;t predict that at some point in the future, she will do it on a whim. Easily poke it through wherever it goes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&lt;br>;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;3. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We have a strange independent relationship. My circle of friends has no intersection with her circle of friends. The only one-way connection is between us. Our respective social circles may have been separated earlier, and the original source may be traced back to ten years ago, when she just returned from Africa. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I saw her on the street. She had become very thin, but very energetic. She was wearing a suspender skirt. Her wheat-colored body was hidden in the skirt, like a new tree, full of life. . She kept talking about what she saw and heard in Africa, and mentioned that a publishing house invited her to write a book because of this. She waved her hand and said like a fly, &quot;I won&#39;t write if it doesn&#39;t make any money.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At that time, I had just started my internship in that southern city, and everything was very new. It was an era when WeChat public accounts had just begun to emerge. Mi Meng had not yet become a phenomenon, and was still giving me all the information. The magazine where I am interning writes some humorous short articles related to history. Everything is very far away from me, whether it&#39;s the lavish luxury close in front of me or the bright lights further away, or even the typhoon days that bring tropical cyclones, the white beaches and the accompanying blue waves that I never take the time to set foot on. , have nothing to do with me at all. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She enthusiastically invited me to her home, her home at that time. I went there and found that the space there was cramped, simple and hasty, and the white tile walls gave me a temporary feel. This shocked me greatly. Even though I knew that the land here was very valuable, I still couldn&#39;t believe that she lived here. , No matter from her daily conversation or my expectations for her, she deserves to live in a better house with more space and a better view. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That night, I was lying on her bed. There was a mahjong mat under me. The small bamboo squares were cooled by the air conditioner. The sunken cabinet at the head of the bed contained the ones she wore. A long wooden bracelet, an ashtray, notes, and books piled beside the bed. I opened her notes, and I couldn&#39;t remember what was written in them, but her handwriting was always very good. As I looked at it, I slowly began to accept that this was her home. There was a period in her life when she had to temporarily stay. Here, in this dark and small space, as long as it can get a little sunshine, it can grow fast and well. I have such confidence in her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This kind of confidence has been continuously verified in the years that followed. She can indeed get better and better and become more and more successful. She can move out of a small house, move to a bigger house, and continue to move to a bigger house... At this point, I will always be happy for her, as if her success is mine, because I She believed this when she was not so successful. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Accompanying those hurried years are the romantic stories in her mouth, such as the strange people she met during the journey, sitting in the sunset and playing strange musical instruments. It sounded more relaxed before I started, and the foreign land was no longer dangerous, but gradually became beautiful. These stories also made me calmer, and I felt that she would definitely go further. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Probably from this time on, the distant places and people living far away in her mouth began to become out of reach, but I like to watch them from a distance in a hazy way, watching them come from her mouth Changes arise, like a mirage. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During that time, she often gave me takeout in the early hours of the morning, or took me to wander in the humid but comfortable night alleys to buy whatever I wanted to eat. She remembered the drinks I loved to drink, and she liked taste, and then after a while, buy it. In fact, she was a few months younger than me, but she gradually began to develop a more mature and sophisticated temperament than me, so that she was full of care and tolerance for me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This good time did not last long, she would soon leave for a new place, and I also quickly left that city. &lt;/p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FsFtIBTsVeIU95XIkLhBkGlHppA9&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FsFtIBTsVeIU95XIkLhBkGlHppA9&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;i>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i>;&lt;div>;Morocco&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;4. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After finishing my internship, I gradually realized that I was not good at wandering around or making a living in the so-called social university. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I do not have any worldly wisdom or tenacity to understand that a print shop that is still brightly lit at two o&#39;clock in the middle of the night is likely to undertake more complex social functions-I call this &quot; &quot;Print shop incident&quot; - This originated from the fact that I passed a print shop late at night with a boy I had a crush on at the time. The lights were still on at two or three in the morning, and the rolling shutter was halfway down. He pointed lightly at the shop. The print shop asked me, &quot;What do you think it is for?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was surprised that he asked this unquestionable question and replied indifferently, &amp;ldquo;Print shop, printing, copying and the like...&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He He quickly interrupted me, &quot;Who would come to print and copy in the middle of the night? Think about it?&quot; It will definitely make other transactions... This makes it impossible for me to refute. I can neither prove that I am right nor point out where he went wrong. I even think that he said There must be some truth; what also shocked me was that I had never thought about such a problem. My indifference to printing shops with lights on in the middle of the night seemed to reflect the bookish carelessness and lack of depth in everything in my heart. It&#39;s natural to understand. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This made me suddenly feel that he, like her, is a real adult. They understand the true face of the world, but I can only see the most superficial layer, and then sprout from these superficial layers. Some literary imagination, such as when a print shop is no longer a print shop, what might it be? Maybe it&#39;s an entrance to an unknown world - this is undoubtedly naive. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I continued to go to school and graduate school, and during it, I seemed to have waited for some moments, the few moments that made me convinced that the useless things I loved would occasionally play a role and make me feel better. My calming down became the only highlight of my academic career. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2014, I went to Taiwan for exchange, and my contact with her became less and less. In the summer of that year, I participated in a literary summer camp in Hong Kong. It was a wild residence of the Department of Biology of the University of Hong Kong. The organizer invited many writers. I remember that there was a female writer at that time who had a calm and relaxed attitude about her. Temperament, she said while sitting in the empty classroom, &quot;The outside is changing, but what does this have to do with me?&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This sentence shows her strong and firm self and her determination not to be shaken or affected by external things, which brings me a kind of strength. It was a bustling era outside, people took to the streets, and there were all kinds of arguments and opinions floating inside. People were trying to argue and prove the rationality and legitimacy of their opinions, but she sat quietly in the house and told us , these will soon pass away, it doesn’t matter. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another day, he was a now-famous translator. It was raining outside after the lecture. His classmates wanted to help him get an umbrella, but he refused and sat on the wooden bar outside the classroom door. The bench said, &quot;If it&#39;s going to rain, let it rain.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At that time, I was almost moved by his detachment. In order not to destroy it, I quickly walked into the rain and left there. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In these moments, I will think of her. What would happen if she were here? Would she also like this atmosphere and want to write something, or would she be dismissive of it? I have no idea. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I desperately hope to gain some nourishment from this literary rhetoric, which will allow me to grow into another kind of mature person, something completely different from her worldly temperament, but still enough. Give me a foothold in this world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later I discovered that this was almost a luxury. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In fact, we have been to several literary events together, and almost every time, she had no sense of participation. After returning from Hong Kong, we all went to Beijing at the same time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One day, she told me that there was a lecture on the poetry of the female poet Zhai Yongming in a bookstore near Wangjing, and we went there together. It was summer, the streets of Beijing were full of dust, and our feet were covered in dust. After arriving at the scene, I forgot what the guests said. I only remember that after the speech, I still raised my hands very enthusiastically to ask questions, while she stepped back very far and said nothing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I am very familiar with this kind of withdrawal of hers, and I always feel that it contains more. Her silence contains not only the knowledge of my questions, but also the judgment of others&#39; possible answers, and more. Things, the overtones that I heard, didn’t hear, and hadn’t absorbed in time, and her criticism of them, were all included in her silence and concession. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In fact, our time in Beijing in 2014 was not very smooth. I resigned frequently and moved from one company to another, trying hard to adapt to a social life that was not suitable for me; she seemed to be forced into a cage, exuding the anxiety of a trapped animal. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her reasons for not going to work at all sound almost ridiculous. Because she had to go to work, she could only choose public holidays when going out. During the National Day holiday that year, she went to Xinjiang and was surrounded by a group of old men and women with long guns and short cannons in the scenic area. She resigned when she came back. The reason was &quot;I don&#39;t want to go out to play on May 11, I want to go out to play on ordinary days.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Neither my existence nor her pretentiousness could last long. We both left Beijing one after another very quickly. The reasons for leaving were all very cliche and embarrassing. I just can&#39;t hang out anymore. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;5.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We have returned to our hometowns successively, but there are still differences. She began to turn traveling around the world into a business, which was surprisingly prosperous; while I continued to look for jobs, quit my job, and then looked for jobs again, until I completely collapsed. Then, inspired by her to start my own business, Started what is called home office freelancing territoryless work, whatever you want to call it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At this time, we almost became people in two worlds. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Once, she called me and asked me what I was doing. I was about to play cards with my colleagues, but I was too embarrassed to tell her this on the phone. Suddenly, I found that the positions between us had changed. She was the one in literature, and I was the reality, a reality that was more helpless, tragic, and unworthy of narration. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This almost made me forget that a very important thing actually happened before this, which completely reversed the almost endangered relationship between us, and that was our correspondence. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That was the only time we broke up. It was caused by a small incident. She teased my mental state like a joke. I was so angry that I blocked her. She wrote me a letter and told me, &quot;That day you said you didn&#39;t plan to be my lifelong best friend. I cried for a long time, but you know, isn&#39;t that just who I am?&quot; So, don&#39;t blame me, I still want to be your best friend for life. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She was sincere, so I wrote back. In these several correspondences, we talked about literature, childhood, our own lives, and thoughts about writing. This was one of our more serious and profound exchanges about literature. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some fragments of her letters left a deep impression on me, which made me discover that she was not just doing business, but that like me, she was in a dilemma between reality and ideals. &amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;It has been a year since I last met you. This year I began to write something seriously again, accumulating more than 100,000 words. This process is very painful, and it is completely different from the mentality I had when I was writing for children&#39;s literature and the like when I was a teenager, because now I often want to deliberately stay smart, but at that time it was all driven by passion. I gave up and deleted it countless times. I doubted the significance of this topic, reopened the folder, and decided to be honest. No matter it was dirty, stupid, or childish, at this stage, it is better to face myself and others sincerely. Think about the level or the meaning of calculation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some time ago in the United States, in order to consolidate my language, I tried to translate some English short stories, which were all written by contemporary writers. Even now, I practice every day. Thinking is often shaped by language. In this process, I increasingly believe that paying attention to the individual and inner world is inevitable for development, and there is no need to feel inferior to anyone else. At the same time, I also feel very regretful that if these excellent works that I have won many awards abroad would have been published in China, there would be almost no possibility of them being published. However, writing is a really bad hobby. If they had to choose again, many people would definitely choose music, art or even carpentry. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking back, the strongest connection we had had had nothing to do with reality. It was completely suspended in the real world, transformed into a confrontation of words and discussions. Other than that, there were some inexplicable things. Regret, envy, competition and reconciliation, as well as the extremely long time of not seeing each other again - these time are used to accumulate strength so that the next time they meet again, the two of them can still stand on the same level and talk freely. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What we can remember about our next gathering is just a discussion about novels. It seemed like a rescue, a rescue that pulled us away from real life, both for me and for her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At that time, her relationship with her boyfriend was tense. One afternoon, after her boyfriend went out, we sat in the living room and chatted. We continued to talk about literature. She mentioned a newly met friend who went to a certain place with her and immediately wrote a novel. After she described that place, After writing a novel, she began to lament, saying that she did not have such talent anyway, even if she saw the same scenery, &quot;All I could think about was business, and there was no way I could write a novel.&quot; She sat on the floor with her hands spread out, Appearing depressed and lost. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then she also talked about the impact of education from the land on artistic creation, such as the inspiration of the African land on Picasso. I sat and listened, occasionally interjecting, sincerely encouraging her to start creating, and she always heard He refused straight away, &quot;I can&#39;t do it, I can&#39;t write.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;But you haven’t tried it yet.&amp;rdquo; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I can’t write&amp;rdquo;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I would like to regard this as a kind of humility from her. I am looking forward to but also a little worried that one day in the future, she will suddenly let me see something she wrote, which contains her All ambitions, setbacks, failures and successes result in an amazing creation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the same time, for those views she mentioned that I had never heard of, I always wondered whether she came up with it herself or saw it somewhere and wrote it down, but because she is always better than me Knowing and comprehending it earlier and faster, so that I could not reveal it before her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After we finished talking, her boyfriend suddenly broke into the door and confessed to us that because he suspected that she was having an affair, he squatted outside the door for more than an hour. After listening to the content of our conversation, he said nothing until I still remember, &quot;I didn&#39;t expect you two women to talk about literature all the time.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is the first time I heard a strange affirmation from a man. From a male perspective, when two women get together, they will definitely talk about love or men. In addition, what we talk about is also weird and illogical in his opinion. We are talking about literature, not bags or house prices.或者股票，我一直为此而自豪，并期望我们能够继续如此，坚定而持续地聊下去，聊那些严肃而高尚的话题，永远不要堕落。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在我回去之后，我们的生活依然像是两条跑道，毫无交集，只有偶然几次她会找我，聊一聊，然后便消失掉。她似乎还是没有准备坐下来开始写作，我几乎没有看到她真正意义上的作品，只有旅行中的零散记录，其中一些句子具有一种新鲜的语调与力量，这让我想到了普鲁斯特所说的，&amp;ldquo;智慧是一种看待事物的观点&amp;rdquo;。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她的确拥有那种不同以往的生活，能够让她脱胎于周遭的庸俗与日常，由此或许能够诞生出一种新的讲述方式。我一边留心这种诞生，一边暗自希望她能尽快开始。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这期间，我们的友谊再一次产生了一些裂痕，但这一次，我怀疑她可能从始至终都不曾知晓。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《我的天才女友》这本书刚刚出现时，我便看了几页，几乎像是一种本能反应，我马上意识到莱农口中那个大家还没开始学习字母、就已经开始会拼写的小女孩，一定会是她的天才女友，并且将永远领先她，超过她，彻底地碾压她。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我对这个故事感到一阵恐慌，仿佛一旦翻开书页，某种悲惨预言便告实现。我拒绝再看下去，并彻底隐藏了我拒绝的真正原因，我对外一直宣称这本书的语言太过直白浅显，&amp;ldquo;一点文字韵味也没有，就像流行小说&amp;rdquo;，这是我当时虚张声势的评语。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;而后，这部由小说衍生的电视剧开始流行时，我又短暂看了几集，在我看到莉拉与莱农去参加老师的晚宴过后，莉拉指责莱农等人所聊的话题毫无建树、纸上谈兵，连真实生活的影子都沾不到，即便是看着电视剧，我都感到一阵刺痛，这几乎就像是她会对我说的话。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;果不其然，不久之后，也可能是在那之前，她在微博上发了一段评语：&amp;ldquo;莉拉在车里嘲讽知识分子那段真过瘾&amp;rdquo;。在这个过程里，我们其实并没有真正联系，连一句话也没有说过。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我彻底对这部小说丧失好感，很长一段时间再也没有打开它。但我也因此知道，原来她也读了这本小说，我为她没有扔下书本感到安心，但我依然无法理解，她同样是读过很多书的人，凭什么能站在另一个制高点&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;即熟稔真实世界并将之玩弄于股掌之间的地方，去嘲笑那些热爱文学的人只是纸上谈兵？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;6． &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她的确可以。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她的身影总是浮现于不同场景里，显得生机勃勃，充满了智慧与斗争，对于想要寻找的事物，她有一种追捕猎物般的耐心与韧性，随时在等待着那些不曾被人发觉、藏在角落中的某些东西，偶尔闪现。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但她曾说过羡慕我，这在我看来几乎不可思议。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2016年，我刚刚回到西安不久，有一天下午，我正口干舌燥地寻找一个藏传寺庙，她突然打来电话，没有任何铺垫与前情，她开始说她羡慕我，羡慕我有那么多的自由时光，能够立马为自己喜欢的事物奔赴某地，然后动手写自己想要写的任何东西。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我说，&amp;ldquo;你也可以啊。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她回答，&amp;ldquo;我不行，我要做生意，我没有时间。再说，我现在写不出来了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我不明白她为什么说自己不行，我坐在一棵巨大的梧桐树下感到一阵疑惑。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我开始向她解释，我并没有多少自由时间，为了挣钱要写一切，无论是给一个书店、奶茶店或者大闸蟹酒家；并且，为了所谓狗屁兴趣奔赴远方毫无意义，到了现场你就会发现，你的采访对象要不拒绝见面，要不就是从白天说到晚上都讲不出任何有意思的东西。除此以外，你永远都不可能写什么自己想写的，有的是人想要这个那个，你得先满足他们。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她不置可否地听着，很快又打断我，非常武断地说，&amp;ldquo;好吧，反正我就是羡慕。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我似乎从来都没珍惜过她口中那些无比珍贵的自由，它们都被我虚掷掉，以至于我时常回想不起来自己曾经干过什么，但她时常会因为一些小事对我表示羡慕，比如我周围的朋友都是能够跟我谈论文学的朋友，或者我竟然能找到活着的诗人，又或者我居然去参加了一个文学聚会！ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她羡慕的这些在我看来都无聊至极，没什么可谈论的，我说这些玩意儿和做生意一样的，接触了就不会觉得有什么稀奇。她在电话那头不说话，这时她会显得有点天真无知，像是一个局促地站在剧场门口的局外人，想要进去瞧瞧里面的演出，而我从后门出来告诉她，里面只能听见观众的哄闹，看见的只有一地瓜子皮。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有时，我会觉得她口中的那些羡慕都是假的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那年冬天，她在东欧荒芜废弃棚屋里遇到了&amp;ldquo;占屋者&amp;rdquo;，那是一个年龄很大的吉普赛浪人，在城市里寻找栖身之所，遇到没有人居住的房子便进去住下来。她与他交流了一阵子，然后为一本艺术杂志写了篇报道。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我记得她在谈话之前，曾在微信里问我应该怎么采访&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;她此前从没采访过任何人。我发给她一大堆语音，指导她要做提纲，调查背景什么的，她没有回复，我猜想她可能点开几个后便失去了兴趣。这让我再次确信，她做什么都不需要我的指导。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这之后，我在一家独立书店看到了这本杂志，那期杂志封面是一个形状可怖的白色怪人，额头还是脸上有一道鲜黄色的光影，我转身对身旁的朋友说，我有个朋友写了一篇文章，登在这上面。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但我没有买这本杂志，也不想看那篇文章。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这件事让我感到生气，凭什么她就可以轻易地学会采访，写完就能发表？而我却需要那么长的时间练习，磕磕巴巴小心翼翼地与被访对象打交道，然后被编辑否定，再经历一二三四五六七八次的修改。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除此以外，我对于这件事所产生的浪漫想象也十分折磨我，那也许是东欧某个城郊的一座荒废房子，没有房顶或者缺了窗户，脏乱的床铺，散落在床边的油桶和木椅，星空下，残破土地上燃着篝火，火光中他衰败地讲述着自己的过往。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这样的选题我没机会找到，倒是她出去旅个游就能碰见并写出来。我没有对她说起这事，这一定会让她感到很得意，并且推翻此前对我的所有羡慕。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我很少将自己的稿子给她看，有时她会找我写点东西，用一种几近恭敬的态度，&amp;ldquo;明总你忙不忙？我想找你写篇稿子。你想写就写。钱的事情不用担心&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;明总是自大学开始，我们互相戏谑的称呼。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我写好后发给她，她总是会说，&amp;ldquo;写得太好了！我这种暴发户也不知道说啥了，给你发个红包吧！ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;说得多了我就觉得全是假的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;只有一次，是我采访她，她将发表后的稿子寄给她的爷爷，老人回复道，&amp;ldquo;今天我仔细地阅读了一遍你的采访文章，查了一下作者，竟是你的挚友明星辰。她现在何处供职，请代我向她问好。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那才是她真正的家，一座位于江边的小城，那里有她的爷爷婆婆和满院子的花草，爷爷的书架上总是摆满了不同时期的《当代》《收获》《人民文学》，这是她告诉我的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;博客时代，她的爷爷也曾受到她的鼓动写过博客，将每日见闻和旧时回忆认真更新在博文里，他是一位退休的老工程师，文风简练，措辞严谨。我当时总在那个博客下面留言，他甚至为了回复我，写了一篇题为《回复明总（允许我也这样称呼您）的一则短讯》的博客短文，文中如此说&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;em>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;今日看到网友明星辰一则关注我的消息，甚为感动，并在此致谢。我开办博客之初尚有网友光顾，后来点击越来越少，是否与年龄和文章内容的贫乏有关？或者尚不懂得与网友交流的技巧？因此最近很少动笔写博客。但也没有停歇，倒专注于用实名为中评社&amp;ldquo;实名网评&amp;rdquo;栏目写些时评文章，因为时评是随新闻而动，时效性强，更新快，不失为练笔和动脑的好平台。从4月30日以来，已被精选刊发14篇文章，有不少还上了栏目头条。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;em>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;当然，如果要抒发情感，还是写博客为宜。 &lt;/span>;&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;em>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;2010年7月10日新浪博客&lt;/span>;&lt;/em>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是十二年前老人写下的一篇短文，过了十年，他依然记得我，这让我非常感动。从中我似乎也明白了她那些令人费解的羡慕实际上也隐藏着真情，她所向往的文学植根于一种理想的土壤中，严谨又朴素，像是她爷爷笔下一篇篇经过仔细观察与认真思索的评论文章，即使无人问津，依然闪烁着某种动人的光彩。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这或许也是我们友谊能够维系的重要原因，它与真实世界无关，经由一条非常微弱的银线牵引联系，在某些时刻，它会破碎或断裂，却又在另一些时候，奇迹般地生长出来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;它攀附在我对她的想象之上，同时也缠绕在她对于我的想象之中，我想象她的精彩纷呈，她想象我的沉默退隐，在这之中，才是某些我们从未料想到的文学时刻。 &lt;/p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fk7f5cegmN8nF4d1a2rfL4Mtw7xk&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fk7f5cegmN8nF4d1a2rfL4Mtw7xk&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;i>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i>;&lt;div>;作者友人的家乡江边&lt;/div>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;7． &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她依然频繁在世界各地游荡，硕果累累地经营着自己的个人事业，无论是对于她曾经去过、正在前往以及将要到达的任何地方，如果不是她提起，我都毫无概念，而她到底是怎样白手成家建立起属于她自己的个人王国，我也从无兴趣。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在她所去过并提到过的世界各处，我对其中几个片段留有印象，并由此产生一些奇异又瑰丽的联想。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个是马丘比丘山脚下的村庄，她到达时是五月，春天还没完全过去。她穿着披风，一个人走在陌生的村庄里，那个村子没有人会说英语。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她到的那一天，正赶上村里举办巨大的狂欢节，一群人在广场上打水仗，&amp;ldquo;就像打群架一样&amp;rdquo;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;她说话时有一种乒乓作响的干脆感，会把很多事情总结得既简练又好笑。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相对应于她的幽默，村子是另一种荒诞的现实，那里到处挂着形状可怖、造型各异的鬼娃娃，大大小小，飘飘摇摇，即便走过一座木桥，都能看到桥头挂着一个一人高的娃娃，&amp;ldquo;风吹过来时，那个娃娃就转啊转&amp;rdquo;。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她在那里遇见了一个售卖巫蛊娃娃的本地人，然后一口气买下了所有娃娃，那是些色彩鲜艳、扎着鞭子的布娃娃，其实并不恐怖，相反有一种意味深长的神情，也许是因为它们没有嘴巴。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我之所以会对这个情景留有印象，也许是因为在我看来她似乎身处险境，无论是所有人都说西语却无法听懂的孤寂，还是我们都无从真正了解的南美狂欢文化之下的幽灵幻影，都让我产生了一种惊险却美丽的感觉。当然，在这种既恐怖又怪异的场景中，她一定会再一次脱身而出，并带走了不被人所察觉的真正宝藏。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些娃娃后来被她全部卖掉，她再也没有去过那里，&amp;ldquo;找不到那个地方，不记得是哪儿。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是我对她另一个印象深刻的细节，无论她经手了多少奇巧精妙的东西，她永远不会将它们留下来。那些经由她费劲千辛万苦跋山涉水找来的宝物，她把它们拿起来，然后就轻松转手卖出去，没有一点留恋和不舍，但这些东西流经她的手掌，某种气息便滞留在上面，入宝山而空手归的旅人，身上笼罩着一种不可思议的气息，仿佛被这座绿意盎然的春山烹蒸过，那些虚空的花鸟就永远不会再飞走。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她反驳过我这一点，说自己并非什么也不留下，但我依然固执地这么认为。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一个则完全与事实相悖，她曾提到某个北非当地市场，我印象中她提到这个集市时说它位于山谷，于是在我的想象中，那是一个四周被荒山围绕、却神秘地在山脚交汇，拥有一片小小绿洲的所在，河水从狭窄的山口流过，人们牵着山羊愉快地走到她的面前。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;实际上，她后来给我看的图片完全不是那样。首先那不是山谷，而是一块平地，更没有什么绿洲或河流，人们挤在一个类似于村口广场的地方，密密麻麻地站着坐着，根本看不明白他们到底在干些什么。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于她来说，印象深刻的场景却不止存在于想象中。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她最近跟我谈起了非洲草原。她每天坐着吉普车，从乞力马扎罗山脚下飞驰向前。她提到了两个场景让她印象深刻，一个是&amp;ldquo;日光下无所事事坐在树下的人&amp;rdquo;，另一个则是&amp;ldquo;特别大的太阳底下，一直在走路的人&amp;rdquo;，不知道她为什么对我提到这个，但从她所描述的语言看来，她对于文字的感知力从未消失过，与我一直痴迷于文字内的幻境不同，她所流连的真实世界为她带来了更为强烈的冲击。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她似乎有了一些变化，谈话中意外地谈到家庭，甚至提到她眼中最酷的草原动物非洲猎豹，竟然被当地司机嫌弃。那位本土黑人司机评价猎豹是&amp;ldquo;草原上最没有责任感的动物，跟母豹生完孩子就跑了&amp;rdquo;，在更多时候，她是极富主见的，随时都可以随意决定自己马上要到哪里去，但在某些时刻，她又显得很没有主意，轻易能够被一个司机或者算命师傅左右看法。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说起自己曾在埃塞俄比亚坐船碰到了一个白人女人带着她的孩子，一路上随着河流飘荡，船只在热带雨林间穿梭时，那女人便低头耐心而恳切地教那个只有几岁的小朋友，&amp;ldquo;这是狮子&amp;rdquo;、&amp;ldquo;这是大象&amp;rdquo;&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说自己对这个场景感到一种向往。我并没有追问她是否真的对于这一切感到羡慕，并愿意以一种践行将之实现，我似乎害怕它会实现，于是我回她说，这大概也只是你的一种文学式的想象。她没有否认。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与她印象深刻的场景不同，我一直记得的是她所拍的一张照片，那是多年前她在印度或者别的什么地方拍下的，那似乎是早晨，雾气蒙蒙，无论是近旁的树木还是远处的人，一切都被笼罩在一种昏黄的不确定之中。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拍摄所在也许是个炎热的地方，但我总觉得它充满了一种寒意，但并非一种紧迫的寒意，那几乎是友好而诚挚的，对于一股即将爆发的热流感到一阵紧缩而清凉的寒意。图片正中，一条路通向了未知的去处，我从未问过她那条路通向哪里，我相信答案大概不重要。 &lt;/p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FrOq6n6zC3P5zLckv7M93Wsjolwv&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FrOq6n6zC3P5zLckv7M93Wsjolwv&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;责任编辑：舟自横&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;征稿信息见@ONE一个工作室置顶微博。更多编辑部的有趣日常请关注小红书：ONE一个编辑部。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FhmWISjmLN6dMYPFmqAMyRsG6bHY&quot; alt=&quot;明星辰&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;明星辰 &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@Moridioteslress的湖底&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;非虚构写作者。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;关注&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;相关推荐&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6132&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;秋天的安慰&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 苏更生&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6129&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;一千块&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 王大烨&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6134)&quot;>;点击可下载ONE一个app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4030]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4171]]><description>&lt;div>;19 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fi1y_KusqnUkpnF77vxlPWPTuTvI&quot; alt=&quot;首页图&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4030&lt;/span>;摄影| Blair Yang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;19&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oct. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;长途巴士的魅力之一在于，移动期间可以享受到座位大小的孤独感。&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>