<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[你，真的想辞职吗？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3910]]><description> &lt;div>;18 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Champagne Jazz Question&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>;You , do you really want to resign? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Rabbit grass answer&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FjssleW4je2fr58qHUiIc07BfDJL&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FjssleW4je2fr58qHUiIc07BfDJL&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Speaking of it, as a As a social worker with more than ten years of work experience, I am a legendary &quot;habitual offender of resignation.&quot; The most exaggerated time was when I cursed my immediate boss with a curse word in the office, and then left the same day without ever returning to work. Bit. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking back now, the eyes my colleagues looked at me that day were full of complex emotions such as confusion, admiration, and surprise. After I scolded the director, I remembered that my probation period was less than one month, so my salary might be withheld and not paid. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In fact, most people who are not deeply involved in the world have great expectations for their lives before entering the workplace. Since when did we start saying &quot;going to work is like visiting a grave&quot;? When did we start feeling anxious on Sunday afternoons and desperate to think about going to work on Monday? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Marx made such a profound statement in the &quot;Economic and Philosophical Manuscripts of 1844&quot; - &quot;Workers do not affirm themselves in their labor, but deny themselves. They do not feel To be happy is to feel unhappy, not to freely exert one&#39;s physical strength and intelligence, but to torture one&#39;s body and destroy one&#39;s spirit...The result is that people can only use their animal functions, such as eating, drinking, living, etc. When you are waiting, you feel that you are moving freely; but when you are using your human functions, you feel that you are just an animal. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is the so-called &quot;alienation&quot; from work, which is the essential reason why most people want to resign - not feeling any value at work The feeling is repeated, repeated, repeated every day. &lt;/strong>;As the economic situation becomes more and more severe and involution intensifies, working hours become longer and longer, which makes people feel as if they are at work as soon as they open their eyes, and exhausted after work. , can’t find any motivation to do anything else. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, although almost every worker talks about &quot;wanting to resign&quot;, there are very few people who actually do it. The reasons are nothing more than the following three points. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;1. People who have limited economic conditions and go to work just to earn &quot;consumption money&quot;;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Living in big cities Young people have to face high expenses every day when they open their eyes. They have to pay rent and spend money on food. After all, their wages seem to be enough for their normal survival. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Wanting to resign but having no money is the normal life of most social workers. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are also some middle-aged people who are old and young. They are the best people to be &quot;manipulated&quot; in the workplace, even if they want to resign ten thousand times in their hearts. , when facing work, you still have to weigh the weights in your hands. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2. Losing your job will lead to social difficulties&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are many in big cities Working young people dare not tell their parents in their hometown the truth after losing their jobs, so they can only hide it. If your parents think that you go to a big city to get a good job and make a lot of money, but if you suddenly say that you want to resign, their emotions will usually be very extreme and intense. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sometimes, even if you don’t care about work, people around you will always ask you what you are doing. Therefore, many people start looking for a job as soon as they resign, or even start looking for a horse before resigning, for fear of being questioned during the &quot;window period&quot; in the workplace. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Resigning is not a panacea for making life better. On the contrary, sometimes, resigning will bring about financial losses and turbulence in life. Many people resign with certainty, but also take action, within two days of resignation. Just crying and having an emotional breakdown in a rented house is not worth the gain. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Think about it, why did you resign? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;1. Seeking better development&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If you feel that you are stuck in your current company or are being held back, Then you can find a new company while you are still young. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the process of searching, it is best to ride the donkey to find the horse, because you do not hate the job itself, but just hate the company you work for. &lt;strong>;The current economic situation is sluggish, and having a job is better than not having one. Therefore, it is important to take one step at a time and assess the situation. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2. My physical and mental health is hindered and I really can’t stand it anymore &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I used to be in I got depressed while working in an advertising agency, and even developed a small tumor on my body. Faced with this situation, this class really couldn&#39;t last a day. So I decided to resign immediately. The reason for resigning is also very simple, that is, my health is not good. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After I resigned, I recuperated for a while. After I recovered, I stopped looking for a job that required overtime. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;3. Purely hate the workplace and hate going to work&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In this case, it is actually more troublesome , because people have to spend money to live, and if they want to spend money, they have to find ways to make money. Without a certain financial foundation, it is difficult to not go to work or work at all. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is important to adjust your mentality, and it is also important to accumulate funds for yourself for rest. If you really hate going to work, you might as well try freelancing. In the process, you can measure and compare whether you have the ability to completely leave the company and survive independently. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are many times when we say we want to resign, but in fact we never take action for a moment. However, in the long-term ideological pull, we will fall into internal friction. The process is like being in a relationship that has no results. You feel that being stuck with your current job is &quot;tasteless, a pity to abandon&quot;, but you don&#39;t have enough courage to take action. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The most painful thing about everything is swinging between two sides, whether it is emotion or work. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So, before shouting &quot;I want to resign&quot; next time, first think about whether you are just &quot;acting like a baby&quot; because you are tired of work, or whether you are really on the verge of collapse. &lt;strong>;Deeds are far better than words, anytime and anywhere. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Zhou Ziheng onewenzhang@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For information on the call for papers, please see @ONE Studio’s pinned Weibo. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmIxumvucSMThvBqzjla4dEmFbwL &quot; alt=&quot;Rabbit Grass&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Rabbit Grass&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@Rabbit Grass Tucao&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style =&quot;&quot;>;Retired copywriter, juggling writer. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Question and Answer&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/question/3867&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Can lowering desires make you happier? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3910)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[两颗子弹]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6092]]><description>&lt;div>;18 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Zhang Zichen&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data -author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FvblM78GbZrbtE-hab2ae-OjHVC8&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FvblM78GbZrbtE-hab2ae -OjHVC8&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Li Mu, a writer who encountered a bottleneck in his creation, turned his life into When used as writing material, the boundary between reality and fiction wandered in his mind. When adapting a novel based on a real case, two bullets, like echoes of the past, penetrated his memory. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A bullet comes out of the barrel and explodes together with a firecracker that flips and falls at the highest point in the silent night before the New Year. Sound, joy mixed with sadness - I wrote this at the beginning of the novel. As usual, the editor responsible for review will reply to me within these two days. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On this day, the fifth day of the twelfth lunar month, the first message came from Wang Yu. We had been separated for a while, and we had not contacted each other in the meantime. When I met her, she was selling insurance. I fell in love with her simply because she looked good. I regarded her as my girlfriend, and she regarded me as my scapegoat. Every time we met, she would introduce the insurance business to me within three sentences. , critical illness insurance, personal accident insurance, family property insurance, all kinds of assumptions, all kinds of plans, it feels like I am going to die at any time, she said, be prepared for a rainy day, life is too impermanent. The third to last time we met before we broke up was at the Jiutian Hotel in front of the Chemical Engineering Vocational School. We were pretending to be Seven Days, but we didn’t even take off our clothes, so they told me that there was a woman who was diagnosed with invasive breast cancer a few days ago and bought Our insurance paid out 500,000 yuan. Look, how good our life is. I immediately softened and said, Wang Yu, is there something wrong with you? Later I put on my clothes and left. After we broke up, I occasionally browsed her Moments and it was filled with insurance advertisements. I even suspected that I had added her work number at that time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She asked me if I was there. I wasn’t sure what I was going to say next, so I didn’t reply. The call came half an hour later. I hesitated for a moment but answered it. She said: &quot;The big boss is busy.&quot; What, you don’t have time to reply to the message? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said impatiently: &amp;ldquo;I didn’t see it, you are talking about something and don’t buy insurance. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said: &amp;ldquo;If I don’t sell insurance, I’ll quit. I’m asking you to do me a favor. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My heart trembled and I said: &quot;Say it first, I can&#39;t guarantee that I can agree. Although we have had a relationship, it has been a while. Don&#39;t take a moment as forever.&quot; . &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She snorted disdainfully and said, &amp;ldquo;I see, the person I am talking about is you. It&#39;s not a big deal, my mom wants to meet you. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Why? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;There are not many days left. I have two wishes before leaving. One is to find my dad, you know, and the second is to bring her a son-in-law back. There is basically no hope for the first one, so we can only satisfy the second one. After all, we have been together before, and with this kind of relationship, she should not be able to see any flaws. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Lend me two thousand yuan, money is a little tight recently. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She hummed, the deal was concluded. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After hanging up the phone, her appearance appeared in my mind unconsciously. She was of medium height, but tall among girls, with long, dyed hair, brown, and big eyes. She has a high nose bridge, fair skin, and slim curves. She is upturned where she should be, and concave where she should be. Thinking of this, she felt that her bladder was filled with discomfort. She ran to the toilet and recalled the first time between the two of them. In her rental house, the opposite person was a beef. There is a hot pot restaurant with a colorful couplet hanging on both sides of the door. One side says &quot;men&#39;s gas station&quot; and the other side says &quot;women&#39;s beauty salon.&quot; These words gave me strength, but in the end I couldn&#39;t use it very well. I made haste and analyzed it afterwards. It was mainly because when I was holding her, she told me that when you are over thirty, you still have to buy insurance. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I peed while standing, and the urine was foaming with white foam. It was a good idea to scoop up a cup of fake beer. Come to think of it, I have basically said goodbye to beer. Last year, when my dad was hospitalized, I took a physical examination and found out that high uric acid was high. If it is not controlled, the consequences will be serious. As for how serious it is, the doctor did not say clearly. I will check myself after I come back. , with lingering fears. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Counting this time, she asked me to help her three times in total. The first one was to buy an insurance, but I ignored it. The second one was to ask me to help her find out the whereabouts of her father. Because I said I knew the police. We were still in a relationship at that time. She said that her father’s name was Wang Jun, who disappeared in 2012. On the day of his disappearance, he was wearing a black polo shirt, a pair of navy jeans, and a pair of Peak sneakers. Apart from that, she Dad is 1.72 meters tall, has a short head, dark skin, a slightly hunched back, and a scar above his eyebrow bone. I said, first of all, your dad has been missing for almost ten years, so inquiries must be timely. Secondly, your dad’s name is too random. Not to mention the whole country, if you walk around the city south and north, you will be suffocated if you drop a stick. Wang Jun, why did you get such a fucking name? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Not long after, the phone received several WeChat messages in succession. It was still Wang Yu. Her online name was &quot;Sibai&quot; and her avatar was a blue cat, which had not changed in so many years. Clicking on it, it was her transfer. A total of two thousand sixty-six dollars was transferred, divided twice. The first transfer was two thousand, and the second transfer was six hundred. There were a few words at the end: Don&#39;t come empty-handed. I accepted the money and returned the gesture with an OK gesture. She replied: The collection of money is quite fast. I replied with an honest smile. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I made myself a bowl of noodles at noon. There was a handful of lettuce and two eggs in the refrigerator. I ate them together. After eating, I changed my outfit and went to the supermarket. At the end of the year, in the supermarket The place was packed with people, and the voices were mixed with the music on the radio, and they were full of joy. I bought some milk and honey with the 600 yuan funded by Wang Yu. When I saw melatonin on the shelf, I sent a message to Wang Yu: Do you want melatonin? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She replied: Are you short-sighted? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I didn’t reply, so I went to check out with milk and honey. It cost about three hundred yuan, and I could still pocket more than two hundred yuan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I arrived at her house at 6:30 pm as scheduled, and she sent me her location. It was not far away, only twenty minutes away. It was still early, so I threw my things in the car and wandered along the road. The car is a Chevrolet I bought from my dad for 30,000 yuan a few years ago. I made it clear when I borrowed it that I would pay it back. The car has traveled over 100,000 kilometers and if there is something wrong, it will not affect normal running on the road. I passed by a cigarette shop and bought a pack of soft Chinese. Wang Yu told me not to act too shabby and to dress up. Not to mention that I am among the best, but at least a middle-class elite. I think I might not be an old lady even if I wear a famous brand. If you know her, why not slap the soft Chinese in front of her face, and add that she smokes this every day, and she cannot get used to other things. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A white sprinkler truck played &quot;Orchid Grass&quot; and drove slowly on the road. The water it sprayed was like a curtain. On the side of the road, an old man wearing a torn cotton jacket bent over and turned over a piece of garbage. Bucket, the sprinkler truck honked twice, but the old man didn&#39;t even look at it, so the sprinkler truck sprinkled water all over him with peace of mind. He was so angry that he followed the sprinkler truck for a hundred meters. I passed the traffic light and passed a gas station. On the small radio outside the gas station, a strong female voice kept shouting: Good news, great news. Get up today and stop to refuel. If you spend 200 yuan or more, you will get a box of mineral water for free. Get a fuel treasure for every RMB 500 purchase, first come first served. Good news, extremely good news... I glanced at the oil price, and it increased by 34 cents in 1992. Damn the international situation. Two hundred meters past the gas station is the Technician College. Wang Yu graduated from the Technician College. She even took me to eat at the Xiaobo Hotel at the west gate of the Technician College. She said she loved eating Xiaobo when she was in school. It was called Xiaobo Restaurant at that time. It&#39;s a shabby place, only 20 square meters, with just a few tables. The boss is called Xiaobo, and his specialty dishes are vinegar-soaked pork liver and ants growing on trees. We also ordered these two dishes when we ate at Xiaobo Hotel. The taste had changed. Wang Yu said no, it was not as delicious as before. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I leaned against the outer wall of the Technician College, which was actually a large barbed wire fence. I took apart the cigarettes and lit one. Behind the barbed wire fence was the playground, where a group of people were playing football. Several people in exaggerated costumes walked towards me. Girls, we looked at each other across a barbed wire fence. We looked like animals being watched. A girl wearing bright lipstick, fishnet stockings, and earrings spoke to me: &quot;Brother, please help me. Help me buy a pack of cigarettes, just fifteen dollars. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After saying that, she slipped a twenty-yuan note through the mesh of the barbed wire fence. I didn’t accept it, so she added, “The remaining five dollars will be used as hard-earned money. Brother, please help me.” busy. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I glanced at them and said, &quot;Does your mother know?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She asked in confusion: &amp;ldquo;What do you know? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said: &amp;ldquo;Did you know you smoke? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She withdrew the twenty yuan angrily and said, &amp;ldquo;Are you sick? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said: &amp;ldquo;Yes, high uric acid means either gout or uremia. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They cursed and left angrily. I finished my cigarette and threw the cigarette butt towards the gas station, but was blown back by a gust of wind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At 6:24 in the evening, I met Wang Yu who came to greet me at the main entrance of Guangfu Garden. I hadn’t seen him for a long time. His hair had grown longer and was dyed back. He wore black, and the rest was basically the same as before, except for a camel-colored trench coat. I was carrying milk and honey with a proud look on my face. She rolled her eyes at me and said, &quot;Does this add up to six hundred?&quot; Can&#39;t you buy some high-end goods? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said in a rogue manner: &quot;I would like to bring a Chinese bottle of Moutai to your mother, is that fair?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said: &amp;ldquo;This is worth three hundred and fifty at most, and you owe me two thousand two hundred and fifty. The friendship price is zero for you. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Walking along a small road, there are scattered stalls on both sides of the road in the community, selling couplets, New Year paintings and various New Year goods. Wang Yu said: &amp;ldquo;I said you are doing this. As for cross-border trade, don’t let it slip. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Got it. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Walking into the corridor and climbing the stairs to the third floor, Wang Yu took out the key and opened the anti-theft iron door and the Panpan wooden door one after another. The room was pitch dark. I didn’t see anything. I smelled it first. The smell of braised pork, Wang Yu turned on the light after entering the door, and saw a shriveled woman lying on an old man&#39;s chair, motionless, which startled me. Wang Yu said: &quot;My mother.&quot; &quot;I put the things on the ground and called aunt. Her mother blinked and agreed. I asked Wang Yu in a low voice: &quot;What&#39;s wrong? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Cancer. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What kind of cancer? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Liver, intestines, lungs. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;If you have all five poisons, you are a good guy. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She punched me, walked to her mother, pointed at me and said, &quot;Mom, someone is here.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I walked to her mother, knelt down and called her aunt again. She slowly stretched out a hand, put it on my arm, rubbed it a few times, and used her hand so low that it almost The inaudible voice said to Wang Yu: &quot;I have no appetite. You eat first. I will go back to bed and sleep for a while. I will eat again when I wake up.&quot; After saying that, she stood up tremblingly. Wang Yu helped her into the room. After a while, she came out and closed the door. I said, &quot;You confessed in vain. Your mother didn&#39;t ask anything.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said: &amp;ldquo;I have been busy all afternoon eating. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Braised pork, prawns, scrambled eggs with fungus, mapo tofu, and meatball soup. Wang Yu took out two cans of beer and said, &quot;Would you like some?&quot; &amp;rdquo;I waved my hand and told her that the beer can’t come because the uric acid is high and she should eat as little prawns as possible. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said: &quot;Then I will look for you and see if there is any other wine.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said: &amp;ldquo;Don’t waste any effort. Even if you don’t have it, there is no rule that you have to drink it when I come to your house. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said stubbornly: &amp;ldquo;Don&#39;t worry, sit down, there must be some. My dad has collected several bottles of French red wine for ten years. You are taking advantage today. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I watched her rummaging through the cabinets, finding the study from the kitchen, and finding the bedroom from the study. Finally, she came over with two bottles of red wine. There was a string of unknown characters drawn on the label of the bottle, and below it was written The year is: 2011. She poured half a glass for herself and a glass for me. She didn’t use a goblet, just an ordinary glass wine glass, two by two and five. She touched one before officially starting to eat. She shook the glass in a decent manner and sipped. After taking a small sip, I, Zhu Bajie, drank it all like I was eating ginseng fruit. She scolded: &quot;You idiot, please slow down. Are you using it as a drink?&quot; Do you drink vintage wine like this? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We each drank a bottle and started drinking. Wang Yu took out the cooking wine from the kitchen and each of us poured a glass. I said, &quot;Your mother is like this and she&#39;s not in the hospital.&quot; ? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said: &amp;ldquo;It’s the same in the hospital. She wants to come back and doesn’t want to go through the trouble. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Behind the dining table was a refrigerator, facing my face. I saw a photo posted on the refrigerator, a family of three, with Wang Yu standing in the middle. The man on the left must be Wang Yu’s father. I pointed to the photo and asked, &quot;Is that man your dad?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She looked back and tore off the photo: &amp;ldquo;Say, Ang, it was taken in Ocean Park. I was twelve years old that year and during summer vacation, he said he would take us to the beach. Play. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Yu pressed the photo on the dining table. I took a closer look. Her father was indeed similar to what she described, but he didn’t look like he was 1.72 meters tall. Wang Yu raised his wine glass to signal. I was the one to take a sip, as if I was drinking red wine. After all, the taste of cooking wine was different from French red wine, and it was hard to swallow. She said, &quot;Why is the big boss so bad that he even needs to borrow two thousand yuan?&quot; What&#39;s up? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said: &amp;ldquo;Stop talking sarcastically. Don’t you know what’s going on with me? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said angrily: &amp;ldquo;Yes! Let you write a short essay to scold me! &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was startled, scratched my head in embarrassment, and said, &amp;ldquo;You saw me. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I feel ashamed to say that after I broke up with Wang Yu, I suddenly had a sudden surge of inspiration. I wrote a novel based on her and published it, depicting her as a selfish and short-sighted vulgar person. Not very kind, mainly because I didn’t expect it to be published. I didn&#39;t intend to be so derogatory to her, but when we broke up, she actually said to me, if you write, can you become Balzac if you write again? This is an insult to me. I didn’t think about Balzac. I just wanted to earn some royalties. This is my only source of income. If I’m lucky, I can publish one or two articles a month and earn thousands of dollars. , if you are unlucky, you will have nothing, and you will be hungry and full. Wang Yu once told me that if you can&#39;t do this, you will be useless. You still have to find a stable job. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I was noncommittal, but what I was thinking was that I just couldn’t keep up my job, so I just stayed at home and wrote. I didn’t have to deal with people face to face, and the only communication was to send what I had written. Editor, say: Teacher, this is my new manuscript. The other party will reply with a message of receipt or directly compare their expressions, and give me feedback after a while. If it passes, I will say thank you. If it fails, I will not let go. After quitting my last job, I started writing. I had no choice but to survive. Fortunately, my composition skills were pretty good when I was in school and I could hold back my words. Over the past few years, I published a lot of them one after another, and I was also fired. Quite often, the editor responsible for reviewing my manuscripts often tells me, Mr. Li, our editorial department believes that the quality of your manuscripts is high, but sometimes the content presented is too dark and not suitable for publication. I wonder if you can Are there any changes in the content? I was also noncommittal, and when I submitted the next manuscript, it was still what they called &quot;too dark.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After drinking a third of the cooking wine, Wang Yu said to go and see her mother, took the wine glasses and poured the remaining contents of the two glasses into the sink. She said she couldn’t drink any more. I was asked to take this opportunity to go downstairs and buy two bottles of fruit-flavored Jiangxiaobai. I shook my head and asked, &quot;Are you still drinking?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said: &amp;ldquo;Drink, it’s so easy to drink and feel happy. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I patted my head and said, &amp;ldquo;What if your mother wants to treat me like a drunkard? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;She just likes Jiu Mengzi. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I went downstairs to buy wine and bought four bottles of Jiangxiaobai with four different flavors. When I came back, all the stalls were gone, except for one selling peanuts and melon seeds, which was far away. I smelled the aroma of peanuts, so I bought a bag of peanuts to use with food and drinks. There are a few street lights on, but most of them don&#39;t work. I turn on one after walking for a while, which is quite good at resource planning. I was smoking a cigarette in the stairwell, and at this time I received a message from the editor that the manuscript was finished, and he also said, Teacher Li, I know what you wrote was a big news. I didn&#39;t go back and walked to Wang Yu&#39;s house. The door was closed. Before I opened it, I heard Wang Yu talking inside: &quot;Oh my god, don&#39;t scare me.&quot; &quot;Then there was Wang Yu&#39;s mother&#39;s strange scream, like a wolf at night, which made people&#39;s hair stand on end. I quickly pushed the door open and went in. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Yu’s mother sat upright on the bed, panting rapidly, as if something was stuck in her throat. Wang Yu said over and over again in a hurry: &quot; Mom, don&#39;t scare me, what&#39;s wrong with you? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her mother pushed her away and stared straight ahead. Then she got up from the bed, put on cotton slippers, walked around the room twice, and then walked towards the living room. He was mumbling as he walked, but I didn’t hear it clearly. It was like he was possessed, and it was a bit scary. I walked to the Buddhist niche on the balcony, pulled out a few incense sticks, and didn’t have the energy to press the lighter. He asked me to help, and I suddenly recovered. She was conscious and ran over to light the incense for her. She inserted the incense into the incense burner and bowed a few times. The water was flowing. Wang Yu held her arm and asked with a cry: &quot;Mom, what&#39;s wrong?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She still said in an inaudible voice: &amp;ldquo;Jade, I just had a dream. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was originally a complete sentence, but she was out of breath and couldn&#39;t connect it. She paused for a while and said, &quot;I dreamed about your dad.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We helped her sit on the sofa. She calmed down for a few minutes, gained strength, and said, &quot;Your dad asked us not to look for him again.&quot; Jade, then don’t go looking for him. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Yu said: &quot;Okay, don&#39;t look for him. Mom, stop talking and have a rest.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She waved her hand, coughed twice, and said, &quot;If you don&#39;t tell me, there will be no chance. Yu, your dad is now relieved.&quot; Do you still remember when you were seven years old, I hired a master to practice at home? That&#39;s for your dad to get rid of evil spirits. Your dad is possessed by evil spirits. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While panting, Wang Yu poured a glass of water and patted her back gently. She took the water glass without drinking it, but held it in her hand with a sad expression and continued: &amp;ldquo ; 1999, I remember, on January 28, in the twelfth lunar month, it was snowing lightly that day. Your dad went to Langfang to buy goods. After dinner, he set off. I could tell you what I had eaten that night, chive pancakes and fried dumplings. Your father ate eight chive pancakes and twenty-three dumplings, and both of us were devoured in one meal. I was no longer working at that time, and your dad didn’t know how long he could work, but he could earn enough money for this trip. He said he would come back to eat mutton hot pot and cross the millennium together. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At this point, she stopped and took a sip of water. I stood up and Wang Yu asked, &quot;What are you doing?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said: &amp;ldquo;Go out and smoke a cigarette. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Her mother patted my leg and said, &quot;It&#39;s okay, just smoke here.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said: &amp;ldquo;Not good. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said: &amp;ldquo;I am already like this, why do I still care about having one more cigarette? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I sat down. There was no ashtray at home, so Wang Yu found an empty flowerpot for me and asked me to light the ashes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Your dad came home at night on December 30th. He took a shower when he got home. There was no water heater at that time, so he took half a basin of cold water from the washbasin and mixed it with half a basin of hot water. Several pots, several bottles of boiling water were used up, and then I lay on the bed shivering. I asked him, are you cold? He didn&#39;t reply to me and slept until dawn. He suddenly yelled and sat up from the bed, which scared me awake. I was surprised. When I went to see him, he was covered in sweat, and the cotton sweater on his body was also stained with sweat. Soaked, I said, had a nightmare? Aren&#39;t you so bold? How could you still be scared by dreams? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After I finished smoking the cigarette, I inserted the butt of the cigarette into the flower pot. The air leaked in the room, and it made me get goosebumps. The window must be not closed tightly somewhere, and I was too embarrassed to check around. , I wrapped my clothes a little tighter. Wang Yu glanced at me and said, &quot;Why don&#39;t you open the oil tent.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said: &amp;ldquo;No need. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another sentence: &amp;ldquo;Where is it? &quot;She got up and entered the room. Taking advantage of the opportunity, her mother asked me: &quot;My child, what is your name?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Li Mu. He has the same name as Li Mu, one of the four famous generals of the Warring States Period. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Xiao Li. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Hmm. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;How long have you been with Yu? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said nonsensically: &amp;ldquo;It’s been a few years. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said: &amp;ldquo;They say that if someone in the family is newly mourned, they cannot get married within three years, but I told Yu that our family doesn’t believe this, so you should get married. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After finishing speaking, he took a breath and added: &amp;ldquo;Of course, if your family has this taboo, then follow your family&#39;s rules. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I said: &amp;ldquo;My family doesn’t believe this either. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Yu brought the oil tincture and opened it. After a while, the oil tincture began to heat up, and the tincture silk turned orange-red, which seemed to calm down. Her mother said: &quot;Xiao Zhou&#39;s family doesn&#39;t believe this either. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I corrected: &amp;ldquo;Auntie, Li Mu. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said: &amp;ldquo;Oh, Xiao Li. Where did you just say that? By the way, Yu’s father had a nightmare. After that night, he started to have a high fever, and he didn’t feel better even after taking medicine and water. I didn’t think much about it, but one night, he held my hand and said, I am being raped. Tangled up. I called him nonsense. He said, I&#39;m not going to lie to you, I was really entangled. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My cell phone rang. I took it out and took a look. It was from the editor. He said, Mr. Li, we are holding an essay competition. The editors think your novel is good. , I would like to ask if you are willing to take this novel to participate in our activities. The first prize is 100,000 yuan, the second prize is 50,000 yuan, and the third prize is 10,000 yuan. I&#39;ll go back, okay. There was some confusion in my heart. One hundred thousand yuan was a big number to me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He sent me another long voice message. Maybe he thought typing was a waste of time, or maybe he was afraid that I wouldn’t have the patience to read on. The green voice strip was like a tongue, so I clicked it and put it to my ear. , he said, that’s right, we hope you can make some expansions on the existing space, enhance some storytelling, enhance some dramatic tension, and arouse readers’ empathy, such as the second victim who fell before the New Year. Or, I can write more about her family. I mean her family situation before and after her murder. Through this comparison, a kind of conflict is formed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I listened twice, but there has been no reply. In my mind, I pictured what this family of three was like before my mother was killed: my father was a factory worker, and his usual hobby was drinking some wine. He was not particular about the food that went with the wine, just pickles and tofu, and he only drank one meal a day and no meal at night. Drink more, one or two. In addition, I like to smoke a hard-shell gold leaf that costs ten yuan. I am very popular in the factory. When I am not busy, I get together with the factory friends to fight landlords. There are no worries or accidents. I will work like this until I retire and watch my son perform in the future. My mother is a cash accountant in a tarpaulin factory. She works meticulously. She has been an accountant for twenty years and has never made a single mistake. She just likes to nag her husband, who drinks and smokes. Sooner or later something will happen. Nagging Her son travels too far to go to school, and sometimes he doesn&#39;t have a phone call for weeks. Even if he has a phone call, it costs living expenses. It&#39;s best not to interrupt her when he nags her, otherwise she will get angry. My son was twenty years old at the time. He was in his first year of college at a public undergraduate school in a provincial capital city. He looked pretty decent, studied well, and was pretty good in all aspects. He was a bit introverted. He talked a lot when he got acquainted with him. He was pursuing a girl from the same city. He was a college student. There is a chance that it won&#39;t work. I want to go home during the winter vacation and buy a computer. I plan to play an online game together in the dormitory after the new year. It won&#39;t work without a computer. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mobile loudspeaker in the community began to shout: In order to create a safe, quiet and secure Spring Festival atmosphere, the community once again reminds residents and friends that it is prohibited to set off fireworks in the community during the Spring Festival. Firecrackers, for those who violate the regulations and set off firecrackers privately, we will... &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Being entangled. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I unconsciously lit up another cigarette, and the smoke curled up into the sky. Her mother said, &quot;Your dad has committed a crime, and there is a life on his hands.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I took a breath of smoke and forgot to spit it out. The smoke lingered in my lungs and turned into coughs. Wang Yu stood up suddenly, her mouth moved, but she didn’t say anything. Said: &quot;On the day I came back, in the deserted countryside a few kilometers east of Fairy Bridge, two people blocked the road and robbed. The truck was loaded with iron. They asked your dad to unload the goods. This was their way of making money, and it was also your father&#39;s way of making money. The goods were gone. Now, your dad can&#39;t get a penny. One of them stood by the car door with a hatchet and asked your dad to turn off the engine and get out of the car. The other held a gun and stopped in front of the truck. Your dad rolled down the window and gave it to the car door. People who smoke and say, brother, it&#39;s not easy. The man didn&#39;t pick up the cigarette and said, who would come out to do this in this damn weather? Stop talking nonsense, you are in bad luck.你爸说，货是真不能卸，我家就在南桥，知道你们苦，去我家吃羊肉火锅，好羊肉，不膻，再喝点儿。提刀的那人用刀把撞车门，撞了十来下，你爸吓得腿发软。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;流动喇叭不响了，王玉有些恼火地说：&amp;ldquo;迟早把这破喇叭砸了，大晚上扰民。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关于一家三口的情节，就按这个思路来扩充吧，我脑子有点难受，嗡嗡的，感觉要吐，法国红酒喝多了也醉，我心想按理说酒量不至于这么差，这才哪到哪？又点了一支烟准备压一压酒劲，烟刚点上，被王玉夺过去，说道：&amp;ldquo;你别不自觉，还一支接一支续上了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;什么东西又顶上了我的大脑，不行了，我赶紧冲到厕所，扒着马桶，吐得稀里哗啦，吐完好受多了，就是眼泪止不住往下掉，来来回回擦拭了好几次，眼眶像海绵似的，挤一挤，又湿润了，打开水龙头，冲了把凉水，想安静一会儿，坐在马桶上，从烟盒里敲出一支叼嘴里，又拿下，不一会儿又放回嘴里，来回数次，最后还是没点，楼下一对夫妻在吵架，我推开窗户，声音尽收耳底，女人说，喝，喝死你。男人说，喝不死，我是酒中仙。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;头再次发昏，刚刚止住的眼泪又开始往下流，自己没察觉，察觉到时已在窗台上汇成了一块浅滩。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在马桶上坐了十来分钟，出来时沙发上就剩了王玉一个人，我问：&amp;ldquo;你妈呢？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;回房睡觉去了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;都讲完了？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;讲完了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;后来呢？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;没什么后来，都是瞎扯的，五句话里面两句真三句假，别信她的，糊涂了。还接着喝吗？你酒量不行啊，这才多少，就吐了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你别激我，咱们接着喝。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一人开了一瓶，我喝的葡萄味，她喝的蜜桃味，没用杯子，对瓶口吹，菜凉了，她问要不要热一热，我说不用，买了花生，就着花生喝。说完捧一把花生扔茶几上，就这么边剥边喝，桌上很快集了一堆花生壳。她说：&amp;ldquo;尽快把钱还我，我手头不比你宽裕多少。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我说：&amp;ldquo;放心，我很快就有钱了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她嗤笑道：&amp;ldquo;又要靠着骂我赚钱？你那些破字能卖几个钱啊？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我摇摇头，说：&amp;ldquo;这次不一样，要发大财。 &amp;rdquo;说完伸出两只手，比了个十的手势。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她身子向后一倾，夸张地张嘴，说：&amp;ldquo;吹牛逼吧你就。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我说：&amp;ldquo;不吹。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;把编辑的语音放给她听，她算是信了，从我手里抢过手机，把对话框往上翻，一直翻到我的这篇名叫《出膛的子弹》的小说，我看到她点开了文档，看了一分钟，关掉文档。说道：&amp;ldquo;有你的，把当年轰动全国的案子变成你的小说。 &amp;rdquo;我沉默，她说：&amp;ldquo;我记得第一次作案是2012年一月份吧，第二次作案就是你小说里写的，年前，死的是个妇女，据说是个会计，去银行取钱，还剩两个工人的工资没发，准备第二天带到厂里给工人发工资的，出了自助取款机，被一枪爆了头。 &amp;rdquo;我继续沉默。她说：&amp;ldquo;你打算怎么写这一家三口啊？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我憋出一句话来：&amp;ldquo;不是给工人发工资，是取钱给儿子买电脑，新闻上说得不对。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她疑惑地问：&amp;ldquo;你怎么知道？哦，对对，艺术加工，给儿子买电脑，那就是个味道了，这么处理确实要比给工人发工资要好。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她举着酒瓶又要来碰，我放下一颗还没剥的花生，碰了一个，她说：&amp;ldquo;一共杀了五个是吧，除了第一个，其他受害人都是在取款机取完钱被一枪爆头，第一个开了两枪。小子枪法还挺准，满城被他搞得人心惶惶，我都不敢一个人走夜路，生怕被盯上。准备实施第六次犯罪的时候被逮捕的，警察抛了个饵，引他上钩，抓到的时候已经快夏天了，他还穿一身大棉衣，头上戴一顶雷锋帽，嘴上挂一个医用口罩，口罩一摘，露出真容了，虽说灰头土脸，但能看出来是个小年轻，横竖不过二十二三，真是心狠手辣。枪是自制的双管猎枪，两颗子弹都在，逮捕时倒是老实得很，没有任何拒捕情节，大概也知道怎么抵抗都徒劳了。这是大案，抓到后不久就判了，死刑没跑，死前还有记者进去采访过，问了些问题，为什么要干这事，后不后悔之类的。抓到了都说自己可怜，八岁那年冬天没了爸爸，十岁那年暑假，妈妈也跟人跑了，高中没念完就开始打工，走哪儿都被欺负，你说怎么就逮着他一个人欺负啊？杀人动机也简单，纯粹是为了钱，在工地打工了一年，年底没拿到钱，讨薪时被老板手下人搧了一顿，躲在被子里哭，哭完出去喝酒，喝得大醉，醉了之后胆子就肥了，想起家里有以前自制的打鸟枪，本来两杆，丢了一杆，端着剩下的那杆就出去了，正巧路过银行时看到有人在取款机取钱，他埋伏在银行对面的公厕，等那人取完钱出来，抬手就是一枪，第一枪没打准，打中了胳膊，那人哀嚎一声，仓惶想跑，赶紧补上第二枪。那两枪之后，就什么顾忌也没有了，大杀四方。问他后不后悔，他想了会儿，笑着告诉记者，不后悔，就是觉得对不起那些被他打死的人。采访完没几天，就在电视上播了，分上下两集。按照推算，这人应该也死好多年了，你怎么想到写这事呢？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我不答，她也没有追问，各自安静地喝完瓶中的酒，还剩两瓶没开，王玉说留着下次喝吧，常来常往。从她家出来，没开车，打了辆出租，进了家门之后就冲到电脑边，趁着酒劲飞快地在键盘上敲敲打打，没用一个小时就把故事拓开了，当即给编辑发过去。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第二天下午收到的回复，他说：李老师，我们觉得您对于悲剧发生前的描述非常好，但是悲剧发生之后我们建议可以再丰富一些，短篇小说的情感浓度通常而言要强于长篇小说，而在这篇小说中，对于悲剧后的生活，除了父亲两年后新娶之外，再没有过多笔墨，儿子这个人物在悲剧之后就消失了，这是一个遗憾，他的部分如果描写得好，甚至可以挑起整个故事的大梁。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我回：了解。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他回：不着急，可以慢慢来，毕竟需要增加一条脉络，活动截止时间还早。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最后一次见到王玉是腊月二十八，她说有东西要给我，我们在市中心的肯德基见面，我到的时候她已经点好了两个套餐，春节临近，肯德基人满为患，都是从楼上超市购物完下来吃个便饭的，脚边堆着大大小小的购物袋，每张脸谱都喜庆得如同年画。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;坐下之后，她从衣服里摸出一个红包给我，我不解地看着她，她说：&amp;ldquo;我妈给你的，她说你第一次去我家，按理是要封红包的，上次给忘了，让我无论如何要交到你手上。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我没接，说道：&amp;ldquo;算了，咱俩也不是真的那关系。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;一码归一码，给你就拿着，不然她心里不安。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;情况怎么样？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;走了，腊月十九，这几天刚忙完后事。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我接过红包，揣进口袋里，看了一眼王玉，憔悴了不少，操办后事是一件累人的事，这一点我深有体会，更何况家里就她一个人。她吸了一口奶茶，问我：&amp;ldquo;入围了吗？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我反问：&amp;ldquo;你妈后来说了什么？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;没什么，你问这个干什么？ &amp;rdquo;她说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;不干什么，但是或许能为我提供一个新的故事素材。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你不许写我爸。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我说：&amp;ldquo;每个人都有被记录的必要，我也只会写这些东西。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她思索了一会儿，一个小孩子跑过来，撞翻了我的奶茶，我抽出几张面纸，擦干净桌子，扶起纸杯，她说：&amp;ldquo;在我七岁那年，我爸中邪了，他杀了人。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我能猜到，说：&amp;ldquo;那两个拦路抢劫的吧？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她点了点头，说：&amp;ldquo;没想杀，原本是想找机会跑，趁着两人说话的空当，赶紧发动车子，挂挡，还没踩油门，两个人听到动静回过了神，站在车门边的用刀砍车窗户，站在车前的端起枪预备扣扳机，我爸慌了，以为自己要死在这里，但是第一枪没响，卡了，他低头弄枪，我爸浑身颤抖着踩下油门，闭着眼睛往前冲，车前端枪的抬起头，车头逼近眼前，还没来得及跳开，被一下子撞飞，落地之后抽搐了两下，不动了。另一个吓傻了，站在原地，握着刀把，我爸意识到撞死了人，这时候也忘了害怕，还有一个呢，他赶紧从车上跳下来，跑过去捡起地上的枪，枪口瞄准拿刀的，拿刀的才想起要跑，发了疯一样跑，我爸就跟在后面追，从马路一直追到草丛，下了雪，都看不清路，深一脚浅一脚，后来那人摔倒了，我爸走过去，对准后脑勺开枪，那人求饶还没喊出口，就应声倒地。后来我爸把两人埋了，脸朝下，没敢看，生怕被缠上，但实际上端枪的那个他是记得长什么样的，就站车前面，灯光一直打在他身上。我爸说他梦里就总出现那张脸，不找他索命，就看着他，心理战术，要把他逼疯。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;撞翻我奶茶的小孩再一次跑过来，我下意识护住杯子，一个妇女紧跟着后面，在小孩快要跑出门的时候一把揪住，对着屁股猛烈拍打了几下，小孩哭了。我说：&amp;ldquo;就为这个找的大师。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她点了点头：&amp;ldquo;嗯，年后的事情了，找了个和尚，我爸向来是不信和尚的。和尚坐在他对面，跟他说了会儿话，我爸问和尚，有人骂你怎么办？和尚说，让他。我爸说，让你妈。和尚说，阿弥陀佛。我爸又问，有人打你怎么办？和尚说，忍他。我爸揪着和尚的袍子，啪啪给了他两个大嘴巴，又给他一脚踹翻过去，和尚理理袍子，重新坐下，说，阿弥陀佛。后来和尚指着一间空屋子说，施主，我们移步说话。我爸就跟着他进去了，两人谈了很长时间，出来的时候我爸给和尚作揖，和尚说，善哉，善哉。当天晚上，我爸买了两刀纸，夜里跑到路口去烧，面朝西，磕了几个头，自那以后他就不做噩梦了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我若有所悟地说：&amp;ldquo;这是得到解脱了，断见思惑，证阿罗汉果。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关于往事的叙述，到此为止，生活一切照旧，他爸辞去了开车的工作，干起了个体户，他的情况是没有办法再开车的。再不久，工厂不行了，一同开车的几个司机纷纷下岗，他们都感慨老王有远见。一直到十年前的某一天，老王离奇离家出走，至今未归。出走前毫无异常，吃了一碗稀饭、两个包子，然后坐在沙发上看电视，电视看到一半，突然起身，嘴里念念有词，等王玉去看他时，发现他老泪纵横，王玉问，爸，你怎么了？她爸说，像，太像了。说完夺门而出。王玉不知道他在说什么，也不知道他为什么出门，更没有追上去，她只看到电视里正在播放那个穷凶极恶的杀人犯最后的自白。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我手机上给王玉转去两千六百块钱，王玉听到手机提示，点开对话框，说道：&amp;ldquo;哟，真发财了啊，给我两千就行，跟你开玩笑的。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你就收着吧。 &amp;rdquo;我平静地说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;也行，十万块到手，不在乎这点小钱了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我说：&amp;ldquo;没，我把车卖了，一万五，先把你的还了，剩下的给我爸。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她诧异地说：&amp;ldquo;没成啊？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我讪笑着：&amp;ldquo;知道你困难，要是不够，我可以再借你点儿，随便什么时候还，我爸那头不着急。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说：&amp;ldquo;没什么困难的，我找到新工作了，你留着还你爸吧。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;行吧。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;今年还是一个人过年吗？ &amp;rdquo;她问我。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;嗯。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她平静地一笑，说道：&amp;ldquo;以后我也一个人过年了。我是家里没人了，没办法，你何必呢？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我摸着手指，说：&amp;ldquo;习惯了，不喜欢掺和别人家庭的事，我爸再婚之后每年三十总是打电话让我去他那儿吃顿饭，去过一次，跟他那个新儿子不太合得来，那次借口送我，在楼道口给我发了一支香烟，我戴上皮手套，跟他倚着楼梯扶手，他说，李牧，你是叫李牧吧？我说，是。他说，听老李提起过几次，他虽说不是我亲爸，但对我还算尽心尽力。我说，他就是这样一个人，对身边人都尽心尽力。他说，李牧，你有没有想过一个问题？我从嘴上拿下香烟，问，什么？他说，你究竟算是谁的儿子呢，你想过这个问题吗？我说，懂了。说完扔掉烟头就走了，后来任他再怎么叫我，我都没去过一次。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她说：&amp;ldquo;以前不明白，经过我妈这事我算明白了，什么都是狗屁，家人最重要，说到底还是你爸，该看他还是得看看，还有你妈，我记得你跟我说过知道她在什么地方了，还过得挺不错，抽空也去看看她。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我无语，太阳从浅浅的云层中出来，一道洁白的光落在我们身边咫尺之遥的地方，只要我们一抬手，或者一伸脚，就能沐浴在它之下，我们准备离开，有一对母子正站在我们身边，等待着我们的座位。起身之后，王玉问我：&amp;ldquo;十万块钱的事还有戏吗？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;还没有写完，有一段情节卡住了，不知道怎么连上，不过现在已经知道了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她给了我一个鼓励的眼神，说：&amp;ldquo;加油。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我点了点头，跟她在春节前倒数第二天的午后阳光下分别，回家之后，我打开电脑，在卡住的地方飞快地补上了最后的情节，并且翻出故事的尾巴，重新写下了一行结束语。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记忆是一块冰冷的金属，没有必要焐热它&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;那篇小说的结尾，我如是写道。这一行字几乎抽干了我的灵魂，我重重地躺在椅背上，片刻之后又坐直身子，按着鼠标将全文选定，没有任何犹豫，按下了删除键，然后默默地抽完了一支香烟，轻轻合上电脑。世界突然陷入了前所未有的寂静，在这寂静之中，我已泣不成声。 &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;责任编辑：舟自横&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;征稿信息见@ONE一个工作室置顶微博。更多编辑部的有趣日常请关注小红书：ONE一个编辑部。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FisR8HRhYXEpSR-TsJkbvMqU2n3c&quot; alt=&quot;张紫晨&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;张紫晨 &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;教师家属&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;关注&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;相关推荐&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6027&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;鱼&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 张紫晨&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6092)&quot;>;点击可下载ONE一个app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.3999]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4123]]><description>&lt;div>;18 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fnkh312NtF7bTX_QnS30MvIh9fl2&quot; alt=&quot;首页图&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.3999&lt;/span>;插画| Teddy Kang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;18&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sep. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;我的整个生命，只是一场为了提升社会地位的低俗斗争。&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 18 Sep 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>