<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[散步之年：「松弛感」怎么就成为了奢侈品？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3975]]><description> &lt;div>;14 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Dika Asks&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>;　How did “relaxation” become a luxury product? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Rabbit grass answer&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpGwu7QFMH-4-ak8IC9dU5iMiScb&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpGwu7QFMH-4-ak8IC9dU5iMiScb&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;I forgot when the word &quot;relaxation&quot; became popular, but I felt that for a while, this word was everywhere. When it comes to taking pictures, don’t be pretentious, pretend not to look at the camera and present a relaxed atmosphere; when it comes to doing things, don’t care too much about the results, be calm and enjoy the process... Relaxation &quot;Feeling&quot; is easy to say but too difficult to do, especially for us East Asians. Hard work has long been a gene passed down from generation to generation. We have to live on a clockwork every day for fear that we are not working hard enough and will fall behind others. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A few years ago, I wrote a novel. In the novel, there was a young man whose back was loaded with springs and was overwhelmed. He often went to the other side of the river to deliver meals to his grandma. One day, he told his grandmother about his troubles. Grandma said that it was okay, it was just the &quot;clockwork monster&quot; causing trouble. Then, grandma opened the boy&#39;s back, helped the boy take out a few springs, and then Put more spring in it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past, I did not believe that people could relax, nor did I believe that &quot;people could not go to work.&quot; However, after being unemployed for a year, I found that everything was a trap, and I had set a trap for myself. Hom. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Relaxation&quot; has become a luxury product in modern society for two reasons: &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Feeling Collective unconscious control, feeling guilty about relaxation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I was a child, the most common words I heard from my parents were &quot;play, play, play. You know how to play all day long, and you can&#39;t learn from others.&quot; Try harder? &amp;rdquo;After hearing this kind of words too much, we naturally put relaxation and hard work in opposition. We will feel that relaxation is shameful, but learning and improving, and constantly pushing ourselves are the right things. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Lack of security and feel that &quot;relaxation&quot; is something only people with good family backgrounds can possess&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Recently There was another saying that was particularly popular last year, called &quot;Life is a wilderness, not a track.&quot; This sentence itself has a very good meaning. It means that people do not have only one way to live. You can explore and live out your life while you are young. Own. But if you think about it carefully, how can those young people with no background and no support from their parents get the opportunity to try and make mistakes? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So many young people from ordinary families will say that those who can &quot;enjoy life first&quot; are those children whose parents have paved the way. We are still poor and have to work hard on our own. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A few years ago, I was convinced that &quot;I can&#39;t relax&quot;. I felt that I was not qualified to relax, and I was very anxious every day. There are a lot of things to worry about, such as whether some company will lay off employees, whether there will be no job opportunities at the age of thirty-five, and what to do if I can&#39;t make money, etc. As expected, I waited for layoffs and a cruel &quot;social trial,&quot; but I survived in the end. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At that moment, I suddenly understood, &lt;strong>;There is nothing that must be done in life. &lt;/strong>;Even if the worst outcome occurs, as long as you are healthy and your family is safe, there is no obstacle that you cannot overcome. &lt;strong>;&quot;Relaxation&quot; does not come from anything given by the outside world, it comes from yourself. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition, &quot;relaxation&quot; is not a posture, but a state of mind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the past year, I have fallen in love with walking. When I feel out of breath, I will go for a walk in nature. &lt;strong>;The grace of the trees and sunshine, the color of the bird’s tail, and the gentle look of the lake are actually all free. &lt;/strong>;It doesn’t mean that you have to go on a trip or sit in a cafe for a day to get a sense of &quot;relaxation.&quot; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Relaxation&quot; is not a luxury, it depends on how you get along with the outside world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When there is no way to make more money, I choose to spend less and look inward. Reading, walking, going to the park, and participating in free activities are actually ways to make yourself happy physically and mentally. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Be able to recognize the nature of anxiety, which may be caused by perfectionism. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I was anxious, I had a low opinion of myself, and there was a voice that often lingered in my mind - &quot;I&#39;m going to be finished, I&#39;m definitely going to be finished.&quot; &amp;rdquo;But in fact, this is just a negative psychological suggestion. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Instead of being trapped in anxiety, it is better to take action. This action does not mean doing things that seem particularly worth doing. &lt;strong>;Sometimes being in a daze is also a right. Being in a daze and letting go should not be harshly criticized. No time will be wasted, as long as you seriously feel the flow of life. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We don’t need to pretend to be relaxed, we need to feel relaxed from the inside out. This is not only to show a better self, but also because life itself is a matter of work and rest. A combination of things. So, when you feel out of breath, go out for a walk.&lt;strong>;Perhaps in this small purposeless &quot;exploration&quot;, you will discover the essence of life and some more beautiful things. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Zhou Ziheng onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see @ONE Studio’s pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmIxumvucSMThvBqzjla4dEmFbwL &quot; alt=&quot;Rabbit Grass&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Rabbit Grass&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@Rabbit Grass Tucao&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style =&quot;&quot;>;Retired copywriter, juggling writer. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Question and Answer&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/question/3959&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;How to &quot;lie flat&quot; correctly? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3976&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;As an adult, what other childish behaviors do you have? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3975)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[清醒梦]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6162]]><description> &lt;div>;14 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Li Tang&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fixaw9LZQki_lwxCM1jKPFaS-0pw&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fixaw9LZQki_lwxCM1jKPFaS-0pw&quot; >;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Many &quot;spontaneous human combustion&quot; incidents have occurred recently, and It has nothing to do with suspenseful murders, and relevant experts can&#39;t give a scientific explanation, but all of this is actually related to dreams. Li He delved deeply into the mysterious phenomenon of waking up and entering dreams, and his pursuit finally led him to the end of reality. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That day, on the third day of his new job, a colleague named Wang suddenly came over during his lunch break and said to him mysteriously: : &quot;Have you also followed &quot;Utopia Agent&quot;?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Team Leader Wang looks to be in his forties, with a square face and fine wrinkles at the corners of his eyes, nose, and mouth. But the wrinkles are not annoying--when they gather together as if alive and form a certain pattern, they seem to make the face look more friendly. Even when he is not smiling, this face looks like he is smiling, but when he does smile, there is an overall feeling of smoothness, which is obviously staged. Too much is not enough - Li He thought of this word. His parents always taught him not to get too close to his colleagues in the workplace, especially before he got to know each other well. Li He sneered on the surface, because his parents had never changed jobs for most of their lives, and they faced the same people waiting for retirement year after year. How much workplace experience could they have? But deep down, he knew that he agreed with this statement. Therefore, he just said &quot;hmm&quot; in a low voice without any unnecessary reaction. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Utopia Agent&quot; is a secretive public account. The subscription base should not be too large. Each article or video has no more than a thousand clicks. Li He&#39;s attention was purely out of curiosity. A month ago, Teacher Sun, the head teacher of the university with whom he had a good relationship, asked him for a drink, and he paid attention to it in a daze. Until now, he still hasn&#39;t figured out what this official account is for. The person in the video is wearing a plush horse head hood from &quot;BoJack Horseman&quot; and a black coat. The voice has been processed by cartoons, making it indistinguishable from male to female. &quot;Ma Nan&quot; doesn&#39;t move much. He sits in front of the camera and talks about how to have &quot;lucid dreams&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What’s so interesting about this? In other words, what&#39;s the point? Each video can be as short as five minutes or as long as half an hour, and Li He closes it in less than a minute each time he clicks on it. It&#39;s really not interesting. He didn&#39;t understand why Teacher Sun recommended this official account to him, but when he drank too much, Teacher Sun would indeed behave in some childish ways, like a college student. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Compared with the inexplicable public account, Li He was more concerned about how Team Leader Wang knew about it. He felt uncomfortable with his secret being spied on. He decided to ask directly: &quot;How do you know?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The answer is not mysterious at all: after Team Leader Wang added his WeChat account, he accidentally discovered that the &quot;1 friend is following&quot; prompt appeared on the official account, and he guessed it. In the whole company, they were the only ones paying attention. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li He is not a sociable person. He basically won&#39;t have any conflicts with his colleagues, but it&#39;s hard for him to get too close. In his previous two jobs, he found that some of his colleagues had really good relationships with each other and often had dinner or drinks together after get off work. Of course, they never called Li He. He always kept to himself, even at lunchtime. He would occasionally envy the friendship between his colleagues, but he would never take the initiative to fight for it. The right distance is the most comfortable. Although, sometimes he feels trapped by his parents&#39; &quot;motto&quot;. Like a curse. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Would you like to have dinner together? &quot;Team Leader Wang said. He took Li He to a Western restaurant near the company. The steak set meal was surprisingly cheap and large. During the meal, he was a little restless and felt that it was awkward for two people to face each other without talking about anything. Just when he was racking his brains to think of a topic, he found that Team Leader Wang was just eating and scrolling on his phone. He was relieved. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That night, they made an appointment to meet at the same place. A remote bar near College Road. This street is dotted with many bars, and most of them are students. If a bar is filled with young men and women, it&#39;s a luxury to expect it to be quiet. In such a bar, extremely loud dance music is often played to add fuel to the flames, even if the space is so cramped that there is no dance floor at all. Young people drank loudly, smoked, chatted and played board games. Li He clearly remembered that the first time he went back to the bar, he was led by Teacher Sun, along with two or three classmates. Previously, in his education, bars were places where only the undistinguished people went, but now that he had just entered college, he was about to break this taboo, and it was his college class teacher who encouraged him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;The head teacher of a university is not a high school teacher. I hope to have a teacher-friend relationship with everyone. &amp;rdquo;This is the opening statement of Teacher Sun’s first class meeting. He was promoted to associate professor at a young age, and he looked not much older than the student. He is indeed very close to them and is recognized by everyone as a good teacher. However, Li He forgot how the two truly became friends - not the friendship between teacher and student, but the sympathy between friends. Maybe it&#39;s their shared hobbies (like the same books and anime), or maybe they have similar personalities. Both of them are people who are not very able to open their hearts to others. The difference is that Teacher Sun hides it very well, making the students who come into contact with him mistakenly think that they will have no reservations about themselves. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I don’t know when, Teacher Sun started to ask Li He to sit in the bar alone every once in a while, or simply have a casual meal and chat. They talked about very ordinary things, interesting little things or difficulties, or some of their own weird thoughts. Li He didn&#39;t think he could be completely honest, but when chatting with Teacher Sun, he was very relaxed and didn&#39;t have to think too much. He could even say something without thinking about it without worrying about making the other person unhappy. What moved him even more was that Teacher Sun did not just listen, but also told a lot about himself. So he knew that Teacher Sun had been married a long time ago and had just given birth to a daughter. They had met on a train. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li He often sees confession scenes in foreign movies. A man stood in the small confessional, talking endlessly to the priest behind the wooden window. He always felt that the pastor was very pitiful and had to accept so many emotional vents that had nothing to do with him. But if he had to choose, he would rather choose the role of a priest. But the ideal situation is: both parties can be both priests and penitents. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He felt Teacher Sun’s trust. Because he found that Teacher Sun would show a rare fatigue in front of him. Sometimes he would show more frustration than Li He, talking about the quarrels with his wife, his daughter&#39;s illness, and the discord with the department leaders... At this time, Li He consciously assumed the role of pastor without any uneasiness. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After graduation, their get-togethers continued, but the frequency inevitably decreased. Over the past few years, their gathering place has been fixed at the &quot;Old Story&quot; bar. They all like the name. The location here is remote, and few students from nearby come here. The background music is mostly quiet jazz, and the low-key wallpaper is almost inaudible. The guests seemed to be influenced by the music and never made any noise. Of course, its customers are sparse, and many times they are the only customers at the table. Li He worried that it would collapse one day. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Exactly that day, the same place, the same people. Teacher Sun talked about the dream that had troubled him for a long time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This thing is very weird. Although the deceased was burned to death, the surrounding objects - including sheets, pillows, wooden bedside tables, etc. - did not burn. Except for the place where he lay, the only damage was to the wall, which was baked a little yellow. The plastic phone case placed on the bedside table melted due to the high temperature, but the phone was not damaged. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is not the first case. A week ago, a similar situation happened in another community. What was even more shocking was that the deceased&#39;s wife was sleeping next to him. In the middle of the night, she was awakened by shouts and found that her husband&#39;s body was covered with blue flames, and his limbs were fluttering like a drowning man. In panic, she beat the flames with quilts and pillows, but it didn&#39;t help. When she got up and ran to the bathroom to fill the basin with water, and then ran back to the bedroom, her husband had turned into ashes. The flame gradually extinguished itself, and the whole process took less than half a minute. There was no fire elsewhere in the house. After police investigation, the possibility of homicide or suicide was ruled out and it was determined to be an &quot;accident.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This matter immediately became a hot topic, and many TV stations launched special programs. Li He watched one of the issues with his father. Two experts and a moderator discussed the phenomenon of &quot;spontaneous human combustion&quot; for half an hour. Spontaneous human combustion was first seen in medical reports in the 17th century. An Italian man named Belician was lying on a straw mat and almost all of it was reduced to ashes. Only his skull and a few finger bones were left. But surprisingly, the straw mat had nothing but the place where he lay. Except for being burned, everything else remained intact. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In this regard, experts have given explanations such as ball lightning, static electricity, candle wick effect, and excessive sodium. They have also made speculations from the perspective of the material of the clothes, the temperature, and whether the person involved drinks or smokes. However, at the end of the program, the host quoted investigations from more professional research institutions, indicating that there are still many unsolved problems about the phenomenon of spontaneous human combustion to this day, and many people also regard it as a supernatural phenomenon. The specific situation requires further research. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;How terrible. &quot;The father suddenly said, &quot;No one knows what will happen in the next second...&quot; Li He looked at his father. He realized that he hadn&#39;t chatted with his father for a long time, but the man in front of him had become bloated and weak, and could be called an &quot;old man&quot;. He still spoke as before, and his eyes were used to staring at another place. At this time, he stared at the screen as if talking to the people in the advertisement. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At this time, my mother&#39;s voice came from the kitchen: &quot;The pot is full of oil and has not been cleaned at all.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My father pretended not to hear, but the annoyance on his face clearly betrayed him. His left hand kept scratching a small piece of skin on the back of his right hand until it was dry and white. Li He noticed that the skin on his father&#39;s hands was as rough as that of an elderly person. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Be sure to turn off the power before going to bed. &quot;My father told me, &quot;Also, don&#39;t charge your cell phone overnight. This is how some fires are caused. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I know. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You don’t know. &quot;My father sighed, &quot;Only when you reach my age will you know that life is not easy. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He understands his father. Within a year, my father attended two funerals, one of a former colleague and the other of his father&#39;s cousin, both of whom were much younger than his father. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While speaking, the movement of my father&#39;s left hand stopped, and the skin returned to its original color. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Is there anything in particular you desire? ” Li He asked. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What? &quot;My father turned his face away and started scratching anxiously with his left hand again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li He said nothing more. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Remember what I said. &quot;My father stood up, walked into the kitchen, and washed the unclean pot again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The day before--he and Team Leader Wang had known each other for more than two months before they finally accidentally chatted about the official account again. It seemed that both of them had forgotten the source of the initial conversation. By then, they had become regular meal partners and had lunch together almost every day. Still, Team Leader Wang was scrolling through his cell phone, while Li He was busy eating, and only occasionally chatted when work was involved. But that day was an exception. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;That public account...&amp;rdquo; Team Leader Wang said, &amp;ldquo;It has been blocked. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li He looked up and saw Team Leader Wang still staring at the phone screen. If there were other people around, he must have thought he was talking to someone else. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He put down his chopsticks and took out his mobile phone. Indeed, the page of &quot;Utopia Agent&quot; is completely blank. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What&#39;s going on? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I don’t know. But he opened a new account. &quot;Team Leader Wang suddenly turned his phone over and asked Li He to look at his phone screen. From the cracked screen, Li He struggled to identify the page of &quot;Dream Agent 2&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Why not change the mobile phone screen? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Get used to it. Team leader Wang smiled and said, &quot;It&#39;s hard to adapt to the change.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li He looked at his cell phone. It was time to go to work, but the other party had no intention of leaving. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;How did you follow this account? ” asked Team Leader Wang. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;He is a teacher in my university. ” Li He said. Teacher Sun&#39;s lonely eyes that night appeared before his eyes again, like an abandoned dog. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Team Leader Wang did not continue to ask. &amp;ldquo;You don’t watch it often, do you? &quot;He leaned back and leaned on the back of the sofa chair in the restaurant. When Li He nodded, he added, &quot;Then you haven&#39;t had a lucid dream either? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I don’t dream. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Team Leader Wang looked at the water glass in ecstasy. Li He&#39;s demeanor is rare in his daily work. Everyone knows that Team Leader Wang works quickly and decisively and never talks nonsense. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Is there anything you particularly long for? &quot;Team Leader Wang suddenly said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What? &amp;rdquo;Li He didn&#39;t quite understand the other party&#39;s intention. This question made him a little nervous for no reason. Therefore, he did not deny or answer, but quietly waited for the other party&#39;s next words. He knew that people who asked questions often did so because they had something to say. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;In the beginning I just did it for fun. &quot;Team leader Wang said, &quot;Lucid dreaming means that you know that you are dreaming and you know that you will not wake up in the future. Ever since I learned how to dream, I have been able to dream clearly every night. It&#39;s amazing, really. Have you seen &quot;Inception&quot;? It’s not that exaggerated, but it’s completely different in person. How do you say it...&quot; He made a gesture he often made during meetings, &quot;It&#39;s easy to become addicted. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li He listened quietly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Later, I often dreamed of a dark place. I didn&#39;t know if I was walking or flying because there was no reference, just darkness. But I know I&#39;m moving forward. I could choose to wake up at any time, but I wanted to see what was at the end of the darkness. Many times I woke up just too tired. &quot;Team Leader Wang picked up the water glass and took a sip of water. After putting it down, his finger marks were stained on the clean glass wall. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Later, I seemed to have finally reached the end. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was a dazzling light, like the sun at the end of a tunnel. The heavy darkness was swept away in an instant. The light gets brighter and brighter, and you know you&#39;re getting closer to it. You feel more excited than you have ever felt before. However, at the same time, a hot air current enveloped you. You feel like your body is losing moisture rapidly, your clothes are getting hot, and your skin is burning. In the dream, you still clearly feel the heat of reality. You know that if you go any further, you will turn into ashes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;So I gave up every time. But I really wanted to see what was in that light. &quot;Team Leader Wang picked up the water glass again and found that the water was gone. He straightened the collar of his neck, then stood up and said to Li He, &quot;It&#39;s almost time. Let&#39;s go back.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The dream was not complicated: he always dreamed of the same girl over and over again. When he was not married yet, he was no longer particularly young and was approaching the age of a mature man. He met a girl when he was studying for his Ph.D., and the two quickly established a relationship and traveled abroad together. On the plane on the way back home, he accidentally turned his head and found that she was crying. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What’s wrong? &amp;rdquo;he asked. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Nothing. The girl said, &quot;I&#39;m just so happy.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That’s it. The dream ends here, just like the memory afterward. He had forgotten what happened next. He only remembered that they broke up less than two months after that. He never saw her again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I don’t know why, I always dream about this scene. &amp;rdquo;He said to Li He. After two glasses of whiskey, his face was rosy, his eyes were shining, and he seemed to be several years younger. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Do you love her? ” Li He asked. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I don’t know. &quot;Teacher Sun shook his head and then smiled, &quot;I don&#39;t know, maybe I just don&#39;t love you.&quot; But what I really thought at that time was that she and I would not have a future. We are very different. She likes strange, exciting and dangerous things. I can&#39;t, I want a stable future. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Just like this. ” Li He said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Yes. &quot;Teacher Sun finished his second glass of wine and fell into deep thought, &quot;If it were her, she might let herself get drunk. And I have to think about the consequences of getting drunk. Even though I really wanted to, my rationality told me that I couldn’t have a third cup. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Rationality. &amp;rdquo;Li He repeated. Tonight, he is the pastor. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Let’s sit for a while. &quot;Teacher Sun said, &quot;It&#39;s still early. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Old Story&amp;rdquo;The bar is still sparsely visited, and the waiter is idly leaning against the bar playing with his mobile phone. The wine rack behind the bar is filled with different types of beer and whiskey. The dim lights shine on these glass products, shining beautifully. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;This is the official account, I recommend it to you. &quot;Teacher Sun quickly tapped his phone a few times, and Li He received a notification from a public account called &quot;Dream Agent.&quot; He opened it casually and looked at the man wearing the horseman mask, wondering why. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;So back in the dream, what did you do? ” Li He asked curiously. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Nothing was done. &quot;Teacher Sun put down his cell phone, tilted his head back, and looked at the plastic human skeleton hanging above Li He&#39;s head as a decoration. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;In the dream, I saw her again. The same position, the same light, she stared at the front seat and shed tears. In the same conversation, I asked her &quot;What&#39;s wrong?&quot; and she answered me, &quot;I&#39;m just too happy.&quot; Then, I hugged her and said in her ear, &quot;I really, really like you.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You learned to have lucid dreams just to say this? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Maybe. &quot;Teacher Sun still waved and ordered a third glass of wine, but it wasn&#39;t that strong. After the sleepy waiter walked away, he said: &quot;Maybe this is a kind of compensation.&quot; Because I used to really like her, but she was very doubtful about it at the time. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So, he repeated this sentence over and over again in his dream. Li He thought to himself. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before leaving, they stood at the door of the bar smoking. Teacher Sun told Li He that he was going to have an academic exchange abroad and it might take him a year and a half. &quot;Let&#39;s have dinner at home before leaving.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li He has been to Teacher Sun’s home several times. My mistress is always hospitable. After finishing her work in the kitchen, she goes to cut fruits. The toddler sat alone in a corner of the house, bathed in sunshine. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The express train called by Teacher Sun came first. He threw away the cigarette butt, waved to Li He in the dark, and got into the car. Li He watched the car disappear at the intersection, and then walked in the other direction. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The swimming pool door is locked and the lights are turned off. His father asked Li He to wait in front of the steps for a while and talk to someone on his mobile phone. &quot;Lao Zhang, it&#39;s me, yes...&quot; He heard his father say, &quot;We&#39;re at the door...Okay, don&#39;t worry, there&#39;s my son...&quot; &lt;p>;Li He stood on the top step and looked at the dim lights of the University Square. Almost all nearby residents were out for a walk, and there were many children. He imagined his parents walking side by side, with his mother taking out her cell phone from time to time to take pictures of the wild flowers on the roadside or the bright moon. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My father finished the phone call and walked up the steps. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is some noise. They both turned around and saw the door of the swimming pool half opened, and a man was greeting them quietly. The restaurant smelled of disinfectant. The lights were turned off, and the faint blue light reflected from the windows floated on the calm water. The water looked turbid and heavy, like oil. Three men were soaking in it, not swimming, as if they were in a hot spring; there were four or five people lying on lounge chairs around the pool. Someone saw them and greeted Li He&#39;s father. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Shh&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;&amp;rdquo;The pool manager promptly reminded, &quot;Keep your voice down.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li He recalled that on the evening news, the handsome male host reported on the five recent cases of &quot;spontaneous human combustion&quot;. Two of them occurred in this city, and the other three occurred in other cities. Like the previous ones, they all occurred while sleeping. Two experts invited in the studio put forward their own speculations - rising global temperatures, urban heat island effect, increased ultraviolet intensity and clothing materials have all become the focus of discussion. However, they obviously lacked confidence and kept repeating that &quot;all this is just speculation without any reliable basis.&quot; In other words, the reason remains a mystery. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Serial spontaneous combustion incidents have caused some panic and doubts. But what really adds fuel to the flames are various self-media platforms and online writers. A large number of articles about the authenticity of spontaneous human combustion have been widely circulated in people&#39;s circles of friends. Most of them are alarmist, but they have received millions of views. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There was only one recliner left, and his father looked at Li He with some embarrassment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;It&#39;s okay,&quot; Li He said, &quot;I&#39;ll go back in a while.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Go back? The father sneered, &quot;No one knows what will happen in the next second.&quot; At least it&#39;s safer here. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to what my father (and others here) think, even if spontaneous combustion does occur, you can jump into the water as soon as possible. Therefore, the swimming pool is the safest place to spend the night. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li He looked at the people soaking in the swimming pool and lying around the swimming pool. Their bodies were covered in a layer of shadow. The moonlight shines in from the window of the swimming pool, and the shimmering and fragmented reflections of the water surface are reflected on the blue wall. He felt that the scene before him was both absurd and extremely real. It was like the first time he heard his father shout &quot;I hate you&quot; to his mother, when he just entered middle school and they were quarreling when he came home. Later, they quarreled more and more often, and said &quot;I hate you&quot; to each other many times, but compared to the first time, their impressions were blurred. Li He once thought that his parents would divorce. Eventually, they both grew old and lost the energy to argue. They have always lived together. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My mother is staying at home alone and should have gone to bed early. She didn&#39;t believe that such a small chance of bad luck would happen to her. At the same time, she did not believe that she would have any good luck. She felt that she was the most ordinary kind of person, living her life quietly without any big storms. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li He said nothing more, turned around and walked towards the entrance of the swimming pool, deciding not to stay in this scene too much. Before walking out of the door, he turned around once and saw his father lying on the couch, motionless, as if he was asleep. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the company, gossip always spreads like wildfire. At first, people thought it was a rumor, but there was some vagueness and uncertainty about its authenticity. The strange thing is that such news will eventually be confirmed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the morning meeting, Team Leader Wang announced his decision in public. According to the version circulated, something went terribly wrong with a project at the company and he had to leave, even though he was clearly taking the blame for someone else. At the meeting, he thanked everyone for their support and understanding over the years, and hoped that his departure would not delay the advancement of other projects. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then, he returned to his work station to pack his things. There wasn&#39;t much that needed to be taken away. Just like the fired employees in the TV series, he also found a few folded cardboard boxes and stuffed all the documents, water glasses, books, chargers and other sundries on the table into them. There is also a photo of him with his son who is in elementary school, but no one has seen the mother of the child. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He called the courier to come to his door and help deliver it away. Others were still busy beside him, and their voices dropped as they passed. Then, he ran to the office several times to complete some procedures. After everything was finished, it was already noon. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This time, it was Li He who took the initiative to walk over and asked, &quot;Would you like to eat?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I have no appetite. &quot;Team Leader Wang said apologetically, &quot;How about having a cup of coffee together? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I happen to be not hungry either. ” Li He said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They came to the coffee shop downstairs of the company. Even though it was a weekday, it was still packed with people. There was no place to sit, so they stood in the corridor holding paper cups, like people taking shelter from the rain, while the sun was shining brightly outside. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I have worked here for fifteen years. Team leader Wang said, &quot;Now I can finally catch up on my sleep.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Want to see what’s inside the light? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Team Leader Wang was stunned for a moment and then came to his senses. &quot;No matter what, I hope I won&#39;t have any dreams.&quot; Lucid dreaming, especially, is very tiring. &quot;He waved his hand and showed his usual smile, &quot;So I envy you very much. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What are you envious of? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;You said you never dream. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li He turned the coffee cup in his hand twice - a thick paper circle was added to the hand to avoid burning his hands. He removed the paper circle and held the paper cup directly with his hand. The coffee has become lukewarm. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I did. &amp;rdquo;He said. This time, he was the penitent. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That was a dream that he thought was a bit funny. There was a time when he often dreamed of flying towards the sun. Below is a sea that is reflected in blood, as if it is about to be ignited by the sun. He felt himself getting further and further away from the sea and getting closer to the sun. The light penetrated his body like a sharp sword. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What then? ” asked Team Leader Wang. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He was suddenly able to see his whole body.他看到光线真的刺穿了皮肤，脸上、脖子、胳膊&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;裸露的皮肤裂开了缝隙，仿佛就要脱落。每到这时，他就吓醒了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王组长点点头。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;这跟我的隧道梦似乎是一体两面。我想要看清光亮里面是什么，而你想看清自己里面是什么。所以我们都是蛾子。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;蛾子？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;蛾子往电灯上扑。它们可能也想搞清楚电灯到底是什么东西。 &amp;rdquo;王组长喝完最后一口咖啡，随手扔进旁边的铁质垃圾桶里，&amp;ldquo;知道为什么吗？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李鹤默然等待答案揭晓。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;因为它们不理解。 &amp;rdquo;王组长笑起来。这是他第一次看到他真正的笑，而不是往常那种为展示亲切的微笑。他为这句废话差点笑出眼泪。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李鹤每天下班后，独自去吃饭，都是家门口固定的几个餐馆。有时他也会自己做点简单的晚饭，但因为隔壁室友每天都要做饭，所以他尽量不去厨房。他也几乎不待在客厅。他基本上都待在自己的房间里，看看书，玩玩手机，然后睡觉。他喜欢这种私密的氛围。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大学毕业后，他发现自己再也无法跟其他人共享居住空间了。或者说，他意识到必须有一间只属于自己、他人不能染指的地方，这近乎于本能的渴望。于是，他租了一间房，价格他还承受得起。面积不大，只要有这么一个房间就够了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他从不轻易走进别人的房间，也不邀请别人进来。即使是父母，即使是孙老师，他也没有告诉过他们地址，好像这是理所应当的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大概在孙老师出国一个半月时，李鹤接到了孙老师的视频通话。他看着手机屏幕上闪烁着孙老师的头像，犹豫了十几秒才接。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我以为你已经睡了。 &amp;rdquo;孙老师理了发，脸在屏幕里显得有些臃肿。身后是一片白墙。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;还没，看了看新闻。 &amp;rdquo;李鹤说。他也看到了自己的脸，于是挪得远了些。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;什么新闻？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;人体自燃。 &amp;rdquo;李鹤说。最近又接连出现了人体自燃事件，一时间在网上搞得人心惶惶。虽然至今加在一起不过十几个，但由于没有确凿原因，像是没有侦破的连环杀人案，每个人都有可能是下一个，几率平等。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你能听到吗？ &amp;rdquo;孙老师忽然说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;听到什么？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;孙老师面露微笑。随着屏幕摇晃，他站起身，朝阳台走去。李鹤这才认出孙老师应该是大学的教师公寓内。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阳台门打开了。孙老师调转了镜头&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;下面，距离公寓不远的地方，一片蔚蓝色的大海像巨大的丝绸铺展开来，波光粼粼。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;这地方很美。 &amp;rdquo;镜头外响起孙老师的声音。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;确实很美。 &amp;rdquo;李鹤说。他仔细看着缓慢浮动的海浪，上面白帆点点，还有云朵的投影。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;你有没有想过，你曾经有机会能过另一种生活。 &amp;rdquo;孙老师的声音说。镜头一直面对着大海，凝固不动。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;比如说，我可以去一个比这里还美的地方定居。只要我辞掉现在的工作，还有&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;抛弃家庭。 &amp;rdquo;李鹤接着说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那声音沉默了。真的有海浪声传过来，隐隐约约。还有汽车的喇叭声。异国的广告牌矗立在阳光下。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我最近又做了梦。 &amp;rdquo;孙老师的声音又盖过了一切声响。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;还是那个梦吗？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;是的，&amp;rdquo;孙老师说，&amp;ldquo;但有点不同&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;还是在那个飞机上，所有人都消失了。只有我和她。我们做爱了。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;再次沉默的间隙，李鹤看到屏幕里有一只鸟落在了阳台的栏杆上，探头探脑。孙老师伸出手，掌心里有两粒花生米。鸟飞走了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;李鹤，&amp;rdquo;孙老师的声音再一次传来，&amp;ldquo;说真的，我有点害怕。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李鹤知道，此刻自己应该像往常一样，像一个尽责的牧师那样，问忏悔者&amp;ldquo;害怕什么&amp;rdquo;。但他什么也没说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过了一会儿，孙老师的镜头重新转了过来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我可以看看你的房间吗？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我的房间？ &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;我好像还从没见过你住的地方。 &amp;rdquo;孙老师有些犹豫，&amp;ldquo;这个请求确实有点奇怪，但我就是想看看，一眼就好。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李鹤默默地将镜头调转。他下了床，举着手机，慢慢地原地转了一圈。这时网络中断了，视频界面自动退出。他松了口气，坐在床沿，觉得一切都很滑稽。后来直到他睡着，孙老师再也没发信息。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王组长离职后，他们没有联系过。偶尔，李鹤会看到他发的朋友圈，都是一些老家的景色。他似乎迷恋上了摄影，照片水准日益精进。直到有一天，他发现王组长的朋友圈变成了一道冷冰冰的直线。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就像是之前的同事一样，大家一旦不在一起工作，无论关系再好，最后还是会淡下来，重归陌路。李鹤又恢复成了自己一个人吃午饭，有时懒得下楼，就叫外卖。天气冷下来了，李鹤每次穿过公司大楼前的马路时，都会下意识地裹紧衣领。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新闻里依然隔三差五有人体自燃发生，但人们的关注度明显降低了。更新鲜，更迅猛的消息无时无刻不在冲击着这个世界。与此相对的，&amp;ldquo;空想代理人&amp;rdquo;屡屡被封，现在已经进化到了&amp;ldquo;空想代理人07&amp;rdquo;。李鹤不知道原因，因为他根本从未打开过。每回都是孙老师将新的公众号推送给他，然后便静静地躺在他的关注列表里。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;又是一个夜晚。睡觉前，李鹤打开了那个公众号。依旧是套着马男面具的人，依旧是经过处理的声音，在视频里讲解清醒梦的技巧。他随手打开一个视频，那是马男在镜头前回答后台读者的留言。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;问：每次入梦，我总是很紧张，没等有什么进展就醒了。请问该怎么办？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马男一本正经地将手肘支在桌面上，竖起食指。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;首先，做清醒梦最重要的一点&amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;那个经过处理的声音说，&amp;ldquo;不要恐惧。 &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他一口气看完了所有视频，然后睡觉。他不习惯黑漆漆的房间，所以每晚都将床头灯调至最暗的模式，开着灯睡。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他再一次翱翔在熟悉又陌生的海面上，可以看到自己投下的倒影。太阳炽烈又美丽，射出万道光芒，燃烧着天际。他不由自主地离太阳愈加接近，海面的倒影则愈加渺小。他又感觉到了皮肤的刺痛，像是细小的针扎。疼痛蔓延。随着那个火球变得巨大、滚烫，皮肤的灼痛已渐渐无法忍受。他看到了逐渐裂开的缝隙，像是即将剥落的墙皮。但是他不愿放弃，依然奔着太阳而去。日光就这样刺穿了他的双眼，世界变成一片耀眼的纯白。他举起手，捂住了眼睛。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他醒来时，天花板上正流淌过莹莹的光。他低下头，看见左手背燃起了一蓬幽蓝的火苗，安静地烧着，没有温度，像是一朵寂静绽放的睡莲。他定定地看了一会儿，火苗慢慢消失了。他抬起左手，没有任何变化，也没有异样的感觉。刚才的一幕仿佛幻觉。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;床头灯仍然暗暗地亮着。拉开窗帘，外面依然有许多楼房里亮着灯。他想到许许多多的人，被分布在这世界的不同角落。一同生活，一同忍耐。那么多的日日夜夜。 &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;责任编辑：舟自横&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;本文选载自《西湖》。 &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;作者&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FsiVrFF70LzdiIAoK5ukO0GjlWR8&quot; alt=&quot;李唐&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;李唐 &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;青年作家。 &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;关注&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;相关推荐&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6161&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;抢跑&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 二老坏&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;阅读&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6163&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;社交网络&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;文/ 任不然&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6162)&quot;>;点击可下载ONE一个app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4056]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4195]]><description>&lt;div>;14 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fi7x193v8ukszfTlWIo0esnskwf9&quot; alt=&quot;首页图&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4056&lt;/span>;摄影| Casey Horner&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;14&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nov. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;我一边踉跄前行，一边重振旗鼓。&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 14 Nov 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>