<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[一个词典｜什么是「瘾」？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3914]]><description> &lt;div>;19 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Question from ONE Editorial Department&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>; What is &quot;addiction&quot;? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; ONE Friendly Answers&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FiDSlHWFHGMT45bYckthzL6lkIO3&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FiDSlHWFHGMT45bYckthzL6lkIO3&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot; https://jinshuju.net/f/WBkPnP&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Excited to give it a try? Click to participate in the &quot;One Dictionary&quot; mobile collection>;>;>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Like a handful of &lt;strong>;salt&lt;/strong>; melting in the chest. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;ONE friend &quot;Tuyue&quot; (15 years old, doing nothing)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Addiction. The prefix of disease has a hidden sound. It&#39;s probably some kind of hidden &lt;strong>;chronic disease&lt;/strong>;, which is not easy to detect and eats up those things that should be good little by little. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;ONE friend &quot;Nai Shi Tier&quot; (16 years old, high school student)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It has always existed and has never been eliminated. It will only &lt;strong>;emerge&lt;/strong>; when you are lonely and lonely, engulfing you and paralyzing you. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;ONE friend &quot;I like to hit the wall&quot; (18 years old, woo woo woo)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The pain when things that should be let go &lt;strong>;cannot be let go&lt;/strong>;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;ONE friend &quot;Please install an air conditioner&quot; (20 years old)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I have a good medicine for continuing to fall and fall without being able to extricate myself, but it is the &lt;strong>;antidote&lt;/strong>; at the moment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;ONE friend &quot;Er&#39;er&quot; (20 years old, a multi-faceted intern who tells himself not to stop thinking)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is a rash in my heart, and the &lt;strong>;itching&lt;/strong>; is unbearable. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;ONE friend &quot;Bu Ping&quot; (21 years old, unemployed female college student)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although it has the word &quot;disease&quot; in it, I think it is actually an antidote. If there were not so many addictive things in my life or the person who made me addicted, I would Can&#39;t imagine how I&#39;m going to&lt;strong>;live&lt;/strong>;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;ONE friend &quot;Edton&quot; (21 years old, a college student with a not very beautiful mental state)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Addiction&quot; to me is a kind of &lt;strong>;joy&lt;/strong>;. If I love something, I will always have expectations for it, no matter what I do. Whether it is waiting, ongoing, or missing, it is all wonderful. I love this feeling of being able to have a huge interest in this world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;ONE friend &quot;Madame Butterfly&quot; (22 years old, future writer who loves flowers and butterflies)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Soaking&lt;/strong>;It is difficult to extricate oneself, actively or forcibly filling the whole body, from the first cilia in the nose to the deepest blood vessels in the alveoli. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;ONE friend &quot;quietly pushed Axis away&quot; (22 years old, a 2023 college graduate who wants to escape reality )&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a high-pressure and high-pressure working environment, dragging your exhausted body home to wash yourself and lie down on the bed, you still have to use your last bit of willpower When I hold my head full of sleepiness and eyelids that are fighting up and down, and watch mindless mobile phone videos and then dream about Zhou Gong, it is not an addiction, it is simply a &lt;strong>;drug&lt;/strong>;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;ONE friend &quot;Duo Yiyun&quot; (23 years old)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;You get sick after hiding for too long, but in the end you have to rely on certain things or desires to &lt;strong>;release&lt;/strong>; yourself; gambling is an addiction, greed for money and lust are also addictions, and even games are called addictions . Everyone is looking for a way to free themselves, and everyone is addicted. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;ONE friend &quot;Coffee&quot; (24 years old, game planner)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The feeling of addiction is the same as the urge to go to the bathroom. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;ONE friend &quot;A keyboard warrior who types quickly&quot; (25 years old, can pretend to be cute and annoying)&lt;/span>; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I ordered takeout in the middle of the night when I &lt;strong>;shouldn’t&lt;/strong>; order it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;ONE friend &quot;There are grievances in the sky&quot; (26 years old, deviant and conformist)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;People do something &lt;strong>;passively&lt;/strong>; for a long time and exclusively. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;ONE friend &quot;631&quot; (26 years old)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;The desire in the heart, the &lt;strong>;projection&lt;/strong>; of desire. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;ONE friend &quot;Ma Meng&quot; (27 years old, idiot)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although there are good and bad aspects, it is a kind of redemption in the heart of the person involved. It&#39;s like:&lt;strong>;You are not a fish, so you know the happiness of fish. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;ONE friend &quot;someone who goes crazy occasionally&quot; (30 years old, quiet fish)&lt;/span>;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Losing the ability to think&lt;/strong>; cannot be suppressed even if you don’t want to. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;ONE friend &quot;Celia&quot; (35 years old, happy person)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp ;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Anything called &quot;addiction&quot; can feel &lt;strong>;&quot;numb&quot;&lt;/strong>; in it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The things that bring &quot;addiction&quot; are different, but the &quot;numbness&quot; they bring is the same. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Why is this? It’s just pain in this world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;ONE friend &quot;Village Mangzi&quot; (38 years old, stay-at-home mother with a smoking addiction)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From another perspective, addiction is actually &lt;strong>;stubbornness&lt;/strong>;. The enthusiasm has long faded, but I still have to play two games every day. Many people ask me if I am addicted to this game. In fact, I just stubbornly want to complete the game. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;ONE friend &quot;Xigua Chen&quot; (41 years old, a handyman)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt; br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right;&quot;>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://jinshuju.net/f/WBkPnP&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Click to participate &quot;One Dictionary&quot; Mobile Collection>;>;>;&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Responsible Editor: Mei Butan onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;See @ for the call for papers information ONE Studio is pinned to the top of Weibo. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8 &quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Complex The cutest people in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3898&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;A dictionary｜What is &quot;literature&quot; in your eyes? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3868&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;A dictionary｜What exactly is &quot;student anger&quot;? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3914)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[怀念时常徒有虚名]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6095]]><description> &lt;div>;19 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Text/Zhou Hongxiang&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data -author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FsgXWBR_H644rVEswjgi5My9-TZW&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FsgXWBR_H644rVEswjgi5My9-TZW&quot;>; &lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Dopamine and endorphins, one creates pleasure in memories, the other heals The pain of remembrance. It is said that it is better to miss each other than to meet each other, but sometimes remembering is just in vain. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Among Eason Chan&#39;s many songs, there are two very interesting dueling songs, &quot;Long Time No See&quot; in Mandarin and &quot;Better Not See You&quot; in Cantonese. The same story, the same melody, but with two moods, as if they are parallel worlds of the same protagonist. The former arrived in the other&#39;s city, but the other is no longer there. I searched through the past photos to find traces of the other&#39;s existence. Even though he knew it was all fantasy and bubble, he still longed to meet the other person on a certain street, as if he had never left. As for the latter, he took an early morning flight to London. They hadn&#39;t seen each other for ten years, and they were finally going to meet each other. However, on the way to reunion, they began to look at each other. In these days of missing each other, both parties have become unfamiliar with each other. How to start a chat, how to relive old feelings, it seems that everything is too embarrassing, times have changed, but when you want to meet, you shrink back or think clearly, it is better not to meet. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gai Ming once lived in Beijing for a period of time, a year or a year and a half. I don’t remember much, but when he was in Beijing, I didn’t know him well until he came back. Coming from my hometown in Northeast China, we only had the opportunity to have a glass of wine when we accidentally returned to Beijing to hold an exhibition. In my impression, he has always been a mysterious person. As a photographer, his aesthetics are very high. Although most of the photographers in his works are naked, they are not pornographic. In addition to his occasional photography works, seeing his solitary little life makes people feel as if he has always been alone. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One night when I was chatting with him, the topic of love suddenly came up. I have always been outspoken and expressed my thoughts. I wanted to say, have you never been in love? Gai Ming said, of course not, there is still love, but it has never been that important to his life. He said that when he likes someone, he will devote himself wholeheartedly. No matter what the other person&#39;s attitude is or whether he responds, he will do his best to express his inner emotions, which is full and charming. The premise is that he must be happy. If once he finds himself in When this relationship starts to be emotionally draining and he starts to worry about gains and losses, he will immediately withdraw and stay away from the relationship. Judging from what Gai Ming told, his memories are very personal, at least most of them belong to him alone. Although the other party is involved, he will not think of the other party out of nostalgia. He is more Yes, I miss myself in a beautiful relationship. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So Gai Ming’s emotions have never been traced. Maybe he has never really confirmed the relationship in many of the relationships, and they are just one-sided love. But in Gai Ming’s words, falling in love is just for happiness. , if you are not happy, how can you fall in love? Even if it&#39;s a secret love, don&#39;t fall in love if you&#39;re not happy. Life is too short, why bother falling in love so hard? Li Zongsheng sang it a long time ago. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For a long time, I have watched Gai Ming take pictures all over the world with a camera on his back. Maybe there are people he liked in the photos, maybe not. The place where love is hidden is always filled with his extreme ego. partially dissolved. After that, he began to organize exhibitions, work as a curator, travel around the world, and cooperate with some avant-garde artists. He spared no effort to attract sponsors to help these unknown but talented newcomers promote their works. He is a person who lives at work, and work is also one of his lovers. During one conversation with Gaiming, he took out a picture album of ruins photographed by a Norwegian photographer after entering the forest. He explained his feelings to me in great detail, and then told me that this was the photography The teacher first gave him a work of his subject. They had sneaked into this forest before, but had never seen the ruins. When they went there again, he was alone. The ruins were very much like their past. Desolate and depressing, but with an unforgettable beauty. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gai Ming told me that there are three types of people in the world, those who live with memories, those who only care about happiness in the moment, and those who are always empty. I said the first two are easy to understand, but who is the third? Gaiming said that people who neither cling to the past nor enjoy the present, and who will not be hurt if they don’t take in their feelings, in other words, are numb people, can of course also be said to be sober people. Numbness and sobriety are just different perspectives, but in fact they have the same attitude. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The third type of person he mentioned does exist around me. Compared with people like Gai Ming who miss the past and just miss themselves, Xiao Sang is a person who has never been No mention will be made of people passing by. There are still many rumors about his love. He is always in contact with different people and has many fleeting relationships. He does not seem enthusiastic enough, but he has an attractive personality. When a lovelorn person sings hoarse in the singing room When he sang &quot;What I miss is talking about everything...&quot;, he would also ask coldly, what is there to miss? In his love history, he often puts his name in the story, remembering what happened with A to B, and telling what C said to him into D&#39;s story. Sometimes we will also hear some contradictions, until As he was talking, he said, Oh, I remembered the wrong person. It hurts to say it this way, but he will not hurt himself. Every time someone around you is heartbroken, it is actually the most effective to go to Xiao Sang for comfort. He can always tell you the truth of love to the point. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ups and downs of love often start with beauty. In the process, you feel the gap, have doubts when it is dull, and finally fall apart. So every review of a broken love is an act of inserting a sharp knife into yourself. When crying, I always don&#39;t understand the changes in the other person. Why can I be so indifferent to you and me one second? The key is that people who are lovelorn will only miss those beautiful things. The more beautiful things are, the more broken they are. Inseparable. Xiao Sang would ask incomprehensively, wouldn&#39;t it be better if we didn&#39;t remember it? Why do people take memories so seriously? Memories themselves are a kind of creation. You can create this so-called &quot;memory&quot; for a certain period of time in the future, so memories themselves are very cheap. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Different from Gai Ming’s rhetoric of “missing the past is nothing more than missing yourself”, Xiao Sang doesn’t even value his own participation. Xiao Sang often said that it is better to miss each other than to meet each other. This sentence should be reversed. It is better to meet each other than to miss each other. Since you want to be alone, go and see him. If you see him, you will give up completely until the other person sees you. It&#39;s worthless, knowing that the good things you miss have long been forgotten by others. If you treat yourself more cruelly, you will look at the past more rationally. There is nothing better than missing it! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When autumn comes, I especially like to take people to drink on the terrace. Sometimes it’s wine, sometimes it’s whiskey. There is always a refreshing feeling in Beijing’s autumn. It feels like, at this moment, everyone will feel more comfortable talking about their own stories. Xiao Sang and I have almost the same point of view on love, so when chatting with several other friends, I would naturally say that good love is always creating beautiful moments, while bad love is just I will miss the beauty that has passed away and will not create it again. When I finished saying this, the terrace fell silent for a moment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All short-lasting love dies due to the word &quot;internal friction&quot;. Some lovers really spend thousands of days, while some lovers spend thousands of days in one day. all over. Those so-called good memories are so precious because neither party is willing to create them anymore, but this also shows that since they are no longer created, the things created that already belong to you are meaningless. The only meaning is that time records your traces, which is just a certain step in your growth. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From a certain point on, Gai Ming became less interested in the people and events around him. I don’t know if it was because the photographer had seen too many people, or if he simply couldn’t understand people’s complex emotions. Take control, he said. Today, what can cause him the most emotional fluctuations are greater environmental changes, such as epidemics, disasters, and the possibility hypothesis of the universe. When it comes to happiness, he has also begun to Empathizes with specific things, but not work. He said that specific dynamic things will make him happy. Cycling, skiing, surfing, mountain climbing, things that consume a lot of physical energy will make him come alive completely. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After more than a year, his personality has also changed subtly. From being emotionally out of control in the past to being calm now, exercise has had a great impact on him. He said that dopamine controls the perception of pleasure, but it is related to desire. It comes easily but is consumed quickly. Most love is caused by dopamine and is fleeting because it does not last long. Endorphins are something that is relatively persistent and difficult to obtain. Medically speaking, it can relieve pain and suppress people&#39;s negative emotions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Being in love produces dopamine, while extreme sports produce endorphins. Put more energy into the sports you like rather than the people, and you will become more charming. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I am non-committal about this suggestion. Maybe in his view, things are either/or, but as far as I am concerned, it is not necessarily the case. Love and sports are not contradictory or conflicting, and you can even like them. It is not impossible for people to exercise together to produce dopamine and endorphins at the same time. This process of participation is also a moment of creating memories. But I have to agree that these momentary happiness will not last forever, and it may not even be worth looking back. Those who let go of the past forever and continue to move forward are often better than those who cling to the past and add filters. People are much more charming. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Everyone has different ways of dealing with memories, just like everyone’s attitude towards love is also completely different, and nostalgia is ultimately the reflection in the wine glass, not the wine, nor the cup, gorgeous under the light It is beautifully presented, but disappears completely after the glass is empty, turning into a scent on the lips that can be savored, but will always be covered by the smell of other foods. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One day in the future, when the person you have feelings for rings your phone again, chic people often have no time to reminisce about the past. A joking &quot;love&quot; is enough to replace everything and let go. Emotions, close the chat window, continue chatting about unnecessary things with the current person, who was looking for you just now? You said, ex, you drank too much, so you sent the wrong message. Then I laughed it off and didn&#39;t delete it because the other person was not that important. Replying to it was a kind of respect for letting go. The past will no longer be mentioned because there are no more ripples. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is the right thing for people who see through love. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Li Jialong&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see @ONE Studio’s pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FnG6mnVK6opY4g75Tw-7h415dwbd&quot; alt=&quot;zhouhongxiang&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;zhou hongxiang&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@zhouhongxiang&lt;/span>; &lt; /div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Young writer, representative works &quot;Famous Fair&quot; and &quot;They Are Burning&quot;&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot; OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Read&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6079&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Breakup is a disaster The Return of the Galloping Horse&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Written by Zhou Hongxiang&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/ span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6061&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Love that never grows up&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Written by Zhou Hongxiang&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, 6095)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4000]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4125]]><description>&lt;div>;19 Sep. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fqqa6iUJhbUR43GABnFAb1UPgPy6&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;VOL.4000&lt;/span>;Photography | Zhu Liang&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;19&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Sep. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;In fact, we have to pass That road is not difficult, it just depends on who is waiting for you on the other side. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 06:25:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>