<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[你为了省钱做过哪些赔钱事？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3994]]><description> &lt;div>;1 Dec. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; ONE Studio Question&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p >;What money-losing things have you done to save money? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; ONE Friendly Answers&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FvMDUeS8_hOF8_bU76kbmcnwJDbv&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FvMDUeS8_hOF8_bU76kbmcnwJDbv&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot; font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;span data-copy-origin=&quot;https://shimo.im&quot; data-docs-delta=&quot;[[20 , &quot;The best way to save money is to increase revenue, not to reduce expenditure. &quot;,&quot;inline-dir:\&quot;ltr\&quot;&quot;]]&quot;>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The best way to save money is to increase revenue, not to reduce expenditure. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rent a house, choose to rent it in the basement for cheaper. I just want to come back and sleep, no matter where I sleep, it will be the same. But on weekends, in order to find sunshine, I have to force myself to go out and play. The money spent on eating, drinking and having fun on the weekend, plus the rent in the basement, was even more expensive than the original rent. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Qiuqiu (24 years old, will change house immediately after the contract expires)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Buy clothes out of season, buy winter clothes in summer and summer clothes in winter. Then, either the clothes have faded, or their body shape has changed and they can’t wear them, or they don’t like them anymore. Then continue to buy clothes for that season. No money was saved at all. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Xiaoer (27 years old, waiting for next spring)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;Music software requires VIP to listen to the whole song. I think you should just pick the singles you like and buy them. Not every song is my favorite. But every month I find a lot of songs, and a single is only 2 yuan, but I end up buying a lot of songs one by one. In fact, I might as well open a membership. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Ten people (29 years old, senior user of a certain dog)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;Don’t go to the hospital if you have a toothache, because you need to buy a piece of material to fill a tooth. It was clear that one bottle of material could not be used up and could not be recycled. I felt very distressed, so I chose to take metronidazole. Then I took too many pills and broke out in hives all over my body. In order to treat the allergy, I took expensive special injections. After the allergy was cured, I went to the dentist. One of the teeth was so severe that I had to kill the nerves and do a crown. But now that I think about it, it only costs one or two hundred to fill a tooth. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Tooth decay (31 years old, envious of sharks’ replaceable teeth)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My mother doesn’t go to formal yoga classes, but practices by herself along with online live broadcasts. Later, the anchor started to sell goods. She bought a bunch of fake and shoddy goods, and she also worked hard until her knees accumulated water and her elbows became inflamed. Then I went to the hospital and had massage and acupuncture for more than half a year, but I still haven&#39;t recovered. Next year she plans to switch to swimming. This is a good exercise because you can’t learn it at home. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Dirty (26 years old, mother is also rebellious)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp ;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Last year, when I was renovating my home, I watched videos online and chose to do the sewing myself. The videos online look so simple, but we can’t do it. A lot of materials were wasted and the work was not strong. It must be because the dust was not sucked clean. Then I asked the master to renovate it again. Haha, I am really a master of saving money. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Dog thief (32 years old, will never change houses again)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I bought a snake board when I was a kid, I could only buy a cheap one with my pocket money. The snake board rotated very stiffly and I broke my arm. I’ve known since the fifth grade that you can’t be greedy for petty gains, as cheap products will definitely lead to bad products. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Mao Jiu (27 years old, money must not be the most important thing)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp ;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After watching the video, you can grow succulents using dragon fruits, and you can grow green plants using avocados. I kept buying dragon fruits and avocados to plant. At first it couldn&#39;t be planted, and later it couldn&#39;t live long after it was planted. I tried for several months and suddenly figured out that the money I spent on fruits was enough to buy a lot of potted plants. Why bother? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Zhan (34 years old, nature lover)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;I don’t want to buy a mop worth more than 20 yuan. The rented room is very small, so I wipe the floor with wet paper towels. You need ten wet wipes to wipe the floor once, once every two days, and you can probably use up a large pack of wet wipes in a month. It was also due to laziness. I had to wash the mop when mopping the floor. The room was too small and there was no place to put it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Ajing (32 years old, no original intention, only to achieve success)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp ;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I was in college, because bathing was very expensive, our dormitory asked us to install a magical bathing device ourselves. It was quite harmonious at first, but then the relationship in our dormitory started to change: whose hair was too long and blocked the toilet, who didn&#39;t clean it carefully, who forgot to store water, who took too long to wash and occupied the bathroom for too long... Got nervous. No one is friendly with anyone, and AA has been restored. For example, everyone in our dormitory has a clothes drying pole, and we have never had dinner together. Everyone lives like an enemy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Yixiu (29 years old, save enough money to have plastic surgery)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My family is in a rural area. About ten years ago, it was very popular to use new energy for floor heating. But in order to save on electricity bills, my dad combined rooms. My parents, who had been separated for a long time, started living together. My brother and I started living together, just to turn off the floor heating in the other two rooms. Until, my dad and my mom quarreled frequently, and my brother and I fought frequently, and we returned to living separately. We found that the floor heating in the other two rooms was broken, so we asked someone to repair it. They removed the furniture, broke open the floor, and checked the pipes. We found that there was too much water and alkali and the pipes were blocked. Then we redecorated again. The whole process cost tens of thousands. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;氵嫫 (30 years old, the one who was taken advantage of)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;This is not a loss of money for me, but it is a loss of spirit. There is a cheap book market in our junior high school, which costs only a few yuan a book. In fact, it is a pirated book with many typos and small and sparse words. I bought a book of famous quotes and memorized them specifically, thinking about writing the sentences in my composition for sublimation. However, if some words were said by Zhang San, they become those said by Li Si in the book. I used the wrong one, and the Chinese teacher punished me by copying the text 30 times. After copying it, I sent it to the principal&#39;s mailbox to report that pirated books were being sold in the book market. It&#39;s a pity it&#39;s useless, it still happens every year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Baker (36 years old, just live a normal life)&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p >; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Nana onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For information about the call for submissions, please see the @ONE Studio pinned on Weibo. The official WeChat account of the editorial department: oneapp2020. Regularly publish Q&amp;A collections, give away books and peripheral gifts, readers are welcome to add. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8 &quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Complex The cutest people in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3992&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;The favorite quotes of ONE authors&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div >; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Question and Answer&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/ 3991&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Reading a lot of books can change your life. Is it a scam? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3988&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What I need VS what I see | Can the Internet really satisfy us? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3994)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[消逝在秋末的喜欢]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6183]]><description> &lt;div>;1 Dec. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;文／Erwachen&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: right; &quot;>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;&lt;strong>;Today&#39;s audio reader is &quot;AI Xiaowei&quot;, post-production David. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpbzFq71I7DamKH_ft6mMa3tqMIP&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src= &quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpbzFq71I7DamKH_ft6mMa3tqMIP&quot;>;&lt;/p>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;This It is a confession of a secret admirer. Between entanglement, ambiguity, suspicion and conjecture, all love will eventually disappear at the end of autumn. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The first time I noticed A Zhou was when I was working overtime and going to have lunch one weekend. It was not long after she moved to a new team. Because I had the impression that the person at her workstation was another colleague. I still remember that at noon that day, a quiet and introverted girl with long hair and light-colored clothes slowly walked from her work station to the dining table without raising her head. I have always felt that the way I stare at others is impolite. But when I met Azhou for the first time and later at lunch, there was always a feeling that she knew I was looking at her, and she was avoiding touching my eyes. There was always something inconsistent with her nature in the crowd. performance of status. I&#39;m very narcissistic, but I&#39;m certainly not narcissistic enough to think that someone I&#39;ve never interacted with in real life would like me. But from the beginning, I felt that I had a two-way love for A Zhou. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before I met Azhou in real life, she and I only communicated on the Internet about work matters. At that time, I felt that this girl was very smart, and her speaking style was very similar to me when talking about my field of expertise. She was logical and eloquent. Since I was the only boy in our team, I took it for granted that she already knew me before I knew her in real life. At that time, I just realized that I started to have a lot of strange psychological reactions to her words, and some of her behaviors seemed abnormal to me. For example, she would explain business logic to her colleagues on my behalf. To state my role in something. At that time, I thought about it, I want to get to know A Zhou in reality. But I probably never thought that the girl who attracted me in reality was A Zhou. So when I found out about it, I felt even more that it was fate. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition to daily communication about work content, we will also talk about other things. The chatting atmosphere is getting better and better, and some interesting topics will be covered besides work topics. The emotions are gradually warming up. This is one of the factors that makes me want to get to know A Zhou in reality. And Azhou knows me in reality, but she doesn’t hate me—at least in my heart I think she doesn’t hate me—and she attracts me, which is the fundamental reason why I started to move towards her. Before I added Azhou on WeChat, she and I had met several times in real life. Those few encounters made me gradually realize that the person who moved my heart in real life and on the Internet was the same person. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first time was one night when I was working overtime. When I got off work, I walked up to the male colleague next to her and asked that colleague why he still didn’t get off work and whether the work went well that day. While we were chatting, A Zhou, who originally had his back to me, turned around. Wearing a mask, but in a completely relaxed state, with the whole body facing me, looking at me, listening to the conversation between me and the colleague. I am a person interested in psychology, and I once learned a way of observing people: If a person doesn&#39;t hate you, then her toes will point towards you when communicating with you. So when I noticed that Azhou&#39;s whole body turned to listen to me, I felt in my heart that at least this girl didn&#39;t hate me. Even though I was not sure which colleague she was with whom I had voice communication at that time, I felt that at least she had a good impression of me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The second time was when I was on my way to eat in other regional canteens. I happened to be wearing glasses that day, so I could still clearly see faces several meters away when walking. When I turned the corner, I saw two girls leaving the cafeteria. When my eyes glanced at them, one of the girls waved to me. The girl immediately turned away when her eyes met mine. This made me suddenly feel a little embarrassed while I was still waving my hands. Did she recognize the wrong person or for some other reason. At that time, I was surprised by A Zhou&#39;s performance. If they were just acquaintances as ordinary colleagues, why would their words and deeds be so strange? Is it just because they are not good at sociability? Perhaps these weird thoughts in my heart are the biggest reason for my emotional failure. People should not like such delicate judgment and analysis, but real and practical behavioral concerns. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The third time was when I came off work one day and met Azhou and his male colleague taking midnight snacks back to the office. I wasn&#39;t wearing glasses that day, but I guessed it was them from their silhouettes. And I waved at that time to say hello to the male colleague. So I was surprised when I saw A Zhou also raised his hand. Although I was surprised, I finally confirmed one thing in my heart: the person my heart beats in real life and the person my heart beats online are the same person. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But one day after those few encounters, I met her on the office floor, and she greeted me with a bright smile. At that moment, I was a little dazed. I responded with a shy smile and quickly Walked by. Then I mustered up the courage to send a message to her office communication software before lunch break that day, saying that I wanted to add her WeChat account; after she woke up from lunch break and saw the message, she gave me her mobile phone number. I think that probably no girl thinks that a boy who adds her on WeChat will think that the other person wants to be friends with her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is said that it is not difficult to get in touch, but the difficulty is how to chat afterwards. I didn’t chat with her immediately after I added her on WeChat. The conversation started when I went to the bookstore that weekend. When I saw an interesting phrase in Reader’s Digest, I took a photo and shared it with her. It took a long time for her to reply to the message, but she answered the message very interestingly, and the conversation pattern for countless subsequent times was the same as that time. Then she said something like &quot;I never forget my original intention&quot;. I was a little surprised. Firstly, it was true, and secondly, she was the same in my impression. The first chat was not so awkward and started so naturally. Later, I started sharing many topics intentionally or unintentionally, such as dusk and sunset, for example, I dreamed of her several times at that time, and when there were weird things, I would share them with her immediately. It was also after that that I realized that I could share what I was thinking, seeing and seeing with her without any motive and that I really liked this person. But when I later deliberately tried to cool down this emotion, I began to doubt myself again. Was it the person I liked her or myself when I liked her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The chat mode between Azhou and I is sometimes like jet lag. When I send her messages at night, she sometimes doesn’t reply until she goes to work the next day. But it&#39;s never perfunctory, sometimes it&#39;s humorous, and sometimes it&#39;s even a little ambiguous. They all say that if you like someone, you have to get in touch with her in reality and understand her life. When I think the time is right, I want to ask her to go out together on the weekend. When I was thinking about which method was safer, I chose voice. Between WeChat calls and mobile phone calls, I chose WeChat voice. After all, I haven&#39;t called her using my mobile phone number yet, and I don&#39;t want her to be abrupt when she receives the call and hears the voice, but the WeChat voice message knows that it is a voice request from me. Azhou didn&#39;t respond to the voice request. She responded with a message after I was thinking about it for half an hour, saying that she and her boyfriend had just gone out for supper, so she didn&#39;t receive the call. Even though I knew that it was not like a girl like her had a boyfriend, I was still emotionally shattered by this sentence at that moment. After scribbling a reply, I didn’t dare to look at my phone anymore, so I covered my phone on the table and went straight to sleep. I woke up in the middle of the night and saw that Azhou had immediately replied to the message, with just two expressions. They say that the dead of night is better for sleeping than chatting, but when I woke up, I still had my mind stimulated by A Zhou’s words and sent a long text to A Zhou. So my relationship with her started to come to an end. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As usual, she responded to the message from the night before when she went to work the next day. She said we could continue to be friends. I thought she definitely didn&#39;t have a boyfriend and said: I was too abrupt yesterday and gave you a lot of psychological pressure. Love lasts forever, so we can start with friends. In fact, I will definitely not pursue a girl who has a boyfriend. But when I fall in love with someone, sometimes there is really no sense at all. In the end, I chose to deceive myself. And before and after that day, I thought about whether I should shorten the distance between me and her in reality. After all, when we come together, we have to return to real life in the end. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My office area and Azhou&#39;s are not far apart, but she is relatively close to the elevator, so I don&#39;t know when she gets off work. I thought about getting off work with her and asked her twice. Once I asked her on WeChat. When she was getting ready to get off work, I happened to come back from outside and saw her packing up and getting ready to go back. I saw her stay at the desk for a while longer, until she disappeared from my sight. Then I received a message on WeChat from her saying that she was going back. Another time it was a rainy day, I took a screenshot of someone telling me that it was raining outside and I needed to use an umbrella when I got home, and asked her to pay attention to it later, and we chatted for a while. She talked about how she was not in a good state recently, and I said how I felt that you were not in a good state recently. The words spoken by both parties were both playful and serious. After a while, I was about to ask her when she would get off work when she said there were oil stains on her clothes and left first. But instead of waiting for me to join her, she left first. However, when I went to get the late night snack, I saw her there. I thought it was a coincidence, so we naturally went off work together. That was the first time I chatted with her in real life, and I kept sharing office anecdotes that I thought were interesting, people we both knew, and things that happened around us. Occasionally I looked at her secretly while talking. I think she was also happy at that time. I seemed to have been sharing at that time. I once thought about whether it would be awkward to talk to her without a topic in real life, but then I realized that it would not be the case, and the atmosphere was even very good. At least when I&#39;m in front of her, I&#39;m really happy and willing to express myself. In front of the person I like, I act like an innocent and romantic child. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, in reality, we only got along with each other once, and then we gradually drifted away from each other. She was very close to the male colleague, so close that I intuitively thought something bad was going to happen. A Zhou&#39;s work circle was basically all girls until she moved to a new team. After that, many of her actions were with that male colleague. Many times when she worked overtime at night and got off work very late, the male colleague would send her home, even though the male colleague was engaged. Of course, although it was not convenient to see her off from get off work, it was still the gentlemanly thing to do. The time I felt something strange was at noon on two consecutive Fridays, they would disappear into the office building at the same time. Although I am a person who loves to think wildly, I will not fantasize about things that are too outrageous. At first I just thought it was a coincidence, but when I actually saw it, I was heartbroken. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I felt uneasy when I first realized they were both out of the office at noon. You know, all of them usually have nap time collectively at noon. I didn&#39;t take a break at noon that day and walked back and forth upstairs and downstairs. When it was time to go to work in the afternoon, they came back one after another. I bumped into A Zhou when I was going to the bathroom. She said hi to me and then quickly lowered her head when I saw it was her. Her face looked very much like the state after the clouds and rain in Wushan. The next Friday, I wondered if the same thing would happen again. Sure enough, she and her male colleague left the office building at noon. When they were about to go to work, the male colleague came back, but A Zhou did not return to the office. In my impression, Azhou is not the kind of person who takes his work so casually. At noon that day, I waited outside for a long time, and I felt like I was mentally distorted. Since then, A Zhou&#39;s behavior has become more and more strange in my eyes, and I have even heard a lot of rumors about him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I think I can’t be internally consumed any longer, even though I really like A Zhou. When she rejected me before, I thought about it, should I not deceive myself, she just has a boyfriend, and let go of the emotional obsession in my heart. But every time I can&#39;t think of a reason to let go. The kind of love I have for her is really pure. Even though I later realized that her personality was not necessarily in line with my values, I still couldn&#39;t let go of her. Or maybe I am paralyzing myself, maybe I just like myself who likes her. I act like a child in front of her and don&#39;t feel bad emotions when I&#39;m around her, but these are just my states. I remembered that when she was chatting, she mentioned that she was in a bad state, and that her family affairs would affect her mood at work. She would talk about her work status, and she would send me a message when she was working overtime on a certain weekend to ask if the answer was right. so. When she was sharing, did I listen carefully, take over what she said, and comfort her. I seem to be doing very poorly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Aries and Sagittarius are so similar and so well matched. Once I was chatting with A Zhou and after I found out that she was a Sagittarius, I started reading zodiac related content like crazy. You will smile when you see good content, and lose your smile instantly when you see sad content. It’s not that I believe in horoscopes, but I am interested in metaphysics. More importantly, I like A Zhou. Love is a superstition about the right time and place. But now, the love has not disappeared, but I am running away. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Li Jialong&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see @ONE Studio’s pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. The official WeChat account of the editorial department: oneapp2020. Regularly publish Q&amp;A collections, give away books and peripheral gifts, readers are welcome to add. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FqoyTXuC48xrNknsC5sXKNaiDQiQ&quot; alt=&quot;Erwachen&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Erwachen &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt; div style=&quot;&quot;>;Use the tip of the pen to shape reason, and use stories to convey sensibility. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/article/6182&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Made in Hong Kong&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Wen/Duan Ziqi&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt; tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Read&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6181&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Sincerely Game&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Boli&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6183)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt; p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4073]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4217]]><description>&lt;div>;1 Dec. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FneelkWdwbKcsZUgUOXZaZ1SvXZ8&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;VOL.4073&lt;/span>;Photography | Minol Song&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;1&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dec. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;There is no winter Insurmountable, there is no spring that will not come. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>