<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[什么都需要原谅吗？有哪些你无法原谅的事情？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3970]]><description> &lt;div>;8 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; KAKAKAKAquestion&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p >;What are some things you can’t forgive? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; ONE Friendly Answers&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgmCG5cdbVonJ9jCZJoeDFuujhHm&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgmCG5cdbVonJ9jCZJoeDFuujhHm&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot; font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Tolerance and generosity are regarded as virtues, but people are prone to moral kidnapping, and your tolerance may be regarded by others as a sign of harm to you. Get out of jail free gold. Forgiveness does not mean healing. Any forgiveness requires facing the scars left by the other party first. This should be a principled thing. What do you think? &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is no holiday on New Year’s Eve this year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Chili, 22 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; My grades were worse than my brother&#39;s, but not by much, but my parents said that the family could only afford one child, so they were partial and asked me to drop out of school and work in order to support my brother in college. The funny thing is that I am the one who is more promising now. Although I don’t mention some things, I can’t get over the hurdle in my heart. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Huangshan Song, 51 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Cheating, in fact, you can just end it if there is no relationship left. Playing the emotional card and trampling on it, the performance cannot show enthusiasm. Looking back at the original appearance and the current attitude, it is not at all sorry for the original joy and no hesitation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Mute, 34 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; It’s really unforgivable that I keep publicizing it even though I know it is an unspeakable pain point of mine. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Xi Yu, 18 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;It didn&#39;t happen to me, but I won&#39;t forgive it. When I was a child, my father would domestically abuse my mother. He would come back to take out his anger on my mother when he lost at cards, got drunk, and was bullied. People of their generation did not have the concept of divorce, and they felt that getting married meant being tied up for the rest of their lives. Later, my dad didn&#39;t dare to do it anymore, because I grew up, and if he dared to do it again, I would teach him a lesson. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Bell-bottom pants, 47 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I am a vegetarian. When I went to eat at someone&#39;s house, the other person added lard to my noodles even though she knew I was a vegetarian. After I tasted it, she said, &quot;I just want to see if you can really do it.&quot; You can eat it. So I was blocked. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Nini, 18 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; When you wake up, no roommate calls you, and you are the only one left in the dormitory. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Mathematical analysis, 24 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;I was in Gaza in 2008, and I still can’t forget that bombs fell from the sky and a building next to me disappeared. The violence remains the same after all these years, and no matter what, opening fire on civilians is wrong and inexcusable. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Lao Zhang, 54 years old&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;No, I will not forgive that relative for not bringing back the news that my father was injured in the factory. Because it was obviously possible to save it, but then he left unexpectedly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;nei, 25 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;University During that period, I was the Youth League Secretary in my class, and I usually participated in many extracurricular activities. I had no intention of socializing with other people in the class. My friends who I had a good time with during military training started talking bad about me everywhere and spread rumors about me. I feel really chilled, but I understand that everyone has their own ambitions. Anyway, if we never meet again, I won’t choose to forgive. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Xianyu Xu, 21 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;We have so many wonderful memories together and I can&#39;t forgive him for leaving me without giving a reason. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Xiao Baibai, 17 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; I can&#39;t forgive myself. There was a classmate with whom I had a good relationship in high school. She seemed very sad when we were studying late at night, and she kept talking to me about life and family. I was a little annoyed because I failed in the exam, so I just gave her a few perfunctory words and left. Unexpectedly, she jumped off the building that night. She didn&#39;t die, but she became disabled. The school felt that the impact was not good and made her drop out of school. I always feel like I have a responsibility, if I would listen to her pain, maybe she wouldn&#39;t be like that. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Hyacinth, 38 years old&lt;/span>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In the name of doing my best, my parents treated me like a commodity with a clearly marked price. When I resisted, they scolded me, threatened me, and morally kidnapped me. I will never forget it in my life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;a little cat, 24 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;When the epidemic was just released and large-scale infections began, every department in the hospital was full of patients. Colleagues started to have fevers one after another. There were fewer and fewer colleagues who could take over the shift, and all the ones who were not serious were Keep trying. In such a situation where everyone is working together, a colleague got weird in the work group, saying that another colleague who had just finished supporting the makeshift hospital came back to work in the department and brought positive symptoms to the people in the department. Everyone saw it. I was speechless. I hurriedly explained it was a joke the next day, and was scolded later. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Worker with a sense of justice, 30 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;When I was in junior high school, I confessed to a girl I liked, and she went to report it to the teacher the next day. And forwarded all our chat records at that time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Only Bai Xuewangxilou, 19 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;When there were three months left before the college entrance examination in my senior year of high school, my parents had a serious quarrel. I am a general student and I go back every day at noon and again at 11pm. Then, they quarreled and divorced in front of me. Actually, I really didn’t want to know about this because it affected my mood in studying. Later they reconciled, but I still feel sad when I think about it now. Can you consider my feelings? In fact, I don’t want to know at all, even if you are pretending to lie to me... span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The company requires employees to advance money, but refuses to give it for several years, and delays in paying wages. Employees are blamed for the leadership&#39;s mistakes. The people live in too much pain. The sky is not responding to calls, the earth and the earth are not working properly. It is difficult for children to go to school and to see a doctor. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Human world, 38 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; When I was young, I lost a watch. It was only seven years ago. At that time, I almost turned over the watch, but I couldn&#39;t find its whereabouts. As a result, last year at a dinner party with old friends, a retired former colleague told me privately that he saw the leader’s child stealing, but he was afraid that speaking out would affect his work. He hoped I could forgive him. But I don’t intend to forgive, and I can’t say that I have to let it go after a long time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Reminiscing about the past and drinking tea, 63 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;My ex used my past stories as something to talk about with others after dinner. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Chen, 25 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Random guessing about other people&#39;s appearance, personality, gender, and temperament is a source of conversation for them, and it is harmful to diversity. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;span style=&quot;color: rgb(128, 128, 128);&quot;>;Li Cangeng, 23 years old&lt;/span>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>; Editor-in-chief: Zhou Ziheng onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For information on the call for papers, please see the @ONE Studio pinned on Weibo. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmgDdOBenMvH6G69S5THIANm6xm8 &quot; alt=&quot;ONE friend&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;ONE friend&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Complex The cutest people in the world&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt; /td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3968&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;What sudden insights did you have last night? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3970)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[冬日已足够美妙]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6154]]><description> &lt;div>;8 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;文／小桃风&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fm5XGmsksnCfgqH7uJFWFMIdpVET&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fm5XGmsksnCfgqH7uJFWFMIdpVET&quot;>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Today is the beginning of winter. Nowadays, we can eat dumplings anytime and anywhere, but festivals, customs, rituals, and family reunions are not something that is readily available. I hope that you in front of the screen can eat a few dumplings, write a diary, make a phone call, and embed ordinary but warm memories into your life through festivals. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&amp;ldquo;It’s the beginning of winter! &amp;rdquo;It’s a language I need to learn again&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Have you noticed that the word &quot;Beidiao&quot; has not been heard for a long time. It seems to have slowly disappeared from modern society. Lost its meaning. As for the word &quot;nostalgia&quot;, I felt it as soon as I said it. It has a very ancient tone. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In this era where high-speed rail and video are so convenient, it seems that I have not done this for a long time. Even for those of us &quot;Beijing drifters&quot; who have been away from home all year round and work abroad, the sadness of leaving our hometown and feeling helpless and without any friends has not returned to our hearts for a long time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They are more entangled in trivial matters such as overtime, morning rush hours, relationships with colleagues, leaders’ opinions, and fluctuations in the economic environment. I just hope that today will be peaceful and peaceful. After today is over, I can fall asleep peacefully with the sound of the short video, and then wake up to see the stock market turn red. That would be great. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Most of what we talk about is gossip about colleagues, hot topics, how to make money, change jobs to increase salary, avoid quarrels with lovers, and provide for retirement. We even start to care about our own health, using smart watches to calculate daily steps, heart rate while sleeping, and calorie weight, but never mention our hometown again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While video chatting with my mother over the weekend, my grandma said beside me: &quot;It&#39;s the beginning of winter, so put on some clothes and don&#39;t forget to eat dumplings!&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My grandma is 83 years old, and she is indeed deaf and blinded at that age. Every time during the video, I asked her a question, and she always answered in a nonsensical way. She just said, &quot;Put on more clothes, don&#39;t catch a cold!&quot; &amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;Go to bed early and don’t stay up late! &amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;The frost is coming, so I need to change to a thicker quilt! &amp;rdquo;Such as this, I think &quot;clichés&quot; that are &quot;useless at all&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I went home one time, I saw that my grandma seemed to have aged again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What does it mean to be &quot;older&quot;? It means that the topics are more monotonous, the eyes are cloudier, and the steps are slower. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I suddenly felt that the world that my grandma and I lived in were no longer the same. The language we use is naturally no longer the same. It reminds me of what Wittgenstein said: &quot;The boundary of language is the boundary of thought.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Solar terms&quot; are the medium through which grandma understands the world, and it is also one of the languages ​​​​for her external communication. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In my world, I don’t use this language at all. In my dictionary, as mentioned above, it consists of colleagues’ gossip, trending events, making money, five insurances and one housing fund, calories, and the stock market. I have never cared about &quot;solar terms&quot;, and I don&#39;t know what is better in various solar terms. Just like I have never cared about, grandma may no longer be able to fully understand my language. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I was a child, I didn’t like festivals and didn’t pay attention to the sense of ritual, because I found them cumbersome and formalized behaviors seemed too nihilistic and false to me. I didn&#39;t quite understand why there were so many festivals, and why so many customs and habits had to be established for each festival? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Now that I have grown up, I don’t have to be forced to celebrate festivals or abide by annoying customs and habits. I can order any takeout I want every day, or I can often visit Internet celebrity restaurants with my colleagues and friends. However, when my friends’ parents invited me to their homes to celebrate the Lantern Festival, Dragon Boat Festival, and Mid-Autumn Festival, I faced the table with delicious food and wine, and looked at the aging but happy faces of my friends’ parents, and I realized that this is a festival. This is the meaning of the sense of ritual. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From then on, I also started to look at the calendar in advance, remembering each festival or solar term, and sent a voice message to my grandma: &quot;It&#39;s the beginning of winter, don&#39;t forget to eat dumplings!&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&amp;ldquo;Get on the bus and get the dumplings off the noodles&amp;rdquo;, being&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;loved&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;always Be confident&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking at the calendar, the latest solar term is &quot;Beginning of Winter&quot; - well, a day when you must eat dumplings. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I think back to the last time I ate dumplings, it was New Year’s Eve. I was still &quot;forced&quot; to finish the task after eating two or three, and went to bed early to sleep. I remember when I was a child, I had to stay up all night to &quot;stay up&quot; on New Year&#39;s Eve, or at least I had to stay awake until 12 o&#39;clock in the middle of the night. The arrival of the New Year is a new beginning, and it is a very exciting time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, this habit has disappeared since I started working. Since New Year&#39;s Eve, I have been thinking about the worry of going back to work for seven days in a row. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;People after work pay more attention to the immediate interests that are visible and tangible, and gradually do not touch the imagination about tomorrow and the future, because the situation is constantly changing, and expectations will always be disappointed. It is better to start early Go to sleep, keep your spirits up, and continue building bricks tomorrow. The performance and bonuses you get in exchange seem to be more practical and useful. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;My mouth and appetite seem to have been fed into the shape of a takeout box and the smell of a restaurant kitchen. My view of the world seems to have been limited to a certain time and space, where it is boring and tired, but regular and stable. My attitude towards life seems to have become unclear. I haven&#39;t been &quot;prejudiced&quot; against anyone for a long time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It sounds like life is miserable. Actually no, we are still busy pursuing career goals and realizing self-worth during the day, but occasionally we feel deserted at night when we feel &quot;something is missing&quot;. But didn’t Mu Xin say: “The best state of life is a deserted and peaceful life.” &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But if you think about it this way, isn&#39;t &quot;pursuing career and self-realization&quot; during the day a sense of ritual? The sense of ritual is the opposite of the &quot;sense of daily life&quot;, and it is also a relationship between yin and yang that are dependent on each other and refer to each other. To live, people need coordinates, scales, schedules, time, other people&#39;s evaluations, etc. as a reference for the process of life. Without these reference points, our lives would be chaotic. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When we occasionally think of some old friends, or a very beautiful moment in the past suddenly comes to mind, that moment must have happened on a special day or occasion. Otherwise, with our limited brain capacity, how can we remember so many things. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Even if it is good, it will eventually be forgotten. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So, it is the solar terms, festivals, rituals, and customs that have engraved our chaotic history and held down our fleeting memories. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I don’t know if you have this saying: &quot;Get on the bus and get the dumplings off the noodles.&quot; It is said that when you see someone off from home, you should make dumplings for him to eat, and when you welcome someone back home, you should cook noodles for him. Needless to say, as a kid who hated eating pasta, I used to find this baseless statement absurd. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Now that I work and live in Beijing, every time I leave or return home on a business trip or trip, I no longer have the concerns and worries of &quot;dumplings on the bus&quot; and &quot;noodles on the bus&quot;. The treatment is good, but I have prepared this two-piece set for myself several times, so I feel safe when traveling and feel at ease when I return home. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Perhaps food is also a symbol, a map of the food we have eaten, and then forms a language. So, when I couldn&#39;t help but cook dumplings and noodles for myself, who was I talking to? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A passage written by Chen Xiaoqing in &quot;The Best Taste in the World&quot; is very touching: &quot;Everyone&#39;s stomach actually has a door, and the key is the food code given to you by your parents and elders in childhood.&quot; No matter where you wander, the door may have been dilapidated, but the combination lock on the door is still closed, waiting for the awakening of your childhood taste imagination. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After reading this passage, the first picture that came to my mind was that during the Chinese New Year when I was a child, the family gathered together to make dumplings, cook dumplings, and eat dumplings. This is the first time of the year. The most solemn ceremony in life. Whenever I think of this scene, my sense of taste seems to go back to that time, when I eat dumplings that are warm in my stomach, with the aroma of wheat mixed with the aroma of meat and vegetables. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is also the aftertaste of the elders in the family smoking, the smell of dumpling vinegar on the tip of the tongue and hovering in the air... It turns out that people need a sense of ritual. Ritual is a medium that helps us record the feelings of those beautiful moments and even takes us back in time. Without rituals, life would have no nodes and memories would be a blur. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It turns out that when people are loved, they will definitely feel confident. Only when they no longer have the companionship, admonishment, and entrustment full of rituals in life can they realize its importance. During the ceremony, I could see &quot;me&quot; only when someone showed concern. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Winter is still here, romance&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;does not&lt;/strong>;&lt;strong>;die&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;Although I am a &quot;newcomer&quot; in terms of solar terms, if I think about it carefully, some national traditions have actually been written in my blood for a long time. Just like the air, they seem to be absent, but in fact they are everywhere. For example, for &quot; &quot;Four Seasons Alternation&quot; is my true love for this natural mechanism. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Especially after I stayed in Australia for several years, I cherished the very regular rotation of the four seasons even more after returning to my country, because for me, a northerner, winter in Australia is not like winter, and summer is not like summer. Many emotions that can only come from experiencing the four seasons are lost. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Soda Green has a four-part album series, which is my favorite concept album: &quot;Spring Sunlight&quot;, &quot;Summer Frenzy&quot;, &quot;Autumn Story&quot; and &quot;Winter is Not Ended&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This album is inspired by Vivaldi&#39;s Violin Concerto &quot;The Four Seasons&quot;. From this point of view, the four seasons are the common wealth of all mankind, inspiring creative inspiration in various fields, but they are subtle and graceful. The Chinese with ancient culture and history have broken down the four seasons into a more subtle and mysterious way. The names of the 24 solar terms are all composed of two characters, which are as concise and beautiful as poetry. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Winter snow, summer cicadas, autumn coolness, spring plowing, some simple and common rhetoric can already describe the &quot;four seasons&quot; beautifully, not to mention the Waking of Insects, Grain Rain, Ear Grains, White Dew, Autumn Equinox, Beginning of Winter, Big Cold... I have been very fond of the climate with four distinct seasons since I was a child. I feel that the law of the four seasons is a natural gift. I have a close friend. When we first met in college, we asked each other what was our favorite season? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The answer was unanimous: the turn of spring and summer. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yes, even though I am now thirty years old and my mind is filled with trivial matters at work and family every day, every year in May, I still can’t help but look forward to the future. The climate affects the body and The spirit is the hope brought about by the change of weather from cold to warm and the recovery of all things. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The movie &quot;The Shawshank Redemption&quot;, which I have watched three times, said: &quot;Hope is a beautiful thing, maybe the most beautiful thing in the world, and beautiful things never die.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I believe so. We live by hope. After winter, spring will come. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;But having said that, winter itself is wonderful enough. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mu Xin said: &quot;If you don&#39;t come, it will snow.&quot; &amp;rdquo;With just this sentence, I seemed to be instantly drawn into a snowy winter day. In winter, I like to walk on the snow-covered streets, with my eyelashes covered with snow and frost, my feet crunching, listening to my favorite music in my headphones, and then walking into a coffee shop with a burning stove and ordering a cup of white coffee. , took out &quot;Snow Country&quot; by Kawabata Yasunari, which I have read three times... How wonderful it would be if time stopped at this moment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I’m afraid that human beings are like me. They always think about spring in winter, so they can’t live well in spring, summer, autumn and winter... So, how should we deal with it? How about welcoming the change of seasons? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Baidu Encyclopedia says: Beginning of Winter is the beginning of winter. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Baidu Encyclopedia also said: Winter is the end and the collection of all things; winter is the season to enjoy the harvest and recuperate. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I realized that the &quot;Book of Changes&quot; says that everything has yin and yang. The two forces are like the action force and the reaction force in physics. The same sex repels and the opposite sex attracts. Both are indispensable. The beginning of winter is the end and conclusion of the year, as well as the hibernation and preparation for the new year. The so-called &quot;beginning of winter&quot; is the time when the old and the new are handed over. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Do you still remember Soda Green’s &quot;Winter is Ending&quot; mentioned earlier? It’s not over yet, continue, that’s exactly what it means. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So, this year I want to take the day of &quot;Beginning of Winter&quot; seriously. I will write a diary to summarize my growth and losses in 2023, and plan carefully what I should do throughout the winter of 2023 to deepen myself, and accumulate strength in an attitude of dormancy and preparation. Wait for spring and then go to work again. In other words, in winter, look inside and cultivate yourself, and in spring, go outside and be a useful person to society. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition, in addition to accumulating strength, my expectations for myself this winter also include some romantic feelings. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The rotation of the four seasons determines the changes in cold and warm weather and describes the changes in the life of crops. What’s even more amazing is that the understanding and definition of seasons reveal the romantic feelings humans have given to the world. The awe and appreciation of nature are the most elementary but also the most precious romance that human beings can contribute. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Because sincere and touching confessions in ancient and modern times, both at home and abroad, are all related to natural and celestial phenomena:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mu Xin: &quot;If you don&#39;t come, it will snow.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Natsume Soseki: &amp;ldquo;The moonlight is so beautiful tonight. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jay Chou: &amp;ldquo;The sky is blue waiting for mist and rain, and I’m waiting for you...&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fitzgerald: &amp;ldquo;The last afterglow brings romance The colors illuminated her face with energy, and her beautiful voice attracted me to hold my breath and lean forward to listen. After a moment, the look disappeared, and each ray left her reluctantly, like a child leaving a fun-filled street at dusk. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The four seasons remain, and romance never dies. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So, how to start this winter? My suggestion is of course to write a diary, eat a meal of dumplings, and officially celebrate the beginning of winter. Otherwise, you will be like me, writing such a large article to reflect on yourself one day in the future. In addition to nostalgia, you will still miss it, and you will only cherish it. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor: Mei Butan&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Today is the beginning of winter, be warm and happy. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/Ftqz_TbzHIaiFJ0m5YDWDERprh0k&quot; alt=&quot;小桃风&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;小桃风&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@是小桃风&lt;/span >; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;An ordinary person. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/article/6131&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;The composition of a home&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Yi Chaonan&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr >; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Read&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6023&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div >;Great Heat&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Written by Wang Xiaofeng&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6154)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4050]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4192]]><description>&lt;div>;8 Nov. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FpTtztlHSSDbnxRlLFpMIqqCSWw3&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;VOL.4050&lt;/span>;Photography | Emma Ou&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;8&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Nov. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Life is not Transient, transient is human. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot; color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>