<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[年轻人vs职场，到底谁整顿了谁？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3931]]><description> &lt;div>;7 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Have you eaten rice dumplings on Christmas?&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p>;Young people vs. the workplace, who is rectifying whom? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; Rabbit grass answer&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original -src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FhaUl2r0KoUPTWfMStM6DID4VmwZ&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FhaUl2r0KoUPTWfMStM6DID4VmwZ&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;The concept of &quot;young people reorganizing the workplace&quot; has actually been popular for a while. It sounds quite refreshing at first glance. It seems that the arrival of young people has improved the workplace ecology that has been criticized for a long time. But if you think about it carefully, those young people who take action to rectify the workplace have more or less several characteristics. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;1. Young enough and fearless enough&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Never I only heard that the post-00s generation was rectifying the workplace, but I never saw the post-80s generation take action. The post-80s generation will always be a submissive model in the workplace. Do those born in the 1980s really don’t want to fall out with their annoying boss and go home immediately after get off work? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Obviously, the problem is that the burden placed on those born in the 1980s is too heavy. All of them, some old at the top and young at the bottom, are completely typical examples of being manipulated by a harsh workplace. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Look at the lively post-00s generation who have just left campus. Because they are young, they have no burden. At worst, they will have to buy two less clothes and eat two less meals. If this company is unhappy today, I can go to that company tomorrow. It’s not like he wouldn’t do this at the age of thirty-five. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;2. The family is well off and there is a way out&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;First grade In the variety show, Xi Rui, a debater famous for &quot;Qi Pa Shuo&quot;, said: &quot;The topic of rectifying the workplace is false, because there are people who have choices in every era.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong>;After finishing speaking, he gave an example: If there is a hot pot restaurant at home, you can raise your head when talking in the office. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Having worked in Beijing and Shanghai for many years, I have a great impression. Those who are more &quot;cowardly&quot; at work and more obedient are foreigners, while local colleagues are more difficult to manage. Some. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some HRs even directly say that they don’t like to recruit local people under the influence of wolf culture. &lt;strong>;Locals own houses and have a way out, and they are less likely to be domesticated in the workplace. But for non-locals who want to rent a house and make money, there is almost no way out. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So, the topic of &lt;strong>;&quot;Young people reorganizing the workplace&quot; is actually a pseudo-concept, which contains a fearless attitude of young people who have just left school. At the same time, there are also some humorous self-deprecations by some veteran social workers in the workplace. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I know many people born in the 1980s. In fact, they generally have a negative attitude towards this topic. They feel that young people today are too difficult to manage and too unwilling to endure hardships. , and smug. But the problem is, everyone comes here from a young age. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Today’s workplace ecological environment is actually different from what it was ten years ago, or even five years ago. And young people grow up in different environments and want different things. It is understandable that they are beginning to wake up. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In an era when material was not abundant, people wanted to make money. As long as they made money, it was no problem to work overtime and stay up late. After decades of development, we have already moved from food and clothing to an era where we need more spiritual sustenance and a sense of value. For today&#39;s young people, what they want in the workplace must be completely different from previous generations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So, young people VS the workplace, who has rectified whom? Is there a standard answer to this question? I don&#39;t think so. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Who can rectify whom? Ultimately, it is a question of the right to speak and the right to bargain. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;1. When there is no &quot;bargaining power&quot;, talking about rectifying the workplace can only be a fantasy. Tan&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For most of us social workers with mediocre families, the word &quot;rectification&quot; is actually a bit too much. There is a word on the Internet called &quot;Kouha&quot;, and the so-called &quot;rectification of the workplace&quot; is mostly just words. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If cleaning up the workplace was really a popular narrative that everyone could practice, then the concept of cool writing would not exist. It is precisely because most social workers are trapped in the workplace and cannot stand up, that they are obsessed with various disguised &quot;workplace rectification&quot; videos on short video platforms. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The so-called &quot;bargaining power&quot; is actually like playing poker. What you are playing against is the workplace. Whether you can win depends on whether the cards in your hand are strong or not. . &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If your family can provide you with an escape route and you are exceptionally good, then if something unpleasant happens to you, it’s okay to leave with your bags or scold the leader angrily. But in the current harsh economic environment, it is best to consider whether your wallet is full. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;>;&lt;strong>;2. If you want to rectify the workplace, it cannot be achieved by willfulness&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;&amp;nbsp;If you want to develop rapidly in a company or industry, you still have to consider the consequences of everything. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sometimes, a moment of &quot;rectifying the workplace&quot; brings enough pleasure, but no one can tell you the answer to the road ahead. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Think about the consequences of everything&quot; is by no means empty talk, it is more like the condensed wisdom of the older generation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are so many smart people who have not solved the problems in the workplace for so many years. Can a newcomer who is just starting out and has no money really solve the problem? &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Fight, wait and see, give it a try, don’t kill your own path. &lt;/strong>;Don’t act impulsively before you have accumulated enough energy, because for most ordinary people from ordinary families, going to work is the only way to earn income. If this road is blocked, it will not do you any good. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For young people, there are many ways to gain a sense of value, and they do not necessarily have to be obsessed with the workplace itself. &lt;strong>;Many times, impulsiveness cannot solve problems, and following trends can easily put yourself in danger. The important thing is to understand where you come from and where you plan to go. &lt;/strong>;The workplace is just one of the arenas in our lives. It is not too late to break out of this limitation when we have accumulated enough energy and capital. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Zhou Ziheng onewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;For information on the call for papers, please see the @ONE Studio pinned on Weibo. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FmIxumvucSMThvBqzjla4dEmFbwL &quot; alt=&quot;Rabbit Grass&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Rabbit Grass&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@Rabbit Grass Tucao&lt;/span>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style =&quot;&quot;>;Retired copywriter, juggling writer. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Question and Answer&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/question/3922&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Life is not bad, but where does the pressure come from? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3919&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Why are some people afraid of praise? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3931)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[最]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6109]]><description> &lt;div>;7 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Article A or B&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt; img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fg2hsdtPnfe0S7mDmALsiPG2NRZY&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fg2hsdtPnfe0S7mDmALsiPG2NRZY&quot;>;&lt;/ div>;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Xiaobai, a male classmate who had not been in contact for ten years, suddenly contacted Chen Fei and started pursuing her . After ten years of separation, either she was the best and was so good that people tolerated her for ten years, or she was the worst and was so bad that she had no choice but to be chosen after ten years. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen Fei and Xiaobai lost contact after they separated arts and sciences in their sophomore year of high school. It was 2012. Chen Fei only read books about sages and didn&#39;t even register a QQ account. Naturally, she didn&#39;t join the class group. Xiaobai asked a lot of people before getting her WeChat account from another mutual friend. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xiaobai saw recent photos in her circle of friends and said, you have obviously matured a lot. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nonsense. Chen Fei typed these two words, deleted them, and wrote them again: Of course, I was seventeen or eighty-eight last time we met, and now I am twenty-seven or eighty-eight. Let me look at you. Are you old? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xiaobai sent a photo of four people in a Martian town, saying it was taken during a trip organized by the company. Xiaobai is standing in the back row, second from the right, and the first from the right is a girl, her head slightly tilted towards him, just like when taking wedding photos. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I feel like there is a student in my class who looks quite similar to you. Sent by Fei Chen. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;How is he studying?&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Not very well. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xiaobai turned around. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen Fei took another look at the group photo and typed to ask, is that person standing next to you your girlfriend? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That’s a colleague, I’m still single. What about you, have you got it yet? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Single...but it can’t be said that I am not settled. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yes, yes, I am not careful with my words. Well, is your family urging you to go on a blind date? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We met once last year and didn’t want to go again. When I met a strange guy, he asked me how many boyfriends I had. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xiaobai made a [baring teeth] expression and asked, have you told him? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;No. I waved my hand to him and asked him to change the topic. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So how many have you talked about? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen Fei searched for a suitable expression on the keyboard, such as [embarrassed], [surprised], [cold sweat], but Xiaobai then added: Just kidding. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May, Xiaobai volunteered to accompany Chen Fei to Weifang to take the teacher&#39;s examination. Previously, Chen Fei had been a substitute teacher in the city&#39;s junior high school for one year, teaching two classes of English. Chen Fei asked on WeChat, &quot;Don&#39;t you have a day off on Saturday?&quot; Xiaobai said that he wanted to go out for a walk. When is the exam specifically? Chen Fei said that he immediately booked high-speed rail tickets for two people on Alipay. Chen Fei&#39;s WeChat transfer was returned by Xiaobai - just come to Weifang and treat me to a meal, followed by a [baring teeth] emoticon. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The tickets were bought together and the seats were right next to each other. Although they didn&#39;t say a few words during the whole process, it was still a very special experience: watching the passing sky outside the window together, it was like spending an hour together. After more than ten years of walking side by side. In the compressed time, the dialogue is folded, but don’t be afraid of being unable to express it. When this journey of 300 kilometers per hour continues to slow down in your memories, what you have said and what you have not said will be revealed one page after another. The page opens. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I arrived in Weifang at three o&#39;clock in the afternoon, went to see the examination room immediately, and then had dinner at a nearby KFC. Xiaobai ordered deep-sea whole shrimp burgers and cranberry cherry juice at the counter. Chen Fei ordered the classic beef burger and hot milk. After ordering, she remembered that she had forgotten to fulfill her previous promise to treat Xiaobai to dinner. Xiaobai said, next time, next time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two of them found an empty seat with their dinner plates and sat down one behind the other. Chen Fei took a sip of milk and pushed the beef burger aside. &amp;ldquo;Forgot one more thing. ” She said, “I don’t want to eat cow meat and drink cow milk at the same time. &quot;Xiaobai smiled and exchanged his cranberry and cherry juice for her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen Fei licked the milk at the corner of her mouth, not hinting at anything, but Xiaobai understood and replaced her beef burger with shrimp burger. He took a sip of milk, ate a bite of beef, and said, I will be the bad guy. After hearing this, Chen Fei was a little touched. The person in front of her was willing to bear things that she didn&#39;t want to bear. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I always feel that you have been in love several times. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Xiaobai heard this, he looked up at Chen Fei and said, &quot;What should I say?&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Intuition, I can&#39;t provide any evidence.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Then your intuition is wrong. I talked about one in college. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Who is chasing whom? &quot;If this was a chat on WeChat, Chen Fei would definitely add a [laughing] expression after this sentence, but in reality, she couldn&#39;t make that mean expression at all, so she could only try her best to The tone was relaxed, making people think it was a casual question. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I must have chased her,&amp;rdquo;Xiao Bai said, &amp;ldquo;It should have been a long time ago. In the second year after graduation, we were completely over. School and outside school were two completely different worlds. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After walking out of KFC, it was getting dark. They stayed in the hotel and went to the examination room early tomorrow morning. Of course, two rooms were opened. At around eight o&#39;clock, Chen Fei was reviewing when she heard a knock on the door. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;So hardworking. &quot;Xiao Bai walked in, went around to the back of the door and checked the keyhole, &quot;I&#39;m here to test for you whether there is any secret camera equipment in the room. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Oh, I just flipped through it casually, feeling very guilty. &quot;Chen Fei said and sat back at the small table, wanting to continue answering questions, but the shoes walking around kept distracting her attention. I remember that I just met Xiaobai at the high-speed rail station this afternoon. His Hongxing Erke was spotless, but it was now showing signs of wear and tear. She put down the carbon pen and said to Xiaobai who was checking the socket, &quot;I haven&#39;t thanked you yet for coming so far to accompany me.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Don’t be so polite. &quot;Xiao Bai put down the socket, walked into the bathroom again, and came out two minutes later, &quot;This room is quite safe.&quot; You can review. I won&#39;t disturb you anymore. If you need anything, call me. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Well, okay. &amp;rdquo;Chen Fei picked up the pen holder and wrote a B on the real test paper. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xiaobai walked out of the room slowly, and was about to close the door with one hand when he suddenly turned around and called her name. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;What’s wrong? &amp;rdquo;Chen Fei didn&#39;t even raise her head. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;I want to go as far as possible with you... I mean, get closer. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen Fei raised the corners of her mouth, &amp;ldquo;Do you want to go further or get closer? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;One meaning, do you really not understand it? &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Understood, I will seriously consider it, but tonight, I have to review first. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xiao Bai nodded and closed the door. The room became quiet again, but Chen Fei had no intention of writing anymore and stared blankly at the cloudy night sky outside the window. Someone reappears after ten years of absence. From the perspective of an old friend, it is a surprise, but from the perspective of a lover, it is not a surprise. She hoped that Xiaobai could explain these ten years. Without an explanation, she could only figure it out on her own. The most idealistic assumption is that inferiority holds him back. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Inferiority is one of the main variants of love. No matter how good a person is, he will feel inferior in front of the person he really likes. If someone is full of superiority when they are with you, they will not respect you after all, and furthermore, they won’t like you that much. The young man trekked for ten years before he got out of the depression in his heart and stepped into a place where he could live and settle down. He rested for a few nights and dreamed of the person he liked at that time every night, so he hit the road again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This assumption was quickly overturned. Xiaobai doesn&#39;t have low self-esteem. Even if he doesn&#39;t go to college, he can still bravely pursue the person he likes. His delicate and considerate nature could only have been trained at that time. Chen Fei closed the review materials and carefully recalled her high school days while brushing her teeth. She was taciturn and never had any conflicts with anyone, because she felt that she could not win against others, either in terms of physical appearance or words. She is the one with low self-esteem. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Either you are the best, so good that people tolerate it for ten years, or you are the worst, so bad that you have no choice but to choose after ten years. Let’s look at four years of college and six years of work. Xiaobai didn’t even have any news. She suddenly appeared ten years later. Maybe it was because she couldn’t find a suitable one in her original circle. Only then did she think of her as an honest girl and her daily life. No maintenance is required, just put on the axle and go on the road, spare tire. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At almost ten o&#39;clock, Xiaobai sent a message from next door: One hour of review is enough, go to bed early. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In fact, Chen Fei had turned off the lights and lay down. She looked at the wall between them, with the moonlight shining on it. She thought about what to say. She typed in the dialog box: I just recalled that when we were in high school, we really had nothing in common. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xiaobai replied, yes, everyone was busy studying at that time. But now we are starting to intersect. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Well, thank you for running around with me today. She wrote this sentence. This is the second thank you tonight. The first time was when she tried to get close to Xiao Bai, and the second time was when she gave up the idea. She returned to her original position, where she should be, as if she had never moved. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;mdash;&amp;mdash;I told you, can you not be so polite? There was another [baring teeth] expression behind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen Fei kind of hates this expression now. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She did not reply. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Early the next morning, Chen Fei walked into the examination room under Xiao Bai&#39;s watch. After the exam, she had lunch at a nearby fast food restaurant. This time, Chen Fei remembered to pay the bill. In the checkout line, she stood in front of Xiao Bai from the beginning. When it was their turn, she pointed directly at the two rectangular dinner plates and told the waiter that they should be tied together. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After lunch, Chen Fei was going to Changqing District to take the next exam. Since there was no conflict in time, she applied to be a teacher in two districts at the same time. However, what she really wants to test is the establishment of her hometown, but the test time has not yet been announced, and Weifang and Changqing are the two places to practice. Xiaobai pushed open the glass door of the fast food restaurant and asked Chen Fei, are you leaving now? Chen Fei said, well, I bought tickets for both of us last night. Xiaobai put away his phone. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the high-speed train, two people no longer sit side by side, nor across from each other, nor even next to each other. They are separated by several rows of strangers. Xiaobai watched Fei Chen sit down next to an aunt, then looked at his ticket, and asked: &quot;Didn&#39;t we buy our tickets together? Why are we so far apart?&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Yes,&amp;rdquo; Chen Fei also pretended to be confused, &amp;ldquo;I don’t know what’s going on. You go and sit down first, we&#39;ll be there in an hour anyway. &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xiao Bai turned around and went back. Chen Fei put on Bluetooth headphones and browsed Douyin. On the way, she caught a glimpse of Xiaobai looking at her while crossing the aisle, and she focused more on the phone screen. Most of the background music on Douyin selects the chorus or the most beautiful lines and repeats them repeatedly. She feels that her ears have been spoiled. Not only does she have to hear the most beautiful part of a song at the beginning, but also after that. Just listen to this part. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jinan West Railway Station is not far from Xiaobai&#39;s unit. Chen Fei asked him to go back and work, &quot;I am already familiar with the following process.&quot; &amp;rdquo;Xiaobai insisted on taking a taxi to Chen Fei and took her to the booked hotel. He said: &quot;Don&#39;t feel bad. It&#39;s not you who is troubling me this time, it&#39;s me who is troubling you.&quot; &amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen Fei said how could it be possible, but she also understood the meaning in her heart. Last night in Weifang, he asked her to make a choice, and she had to give an answer. The answer can be given in two or three sentences, or you can let the other party understand it through constant hints. Rather than breaking up on bad terms, everyone should try their best to choose the latter option so that each other can escape unscathed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When Xiaobai asked to have dinner or play together again, Chen Fei&#39;s excuses changed from the previous ones: &quot;There are more classes today&quot;; &quot;I have to stay and study at night&quot;; &quot;I will definitely do it next time&quot;. In the middle period, &quot;too lazy to move&quot;, &quot;it depends on the situation&quot;, &quot;going home to take my grandma&#39;s blood pressure&quot; and then to the late period, Gu Zuoyuan, it is a process from realism to freehand brushwork. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Replying messages is getting slower and slower, sometimes every one day, sometimes every two days. If someone ignored her like this, she would have blocked them long ago. But Xiaobai just lowered his expectations and asked in his last WeChat chat, is there still a chance to see each other again? Nothing else, just meet up. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen Fei was very happy. This guy finally got the idea and was about to give up. But there is really no point in seeing each other again. She believes that if she wants it, she can get the explanation, explanation or a smooth lie she wants. The atmosphere has arrived, even if it sounds fake, it is touching, but we cannot always stand under the dyed lights of the theater. We will eventually walk through the dim corridors and return to ordinary alleys, facing each other face to face every day and every night. At that time, Are you still in the mood to lie? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She replied to Xiaobai like this: I feel that our personalities are not suitable for each other. I have never been embarrassed to tell you. You can find someone else. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I heard similar excuses before and thought they were cliche. After personal experience, I realized that &quot;inappropriate&quot; is the most suitable, gentle and non-irritating. You don&#39;t need to point out the other person&#39;s mistakes all the time. If he is wrong with you, it may not be the case with others. Some people will care about whether they are the other person&#39;s first and firm choice for a while, but if they get along well later, it doesn&#39;t matter. Some people will always care, never be able to convince themselves, and always remain prejudiced. She admits this is her bias. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xiaobai said, OK. Then everyone was relieved. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I forgot that it was the morning of the first few days after the disconnection. There was drizzle outside the window, and Chen Fei was clearing away the lesson plans on the coffee table. Her mother called and said that the son of her father’s old classmate would come home for dinner in the evening. Chen Fei went over to chat with someone. She didn&#39;t act coy as before, and agreed happily in her heart. Mom also told me to go home early in the evening and make dumplings together, stuffed with beef and green onions. She said, OK, I&#39;ll go there after get off work. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After hanging up the phone, Fei Chen took a box of yogurt for breakfast as usual, but after weighing it, he put it back in the refrigerator. She did not want to eat cow meat and drink cow milk in one day. Twenty minutes later, I bought a cup of red date and soy milk from a steaming breakfast stall in front of the school. It tasted good. She was not completely changed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That night, Chen Fei met the son of her father&#39;s old classmate. She felt that it was okay, but he didn&#39;t like her. Not being able to meet someone you like is not the risk of going on a blind date, but meeting someone you like but they don&#39;t like you is. Think about it again, this is not just a blind date risk, you fall in love with anyone anywhere, there is such a risk. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In July, after passing the interview as a teacher in her hometown, Chen Fei was officially assigned to a junior high school in a neighboring county, where she met her sweetheart. That guy&#39;s surname was Jin. He once represented the school and won the best soloist at the city&#39;s faculty and staff National Day performance. He also smashed a colleague&#39;s house to pieces because of his drunkenness. In addition, Chen Fei doesn&#39;t know enough about his past. What is certain is that they became a couple when they first met each other. Therefore, she firmly believes that if they met ten years ago, they would have known each other ten years ago. Together. She will be sweet to this destined person for a while, and no matter what changes happen, she will try her best to survive her whole life. Whether we lived happily or not is beyond the scope of this story. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Mei Butan&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see the @ONE studio pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FscLfk-7PTXX7lPE2CpPW0OHSy7b&quot; alt=&quot;A or B&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;A or B&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span >; &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Young authors. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/article/6072&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Touch&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/A or B&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Read&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/6036&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>; Line up to go to the party&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/A or B&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text -align:center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6109)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt; /div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4018]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4157]]><description>&lt;div>;7 Oct. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FuSzih6tky1HuEmtWi9M_EVcslr8&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p >;&lt;span>;VOL.4018&lt;/span>;Photography | Caleb George&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;7&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Oct. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p>;I sometimes I wonder if I really don’t need other people that much, or if I just keep my distance because I can’t be myself when I’m with them. Our conversations were like parallel soliloquies with no overlap. What we share may be nothing more than mutual incomprehension. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>