<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>ONE·one</title><description> ONE · One full-text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://wufazhuce.com <item><title><![CDATA[朋友有了新朋友，友谊顺位下跌怎么办？]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/question/3999]]><description> &lt;div>;6 Dec. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;div>; Oh, Ah Piao asked&lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;margin-top: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;p >;What should I do if my friend has a new friend and the friendship ranking drops? &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; A Mingzi answered&lt;/div>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data- original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgNrc_IVySykGahrke5jPHnGhFqb&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/FgNrc_IVySykGahrke5jPHnGhFqb&quot;>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;Maybe it’s related to my age and wandering around. I have a lot of friends. Of course, I know that the core of this problem is that this &quot;friend&quot; is the kind of friend that is difficult to replace. I just want to explain why this situation happens from my own perspective. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At different stages of life and in different places, I have been a core friend of some people. Later, there are always some friends who will be replaced for various reasons, including childhood playmates, classmates who go to and from school together, teammates on the college basketball team, partners at work, people with common interests and hobbies... ;All good things come to an end. &amp;rdquo;&amp;ldquo;In the end, they were all scattered in the wind. &amp;rdquo;No, in fact, most of them still keep in touch, but we know each other very well. Made new friends, closer friends. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;How did these things happen? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Childhood playmates, childhood classmates, we have been separated for a long time. At that time, the common fun in each other&#39;s eyes was also used to bring back memories. and things to laugh at. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The reasons for separation from other friends are basically similar. We went to different places and had different lives. Our understanding and cognition were also changing. At some points, we would naturally devote ourselves to new things. Go in the environment and communication. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I will make new discoveries and new possibilities, and I will recommend them to my friends, but he may not be interested. Will I lose interest because of this? Do I want to be on the same frequency with him all the time? Do you want to hold on to what you have? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;No, because I know that this kind of friendship will turn into a bond. People are always individuals and live in groups whose boundaries are constantly expanding. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is how I choose and treat my friends, so I should also accept the fact that I am replaced by others in the eyes of the friends I value. In my opinion, this is a &quot;natural&quot; attribute and is in line with the laws of development of things. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When you first realize the direction and shift in the focus of friendship, you will inevitably feel reluctant to let go, not understand, feel a little disappointed or complain, but calm down and judge based on the specific reasons, you will find that things will work out. It actually makes sense to happen. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If it is reasonable, it will be easier for people to accept. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Friends belong to the &quot;emotional&quot; level in a sense, and sensibility is actually the most susceptible to change and deviation. In fact, the so-called sensibility can be analyzed rationally. Friends are often a kind of &quot;need&quot; and &quot;help&quot;. These two words are not snobbish in the practical sense, but refer more to emotional value. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When a friend you value very much has a better friend, it actually means that he has new &quot;needs&quot; and needs some kind of &quot;help&quot;. For example, someone can help you. Talking to him about deeper topics can allow him to have better communication in areas of interest, etc. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;From a friend&#39;s perspective, I would be happy for him, and I believe he would understand if the same situation happened to me. Otherwise, what kind of friends are we? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Of course, I will still cherish this friend, and I will also be curious about his new friends. I will make my own judgment on whether I can become friends with his new friends. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Whether it is becoming friends with his new friends, or I have more time and energy to meet new friends, it is a good thing, our boundaries are expanding. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If you draw the ground as a prison, you will only see the sky at the mouth of the well, and you will think that is all. Try to open more maps, go around more, accept changes, and enrich your life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So, as long as they are friends, it’s good enough,&amp;nbsp;it doesn’t matter where they are. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The most critical question is always whether you are the first position in your own heart. This is not selfish, but you should never look at your position with others as the center. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;You yourself are the center, and those around you are constantly rotating. The so-called positions that change are others. &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor in charge: Nanaonewenti@wufazhuce.com&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see @ONE Studio’s pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. For more interesting daily news in the editorial department, please follow Xiaohongshu: ONE Editorial Department. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Respondent&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fmxa2oRzrp7_P6oM1q -q0orw7KUD&quot; alt=&quot;Ah Ming Tsai&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Ah Ming Tsai &lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;@_阿明泽&lt;/span>; &lt;/div >; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;Freelance Writing/Art&lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/ span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>; Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3998&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Why do people show different &quot;personalities&quot; when faced with different environments? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Q&amp;A&lt;/span>; &lt; /td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/question/3996&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Is &quot;I am born to be useful&quot; a scam? &lt;/div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>;&lt;div style=&quot;text-align:center ;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(4,3999)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 06 Dec 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[小镇病人]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/article/6179]]><description>&lt;div>;6 Dec. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;Tang Chong&lt;/p>; &lt;div>; &lt;p>;&lt;div contenteditable=&quot;false&quot;>;&lt;img data-author=&quot;&quot; data-original-src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fv2fgzlVt42wEnKQ0hx9MBiOfoLn&quot; data-source=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fv2fgzlVt42wEnKQ0hx9MBiOfoLn&quot;>;&lt;/div >;&lt;div>;&lt;div style=&quot;font-size:26px;line-height: 1;&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Distant friends, this is a letter from me. About hometown, about growing up, about life. &lt;/p>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;&lt;br>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hello, Hong. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I was a boy, the two movies that had the greatest impact on me were &quot;The Pianist&quot; and &quot;Sweetie&quot;. The former is a romantic fable, with the ocean, piano, and abandoned cruise ship, hazy and dreamy, making people unable to help but indulge in the fantasy of loneliness. The latter is very realistic. Times have changed. People have left their hometowns for a living. They have exhausted all their tricks and finally become like a leaf of duckweed. This is an unavoidable question that always brings people back to reality. It seems that the former is about loneliness and self, and the latter is about love and times, but I always feel that in the final analysis, these two movies are about the same word, hometown. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is a word that is far away from me. Starting last year, I like to read some authors who write about life and are sensitive to daily emotions. I don&#39;t have the ability to observe and feel life in detail. I envy them for being able to stay in a certain fixed environment and lifestyle for a long time, or in other words, have stayed. I am twenty-four years old this year. I have lived in rural areas for two years, Northeastern for seven years, small towns for four years, Ningxia for one year, Guangdong for one year, and county towns for three years. This is my sixth year in Chengdu, and I have moved countless times in these six years. How many times have I cleaned my house? Life is not stable, and times are changing too fast. Like a person lost in the forest, he can only remain uneasy and awake all the time, and naturally it is difficult to calm down and feel. I have traveled to the northeast, northwest, southeast, and southwest, but there is no place I call my hometown. My hometown is a place I can go back to, but they are neither. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For a few years, I also placed my hope on others, but the further I travel, the more I realize that everyone has their own path, and when they reach a fork in the road, they will eventually part ways. Although everyone will have different people and different lives at different stages, which seems wonderful and has many possibilities, the fact is that no one person or life really belongs to anyone. People are always passers-by in the world. Without the life experience of staying for a long time, I lack the ability to settle down, so I am still drifting, and I don’t even have the courage to land. Just like 1900 in the movie, he never had the courage to get off the ship that trapped him and see the truly wonderful world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For many years, I was lonely and felt like a patient. So there is Feng Town, that windy and foggy place that always appears in my articles, with forests, terraced fields, mountains, the Jialing River and countless people who want to escape. It is a collection of many small towns in my memory. This fictional place has become my hometown. In the beginning, it was just a field of flowers and meadows, with wind blowing and dandelions flying all over the sky, where I could shout, run and cry freely in those moments of overwhelming uneasiness. Later, some people walked in from the story, and it gradually became broader, with low buildings, winding national roads, rushing rivers and some desires. It began to become concrete and began to connect with life, people, and changes. The big world creates connections. In the past few years when it became wider, some people began to yearn for this place. When I was living in the city and out of breath, I would go to some small towns and small towns to hide. Unexpectedly, in those small places where I escaped from life, You can meet more and more outsiders. I gradually realized that the past few years may have awakened many people and caused many people to suffer from the same disease as me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I started trying to understand more people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lao Tang was sixteen years old when he left his hometown and had just finished his third year of junior high school. He had two choices before him: spend 80 yuan to learn radio from relatives, or learn the carpentry trade from his grandfather at home. But he felt angry and finally chose the third option, traveling far away to work hard. In those few years, young people from my hometown were chasing each other towards the big world. The two places with the most people were Northeast and Guangdong. This can be roughly divided into two kinds of thinking: after the reform and opening up, Guangdong became a dream land, representing chaos and opportunities, so I chose Guangdong boldly and aggressively. As the big brother, the Northeast appears to be stable, and there may not be many opportunities, but the development is mature. As long as you are willing to work, you can always make a living, which makes people feel confident, so those who are timid and seek stability go to the Northeast. Old Tang was the latter. Although he felt uneasy, he still cherished his dream and took the long-distance green train with his fellow villagers to the Northeast, which was about to decline, a distant place that held infinite hope for him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When we arrived in Dalian, the first thing we needed to do was to find food and accommodation, but these two things were not easy. Old Tang and his fellow villagers held up signs on the roadside asking for work, but they couldn&#39;t understand Dalian dialect and couldn&#39;t speak Mandarin well. The boss found it troublesome and would always look for those who could communicate first. When their turn came, they were left with low wages. People do hard work. Even so, there was little life. Little did they know that Northeasterners were also fleeing their hometowns at that time. If your income is small, you have to live frugally. Guo Degang talked about the hard days in the program. He could eat a bowl of batter at three or four in the afternoon to last a whole day. They were the same way. When they were not working, they only had a bowl of batter, two bottles of boiling water, sprinkled with a few grains of salt, and tried to move as little as possible except for work. Housing is another issue. At that time, they lived in Datongpu, where migrant workers from all over the world were crowded together. Money was sewn into their underwear, daggers were hidden under their pillows, and the only exposed belongings were bedding and bowls. The landlord is not far away. If someone checks their temporary residence permit, he will say hello in advance and ask them to hide their things and leave first. One winter night, they were awakened by a knock on the door. When they opened the door, they saw it was someone from the government. After checking, they found that they did not have temporary residence permits, so more than a dozen young people were put on liberation trucks and sent to the reception center in Lushun overnight. The people in the truck were shivering from the cold. Some people were scared and asked, &quot;Will they arrest us and put us in jail?&quot; Old Tang was frightened when he heard this. He waited for the car to reach halfway, took advantage of the slow speed, flipped over the car, and ran as fast as he could, not daring to look back. After running for an unknown amount of time, I was still afraid of someone chasing me, so I hid in a dry drainage ditch and survived the night. Old Tang said that he was so happy when he woke up and found that he was still alive, that kind of pure happiness. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Not long after, he wrote his first letter home after almost a year away from home. There were tears on the paper. A month later, my grandfather wrote back, telling me about the current situation at home, and finally said, be brave, put down roots, and don’t come back. Holding the letter, he didn&#39;t know whether to cry or laugh. He just felt empty in his heart and didn&#39;t know where to go. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This kind of emptiness has turned into another kind of emptiness after more than thirty years. Later, Old Tang stayed in Dalian, learned a trade, and finally found a way out. Then he got married and had children. Ten years later, he got divorced because of a dispute over where to buy a house. My mother wants to stay in Dalian, and he wants to go back to Sichuan. They are two different people. Later, he got a new family and went to Chengdu, Ningxia, and Guangdong. He saved some money and a few houses that he rarely lived in. Finally, he stayed in Tibet and was still the furthest person in the family. This summer, I accompanied Old Tang back to his hometown for a physical examination. In the hospital, he was as quiet as an old man, didn&#39;t know the procedures, and was as cautious as a child. Only then did I realize that he was really getting old. I had to work and was anxious to return to Chengdu, so we went back to town to worship our ancestors after his physical examination. It has been nearly ten years since my grandfather passed away. He burned paper and told the tombstone with a smile that he had been lucky in the past few years. He said that the children have grown up. Then he was silent, lowered his head, shoulders trembling, and made no sound until the sparks in front of the grave were completely extinguished. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past two years, the biggest conflict between Old Tang and I was also the house. He prepared a sum of money, which was enough to make a down payment in Chengdu. My income was gradually increasing, and he hoped that I could buy a house as soon as possible and settle down. But I was very resistant, not because I didn’t want to take on the responsibility or the pressure of a loan, but because I was afraid. I am used to wandering, but I am afraid of stability, afraid that life will turn me into a meek adult. We argued about this several times and got red-faced. This time he saw me off when I left home, but on the way he suddenly asked, &quot;Do you like Chengdu?&quot; I said, I can’t tell whether I like it or not. He said, if you don&#39;t like it, just leave and go to a place you like. I asked, why did you suddenly say this? He said, after this physical examination, I have also figured out that once your mother-in-law dies, we will not be able to come back. Maybe I can come back, but your generation cannot come back. It is better to find a place you like and put down roots. . I asked, what about you? He drove the car without looking at me. He just said, I have my way, you have your way, and when your brother grows up, he will also have his way. This is how life is, walk out of the house and become an adult. There&#39;s no turning back. Not long after, he also returned to Tibet, and posted a message on Moments on the road, a national road covered with snow, with the caption &quot;Let&#39;s go.&quot; He probably liked it there. I often think of his words that day. Only then did I realize that in his tears at the grave, I was also there. We have always been the same, we have the same disease. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the first two years after I arrived in Chengdu, I spent many sunny evenings wandering around the streets, firstly because I wanted to see Chengdu, and secondly because my girlfriend at the time liked walking. We were both poor students at that time. We bought two drinks and walked aimlessly and chatted. We randomly found a restaurant to have dinner. It was the most interesting and cheapest date because we had endless topics to talk about and everything in front of us was... Be fresh. At first, because of my chauvinism, I thought this kind of date was a bit shabby, but she comforted me and said it would be nice if we could be together. She said that walking is a pure exercise that requires no route, equipment, or even companions, but the experience is unique. Walking among the crowd, I feel like waves in the sea. When I am tired from walking, I sit on the roadside and take a rest, and I feel like an island. She said, close your eyes and give it a try. I closed my eyes, still unable to connect myself with the waves and islands, but I imagined drifting alone on the ocean, a vast tranquility, indeed very similar to walking. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I also gradually fell in love with walking, and after the breakup, I discovered the difference between one person and two people. When walking alone, you usually don&#39;t think about anything during the journey, you just feel that the camphor trees are falling leaves, the bougainvillea is blooming, and the long summer is coming quietly. These changes are hidden in time. They are light and difficult to detect. They have their own rhythm of passing, and there is inevitably a slight chill. But together, the two of them focused outward, and the city in front of them began to flow concretely. Workers walking in a hurry with tired eyes, street girls yawning in the alley, owners playing with mobile phones at stalls, and students walking together. Under the sun, the city is running, and the young faces are moving in an orderly manner, representing something that is difficult to change. life order. And we enjoy ourselves outside the order, and because we have someone to keep us company, we have some warm air, so that we will not be overwhelmed by desolation. In the two years after we broke up, I walked a lot of untraveled roads by myself. I could escape life for a short time on the road, and escape the lightness that couldn&#39;t land, but I inevitably thought of her all the time on the road, so I gradually gave up on this project. Hobby. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A word that suddenly became popular this year is city walk, which means walking casually on the street, reaching the intersection and then deciding the direction of the next section of the road, which is just wandering. This kind of activity has caused some controversy, because after being packaged by bloggers, it sounds very much like a group of idle urban youths pretending to enjoy false freedom with coffee. It is quite petty bourgeoisie and deliberate, like a group of empty and vain self-interests. What anist would do. Walking is an interesting thing in itself. The main reason for the prejudice is probably its sense of form. Paying money to go shopping is already outrageous. Chengdu even has a street stroll activity that screens age, occupation and photos, which is too outrageous. But later I discovered that local youths usually do not participate in such activities. They organize activities and charge fees, just like people living on the plateau do not cheer for the blue sky, but only stand on the roadside selling oxygen bottles. I know that among the people who participate in this kind of activity, there are some who are purely passionate, some who are unconventional, and some who have evil intentions, but I still can’t help but wonder if more of them just follow the trend in confusion. These people, like me, who have left their homes and have no one to rely on, do not want to be ahead, but are afraid of being abandoned. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In fact, who is not? Especially in this era of endless new things, full of disputes between the old and the new, if you click on any news, you can immediately see countless interpretations, and they represent countless values. Fellow self-media colleagues make a lot of money by talking about men and women. Bo Man, many people are patriotic in the morning and angry in the afternoon. What should they believe? Everyone knows to think independently, but there are too many voices that can almost affect the facts, so everyone becomes more and more impetuous. Working in a financial company, experts talk about the future. The country is in a period of economic transformation. The future will definitely be dominated by the digital economy. The power of individuals and communities will exceed that of enterprises. Blockchain technology will also make breakthroughs, and everyone will become indispensable. One link, with patience, everyone can live better. They are people with great dreams, and they speak passionately, like The Wolf of Wall Street. I don’t doubt the possibility of this dream coming true. After all, everything is changing rapidly now, and no one can say for sure what it will look like in the end. . I&#39;m just thinking about the cost of this change. The price is to revolutionize the traditional business order and way of life, which means that everything that makes us feel safe is rapidly decaying. But no matter how magnificent the words are, they will eventually fall on people. There are people in the world who dared to go to Guangdong alone to conquer the world thirty or forty years ago, as well as Old Tang. The meek Old Tang, the simple Old Tang, the Old Tang who never wanted to be a social elite or a pillar of the country, what should they do? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;No answer. This is an era that will never last forever. The wind was so strong that we had no choice but to hug a tree. While hugging it tightly, I was worried that it would suddenly fall over. Even in that vibrant financial company, I could see many blank and tired eyes. When I left that company, I was even more convinced that many people suffered from the same disease as me. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The girl I walked with later went to Shenzhen and made some money as a salesperson. She finally changed from ponytail jeans and cartoon sweatshirts to long-haired shirts and woolen windbreakers, becoming what she had longed for. kind of woman. This spring we met. She said she had resigned and was going back to her hometown. I thought she was tired, so I just said, &quot;It&#39;s fine. What are you going to do next?&quot; She said, let’s take the exam, I want to go abroad. I was a little surprised. I don’t seem to know what I want now, she said, but I can’t seem to stop. I don’t know, what about you? I am silent. I can&#39;t answer. I don&#39;t know either. At the end of the conversation that day, I finally asked her, do you still like walking? She looked at me, also silent, and then shook her head. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the end of September, I returned to my hometown to take care of my mother-in-law. I finally had some free time during the National Day. I drove along the rural and county roads, stopping in every small town I passed to take a look around. During the holidays in previous years, fellow villagers from Chengdu and nearby provinces and cities would sometimes make appointments to go home together during the Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day. On the way, they would forget about trivial matters and reminisce about old times, life and scenery, with a relaxed heart, which was very enjoyable. After returning home, classmates gather, get married, and the town takes advantage of the excitement to hold markets for several days, creating a somewhat festive atmosphere. But this year&#39;s National Day, there is no lively atmosphere in these small towns. Even during the fair, there are only a few old people and middle school students on the streets. Among young people, some are probably traveling, some are still working, and some are hiding in rental houses, taking advantage of the rare time to escape from the world. Perhaps for many people floating in the big world, this is no longer a place where they can &quot;go back&quot;. I come back every summer, and I can feel even more that the changes in the town are not sudden, but happen bit by bit. In the past few years, the pace has been especially fast. Presumably the farther away the child is, the older the mother will be. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The night before I left, I climbed to the top of the building with a mat and a thin quilt and lay down under the stars just like I did when I was a child in the small town. I watched &quot;The Pianist on the Sea&quot; and &quot;Sweet Honey&quot; again that day, and the scenes that moved me the most were still the two scenes from before: 1900 sitting in the cabin, silently looking at the vast ocean outside the glass, silently looking at myself life; at the end of the latter, Li Qiao and Li Xiaojun meet again on the streets of a foreign country. The news of Teresa Teng&#39;s death is being broadcast on TV. From the mainland to Hong Kong, and Hong Kong to the United States, people around them come and go, and the wind of the times changes. Things changed again and again, decades passed, and the two birds that had been flying all their lives finally landed at this moment. After watching the movie, my phone was almost out of battery, so I played some songs again. Pu Shu sang in the song:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The world is in the fog, and those people are saying&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;ldquo;Come &quot;Bar&quot; and disappeared&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I have never seen this maze clearly&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All the wrong intersections&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those who died stayed in the night sky &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lighted for you&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sometimes you ride the wind, sometimes you sink&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sometimes there is a rainbow at midnight&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sometimes you sing Singing, sometimes you are silent&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sometimes you look at the sky&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I put my head on my hands and looked at the night sky of the small town, unable to hold back my tears. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;But we still have to hit the road. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The next morning, I drove away. The sky was slightly awake and there was no one on the street. There was only mist all over the mountains and plains and the faint chirping of birds. I turned on the fog lights, slowed down the car, and drove along the path toward the national highway. Passing by a village, the mountains behind are covered with cypress trees, hidden in the heavy fog. Several bungalows line the asphalt roadside, almost all of them deserted. In the widest one, there is a dead tree in the courtyard, and its dead body is also very thick. Weeds are everywhere. The collapsed side house is only gravel and bricks covered with cobwebs, which are also lying quietly in the grass. A large piece of the wall was peeled off, and the door lock was also covered in black rust. The door was dark inside, and a few clumps of weeds poked their heads out, struggling to get out of the crack in the door. Driving further, you can see the mottled writings on the walls: The vast world...the fewer students and the better students...the construction of a new countryside and so on. There is a stone bridge at the head of the village, and the stream under the bridge flows to the Jialing River on the other side of the mountain. An old man in an old cotton-padded jacket sat on the bridge pier with a cane, his face wrinkled, watching me pass by. The surrounding fields are silent, there is no sound of wind, no chirping of insects, the sun is about to rise, only the fog in front flows quietly in the faint light. &lt;/p>;&lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;Editor-in-charge: Mei Butan&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Please see the @ONE studio pinned Weibo for information on the call for papers. The official WeChat account of the editorial department: oneapp2020. Regularly publish Q&amp;A collections, give away books and peripheral gifts, readers are welcome to add. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Author&lt;/p>; &lt;hr style=&quot;margin-top: 15px;&quot;/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 50px;&quot;>; &lt;img src=&quot;http: //image.wufazhuce.com/FgZOnw_9DnMK296BOnNzjPRhZ-Qc&quot; alt=&quot;Tang Chong&quot;>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;div>;Tang Chong&lt;span style=&quot;font-size: 10px&quot;>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span>; &lt; /div>; &lt;div style=&quot;&quot;>;A young man from a small town who is good at cooking and loves to write. &lt;/div>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td width=&quot;60px&quot;>; &lt;!-- &lt;span onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2, )&quot;>;Follow&lt;/span>; -->; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;p>;Related recommendations&lt;/p>; &lt;hr/>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Reading&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt; a href=&quot;/article/5950&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;Send running water&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Tang Chong&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt; tr>; &lt;td style=&quot;width: 40px;&quot;>; &lt;span>;Read&lt;/span>; &lt;/td>; &lt;td>; &lt;a href=&quot;/article/5914&quot; data-ajax=&quot;false&quot;>; &lt;div>;We The sky&lt;/div>; &lt;div>;Text/Tang Chong&lt;/div>; &lt;/a>; &lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;table>; &lt;tr>; &lt;td>; &lt;div style=&quot;text-align :center;padding:5px;&quot; onclick=&quot;OneAPP.openDetail(2,6179)&quot;>;Click to download ONE app&lt;/div>;&lt;/td>; &lt;/tr>; &lt;/table>; &lt;/div>; &lt;/div >; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 06 Dec 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[VOL.4078]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://m.wufazhuce.com/one/4222]]><description>&lt;div>;6 Dec. 2023&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div>;&lt;div role=&quot;main&quot;>; &lt;div>; &lt;img src=&quot;http://image.wufazhuce.com/Fgxeb-iiJif2qvOE-ixwt5lJQuOZ&quot; alt=&quot;Homepage Picture&quot; />; &lt;p>;&lt;span>;VOL.4078&lt;/span>;Photography | Greenforce Staffing&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;6&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Dec. 2023&lt;/p>; &lt;div>;&lt;/div>; &lt;p >;Perhaps the ideal state would be to write a novel as if it were a diary. We are less vain when writing a diary. The diary is for ourselves. We will not be proud of some words or frustrated by clumsiness. &lt;/p>; &lt;/div>; &lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 06 Dec 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>