<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平向第二届全球数字贸易博览会致贺信]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/24/nw.D110000renmrb_20231124_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 24, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 23&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;On November 23, President Xi Jinping addressed the second global Congratulatory letter from Digital Trade Expo. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that currently, global digital trade is booming and has become a new bright spot in international trade. In recent years, China has actively aligned itself with high-standard international economic and trade rules, established and improved a digital trade governance system, promoted the reform and innovative development of digital trade, and continuously provided new opportunities for the world with China&#39;s new developments. It is hoped that all parties will make full use of the Global Digital Trade Expo platform to discuss cooperation, jointly promote development, and share results, and work together to build digital trade into a new engine for common development and inject new momentum into world economic growth. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The second Global Digital Trade Expo opened in Hangzhou, Zhejiang Province on the same day, with the theme of &quot;Digital Trade &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Business Connecting the World&quot;, and was co-sponsored by the Zhejiang Provincial People&#39;s Government and the Ministry of Commerce. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平致电祝贺博阿凯当选利比里亚总统]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/24/nw.D110000renmrb_20231124_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 24, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 23&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;On November 21, President Xi Jinping called Joseph Niou Ma Boakai, congratulations on his election as President of the Republic of Liberia. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that under your promotion, all walks of life in Liberia have reached a consensus on adhering to the one-China principle, and China expresses its appreciation. The two peoples have joined hands to fight Ebola and the COVID-19 epidemic, carried out fruitful cooperation in the field of economic and social development, and forged a profound friendship. I attach great importance to the development of China-Liberia relations and am willing to work with you to deepen friendship and mutual trust between the two countries, strengthen mutually beneficial cooperation, and better benefit the two peoples. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平向阿根廷当选总统米莱致贺电]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/24/nw.D110000renmrb_20231124_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 24, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 23&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;On November 21, President Xi Jinping called Javier Mi Rai, congratulations on his election as President of the Argentine Republic. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that China and Argentina are both major developing countries and important emerging market countries. The two countries have always adhered to mutual respect, equal treatment, mutual benefit and win-win results, and firmly supported each other on issues involving each other&#39;s core interests. Practical cooperation in various fields has brought tangible benefits to the two peoples. China-Arab friendship is deeply rooted in the hearts of the people, and it has become a general consensus among all walks of life in the two countries to continuously promote China-Arab relations. I attach great importance to the development of China-Arab relations and am willing to work with President-elect Milais to continue China-Arab friendship, support the development and revitalization of our respective countries through win-win cooperation, promote the stability and long-term development of China-Arab relations, and better benefit the two peoples. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 《习近平谈治国理政》第四卷英文版推介会在尼泊尔举行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/24/nw.D110000renmrb_20231124_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 24, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Kathmandu, November 23&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Yi Aijun) &quot;Xi Jinping Talks about the Governance of China&quot; A promotion conference for the English version of Volume 4 was held on the 23rd in Kathmandu, the capital of Nepal. Former Prime Minister of Nepal Jalanath Khanal attended the promotion meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Kanal said in his speech that in &quot;Xi Jinping: The Governance of China&quot;, he read &quot;the far-sightedness of building socialism in China in a highly innovative and constructive way.&quot; Readers can find answers to China&#39;s rapid development in &quot;Xi Jinping: The Governance of China&quot;. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Chinese Ambassador to Nepal Chen Song said in a speech that the release of the English version of the fourth volume of &quot;Xi Jinping: The Governance of China&quot; in Nepal will help people from all walks of life in Nepal increase their understanding of why the Chinese Communist Party can succeed and deepen their understanding of The understanding of China&#39;s path, China&#39;s governance, and China&#39;s principles will help China and Nigeria continue to move their strategic partnership of ever-lasting friendship towards development and prosperity to new heights. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;This promotion meeting was hosted by Foreign Languages ​​Publishing House and China International Book Trading Group Co., Ltd. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 《习近平关于尊重和保障人权论述摘编》（西汉对照）全球首发式在马德里举办]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/24/nw.D110000renmrb_20231124_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 24, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Our newspaper, Madrid, November 22&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Yan Huan and Xu Hailin) ​​&quot;Xi Jinping on Respect and Guarantees The world premiere of &quot;Excerpts of Human Rights Discourses&quot; (Western Han Dynasty) and the &quot;Human Wisdom for Global Governance&quot; exchange seminar were successfully held in Madrid, the capital of Spain, on the 22nd. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;José Luis Centralia, Chairman of the Spanish Communist Party, Qu Xun, Minister of the Chinese Embassy in Spain, and other guests attended the event and delivered speeches. More than 50 Chinese and Western experts, scholars, heads of associations, and people friendly to China from the fields of politics, economy, culture, etc. attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Centeria said that protecting human rights is the mission of every country, but there is no unified standard for implementation, and protecting human rights needs to adapt to the national conditions of each country. The rights to survival and development are the first basic human rights. China gives priority to rural and most backward areas, helping many people escape poverty and live a well-off life. As basic needs are guaranteed and life becomes richer, the Chinese people have gained a more equal, democratic, just and secure social environment. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Marta Montolo, manager and institutional relations director of Zhihua Lecture Hall in Spain, believes that &quot;Excerpts of Xi Jinping&#39;s Excerpts on Respecting and Protecting Human Rights&quot; is an authoritative treatise with rich connotations and profound thoughts, which can be shown to the world It reflects China’s concepts and practices in respecting and protecting human rights. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Antonio Segura, founding president of the Spanish Association of Friendship Lawyers with China, said that all countries have made many commitments to the development of human rights, including ensuring the tranquility, safety, comfort and health of citizens’ lives, and today’s book The book clearly answers how China respects and protects human rights. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Qu Xun said in his speech that since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core has insisted on respecting and protecting human rights as an important task of governing the country, and has embarked on a path that conforms to the trend of the times and The human rights development path that suits the country&#39;s national conditions has promoted China&#39;s human rights cause to achieve historic achievements. This year marks the 50th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and Spain. Over the past half century, the healthy and smooth development of China-Spain relations is fundamentally based on adhering to the original aspiration of establishing diplomatic relations of mutual respect, equality and mutual benefit, and adhering to the right path of friendly coexistence between countries with different cultures and systems. There is no one-size-fits-all path for human rights development in the world, and there is no best way to protect human rights, only better ones. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The Chinese version of &quot;Excerpts of Xi Jinping&#39;s Essays on Respecting and Protecting Human Rights&quot; is edited by the Party History and Documentation Research Institute of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China. It is divided into 9 topics and systematically collects a series of remarks by General Secretary Xi Jinping on respecting and protecting human rights. Important discussion. The English-Chinese, Western Han, French-Chinese, Russian-Chinese, and Japanese-Chinese versions of the book were translated by the Party History and Literature Research Institute of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and published by the Central Compilation and Translation Press. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 李强赵乐际分别会见乌拉圭总统拉卡列]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/24/nw.D110000renmrb_20231124_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 24, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 23&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Premier Li Qiang of the State Council met at the Great Hall of the People on the morning of November 23 Uruguay President Lacalle is in China for a state visit. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Li Qiang said that since the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and Ukraine 35 years ago, the two sides have always adhered to mutual understanding, mutual trust and mutual support, and the relations between the two countries have achieved high-level development. Yesterday, President Xi Jinping and Mr. President jointly announced the establishment of a comprehensive strategic partnership between China and Ukraine, opening a new chapter in bilateral relations. China is willing to work with Uzbekistan to follow the strategic guidance of the two heads of state, promote China-Uzbekistan relations to continuously rejuvenate and achieve new results, and build mutual respect and trust between countries with different social systems, mutual benefit and complementarity between countries with different economic sizes, and mutual learning and mutual learning between countries with different cultural backgrounds. A model of appreciation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Li Qiang pointed out that China is willing to continue to firmly support each other with Uzbekistan on issues involving each other&#39;s core interests and major concerns. Both sides should uphold the principle of mutual benefit and win-win, give full play to complementary advantages, take the signing of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; cooperation plan as an opportunity to promote the continuous increase and improvement of bilateral trade, improve the level of trade and investment facilitation, and strengthen clean energy, communications, technological innovation, finance Cooperate in other fields and expand people-to-people and cultural exchanges in culture, tourism, education, sports, and local areas. China supports Uruguay in playing a greater role in regional affairs and is willing to work with Uruguay to deepen overall cooperation between China and Latin America, promote the construction of a community with a shared future between China and Latin America, safeguard multilateralism and an open world economy, and better safeguard international fairness and justice. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Lacalle said that although Ukraine and China are far apart, political mutual trust and mutual understanding between the two countries are increasingly deepening. The establishment of a comprehensive strategic partnership between Ukraine and China has opened up broad prospects for the development of bilateral relations. Uruguay is firmly committed to closer relations with China and actively participates in the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. It is willing to uphold traditional friendship with China, deepen political mutual trust, strengthen exchanges and cooperation in economy, trade, investment, culture, education, local and other fields, and accelerate the cooperation between Uruguay and the Southern Common Market. The construction of China&#39;s free trade partnership has promoted the continuous and in-depth development of relations between the two countries. Uzbekistan is willing to make positive contributions to deepening cooperation between South Africa and China and Latin America and China. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Wu Zhenglong attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 23. Zhao Leji, Chairman of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, met with Uruguay President Lacalle in Beijing on the 23rd. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Zhao Leji said that since the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and Ukraine 35 years ago, the relationship between the two countries has withstood the test of international vicissitudes and has become a model of harmonious coexistence and win-win cooperation between countries with different political systems and different economic sizes. Yesterday, the two heads of state jointly announced the establishment of a comprehensive strategic partnership between China and Ukraine, which is an important milestone. Both sides should follow the strategic guidance of the two heads of state, respect each other, trust each other, and support each other, and jointly build the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; with high quality to bring more benefits to the people of the two countries. Next year will mark the 65th anniversary of exchanges between the legislative bodies of the two countries. The National People&#39;s Congress of China is willing to maintain traditional friendship with the Uruguayan Congress, deepen exchanges and exchanges, and provide a solid legal guarantee for China-Uruguay&#39;s practical cooperation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Lacalle said that Ukraine-China relations have a solid foundation and solid mutual trust. My visit has achieved fruitful results and the two sides have established a comprehensive strategic partnership. Uzbekistan will actively implement the consensus reached by the two heads of state and the results of this visit, strengthen exchanges between the two countries&#39; legislative bodies, and consolidate public opinion on the friendship between Uzbekistan and China. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xiao Jie attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 韩正出席第二届全球数字贸易博览会开幕式并致辞]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/24/nw.D110000renmrb_20231124_7-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 24, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Hangzhou, November 23&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Han Jie, Zhang Xuan) Vice President Han Zheng 23 On the same day, I attended the opening ceremony of the 2nd Global Digital Trade Expo in Hangzhou, Zhejiang, and read out President Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter and delivered a speech. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Han Zheng said that President Xi Jinping sent a special congratulatory letter, which fully reflects the Chinese government’s firm determination to work with other countries to build an open world economy and promote the prosperity and development of global digital trade. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Han Zheng pointed out that digital trade is becoming a new trend in the development of international trade and a new growth point for future development. China&#39;s digital trade development has unique advantages, with massive data resources and rich trade digital application scenarios. China lists digital trade, trade in goods and trade in services as the three pillars supporting the construction of a strong trading nation. China is willing to work with other countries to create an open, inclusive, fair, just and non-discriminatory digital economic development environment and jointly promote the high level of global digital trade. Quality is sustainable. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Han Zheng said that China is willing to uphold the global concept of win-win cooperation, actively participate in the formulation of international rules and standards in the digital field, explore more institutional opening results, and promote a higher level of opening up in the digital field. China will continue to accelerate digital transformation and the development of cross-border e-commerce, promote the construction of digital infrastructure, build a &quot;Silk Road e-commerce&quot; cooperation pioneer zone, build a &quot;Belt and Road&quot; e-commerce market with partners, and maintain the global digital industry chain supply. The chain is safe and stable. China is willing to strengthen communication with all parties, seek common ground while reserving differences, and jointly make good use of the Global Digital Trade Expo, an international public service product, to promote more pragmatic cooperation results. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The theme of this digital trade fair is &quot;Digital Trade &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Business Globalization&quot;. About 1,000 representatives from China and all walks of life from 63 countries and regions, 68 international organizations and overseas business associations Attend the opening ceremony. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Before the opening ceremony, Han Zheng inspected the exhibition hall, listened to situation reports, interacted with the heads of exhibiting companies, and inspected the development of the digital economy of the New H3C Group. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 图片报道]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/24/nw.D110000renmrb_20231124_8-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 24, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231124/1700768581353_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/ TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Currently, the national autumn grain harvest is coming to an end, and the annual grain output is expected to hit a record high. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Autumn grain procurement work is in full swing in many places. On November 22, the State Administration of Grain and Material Reserves released the latest data showing that various grain companies in the main production areas purchased more than 60 million tons of autumn grain. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The picture shows November 23, Tongjiang Village, Jiangxi Town, Jiangnan District, Nanning City, Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region. The late rice has entered the maturity stage and a bumper harvest is in sight. The golden rice and the quaint villages complement each other. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Photographed by Yu Xiangquan (Image China)&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https: //feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color :orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 分类指导  精准施策（学思想 强党性 重实践 建新功）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/24/nw.D110000renmrb_20231124_9-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 24, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;In the second batch of thematic education on studying and implementing Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, Henan organized party members, cadres and The party organization provides classified guidance and precise policy implementation, coordinates full-coverage development and field-specific promotion, and connects the implementation of higher-level requirements with the actual situation at the grassroots level to ensure that thematic education achieves effective results. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Adhere to high-quality promotion and high-standard implementation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Henan pays close attention to the leading groups and leading cadres at or above the county level, and carefully conducts self-study on the basis of self-study. Run a good reading class and divide it into two periods of intensive study and seminar. Formulate a study plan for the theoretical study center group, with one topic per month, focusing on quiet study, concentrating on understanding, and in-depth research. Cadres at or above the county level across the province have gone to the grassroots level to carry out propaganda and conduct research, and solve &quot;big problems&quot; based on &quot;small incisions&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taking the theme education as an opportunity, Xinyang City established a &quot;four one&quot; mechanism for investigation and research, namely &quot;a research topic, a set of research plans, a list of results transformation, and a high-quality research report&quot;. Municipal-level cadres led research on 52 topics in 12 aspects, including the high-standard construction of the Southeast Henan High-tech Zone, deepening the construction of national climate investment and financing pilot projects, and inheriting and carrying forward the spirit of the Dabie Mountains, so that cadres can truly engage in the work, solve problems, and apply results. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Focusing on promoting Chinese-style modernization, Henan has further promoted the construction of &quot;three batches&quot; projects and &quot;ten thousand people to help ten thousand enterprises&quot; activities, and strives to cultivate 28 industrial chains worth 100 billion yuan in seven major industrial clusters. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the same time, the responsibilities of provincial-level leading units and city and county party committees will be consolidated, and top-down efforts will be coordinated to focus on tackling key problems. For problems that are difficult to solve at the grassroots level alone, we urge higher-level units to take the initiative to recognize them and work together to solve them. We identified 342 rectification matters at the municipal level and 1,728 at the county level, and detailed measures to implement real improvements. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Improving accuracy and enhancing effectiveness&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Henan adheres to classified guidance and ensures effective coverage based on the characteristics of party organizations in different fields and party members of different groups. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The secretary of the party organization should be a good leader. A notice on consolidating the theme education responsibilities of party organization secretaries was issued, and the responsibilities and tasks of party organization secretaries were clarified by field. A total of 188,000 party branch secretaries were trained by adopting the method of focusing on demonstrations in provinces, focusing on key points in cities, and focusing on all employees in counties. The 13,000 first secretaries stationed in villages are required to take the lead in receiving education and assisting in education, so as to drive party members and cadres to truly study theory, do practical work, and make real improvements. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Create a good platform for party members. Relying on the &quot;Three Meetings and One Lesson&quot; and thematic party days, learning is carried out through various forms such as &quot;Party classes have begun&quot;, party members&#39; evening classes, reading sharing sessions, and online micro-party classes. Carry out activities such as point management for rural party members, lighting up &quot;micro-wishes&quot; for community party members, &quot;double registration&quot; for party members in government agencies and party organizations, and job training for party members in enterprises, to select a group of role models around them and guide party members to make contributions based on their posts. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hebi City Junxian County organized party members and cadres at all levels to move &quot;small benches&quot; to people&#39;s homes to ask people&#39;s needs and advice face-to-face, explain policies, listen to demands, resolve disputes, and connect feelings. Sincerely do practical things and solve problems for the masses. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In view of the characteristics of the &quot;two new&quot; organizations and new employment groups, Henan adopts joint construction, regional construction and other methods to promote the construction of party organizations; relying on platform enterprises, red stations, etc., to carry out theme education according to local conditions. Centrally investigate the relationship between floating party members and party organizations, straighten out the formal organizational relationships and &quot;timely transfer out a batch&quot;, clarify that temporary organizational relationships are subordinate to &quot;two-way joint management of a batch&quot;, and track and contact the party organizations in the places where they leave the country to &quot;manage a batch in full&quot; to ensure that 227,000 Famous mobile party members do not miss out on studies or fall behind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Continue to make up for shortcomings, strengths and weaknesses, and activate power&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Henan seizes the opportunity of thematic education, focuses on strengthening the foundation and laying a solid foundation at the grassroots level. We concentrated on rectifying weak and disorganized party organizations, evaluated the effectiveness of the rectification of 1,286 weak and disorganized village party organizations investigated at the beginning of the year, and used the results of the mid-term analysis of the two committees to investigate 834 new ones. While dispatching the first secretary and work team, we also investigated individual issues. In outstanding villages, 3 to 5 outstanding party members and cadres will be sent to the village to reorganize the branch team. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In combination with thematic education, Huaiyang District of Zhoukou City set up a &quot;post-evaluation&quot; working group to rectify weak and disorganized party organizations and went to Baimiao Village to focus on branch construction, industrial development, environmental improvement, safety construction, and serving the people etc., adopt the four-step method of &quot;listening, checking, watching, and evaluating&quot; to carry out the acceptance evaluation in a solid manner. Today, the roads in Baimiao Village are clean and tidy, the village has a completely new look, and the two committees are united, collaborative, and full of energy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Effectively empower and reduce the burden on the grassroots. Henan has done a good job in the &quot;second half of the article&quot; in the reform of township and sub-district institutions and continued to promote &quot;reducing counties and replenishing townships&quot;, with a total of more than 75,000 sinking establishments; it has issued 4 catalogs including the &quot;Henan Province Village-level Organization Work Guidance Catalog&quot; and carried out Special rectification of outstanding problems in grassroots governance will be carried out, focusing on solving problems such as arbitrarily pressing tasks and &quot;formalism at the fingertips&quot;, so as to clarify responsibilities and reduce burdens on village-level organizations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Discipline Inspection and Supervision Committee of Yexian County, Pingdingshan City, combined with special rectification of outstanding problems in grassroots governance, strengthened the restriction and supervision of the exercise of power, implemented an integrity risk prevention and control project throughout the county, and established a prevention and control system at different levels. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 共享数字贸易发展新机遇（今日谈）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/24/nw.D110000renmrb_20231124_10-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 24, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Digital trade is an important pillar in building a trade power, and the Global Digital Trade Expo is an important platform to promote the development of digital trade. On November 23, President Xi Jinping sent a congratulatory letter to the Second Global Digital Trade Expo, pointing out that “global digital trade is booming and has become a new highlight of international trade”, emphasizing “promoting the reform and innovative development of digital trade, and constantly taking China’s new development as a benchmark for the world” Provide new opportunities&quot; and hope that all parties will &quot;join hands to build digital trade into a new engine of common development and inject new momentum into world economic growth.&quot; &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Walking into the second Global Digital Trade Expo, flying vehicles, driverless cars, outdoor live working robots, etc. are competing to appear, artificial intelligence, big data, cloud computing, Internet of Things, virtual reality, etc. Achieve breakthroughs, digital creativity, digital healthcare, digital entertainment, etc. find application scenarios... With the help of digital trade, more and more new technologies, new products, new services and new scenarios are coming from dreams into reality, not only for Qianxing All industries bring vitality and vitality, and also broaden the depth and breadth of a better life. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;China’s new development brings new opportunities to the world. Data shows that my country&#39;s import and export volume of digitally delivered services will reach US$372.71 billion in 2022. While the scale continues to expand, the structure continues to be optimized, making it possible to jointly build, discuss, promote and share new opportunities for the development of digital trade. The successful holding of the Global Digital Trade Expo is a strong proof that China’s door to opening up will only open wider. Making full use of the Global Digital Trade Expo platform to promote high-quality development of global digital trade, discuss cooperation, promote development, and share results will surely create new advantages in the development of digital trade and add impetus to world economic growth. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 共同把握新机遇  携手打造新引擎]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/24/nw.D110000renmrb_20231124_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 24, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;On November 23, President Xi Jinping sent a congratulatory letter to the 2nd Global Digital Trade Expo. It sparked an enthusiastic response from people. Everyone expressed that President Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter pointed out the direction for jointly promoting the high-quality and sustainable development of global digital trade. They will jointly seize the development opportunities of global digital trade in accordance with the requirements of the congratulatory letter, make full use of the Global Digital Trade Expo platform, and work together to build digital trade into a common development A new engine that injects new impetus into world economic growth. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;More than a month ago, President Xi Jinping announced at the opening ceremony of the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum that &quot;China will hold a &#39;Global Digital Trade Expo&#39; every year&quot;, fully demonstrating China&#39;s willingness to work with all countries We are determined to build an open world economy and promote the prosperity and development of global digital trade. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Zhu Yong, Director of the Department of E-Commerce and Information Technology of the Ministry of Commerce, said that President Xi Jinping sent a congratulatory letter to the second Global Digital Trade Expo in order to give full play to the role of the Digital Trade Expo as a global public product and promote global digital trade. Trade development provides important guidance. In the next step, we will make good use of the professional open platform of the Digital Trade Fair to further align with high-standard international economic and trade rules, work with all parties to build a global governance system in the digital field, cultivate new momentum for the development of digital trade, and enhance the resilience of the global digital industry chain and supply chain. , promote high-quality and sustainable development of the global digital economy, and contribute China&#39;s strength to the recovery of the world economy. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“President Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter once again made us feel China’s determination to continue to expand its opening up to the outside world, and strengthened our confidence in deeply exploring the Chinese market.” The global senior vice president of Takeda Pharmaceuticals, a multinational pharmaceutical company, who listened to the congratulatory letter, and Takeda Shan Guohong, President of China, said that the Digital Trade Fair has built a valuable platform for countries to discuss cooperation, jointly promote development, and share results, which is conducive to jointly discussing the future development of digital trade and sharing the opportunities and dividends of digital economic development. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Currently, global digital trade is booming and has become a new bright spot in international trade. In his congratulatory letter, President Xi Jinping mentioned that &quot;China&#39;s new development will continue to provide new opportunities for the world&quot; and &quot;jointly build digital trade into a new engine for common development&quot;, which aroused widespread resonance from all walks of life. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;New Development Bank President Rousseff said that China has made remarkable achievements in empowering high-quality development with the digital economy. The second Global Digital Trade Expo will showcase corresponding products and solutions that deeply integrate the digital economy and the real economy. program to demonstrate the development potential of digital trade and digital finance. It is believed that this digital trade fair will make new contributions to world economic growth. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Finland is one of the guest countries of this year’s Digital Trade Fair, and Finnish companies focus on displaying products in industrial digitalization and other aspects. Meng Lan, Ambassador of Finland to China, said that digital trade plays an important role in trade cooperation between the two countries, and China&#39;s huge digital industrial system provides Finland with broad opportunities to develop related new products, new technologies, and new services. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In recent years, digital trade in Zhejiang Province has continued to grow rapidly. Among the four areas of the Zhejiang Pilot Free Trade Zone, the Hangzhou area highlights digital trade. Chen Weijing, full-time deputy director of the Hangzhou Area Management Committee of the China (Zhejiang) Pilot Free Trade Zone, said that Hangzhou will give full play to the superimposed effect of the &quot;Digital Trade Fair + Free Trade Pilot Zone&quot;, actively practice institutional openness, start the construction of &quot;China Digital Trade Port&quot;, and focus on Build a global digital trade innovation leading source, a cutting-edge trend release place and an international hub for digital trade, and strive to build a global digital trade center. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The rapid development of digital trade is inseparable from the high empowerment of data as a new production factor. A set of data in the Comprehensive Hall of the Digital Trade Fair is eye-catching: in 2022, China&#39;s data output will reach 8.1ZB, a year-on-year increase of 22.7%, accounting for 10.5% of the total global data output, ranking second in the world; the scale of China&#39;s digital economy will reach 50.2 trillion Yuan, ranking second in the world in total. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“President Xi Jinping’s important speech puts forward new requirements for us to consolidate our advantages in digital economic development and deepen international cooperation in the digital economy.” Luan Jie, the preparatory team of the National Data Administration, said that the next step will be to continuously improve the basic data system and promote Supply more high-quality data, cultivate the data industry, and continuously activate the value of data elements; deepen international cooperation in the digital economy, strengthen policy connection, experience exchange, and project cooperation with countries co-building the “Belt and Road” to promote a more open, inclusive, and universal Hui’s Digital Silk Road. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;iFlytek Co., Ltd., which has participated in the Digital Industry Fair for two consecutive years, brought its latest scientific and technological achievements in artificial intelligence, including large models, to the exhibition this year. Listening to President Xi Jinping&#39;s congratulatory message on the spot, Sun Dongping, Vice President of iFlytek Co., Ltd., said that the company will continue to increase investment and research and development in key core technologies, work with global partners to promote the innovation and application of artificial intelligence technology, and accelerate the implementation of the industry. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Li Xiaolin, chairman of the China E-commerce Rural Revitalization Alliance, said that judging from the more than five years of practice of the China E-commerce Rural Revitalization Alliance, the digital economy has played a significant role in promoting agricultural modernization in underdeveloped areas. In the next step, we will accelerate our pace to seize new opportunities in the development of the digital economy, and continue to use digital technology to empower rural revitalization and assist agriculture. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;(Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 23rd&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Reporters Xie Xiyao, Yan Fuxing, Wen Jinghua, Zhang Xuan, Huang Xiao)&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 24 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>