<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 高质量共建“一带一路”行稳致远（推动共建“一带一路”高质量发展）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/12/nw.D110000renmrb_20231012_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 12, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Opening words&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This year is the tenth anniversary of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s major initiative to jointly build the “Belt and Road” anniversary. Over the past ten years, under the personal planning, deployment and promotion of General Secretary Xi Jinping, the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; has always adhered to the principle of extensive consultation, joint contribution and shared benefits, upheld the concepts of openness, greenness and integrity, and implemented high standards, sustainability and benefiting people&#39;s livelihood. As a goal, we have achieved substantial and significant historic achievements. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This newspaper will launch the column &quot;Promoting High-Quality Development of the Belt and Road Initiative&quot; from today to provide in-depth coverage of the Belt and Road Initiative from concept to action, from vision to reality, and continuously enhance the co-construction of the country&#39;s people. The sense of gain, happiness and security have become popular international public goods and international cooperation platforms, demonstrating the unswerving efforts of all parties to promote high-quality joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and jointly create a better future. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the autumn of 2013, General Secretary Xi Jinping proposed the major initiative of jointly building the &quot;Silk Road Economic Belt&quot; and the &quot;21st Century Maritime Silk Road&quot;. Use China’s solutions to solve global development problems and encourage countries around the world to join hands on the road to prosperity. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out: &quot;I proposed the joint construction of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; initiative to inherit the spirit of the Silk Road, work together to build an open cooperation platform, and provide new impetus for the cooperative development of various countries.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;After 10 years, the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; has become a major practice in building a community with a shared future for mankind, opening up a new path for mankind to jointly realize modernization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Facing the future, as a long-term, cross-border, systematic world project and century project, the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; will start from a new starting point and will be more innovative and dynamic, more open and inclusive, Open a new window of opportunity for China and the world, and draw a beautiful picture of a community with a shared future for mankind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Focus on the fundamental issue of development and activate the driving force for jointly building national development&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A small piece of grass can lead to thousands of miles of love. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Under the patient and meticulous guidance of Chinese experts, after several years of growing Juncao mushrooms, my income has greatly increased.” Theo Aihra from Lesotho, a mother of two girls, participated China-aided Juncao technical cooperation project in Lesotho has embarked on the road to poverty alleviation and prosperity. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Chinese Juncao technology can help achieve multiple sustainable development goals. It can not only promote the development of animal husbandry, help African people get rid of poverty and increase employment, but also set a model for preventing and controlling soil erosion.&quot; South Africa &quot; The Independent commented in an article. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Development is the eternal theme of human society. Over the past 10 years, the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; has focused on the fundamental issue of development, making contributions to solving the problem of global development imbalances and promoting countries to jointly modernize. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Activate the power of jointly building national development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Implement a large number of infrastructure construction projects to promote the co-building countries to make considerable progress in railways, highways, shipping and other aspects; actively carry out international cooperation in the field of emergency management, and have successively dispatched rescue teams to carry out rescue and rescue operations; to Tonga , Madagascar and other countries have provided emergency humanitarian material assistance and expert technical guidance... Over the past 10 years, the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; has focused on solving the main bottlenecks that restrict connectivity and economic development in most developing countries, improving local production and living conditions and The development environment has enhanced the hematopoietic function of economic development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The connectivity of infrastructure has effectively reduced the cost of participating in international trade for co-building countries and improved the ability and level of access to the world economy. Research from the Asian Development Bank shows that for every 10% reduction in infrastructure trade costs in landlocked countries, their exports will increase by 20%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Enhance the ability of jointly building the country to reduce poverty. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 2,000 agricultural experts and technicians have been dispatched to more than 70 countries and regions, and more than 1,500 agricultural technologies such as Juncao and hybrid rice have been promoted to many countries... In the past 10 years, China and relevant countries have The &quot;Vision and Actions for Jointly Promoting Agricultural Cooperation in the Construction of the Belt and Road Initiative&quot; was released, and more than 100 agricultural and fishery cooperation documents were signed with nearly 90 co-building countries and international organizations. The trade volume of agricultural products with co-building countries reached 139.4 billion US dollars, helping Asia, Africa, the South Pacific, Latin America and the Caribbean are promoting rural poverty reduction. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When one person is employed, the whole family will be lifted out of poverty.” In the process of jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, China and relevant countries have actively promoted the construction of industrial parks and guided enterprises to create jobs for local residents through high-level industrial cooperation. A research report by McKinsey &amp; Company shows that the localization rate of Chinese companies’ employees in Africa reaches 89%, effectively creating employment for the local population. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Enhancing people’s livelihood and well-being in jointly building the country. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Repair and maintain bridges to solve residents’ travel problems; drill wells to meet villagers’ drinking water needs; install street lights to illuminate pedestrians’ way home at night… In the past 10 years, Chinese companies have implemented more than 300 projects in the co-building countries We have launched &quot;Love and Assistance to the Needy&quot;, &quot;Rehabilitation and Medical Assistance&quot; and &quot;Happy Home&quot; projects, assisted in the construction of the headquarters of the African Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the Philanthropy Medical Emergency Center in Gwadar, Pakistan, and helped Cameroon, Ethiopia, Djibouti and other countries solve the problem of drinking water for the people. Each of these &quot;small but beautiful&quot; and &quot;beneficial but practical&quot; livelihood projects and public support projects has helped local people solve their urgent needs and improve their living conditions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Build a global development pattern that features universal benefits, balance, coordination and inclusiveness, win-win cooperation, and common prosperity&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mountains are no longer high and the road is no longer long. The Silk Road of Friendship is full of vitality. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On April 13, the cross-border passenger train on the China-Laos Railway was officially launched. The Vientiane Railway Station in Laos was crowded with people early in the morning, many of whom were taking a train for the first time. Passengers took selfies and cheered, proud to witness this historic moment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I truly feel China’s rapid development and look forward to my country riding on the ‘One Belt, One Road’ initiative to achieve greater development.” said Liu Yalan, a Lao international student at Dalian Medical University. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; is committed to realizing world interconnection and interconnected development, further opening up the main artery of economic globalization, and smoothing the flow of information, capital, technology, products, industries, and personnel. , and promote international cooperation on a larger scale and at a higher level. We should both enlarge and divide the &quot;cake&quot; of economic globalization, and strive to build a global development pattern that is inclusive, balanced, coordinated and inclusive, with win-win cooperation and common prosperity. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Enhance global development momentum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Gauchari region in southern Jujuy Province, Argentina, has an average altitude of more than 4,000 meters. China Power Construction Group and Shanghai Electric Power Construction Co., Ltd. jointly won the bid for the Gaocharui Photovoltaic Power Station Project, which was officially connected to the grid for power generation in September 2020. It not only helps to improve the local power supply situation, but also reduces fossil fuel consumption and optimizes local energy. structure to support the sustainable development of the local economy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Deepen regional economic cooperation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fruits and vegetables produced in Ili, Xinjiang, can enter the Kazakhstan market in just a few hours through the fast customs clearance &quot;green channel&quot; at the Horgos Port; Uzbekistan&#39;s cotton yarn, agricultural products, etc., can pass through the China-Europe Railway Express A steady stream of goods are arriving in China; Kyrgyzstan’s honey, fruits and other high-quality agricultural products have made their way to the dining tables of the Chinese people... The countries co-constructed by the “Belt and Road” are developing increasingly closely, and the level of regional economic cooperation has been significantly improved. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Promote global economic and trade development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A set of figures is a vivid portrayal of the joint construction of the “Belt and Road” that enhances the attractiveness of participating countries and regions to global high-quality capital: in 2022, Southeast Asia’s cross-border direct investment inflows will account for 17.2% of the world’s total, which is 17.2%. It increased by 9 percentage points in 2013; the scale of foreign direct investment flowing into Kazakhstan increased by 83% year-on-year, the highest level in history. The World Bank&#39;s &quot;Belt and Road Economics: Opportunities and Risks of Transportation Corridors&quot; research report shows that since the implementation of the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, global trade costs can be reduced by 1.8% through infrastructure construction alone, making China-China Trade costs on the Asia-West Asia Economic Corridor are reduced by 10%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Promote the formation of a new situation of people-to-people exchanges, cultural integration, and people-to-people connections around the world&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thailand&#39;s Thai-Chinese Rayong Industrial Park is lined with factories amid the shadow of coconut trees. Thai boy Nattaw was very busy on the production line...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March 2016, the world&#39;s first Luban workshop, jointly built by Tianjin Bohai Vocational and Technical College and Thailand&#39;s Ayutthaya Technical College, was officially unveiled , marking that China’s vocational education has gone abroad and shared high-quality vocational education resources with other countries. In this year, Natawu entered the Luban Workshop in Thailand to study, and then gradually grew into an engineer. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Luban Workshop in Thailand has not only improved the level of local vocational education, but also further strengthened educational exchanges and training between Thailand and China, and enhanced the friendship between the two peoples. I hope that the Luban Workshop will continue to develop and cultivate more skills Talents drive technological innovation and upgrading.&quot; said the relevant person in charge of the Thailand Vocational Education Commission. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Civilizations are colorful due to exchanges, and civilizations are enriched due to mutual learning. The joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; adheres to the civilizational outlook of equality, mutual learning, dialogue, and inclusiveness, insists on promoting the common values ​​​​of all mankind, jointly builds a path of exchanges and mutual learning among civilizations where each has its own beauty, and benefits are shared, and promotes the formation of people-to-people and cultural exchanges among countries around the world. A new situation of cultural integration and people-to-people bonds. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——The people-to-people and cultural exchange mechanism is increasingly improving. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The “Belt and Road” News Cooperation Alliance, the “Belt and Road” Think Tank Cooperation Alliance, the “Belt and Road” International Science Organization Alliance, the “Belt and Road” Medical Talent Training Alliance... In the past 10 years, we have jointly built the “Belt and Road” &quot;Various cooperation mechanisms have emerged in a concentrated manner, forming a pattern of people-to-people and cultural exchanges with diverse interactions and a hundred flowers blooming, which has effectively promoted mutual understanding and mutual respect among the people of various countries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Quality brand projects stand out. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Silk Road (Dunhuang) International Cultural Expo, &quot;One Belt and One Road&quot; Great Wall International Folk Culture and Art Festival, Silk Road International Art Festival, Maritime Silk Road International Art Festival, &quot;Belt and Road&quot; Youth Stories Conference, &quot;Ten Thousand Miles of Tea Ceremony&quot; Cultural Tourism Expo... In the past 10 years, the continuous emergence of exciting activities, high-quality brands and landmark projects have become an important carrier for all parties to jointly promote people-to-people bonds, and have enhanced people&#39;s support for the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; a sense of intimacy and identity. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Friendly exchanges among young people bring together people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the past 10 years, the youth of the Jointly Building Country have taken practical actions to carry out extensive cultural exchanges and cooperation on people&#39;s livelihood, gathering a majestic youth force to promote people-to-people connectivity and achieve common development. The &quot;China Youth Global Partnership Action&quot; has received widespread response from around the world, and more than 100 national youth organizations and international organizations have established exchange and cooperation relationships with China. The &quot;Silk Road Incubator&quot; Youth Entrepreneurship Program, the China-Central and Eastern European Countries Youth Maker International Forum and other activities were successfully carried out, becoming an important platform for the youth of the joint construction country to deepen friendly exchanges and cooperation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking back at the past, the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; follows the trend, wins the hearts of the people, benefits people&#39;s livelihood, and benefits the world. It has formed a criss-cross network of win-win cooperation on this earth. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking to the future, the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; has strong vitality and broad development prospects. China will work with other countries to unswervingly promote high-quality joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, making the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; more prosperous and broader, and injecting new and powerful impetus into building a community with a shared future for mankind. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平将出席第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛并举行有关活动]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/12/nw.D110000renmrb_20231012_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 12, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 11th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Foreign Ministry Spokesperson Hua Chunying announced on the 11th: The Belt and Road International Cooperation Summit Forum will be held in Beijing from October 17th to 18th, with the theme of &quot;High-quality joint construction of the Belt and Road Initiative and joint efforts to achieve common development and prosperity.&quot; President Xi Jinping will attend the opening ceremony of the summit forum and deliver a keynote speech, and hold a welcome banquet and bilateral activities for guests coming to China to attend the summit forum. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 思想之光照亮前路  凝心聚力再谱新篇]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/12/nw.D110000renmrb_20231012_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 12, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;In the past few days, General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions on publicity and ideological and cultural work and the spirit of the National Conference on Publicity and Ideological and Cultural Work have been widely recognized by the general public. It continues to arouse enthusiastic responses among party members, cadres and the masses. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Everyone unanimously stated that Xi Jinping’s cultural thoughts are of milestone significance in the history of the development of the party’s propaganda, ideological and cultural undertakings. It is necessary to thoroughly study and implement Xi Jinping’s cultural thoughts, implement all requirements and deployments to the letter, and write a new A new chapter in the ideological and cultural undertakings of the times. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Continue to strengthen the study, research and interpretation of Xi Jinping’s cultural thoughts&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“From deepening the reform of the cultural system, to promoting the deep integration of culture and tourism, to promoting cultural undertakings and High-quality development of the cultural industry... A series of key measures in the cultural field are fundamentally based on the leadership of General Secretary Xi Jinping in planning and the direction of Xi Jinping&#39;s cultural thoughts.&quot; Cai Ping, director of the Policy and Regulations Department of the Ministry of Culture and Tourism, said that on the new journey, Xi Jinping Cultural ideas are powerful ideological weapons and scientific action guides for us to do a good job in cultural and tourism work and create a new situation in socialist cultural construction. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Xi Jinping’s cultural thoughts not only have innovations and breakthroughs in cultural theoretical perspectives, but also have deployment requirements in the layout of cultural work. They have clarified the ‘road map’ and ‘mission statement’ for cultural construction in the new era.” Wang Fengxiang, a researcher at the Institute of Journalism and Communication of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, said that we will continue to strengthen the study, research, and interpretation of Xi Jinping’s cultural thoughts and contribute our own strength to promote the new development of propaganda, ideological and cultural undertakings. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, driven by major literary activities such as the &#39;New Era Mountain and Rural Changes Creation Project&#39; and the &#39;New Era Literary Climbing Project&#39;, the literary cause and writers&#39; association work have made great progress and progress, has become a vivid reflection of the party&#39;s innovative theory guiding practice.&quot; Fu Xiuying, deputy editor-in-chief of the Chinese Writers Association&#39;s &quot;Chinese Writers&quot; magazine, said that we must focus on studying and implementing Xi Jinping&#39;s cultural thoughts, focusing on the implementation of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China Regarding the strategic deployment of cultural construction, we will strengthen theoretical study and promote practical work, and we are determined to write for the people, sing for the new era, and promote the literature of the new era to reach new heights. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Forward the link, read the news together... Party members and cadres of the Propaganda Department of the Tianjin Municipal Party Committee immediately studied the important instructions of General Secretary Xi Jinping and the spirit of the meeting, and conducted in-depth discussions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out that ‘the propaganda of ideological and cultural work is related to the future and destiny of the party, to the long-term stability of the country, and to the cohesion and centripetal force of the nation. It is an extremely important task.’ We must do this well. It is our duty to carry out our work.&quot; Xu Zhong, deputy director of the Propaganda Department of the Tianjin Municipal Party Committee, said that we will give full play to the advantages of social science theoretical research, continue to strengthen research and interpretation around Xi Jinping&#39;s cultural thoughts, carry out targeted investigations and studies to implement the spirit of the meeting, and solidly Promote the construction of a culturally strong city to a new level. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Focus on the new situation, new challenges, and grasp new tasks and new requirements&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the new era and new journey, strategic opportunities and risks and challenges coexist, and publicity, ideological and cultural work is also facing New situation and new tasks. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized ‘focusing on the primary political task of arming the whole party with the party’s innovative theories and educating the people’, pointing out the direction for our next research and practice.” Central Party School (National Academy of Administration) ) Zhang Jun, deputy director of the Department of Literature and History, said that the next step is to carry out in-depth sorting, research and summary around Xi Jinping’s cultural thoughts, to deeply grasp the connotation of the “seven focuses”, and to truly learn, understand, believe and apply, and deepen internalization and transformation. At the same time, we will promote the party’s innovative theory to spread more widely, broadly and deeply. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After studying General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions and the spirit of the meeting, Zhu Shaohui, secretary of the Wuhua County Party Committee, Meizhou City, Guangdong Province, was deeply touched by the requirement to “strengthen the party’s leadership in publicity, ideological and cultural work.” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For the next step of work, Zhu Shaohui also has a clear idea: &quot;We will focus on the primary political task of arming the whole party with the party&#39;s innovative theory and educating the people, tap cultural resources, improve capabilities and skills, and comprehensively strengthen Building a culturally strong county.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dunhuang, Gansu Province is experiencing a tourism peak during this Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday. Tourists from all over the country appreciate the ingenuity of their ancestors at the monuments and feel the Chinese culture that has lasted for thousands of years. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After studying the important instructions of General Secretary Xi Jinping and the spirit of the meeting, Su Bomin, the director of the Dunhuang Academy who has just completed a survey related to overseas Dunhuang studies, is very excited: &quot;Dunhuang culture shows the breadth, depth and openness of China&#39;s excellent traditional culture. Tolerance is a precious legacy left to us by our ancestors. The Dunhuang Academy will adhere to integrity and innovation, and actively use digital technology to promote the creative transformation and innovative development of Dunhuang culture.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized in important instructions that &quot; &quot;Strive to strengthen the construction of international communication capabilities and promote exchanges and mutual learning among civilizations&quot;, Liu Cong, deputy editor-in-chief of CGTN and deputy director of the English Center of China Central Radio and Television Station, feels that he has a heavy responsibility on his shoulders. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liu Cong said that CGTN will thoroughly study and implement Xi Jinping’s cultural thoughts, practice hard to practice international communication skills, keep pace with the times to create a high-level professional platform and talent team, and make contributions to enhancing the communication and influence of Chinese civilization. should contribute. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Implement all requirements and deployments to the letter&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The value of theory lies in guiding practice. General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions have a macro-level overall Guidance and practical paths at specific levels are very instructive and operational.&quot; Deng Wugui, executive deputy director of the Propaganda Department of the Hubei Provincial Party Committee, said that Hubei will thoroughly study and implement Xi Jinping&#39;s cultural thoughts and deeply grasp the importance of the &quot;seven focuses&quot; Requirements: strengthen cultural self-confidence, promote the creative transformation and innovative development of Jingchu culture, accelerate the construction of a culturally strong province, and inject strong spiritual power into the new journey. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;No. 76 Xingye Road, Shanghai, the site of the National Congress of the Communist Party of China, original situational party classes, &quot;Journey of Original Aspiration&quot; interactions and other various activities further promote the red spirit. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Xinyi, director of the Department of Propaganda and Education of the First Memorial Hall of the Communist Party of China, said that as a post-90s party history educator, she will implement the spirit of the General Secretary’s important instructions, innovate methods and tell red stories well, Promote the extensive cultivation, in-depth dissemination, and solid practice of socialist core values, so that the strong voice of the era of love for the party, patriotism, and love for socialism will continue to play. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Dongchengyu Community, Zharut Banner, Tongliao City, Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region, accompanied by the high-pitched tunes of national musical instruments, the dance &quot;Horseback Love&quot; performed by the Ulan Muqi team attracted continuous applause from the people of all ethnic groups present. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized ‘strive to promote the prosperity and development of cultural undertakings and cultural industries’, which further strengthened our determination and confidence in building a strong ‘Red Literary Light Cavalry’.” Head of the Ulan Muqi Regiment directly under the Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region Xing Lili said that the next step will be to arrange creative personnel and business backbones in a planned way to rural pastoral areas, factory communities and other front lines to find inspiration, accumulate materials, absorb the nutrients of traditional culture and art, and create educational and educational content in a form that is popular with people of all ethnic groups. Le&#39;s works allow more excellent cultures rooted in northern Xinjiang to rejuvenate in the new era. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“One point of deployment, nine points of implementation. To continuously create a new situation in propaganda, ideological and cultural work in the new era, a talented team of propaganda, ideological and cultural cadres with strong politics and high abilities is indispensable.” Secretary of the Baise Municipal Party Committee, Guangxi Zhuang Autonomous Region Huang Rusheng said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huang Rusheng said that as an old revolutionary area, Baise City will rely on its rich red culture, historical culture, and national cultural resources to cultivate and select &quot;good cadres like Huang Wenxiu&quot; and encourage everyone to keep in mind the original intention and mission and continuously strengthen &quot; &quot;Four Forces&quot; will promote Xi Jinping&#39;s cultural thoughts to take root in Baise and provide a strong political guarantee for shouldering the new cultural mission. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 11)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href =&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 切实增强做好新时代新征程宣传思想文化工作的责任感使命感]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/12/nw.D110000renmrb_20231012_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 12, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;The National Propaganda, Ideology and Culture Work Conference held recently emphasized that we must closely focus on studying and implementing Xi Jinping’s cultural thoughts and focus on the implementation of the Party’s Second The ten major strategic arrangements for cultural construction have effectively enhanced the sense of responsibility and mission for promoting ideological and cultural work in the new era and new journey, and promoted the implementation of various tasks. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping’s cultural thought is a theoretical summary of the practical experience of party leadership cultural construction in the new era. It enriches and develops Marxist cultural theory and marks that our party’s understanding of the laws of socialist cultural construction with Chinese characteristics has reached a new height. , indicating that our party’s historical confidence and cultural confidence have reached a new height. The most important outcome of this meeting is the formal presentation and systematic exposition of Xi Jinping’s cultural thoughts, which is a milestone in the history of the development of the party’s propaganda, ideological and cultural undertakings. Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core has made systematic plans and arrangements for propaganda, ideological and cultural work from an overall and strategic perspective, and promoted historic achievements in ideological and cultural propaganda in the new era. The overall situation in the ideological field has changed The cultural self-confidence of the whole Party and the people of all ethnic groups in the country has been significantly enhanced, and their spiritual outlook has become more vigorous. To better shoulder the new cultural mission of the new era, the most critical thing is to thoroughly study and implement Xi Jinping’s cultural thoughts, make good use of this powerful ideological weapon and scientific action guide, consciously implement it in all aspects and the entire process of publicity, ideological and cultural work, and better Transformed into vivid practice to solidly promote the construction of a socialist cultural power and the modern civilization of the Chinese nation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China drew up a grand blueprint for comprehensively building a modern socialist country and comprehensively promoting the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation with Chinese-style modernization. It proposed that by 2035, the country will become a cultural power and the country’s cultural soft power will be significantly enhanced. To achieve the goals and tasks, we have made major arrangements to promote cultural self-confidence and self-improvement and create new glories for socialist culture. We must deeply realize that culture is the soul of a country and a nation. Without a high degree of cultural self-confidence and cultural prosperity, there will be no great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation; Chinese-style modernization is a modernization that coordinates material civilization and spiritual civilization, and develops culture Career is the basic way to meet the people&#39;s spiritual and cultural needs and protect the people&#39;s cultural rights and interests; promoting Chinese-style modernization is an unprecedented and pioneering undertaking. We must inspire the spirit of self-confidence and self-improvement of hundreds of millions of people and gather the powerful force of unity and struggle. On the new journey, we can only adhere to the guidance of Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, fully implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Party, thoroughly study and implement Xi Jinping Thought on Culture, strengthen cultural confidence, uphold openness and inclusiveness, persist in integrity and innovation, and fully inspire the whole nation. Cultural innovation creates vitality, continuously consolidates the common ideological foundation for the united struggle of the whole party and the people of all ethnic groups, and continuously enhances the country’s cultural soft power and the influence of Chinese culture. Only then can we provide strong ideas for comprehensively building a modern socialist country and comprehensively promoting the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation. Guarantee, strong spiritual strength, and favorable cultural conditions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: &quot;In the new era and the new journey, the world&#39;s major changes unseen in a century are accelerating. The great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation has entered a critical period. Strategic opportunities and risks and challenges coexist. The propaganda, ideological and cultural work is facing a new situation. New tasks must have a new atmosphere and new actions.&quot; We must unify our thoughts and actions with the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s important instructions and the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, and effectively enhance the sense of responsibility and mission to do a good job in promoting ideological and cultural work in the new era and new journey. It is necessary to focus on the primary political task of arming the whole party and educating the people with the party&#39;s innovative theories, and persist in using Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era to focus on the soul, work hard on true learning, true understanding, true belief and true application, and deepen internalization and transformation. Better unify thoughts and actions. We must focus on the new cultural mission of continuing to promote cultural prosperity, building a cultural power, and building the modern civilization of the Chinese nation at a new historical starting point, raise the banner, gather people&#39;s hearts, educate new people, develop culture, and display our image, and carry out cultural development in practice and creation. Create, realize cultural progress in historical progress, continue the historical context and compose contemporary chapters with the righteousness and vigor of keeping integrity and innovation. We must firmly grasp the major requirements of the &quot;Seven Focuses&quot;, focus on strengthening the party&#39;s leadership in publicity, ideological and cultural work, focus on building a socialist ideology with strong cohesion and leadership, focus on cultivating and practicing socialist core values, and focus on improving news The power of public opinion dissemination, guidance, influence and credibility, strives to maintain the Chinese context, promote the creative transformation and innovative development of China’s excellent traditional culture, strive to promote the prosperity and development of cultural undertakings and cultural industries, strive to strengthen the construction of international communication capabilities, and promote exchanges and mutual learning among civilizations. , and constantly create a new situation in publicity, ideological and cultural work in the new era. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The grand goal of building a strong country and rejuvenating the nation is inspiring and inspiring. To do a good job in promoting ideological and cultural work in the new era and new journey has a great responsibility and a glorious mission. Let us unite more closely around the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core, adhere to the guidance of Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, fully implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Party, thoroughly study and implement Xi Jinping Thought on Culture, and bear in mind that &quot;the country is big&quot; &quot;Those who work hard&quot;, improve their political standing, strengthen their responsibilities, conscientiously implement the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, better shoulder the new cultural mission with an indomitable attitude of struggle, and strive to build a strong socialist cultural country and build a modern civilization of the Chinese nation. and demonstrate new atmosphere and new achievements in practice. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 丁薛祥会见德国大众汽车集团管理董事会主席奥博穆]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/12/nw.D110000renmrb_20231012_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 12, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 11 On the same day, he met with Obermu, Chairman of the Board of Management of the German Volkswagen Group in Beijing. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Ding Xuexiang said that the economies of China and Germany are highly complementary and have huge space for cooperation. As important global economies and responsible powers, the two countries should work together to promote trade and investment liberalization and facilitation, jointly maintain the stability and security of global industrial and supply chains, and contribute to world economic growth and global economic governance. China&#39;s door to opening up will only open wider and wider, and China-Germany cooperation in the automotive field has broad prospects. We are willing to provide better environment and conditions for foreign-funded enterprises, including Volkswagen Group, to invest and operate in China. We welcome Volkswagen Group to continue to leverage its advantages, expand investment in China, and achieve greater development through win-win cooperation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Obomu thanked China for its strong support for the Volkswagen Group’s development in China, saying that the Volkswagen Group cherishes its friendship with China and the Chinese people, will increase investment in key areas, and continue to deeply explore the Chinese market. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 韩正会见瑞典银瑞达集团董事会主席瓦伦堡]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/12/nw.D110000renmrb_20231012_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 12, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 11th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Vice President Han Zheng met with Swedish Bank Ruida in Beijing on the 11th Wallenberg, chairman of the group&#39;s board of directors. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Han Zheng said that since the beginning of this year, China&#39;s economy has generally recovered and is improving, and the expected growth target for the whole year is expected to be achieved. China&#39;s basic national policy of reform and opening up will not change, and it will continue to raise the level of opening up to the outside world in the process of promoting Chinese-style modernization, creating greater room for development of China-EU and China-Switzerland economic and trade cooperation. China is willing to strengthen communication with Sweden on the basis of mutual respect, mutual trust, equality and mutual benefit, properly handle differences, and push bilateral relations to move steadily in the right direction. It is hoped that the Swedish business community, represented by Mr. Wallenberg, will continue to play an active role and make due contributions to strengthening practical cooperation between China and Europe and maintaining the stability of the industrial and supply chains. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Wallenberg expressed support for Sweden, the EU and China in establishing good and stable relations, and hoped to find more ways to promote dialogue between Europe, the United States and China and help the sustainable development of the global economy. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 图片报道]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/12/nw.D110000renmrb_20231012_7-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 12, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231012/1697055006740_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/ TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Recently, the rice fields in Jinfeng Town, Zhangjiagang City, Jiangsu Province ushered in the harvest season. Rice fields, residential buildings, and the Hu-Sutong Yangtze River Highway and Railway Bridge in the distance form a rural picture that combines modern and pastoral styles. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Photographed by Shi Bairong (Image China)&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 国务院印发《关于推进普惠金融高质量发展的实施意见》]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/12/nw.D110000renmrb_20231012_8-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 12, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 11th&amp;nbsp; Implementation Opinions&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Implementation Opinions&quot;) clarifies the guiding ideology, basic principles and main goals for promoting the high-quality development of inclusive finance in the next five years, and proposes a series of policy measures. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The &quot;Implementation Opinions&quot; emphasize that the high-quality development of inclusive finance must be guided by Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, thoroughly implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Party, and conscientiously implement the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee and the State Council, Uphold the leadership of the Party, adhere to the supremacy of the people, adhere to policy guidance, adhere to reform and innovation, adhere to safe development, basically build a high-quality inclusive financial system in the next five years, and strive to achieve more universal basic financial services, more convenient financing for business entities, and more financial services. Support the goals of more powerful rural revitalization, more complete financial consumer education and protection mechanisms, more effective financial risk prevention and control, and more complete inclusive financial supporting mechanisms. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The &quot;Implementation Opinions&quot; propose that it is necessary to optimize products and services in key areas of inclusive finance, support the sustainable development of small and micro business entities, facilitate the effective implementation of the national strategy of rural revitalization, improve the quality of financial services in the field of people&#39;s livelihood, and give full play to inclusive finance. The role of finance in supporting green and low-carbon development. It is necessary to continue to deepen the structural reform of the financial supply side, improve the organizational system of multi-level inclusive financial institutions, guide various banking institutions to adhere to their positioning and healthy competition, improve the high-quality inclusive insurance system, enhance the efficiency of the capital market in serving inclusive finance, and orderly Promote the development of digital inclusive finance. We must focus on preventing and defusing financial risks in key areas, focusing on accelerating the reform of small and medium-sized banks to eliminate risks, improving the governance mechanisms of small and medium-sized banks, and resolutely cracking down on illegal financial activities, so as to maintain the bottom line of preventing systemic financial risks. It is necessary to improve the financial literacy and financial capabilities of the public, improve the protection system for the rights and interests of financial consumers, improve the legal level of inclusive finance, strengthen policy guidance and governance coordination, improve credit information sharing, risk sharing compensation and other mechanisms in key areas, and provide high-level inclusive finance Quality development creates a good ecology. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The &quot;Implementation Opinions&quot; make it clear that the party&#39;s overall leadership must be upheld and strengthened, and the party&#39;s leadership must be effectively implemented in all fields, aspects and links to promote the high-quality development of inclusive finance. It is necessary to strengthen monitoring and evaluation and establish a sound evaluation system. It is necessary to promote pilot demonstrations and actively and steadily promote mature experience. It is necessary to strengthen organizational coordination, optimize the coordination mechanism for promoting the development of inclusive finance, strengthen the linkage between the central and local governments, and coordinate measures to local conditions to promote the high-quality development of inclusive finance. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 五个合作项目  十年繁荣之路（经济新方位·特别报道）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/12/nw.D110000renmrb_20231012_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 12, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231012/1697055018510_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;Picture ①: Jakarta-Bandung High-Speed ​​Railway Dekarur stand. &lt;BR/>;Photographed by Shi Jiamin (People’s Vision) &lt;BR/>;Picture 2: Maputo Cross-Sea Bridge, Mozambique. &lt;BR/>;Photo provided by China Road and Bridge&lt;BR/>;Photo ③: China National Building Materials Zambia Industrial Park. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Zhou Yuanping (Image China) &lt;BR/>;Picture 4: Brazil’s Belo Monte UHV Phase II Project. &lt;BR/>;Photo provided by State Grid &lt;BR/>;Picture 5: Port of Piraeus, Greece. &lt;BR/>;Photo courtesy of China COSCO Shipping&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;The 3rd “Belt and Road” International Cooperation Summit The forum will be held in Beijing from October 17th to 18th, with the theme of &quot;High-quality joint construction of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; and joint efforts to achieve common development and prosperity.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This year marks the tenth anniversary of the joint construction of the “Belt and Road” initiative. As the main force in construction, my country&#39;s central enterprises have actively deployed and participated extensively. From large-scale infrastructure to &quot;small but beautiful&quot; people&#39;s livelihood projects, roads, bridges, ports, parks, and equipment projects have driven technology, standards, and equipment to go global, and also brought benefits to co-construction partners. Up to now, central enterprises have more than 8,000 institutions and projects, directly creating employment for nearly one million foreign employees. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Infrastructure &quot;hard connectivity&quot;. In the past 10 years, central enterprises have undertaken more than 200 major infrastructure projects such as overseas ports, railways, and airports, and star projects such as the Jakarta-Bandung High-speed Railway, the Maputo Cross-Sea Bridge, and the Port of Piraeus have emerged. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rule standard &quot;Soft Connect&quot;. Over the past 10 years, China and co-building countries have made positive progress in the docking of working systems, coordination of technical standards, mutual recognition of inspection results, and networking of electronic certificates. The overseas service networks of the three major telecom operators cover more than 40 countries, laying a &quot;highway&quot; for new infrastructure. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Work together to build a “connected heart” between the people of the country. In the past 10 years, central enterprises have built and operated more than 20 industrial parks. On the one hand, they have actively attracted local and third-country industries to settle in and helped host countries build an international production capacity cooperation platform; on the other hand, they have assisted local governments in solving problems such as transportation, water, electricity, We have undertaken more than 270 hydropower, wind power, and photovoltaic projects to address people&#39;s livelihood issues such as employment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Working together and helping each other, the road to achieving common development and prosperity will become wider and wider. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;印度尼西亚雅万高铁——&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;钢铁巨龙&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;提速发展&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10月2日，印度尼西亚，雅万高铁正式启用。这是东南亚第一条高速铁路，也是中国高铁首次全系统、全要素、全产业链在海外落地。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为雅万高铁承包商联合体指挥长，辛学忠早早来到雅加达哈利姆站，乘坐首发列车。 “我的心情就像队伍等待检阅一样激动。”辛学忠说，雅万高铁沿线地形复杂，特别是爪哇岛区域，施工难度极大。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;列车一路飞驰。车身印着科莫多龙的纹样，座椅点缀着印尼蜡染花布风格的祥云图案，凸显当地特色。 “雅万高铁动车组依托复兴号中国标准动车组技术平台设计制造，同时增添了适应性优化设计，以适应印尼高温高湿高盐雾的运营环境。”中车四方股份公司设计师张喆清介绍。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;说话间，列车穿越了全线最长隧道——6号隧道。身为隧道的建设者，中国中铁印尼雅万高铁项目工作人员綦敦强说：“为了确保隧道如期贯通，采用了超前地质预报、边墙注浆等多项工法，将我们的经验全部用到了雅万。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;40分钟后，列车顺利抵达万隆帕达拉朗站。当地民众载歌载舞，热烈庆祝，盼望更多新的经济活动随高铁而来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度尼西亚雅万高铁建设者古纳万：以前，从雅加达到万隆要3个多小时，高铁通车后只需不到1个小时。能参与国家第一条高铁的建设，我非常荣幸！ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;莫桑比克马普托跨海大桥——&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;飞虹跨海&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;气象一新&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;非洲南部，莫桑比克首都马普托入海口，马普托跨海大桥宛若飞虹，跨越蓝色海湾，将北岸主城区和南岸卡腾贝地区紧紧相连，凭借680米长的主跨长度，一举刷新非洲悬索桥主跨径之最。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大桥地处城市交通枢纽，既要保障10万吨级货轮通航需求，又要最大限度降低对航空安全的影响。 “当初几易其稿才确定双塔单跨锚碇式悬索桥方案，形成了近2500张图纸的成套技术规程。”中国路桥公司莫桑比克办事处开发部负责人陈豪举说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“受当地气候因素影响，普通沥青混合料容易开裂，降低施工质量。”陈豪举介绍，项目团队进行大量试验，不仅攻克了沥青浇筑难题，还丰富了大吸水率粗骨料配置高性能混凝土的研究成果。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2018年大桥通车以来，马普托气象一新。南岸，昔日渔村卡腾贝，如今商业区、居民区房屋林立。从马普托到南非，客货运时间从4小时缩短至1.5小时。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在莫桑比克，由中国路桥承建的又一座大桥——萨韦河新桥即将建成通车，中国桥梁“走出去”的故事还在续写。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;莫桑比克卡腾贝居民富莫：马普托跨海大桥给我们带来很大的变化。以前我们穿越海湾到市区十分困难，现在可以更方便地做生意，生活质量也改善了。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;中国建材赞比亚工业园——&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;绿色工厂&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;惠及民生&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;赞比亚首都卢萨卡往东南约30公里，中国建材赞比亚工业园坐落在丘陵山谷中。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;水泥、烧结砖等产品源源不断产出，却没有老式水泥厂灰尘漫天的景象——对这座现代化工厂，工业园安全环保部副部长陈立新很自豪：“工厂采用多项节能环保工艺，尽量选用工业副产品作为原材料，例如石膏尾矿、炉渣等。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;创造经济效益的同时，工业园还带来了当地道路、供水、照明等方面的民生改善。 2019年3月，附近齐亚亚村村长约翰·达卡和陈立新聊天时说：“村里有一段道路被阻断，村民们外出常要绕道。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当时兼任工业园所属石灰石矿矿长的陈立新和同事们商量出解决方案：矿山剥离需要排土，修路则要用土，何不“废土”利用？既解决村民出行难题，又消化渣土，一举两得。说干就干，项目团队爬高走低、踏勘场地。 3个月后，一条兼顾安全性与便捷性的村道顺利铺通。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们将继续努力，为深化共建&#39;一带一路&#39;合作、增进中非友谊贡献自己的力量。”陈立新说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国建材赞比亚工业园仓库主管伦古：工业园还帮我们扩建修缮了通往首都卢萨卡的道路，孩子上学、村民看病都十分方便，真令人高兴！ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;巴西美丽山特高压二期项目——&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;澎湃电力&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;源源赋能&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴西托坎廷斯州大草原上，国家电网巴西控股公司运维部技术处经理崔大伟开车前往实训基地。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我见证了项目从建设到投运的全过程。”崔大伟介绍，美丽山±800千伏特高压直流输电二期项目由中国国家电网公司投资建设运营，线路总长约2500公里，将电力从巴西北部的美丽山水电站输送到巴西东南部，与一期项目共计可满足约2200万人口的用电需求。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;带电作业技术是我国特高压直流输电线路的重要检修手段，在线路不停电、电量“零损失”情况下完成缺陷处理，保障持续供电。我国技术与当地经验如何结合？崔大伟和同事与巴西国家电力公司电科院多次交流，参与试验，推动特高压带电作业屏蔽服获得巴西劳工部认证。去年，线路铁塔附近的间隔棒损坏后，当地通过带电作业方式更换。这是巴西首次±800千伏特高压直流输电线路带电检修。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年，国网巴控公司组织了两轮培训，带电作业人员增加到40多人。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴西电力领域专家法比亚诺：美丽山特高压二期项目的投运，让我们了解到中国的先进技术。中国带电作业标准规范与巴西本地相结合，帮助我们培养更多线路运维人才。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 希腊比雷埃夫斯港——&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;千年古港&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;活力重现&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国和希腊友好交往源远流长，早在2000多年前就通过古丝绸之路实现交流往来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无垠海面，航路繁忙。爱琴海边，千年古港涅槃重生。 “作为希腊航运业的重要港口，比雷埃夫斯港一度陷入低谷，不少船东甚至弃港而去。”中远海运比雷埃夫斯港口有限公司副总裁金备源说，得益于中国企业的参与，比雷埃夫斯港活力重现，年集装箱吞吐量全球排名最高提升到第二十五位。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;更换老旧设备、翻新码头、采用数字化管理系统、提高码头客户服务标准、吸引高精尖人才入职……目前，比雷埃夫斯港已成为地中海领先的集装箱大港、欧洲最大的渡轮港口以及欧洲第三大邮轮母港。 2022年度，比雷埃夫斯港实现营业收入同比增长26.2%，净利润同比增长43.9%，分红水平提高到中国远洋海运集团收购前的12倍。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“截至2022年，中国远洋海运已在当地直接创造就业岗位约4000个，间接创造就业岗位1万多个，带动希腊GDP提高1.56个百分点。”金备源说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中远海运比雷埃夫斯港口有限公司董事会秘书萨瓦斯：2016年中国远洋海运集团开始管理港口，开展了许多投资和项目，对经济发展作出了巨大贡献，我感到非常骄傲。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本期统筹：殷新宇&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;蒋雪婕&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;吕&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;莉&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;融媒创作：刘莉莉&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;罗&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;彦&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;娄霄霄&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;版式设计：沈亦伶&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;数据来源：国务院国资委等&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 推动共建“一带一路”经贸合作不断迈上新台阶（共建“一带一路”·权威访谈）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/12/nw.D110000renmrb_20231012_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月12日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;十年来，中国与共建“一带一路”国家经贸领域合作取得一系列实打实、沉甸甸的合作成果。商务部副部长郭婷婷在接受新华社记者专访时表示，在以习近平同志为核心的党中央坚强领导下，中国坚持共商共建共享原则，与共建国家加强经贸领域务实合作，规模稳步扩大，质量持续提升，携手实现互利共赢。未来，中国将持续深化与共建国家务实合作，推动共建“一带一路”经贸合作不断迈上新台阶。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 三个“更加”凸显经贸合作量稳质升&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国与共建国家经贸合作取得的积极成效，郭婷婷用三个“更加”来概括。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;贸易投资更加深化——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国超大市场为共建国家提供了重要发展机遇，来自共建国家的商品在中国整体进口中占比已经接近一半。”郭婷婷说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郭婷婷介绍，中国是110多个共建国家的主要贸易伙伴，2022年与共建国家的货物贸易规模接近2.9万亿美元；2022年对共建国家直接投资超过300亿美元，吸引投资超过200亿美元，涵盖研发设计、生产制造、商贸物流等多个领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国与共建国家的贸易投资合作，促进了资源要素优化配置，推动了产业链供应链融合发展，为建设开放型世界经济注入更多动能和活力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;项目合作更加丰富——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这十年，中国在共建国家承包工程的完成营业额，每年都超过1000亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中老铁路通车，非洲疾控中心总部项目竣工，推进菌草、杂交水稻等一批“小而美”项目……细数标志性项目、援外成套项目、惠民生项目，郭婷婷说：“这些合作项目，助力共建国家完善基础设施建设，推动互联互通，改善民生福祉，增强了共建国家的发展能力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;平台机制更加健全——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郭婷婷介绍，中国已与20个共建国家签署自贸协定，特别是推动了《区域全面经济伙伴关系协定》（RCEP）全面生效，建成了全球最大自贸区；与相关国家签署了47个绿色、数字和蓝色领域的投资合作备忘录，“丝路电商”合作伙伴国增加到30个，新领域合作不断拓展；举办进博会、服贸会、广交会、投洽会、数贸会和一系列区域性展会，鼓励和支持各国企业共享“一带一路”发展机遇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 基础设施建设助力共建国家拓展发展空间&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;基础设施建设是共建“一带一路”的重要领域。郭婷婷介绍，十年来，中国在共建国家承包工程累计签订合同额2万亿美元，完成营业额1.3万亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郭婷婷认为，在共建“一带一路”倡议引领下，中国企业积极参与共建国家基础设施建设，助力共建国家夯实发展基础，拓展发展空间，主要呈现四个特点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一是行业分布广泛，涉及交通运输、民用建筑、电力工程、石油化工、通信工程、工业建设、水利建设、废水处理等诸多领域；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;二是标志性项目相继建成，包括中老铁路、雅万高铁、蒙内铁路、柬埔寨金港高速公路、巴基斯坦拉合尔轨道交通橙线项目等，都产生了广泛影响力和显著示范效应；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三是新兴领域快速发展，今年前8个月，中国企业在共建国家新签订节能环保类项目合同额160亿美元，同比增长22.2%，充分体现了“绿色”这一共建“一带一路”鲜明底色；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;四是有效惠及当地民生，累计在共建国家实施援外项目超过1600个，建设了一大批教育、卫生、环保、减贫等项目，助力共建国家增进民生福祉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郭婷婷说，下一步，商务部将指导企业扎实推进境外项目建设，推动更多高质量项目落地，将着力抓好四方面工作：一是加强战略对接、规划对接和产业对接，进一步深化基础设施项目互联互通；二是推动对外承包工程提质增效，支持设计咨询企业走出去，促进投资、建设、运营综合发展；三是拓展合作新领域，引导企业加强绿色基建、新型基建合作，助力共建国家实现绿色发展、数字化发展；四是深化三方和多方市场合作，发挥各方技术、资金、管理等方面特长，实现优势互补、共同发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 深化经贸合作推进与共建国家签署自贸协定&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“从实践角度看，自贸协定能够有效稳定和深化参与方的经贸合作，促进企业发展、增进民生福祉。”郭婷婷说，目前中国已同28个国家和地区签署自贸协定，其中包括20个共建国家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她介绍，十年来，中国与韩国、格鲁吉亚、厄瓜多尔、尼加拉瓜等签署双边自贸协定，与东盟、智利、新西兰等签署自贸协定升级议定书。2020年11月，中国与东盟10国和日韩澳新正式签署RCEP，今年6月已对全部15个成员生效。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“总的看，我们已经初步建立起立足周边、辐射&#39;一带一路&#39;、面向全球的自贸区网络。”郭婷婷说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郭婷婷表示，下一步，将按照党中央部署，不断扩大面向全球的高标准自由贸易区网络，积极推动加入《全面与进步跨太平洋伙伴关系协定》和《数字经济伙伴关系协定》，高质量实施RCEP，推进与东盟、海合会、塞尔维亚、洪都拉斯、新西兰、秘鲁等自贸协定谈判或升级谈判进程，让参与方的企业和人民更早、更多享受到自贸协定的制度性红利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（新华社北京10月11日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;记者谢希瑶、潘洁）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[03版要闻 - 共同书写丝路时代新篇]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/12/nw.D110000renmrb_20231012_1-03.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月12日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛将于10月17日至18日在北京举行。这是纪念“一带一路”倡议提出10周年最隆重的活动，也是各方共商高质量共建“一带一路”合作的重要平台。接受本报记者采访的国际人士高度赞赏共建“一带一路”合作10年来取得的累累硕果，热切期待本届高峰论坛凝聚起携手推动高质量共建“一带一路”的最大合力，书写国家互利共赢、人民相知相亲、文明互学互鉴的丝路时代新篇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“期待中国智慧继续为国际发展事业提供指引”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高峰论坛期间的活动包括开幕式，互联互通、绿色发展、数字经济3场高级别论坛，以及关于贸易畅通、民心相通、智库交流、廉洁丝路、地方合作、海洋合作的6场专题论坛，同时还将举办企业家大会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;老挝建国阵线中央委员布拉帕表示，本届高峰论坛将回顾共建“一带一路”合作历程，凝聚各方合作共识，巩固良好合作态势，对推动各方进一步加强发展战略对接、深化伙伴关系、实现联动发展具有重要意义。“如何引领高质量共建&#39;一带一路&#39;、促进国际社会团结合作，世界期待听到中方观点和主张。相信本届高峰论坛将为共建&#39;一带一路&#39;的未来指明方向。”布拉帕表示，10年来，老中共建“一带一路”为老挝开创了新的发展机遇，期待双方合作不断深化，持续造福两国人民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;南非约翰内斯堡大学非洲—中国研究中心高级研究员科菲·库阿库认为，在共建“一带一路”倡议提出10周年之际举行本届高峰论坛意义重大。中国始终坚持普惠包容、互利共赢，致力于让各国人民分享发展果实。期待在“智库交流”专题论坛上，各方代表能就深化农业、基础设施建设等领域合作展开交流，让共建“一带一路”继续切实提高共建国家人民生活质量，让更多人摆脱贫困，“期待中国智慧继续为国际发展事业提供指引”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿联酋通讯社记者费拉斯·哈桑即将赴华参与报道本届高峰论坛及相关活动。他表示，高峰论坛的规模令人瞩目，内容设置有利于增进各国相互理解与合作、凝聚共同发展的力量，各界都期待倾听中方关于合作、发展、和平与繁荣的观点和主张。哈桑说：“共建&#39;一带一路&#39;的凝聚力在于其传递了开放、包容和共赢的理念，期待高峰论坛就如何推进高质量共建&#39;一带一路&#39;指明方向和路径。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蒙古国国际问题专家、前外交官巴雅尔呼表示，共建“一带一路”推动全球共同发展取得巨大进步。过去10年的成果是非常好的开端，许多国家和地区积极支持并参与其中。目前已有来自130多个国家、30多个国际组织的代表确认与会，这是共建“一带一路”倡议得到国际社会广泛支持的很好证明。蒙古国将继续同中国携手共建“一带一路”，实现共同发展，造福两国人民，推动蒙中务实合作不断取得新成果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; “共建&#39;一带一路&#39;的成果是实实在在的”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共建“一带一路”倡议源于中国，机会和成果属于世界。“一带一路”不是简单的一条路或一条经济带，而是让全人类共同进步的倡议。国际人士认为，10年来，共建“一带一路”合作成果丰硕，为各国共同发展开辟了新道路，世界期待这一倡议推动人类社会实现更好发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿尔巴尼亚全球化研究院执行院长马尔塞拉·穆萨贝卢表示，10年来，共建“一带一路”在全球范围内取得了令人瞩目的成就，尤其在互联互通领域涌现出大量成功案例。在中东欧地区，匈塞铁路、克罗地亚佩列沙茨大桥、希腊比雷埃夫斯港等项目，都为促进当地经济发展、实现互联互通作出了突出贡献。“期待本届高峰论坛为解决当今全球性问题、推动构建人类命运共同体作出新的贡献。”穆萨贝卢表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国拉丁美洲和加勒比经济委员会执行秘书何塞·曼努埃尔·萨拉萨尔—希里纳奇斯认为，共建“一带一路”鼓励对经济发展至关重要的领域进行投资，倡导贸易投资自由化便利化，提供有效的减贫路径，受到世界上大多数国家尤其是广大发展中国家的欢迎。在拉美和加勒比地区，共建“一带一路”促进了相关国家投资多样化，增加了对中国市场的出口，许多国家从与中国的合作中受益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“共建&#39;一带一路&#39;倡议秉持共商共建共享原则，践行真正的多边主义，得到国际社会广泛支持和参与。”古巴拉丁美洲通讯社社长路易斯·冈萨雷斯表示，“倡议主张各方平等相待、开放包容、合作共赢，有利于推动全球治理体系朝着更加公正合理的方向发展。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“让发展的红利惠及世界，让缓解冲突、减少贫困成为可能。共建&#39;一带一路&#39;的成果是实实在在的。”库阿库说，在非洲，共建“一带一路”帮助许多国家构建起基础设施网络，推动实现非洲大陆互联互通、经济一体化。面向未来，这一倡议还将为非洲国家工业化、现代化进程作出积极贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴雅尔呼表示，环境问题是全球面临的共同挑战，绿色发展是共建“一带一路”倡议的重要内容。蒙古国提出了“种植十亿棵树”计划，是遏制荒漠化、应对气候变化、加强环境保护的具体举措。中国在荒漠化治理方面积累了丰富实践经验，值得蒙古国学习借鉴。目前，两国正在开展相关合作，绿色合作前景广阔。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; “高质量共建&#39;一带一路&#39;将不断创造新的发展机遇”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10年来，共建“一带一路”倡议在全球范围内受到广泛好评。当前，世界百年未有之大变局加速演进，全球性挑战层出不穷，国际社会迫切需要团结起来，推动高质量共建“一带一路”不断取得新成果，拓宽各方携手前进的阳光大道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;委内瑞拉中国问题研究中心主任艾马拉·格德尔表示，共建“一带一路”倡议与广大拉美和加勒比地区寻求和平、稳定和发展的愿望高度契合。从智能电网技术到风力、水力发电等，中国企业为拉美国家实现可持续发展作出重要贡献。“拉美和加勒比地区对先进基础设施和清洁能源有着巨大需求，高质量共建&#39;一带一路&#39;将不断创造新的发展机遇，极大提升地区国家的发展潜力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是一个合力应对全球性挑战、促进人类共同进步的平台。”在哈桑看来，通过推进绿色丝绸之路、数字丝绸之路建设，共建“一带一路”为全球可持续发展提供了强大驱动力。他期待本届高峰论坛帮助各方加强跨国合作和技术交流，推进绿色技术研发和应用，更好应对气候变化挑战，同时帮助各方共享数字经济红利，加速数字化进程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;泰国开泰银行高级副总裁蔡伟才说，“泰国4.0”战略提出要大力发展高科技、新能源、数字经济等，高质量共建“一带一路”符合泰国发展需求，泰中两国共建“一带一路”合作前景广阔。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;布拉帕说，在全球经济复苏艰难、国际发展合作动能不足的当下，高质量共建“一带一路”顺应了经济全球化的潮流，顺应了各国特别是广大发展中国家求和平、谋发展、促合作的愿望。中国持续深化可再生能源领域国际合作，在共建“一带一路”国家实施了一批绿色低碳可持续的清洁项目，帮助有需要的国家和地区推广应用先进绿色能源技术。老中合作开发光伏发电等项目，不仅将带动中国清洁能源优势产能出海，也将加快老挝能源转型，对促进可持续发展意义重大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（本报北京、曼谷、约翰内斯堡、迪拜、乌兰巴托、罗马、里约热内卢、墨西哥城10月11日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;记者龚鸣、孙广勇、闫韫明、管克江、霍文、谢亚宏、陈一鸣、彭敏）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 12 Oct 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>