<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 铸就中华文化新辉煌]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/07/nw.D110000renmrb_20231007_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, October 7, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;The rejuvenation of a nation requires strong material power as well as strong spiritual power. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core has taken charge of the overall situation, placed ideological and cultural propaganda work in an important position, and guided the ideological and cultural propaganda work to achieve historic results in raising the flag and rectifying the source. Achievements, historic changes, showing a new look and embarking on a new journey while keeping integrity, innovation, and pioneering spirit. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Be far-sighted and directional, pointing the way forward for the development of propaganda, ideological and cultural undertakings in the new era&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the foot of Yanshan Mountain, the national style is grand and the cultural context is endless. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On June 1, 2023, General Secretary Xi Jinping visited the Central Headquarters of the National Library of China, located on the northern extension of the central axis of Beijing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Walking into the National Study Room, the General Secretary looked at the starry sky dome in the central caisson at the top. On the dome, the astronomical charts carved in stone from the Song Dynasty show the wisdom of the ancients, and the stars are brilliant, vast and profound; in the study, 15 groups of giant bookcases display nearly 30,000 volumes of New China&#39;s high-quality publications, and the starry sky of ideas is magnificent. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Civilization is everlasting, and ideas keep pace with the times. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the symposium on cultural inheritance and development held the next day, General Secretary Xi Jinping profoundly summarized a series of new ideas, new perspectives and new conclusions put forward in cultural construction since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, and emphasized that these important perspectives It is a theoretical summary of the practical experience in building party leadership culture in the new era and is the fundamental basis for doing a good job in publicity, ideological and cultural work. It must be implemented and continuously enriched and developed in the long term. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In August 10 years ago, the first national propaganda and ideological work conference was held after the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China. General Secretary Xi Jinping’s speech was very meaningful:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I have been thinking about a question... Can we Chinese Communists uphold the party’s leadership, uphold and develop socialism with Chinese characteristics in an increasingly complex international and domestic environment? , this still requires us, generations of Communists, to continue to answer. To do a good job in ideological work and propaganda and ideological work, we must understand it in this context.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sober and calm questioning, throughout Foresight and foresight in promoting ideological and cultural undertakings. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is a major proposition under a new historical coordinate: Socialism with Chinese characteristics has entered a new era. Faced with the overall strategic situation of the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation and the world&#39;s major changes unseen in a century, they are intertwined, stirred up and influenced each other. How should we focus our hearts and souls and hold high our banner? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is the call of the times to promote theoretical innovation: if a nation wants to be at the forefront of the times, it must have theoretical thinking and correct ideological guidance for a moment. If we want to continuously promote the Sinicization of Marxism and constantly climb to new ideological peaks, how should we summarize experience and grasp the rules? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is a high degree of consciousness that continues the historical context: without a high degree of cultural confidence and without cultural prosperity, there will be no great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation; without the prosperity and development of socialist culture, there will be no socialist modernization. To promote the construction of a socialist cultural power, how should we take the initiative and make another glorious chapter? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Ideological work is an extremely important task for the Party. It is work that establishes the heart for the country and the soul for the nation.” General Secretary Xi Jinping profoundly pointed out. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Keep abreast of the pulse of the times, focus on central work, highlight problem orientation, and promote the ever-changing atmosphere in the field of publicity, ideology and culture. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Get to the bottom of things and uphold and strengthen the Party’s overall leadership over propaganda, ideological and cultural work——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;November 2013, Beijing, the Third Plenary Session of the 18th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At this important meeting that officially opened the new era of comprehensively deepening reforms, General Secretary Xi Jinping’s words on ideological work were inspiring:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“While concentrating on economic construction, At the same time, ideological work must not be relaxed or weakened for a moment, and the leadership, management, and discourse power of ideological work must be firmly in our hands and must not be left aside at any time, otherwise we will make irreparable historical mistakes.” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ideology is about flags, roads, and national political security. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the rapid development of economy, science and technology and the profound adjustment of social structure, erroneous ideological trends such as money worship, hedonism, extreme individualism and historical nihilism appear from time to time. Online public opinions are chaotic and have seriously affected people&#39;s thinking and society. public opinion environment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Focusing on solving the problem of weakening party leadership in the ideological field, General Secretary Xi Jinping made the final decision: “We must strengthen the party’s overall leadership over propaganda and ideological work, and clearly insist on the party’s management of propaganda and ideology.”&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;The National Propaganda and Ideological Work Conference was held twice, emphasizing that “to do a good job in propaganda and ideological work, the whole party must take action” and “build a socialist ideology with strong cohesion and leadership”; at the symposium on literary and art work, it was pointed out that “the Party’s Leadership is the fundamental guarantee for the development of socialist literature and art&quot;; at the party&#39;s press and public opinion work symposium, it was emphasized that &quot;the media sponsored by the party and the government are the propaganda positions of the party and the government and must be surnamed party&quot;; at the network security and informatization work symposium The Party Central Committee demanded that “our leading cadres should go wherever the masses are”; at the symposium on philosophy and social sciences, it was pointed out that “strengthening and improving the party’s leadership over philosophy and social sciences work is fundamental to the prosperity and development of philosophy and social sciences in our country. Guarantee&quot;; at the National Conference on Ideological and Political Work in Colleges and Universities, it was emphasized that &quot;firmly grasp the party&#39;s leadership over the work of colleges and universities&quot;...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping clarified his principled position on a series of fundamental issues and clarified the fog of understanding , corrected work orientation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If the direction is clear, the thinking will be clear. Targeted measures have emerged one after another:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Establish and uphold the fundamental system of Marxism’s guiding position in the ideological field; formulate implementation measures for the ideological work responsibility system, and clarify party committees at all levels in the form of intra-party regulations (Party Group) Responsibilities; resolutely fight against all kinds of historical nihilistic tendencies such as distortion, vilification and blasphemy of heroes and martyrs, and formulate and promulgate the Law on the Protection of Heroes and Martyrs; vigorously rectify the online ecological chaos and establish a three-level network information management system at the central, provincial and municipal levels; formulate The first basic and backbone intra-party regulation on propaganda work, the &quot;Regulations on the Propaganda Work of the Communist Party of China&quot;, uses a rigid legal system to provide strong guidance and support for the whole party to carry out propaganda work...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lipo By simultaneously promoting the turbid and promoting the clear, the once passive situation in the ideological field has been fundamentally reversed, and the situation in the ideological field has undergone an overall and fundamental change. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Keeping integrity and pioneering new ideas, clearly put forward the major conclusion of &quot;two combinations&quot; -&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Why the Communist Party of China can do it, why socialism with Chinese characteristics is good, in the final analysis, it is the practice of Marxism, and it is China Marxism adapts to the changing times. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On July 1, 2021, in Tiananmen Square, a conference to celebrate the 100th anniversary of the founding of the Communist Party of China was held grandly. General Secretary Xi Jinping’s words are sonorous: “Insist on combining the basic principles of Marxism with China’s specific reality and with China’s excellent traditional culture, use Marxism to observe the times, grasp the times, and lead the times, and continue to develop contemporary Chinese Marxism and 21st century Marxism. Doctrine!&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is the first time that the major thesis of &quot;two combinations&quot; has been formally put forward. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since then, the &quot;two combinations&quot; have been written into the &quot;Resolution of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China on the Major Achievements and Historical Experience of the Party&#39;s Centenary Struggle&quot; and the report of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the foot of Wuyi Mountain, Zhu Xiyuan said that &quot;we must organically combine adhering to Marxism with the promotion of China&#39;s excellent traditional culture&quot;. At Yinxu, he emphasized that &quot;the fundamental way for us to promote the sinicization of Marxism with the times is &#39;two Combination&#39;&quot;, profoundly explained the significance of &quot;two combinations&quot; at the symposium on cultural inheritance and development, pointing out that &quot;&#39;two combinations&#39; are the greatest magic weapon for our success&quot;...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Continue to deepen our understanding of the party Understanding the regularity of theoretical innovation, General Secretary Xi Jinping’s discussion of the “two combinations”, especially the “second combination”, has continued to deepen, indicating that our party’s understanding of China’s path, theory, and system has reached a new height, indicating that our party’s understanding of China’s path, theory, and system has reached a new height. The historical confidence and cultural confidence have reached a new height, indicating that our party’s consciousness of promoting cultural innovation while inheriting China’s excellent traditional culture has reached a new height. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Consolidate the foundation and cultivate the foundation, and strengthen self-confidence from the continuous history and culture——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sansu Temple in Meishan, Sichuan. Centennial ginkgo trees and thousand-year-old yellow kudzu trees are full of vitality. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On June 8, 2022, General Secretary Xi Jinping came here to inspect the thousand-year-old ancient temple. He said with deep feeling: &quot;A drop of water can see the sun, and a Sansu Temple can see our Chinese culture. It is broad and profound. We say that we must strengthen cultural self-confidence, and China has the &#39;Three Soviets&#39;. This is an important example.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Continuity, innovation, unity, inclusiveness and peace - General Secretary Xi Jinping He profoundly summarized the five outstanding characteristics of Chinese civilization and pointed out that &quot;cultural confidence comes from our cultural subjectivity.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the mind of the General Secretary, cultural self-confidence is the most basic, profound and lasting force in the development of a country and a nation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Went to the Dunhuang Academy to host a symposium, affirming that &quot;Dunhuang culture demonstrates the cultural confidence of the Chinese nation&quot;; went to the Yangpu Riverside in Shanghai, emphasizing &quot;preserving the city&#39;s historical and cultural memory so that people can remember history and remember it&quot; Nostalgia, strengthen cultural self-confidence, and enhance feelings about home and country&quot;; cordially communicated with teachers and students at Yuelu Academy, encouraging &quot;contemporary students must further strengthen cultural self-confidence in the process of inheriting China&#39;s excellent traditional culture&quot;; came to Yungang Grottoes and pointed out that &quot; Let tourism become a process for people to understand Chinese culture and enhance cultural confidence&quot;...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping has placed cultural confidence at an unprecedented height, cultivating the spiritual strength of the whole nation and laying the foundation for rejuvenation. The great cause is concentrated. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The outline outline outlines a blueprint path for the construction of a culturally powerful country -&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Culture rejuvenates the country, and a strong culture strengthens the nation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Contemporary Chinese Communists and the Chinese people should and must be able to shoulder the new cultural mission, carry out cultural creation in practical creation, and achieve cultural progress in historical progress!”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; In the report of the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping put forward the major proposition of &quot;new cultural mission&quot; for the first time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Standing at the height of building a strong country and rejuvenating the nation, General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out the way forward for building a socialist cultural power:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Focusing on the new situation, new tasks and new requirements, he clearly proposed propaganda and ideological work We must consciously assume the mission of &quot;raising the flag, gathering people&#39;s hearts, educating new people, developing culture, and displaying our image&quot;;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cultivate a positive, healthy, and positive Internet culture, and make it clear that &quot;the Internet has become a platform for public opinion struggles.&quot; &quot;The main battlefield&quot;, bluntly stated that &quot;if you cannot pass the Internet, you will not be able to pass the long-term governance&quot;;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Emphasis on adhering to the people-centered creative orientation, and held the meeting again after 72 years to guide the progress of Chinese literature and art A symposium on the direction of cultural relics pointed out that &quot;there are a hundred or a thousand methods of literary and artistic creation, but the most fundamental, most critical and most reliable method is to take root in the people and take root in life&quot;;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Care about the protection and use of cultural relics and the protection and inheritance of cultural heritage, &quot;cultural footprints&quot; throughout the country, inspecting cultural landmarks, exploring the roots of civilization, and remembering &quot;protecting the city&#39;s historical and cultural heritage as we cherish our own lives&quot;;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Attach importance to accelerating the construction of Chinese discourse and Chinese narrative system, requiring &quot;efforts to create new concepts, new categories and new expressions that integrate China and foreign countries, tell Chinese stories well, and spread Chinese voices well&quot;;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strive to promote exchanges and mutual learning among civilizations, once and for all He has acted as a &quot;cultural spokesperson&quot; during overseas visits, demonstrated the broad mind of Chinese civilization in home diplomacy time and time again, and vividly interpreted that &quot;civilizations are colorful due to exchanges, and civilizations are enriched due to mutual learning&quot;;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…… &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping has clearly defined the mission of publicizing ideological and cultural work with the historical initiative, extraordinary theoretical courage, outstanding political wisdom, and strong mission of a Marxist politician, thinker, and strategist. task, promote propaganda, ideological and cultural construction and open a new chapter. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Create souls with intellectuals and bacon, and promote ideological and cultural propaganda to achieve new results&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core Under the leadership of the Party Central Committee, the situation in the ideological field of our country has undergone overall and fundamental changes. The cultural confidence of the whole Party and the people of all ethnic groups has been significantly enhanced. The cohesion and centripetal force of the whole society have been greatly improved, providing a new situation for the cause of the Party and the country in the new era. A strong ideological guarantee and strong spiritual strength. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strengthen the ideological arm, and the Party’s innovative theories are deeply rooted in the hearts of the people——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Entering the Beijing Book Building, in front of the “Study and Implementation of Xi Jinping’s Socialist Thought with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era Theme Educational Books” area, &quot;Selected Readings of Xi Jinping&#39;s Works&quot; is placed in a prominent position, attracting many readers to stop and read. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As an authoritative textbook for in-depth study and implementation of the Party’s innovative theory, on April 3 this year, this important work of General Secretary Xi Jinping edited in the name of the Document Editing Committee of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China was officially published. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the same day, the theme education work conference was held in Beijing, and &quot;a new learning competition&quot; kicked off. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Standing at the strategic height of realizing the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation, the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core leads the whole party to promote the development of the cause with great theoretical study and strong ideological arming. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From the previous centralized education within the party that insisted on theoretical learning as the primary task, to the establishment of a central propaganda team to carry out grassroots propaganda, under the personal care and guidance of General Secretary Xi Jinping, from the central to local governments, the atmosphere of theoretical learning has become increasingly strong . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Deepening theoretical research and promoting systematic and academic construction are the basic prerequisites for strengthening the party&#39;s theoretical arm. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Entering a new era, the construction of platforms such as Marxist theoretical research and construction projects has been solidly advanced. The Research Center for Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era has achieved fruitful results. The philosophy and social science circles have grasped the essence of theory and explored the spiritual connotation. The understanding of the party’s innovative theory continues to deepen. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On January 1, 2019, a new thinking learning platform with powerful functions and rich content - &quot;Xueqiangguo&quot; was unveiled. Within three months of its launch, the number of registered users exceeded 100 million. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Popular theoretical readings such as &quot;Chinese-style Modernization Face to Face&quot; and &quot;Century Party Face to Face&quot; make the theory more vivid and perceptible; new carriers and new positions such as the New Era Civilization Practice Center and the County-level Integrated Media Center support the party&#39;s innovation The theory continues to penetrate into the grassroots; brand columns such as &quot;First Observation&quot;, &quot;First View&quot; and &quot;Current Affairs News Eye&quot; launched by major central media have continued to extend the scope and breadth of the theory&#39;s popularization...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The light of thought illuminates the way forward. , the craze for learning surged across China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nowadays, open classes on popular theory have triggered a &quot;drama-chasing&quot; effect among young people. Theoretical study guidance books have been listed among the &quot;100 Books Favored by Farmers&quot;, and the good voice of the Party has become the most powerful voice in society. The sound reaches directly into the hearts of the people and echoes across the land of China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Inspiring spiritual morale and greatly enhancing the cohesion and centripetal force of the people across the country——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On July 1, 2021, a meeting to celebrate the 100th anniversary of the founding of the Communist Party of China was grandly held in Tiananmen Square. The grand ceremony of the country inspired hundreds of millions of Chinese people to express their love for the Party and country. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As General Secretary Xi Jinping said: &quot;The celebrations are grand, solemn and magnificent, and the rituals sequence the universe and bring harmony to the world.&quot; &quot;It plays a role in unifying thoughts, gathering strength, inspiring people, and boosting morale.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From commemorating the 70th anniversary of the victory of the Anti-Japanese War and celebrating the 40th anniversary of reform and opening up, to celebrating the 70th anniversary of the founding of New China and the 100th anniversary of the founding of the Communist Party of China, the publicity, ideological and cultural front focuses on important nodes and major events to promote the integration of the hearts of the party and the people. , the national prestige and the military power are demonstrated, gathering together the indestructible majestic power. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The party’s news and public opinion work is related to the cohesion and centripetal force of the entire party and the people of all ethnic groups in the country. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On February 19, 2016, General Secretary Xi Jinping spent a whole day going to People’s Daily, Xinhua News Agency, and CCTV for on-the-spot investigation, and chaired a symposium on the party’s news and public opinion work, and proposed new The responsibilities and missions of the party’s news and public opinion work under the conditions of the times:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Hold the banner high, lead the way, focus on the center, serve the overall situation, unite the people, boost morale, cultivate people’s morale, unite efforts, and clarify fallacies , distinguish right from wrong, connect China and foreign countries, and communicate with the world.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Three years later, on January 25, 2019, General Secretary Xi Jinping led the members of the Political Bureau of the 19th CPC Central Committee to move the &quot;classroom&quot; of collective learning to Zhongnanhai To the front line of media integration development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the &quot;Guiding Opinions on Promoting the Integrated Development of Traditional Media and Emerging Media&quot; and &quot;Opinions on Accelerating the In-depth Integrated Development of Media&quot; have been issued successively. Taking integrated development as a breakthrough, mainstream media In the changing times, &quot;the butterfly breaks out of its cocoon and changes&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The major media outlets are in full bloom, with text, pictures, audio and video competing to use innovative means and all-media presentation to record the touching moments of poverty alleviation and outline a beautiful picture of a well-off society in an all-round way. It shows a vivid picture of high-quality development and gathers the strength for progress with each fine masterpiece. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wherever the people are, there is the focus of concentration. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Cyberspace has become a new space for people’s production and life, so it should also become a new space for our party to build consensus.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For more than ten years, whether it is organizing China Internet Activities such as the Civilization Conference and the Wuzhen Summit of the World Internet Conference have also carried out special governance actions such as &quot;Network Cleaning&quot; and &quot;Qingming&quot; to accelerate the cultivation of a healthy network culture and continuously gather forces for good. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;New people of the era who have firm ideals and convictions and are worthy of the important task of national rejuvenation are constantly emerging——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On April 25, 2022, at the Lide Building of Renmin University of China, a concert titled &quot;Inheriting China Ideological and political courses with the theme of &quot;The spiritual pedigree of Communists and becoming new people of the era worthy of the important task of national rejuvenation&quot; are ongoing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping walked into the classroom, waved to the teachers and students, sat among the students, listened to the lectures and participated in the discussions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the warm applause of teachers and students, the General Secretary started from the extraordinary road China has traveled, and talked about Marxism in the cave dwellings of Yan&#39;an, the poverty and poverty at the beginning of the founding of New China, and the thunder of reform and opening up. Cross the blank... He encouraged the students to bravely be pioneers and career pioneers in the new journey of comprehensively building a modern socialist country. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From the spirit of poverty alleviation and the spirit of fighting the epidemic, to the Beidou spirit and the Silk Road spirit of the new era... we will carry forward the spiritual pedigree of the Chinese Communists with the great party-building spirit as the source, and create spiritual monuments one after another to help new people of the era grow. Provide solid support;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From the &quot;Implementation Outline for Citizen Morality Construction in the New Era&quot; and the &quot;Implementation Outline for Patriotism Education in the New Era&quot; have been issued successively, to the continuous emergence of &quot;models of the times&quot; and &quot;good Chinese people&quot;... core values ​​of socialism Widely disseminated, love for the party, patriotism, and love for socialism have become a strong voice of the times;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From the issuance of the &quot;Opinions on Strengthening and Improving Ideological and Political Work in the New Era&quot; to comprehensively improving the level of ideological and political course construction and innovating Methods and methods... The quality of ideological and political work at the grassroots level continues to improve, and the ideological and political work system is increasingly improved;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Establish a Martyrs&#39; Day, award the &quot;July 1st Medal&quot; and &quot;Medal of the Republic&quot;, and establish and improve the party and country&#39;s meritorious honors Commendation system... A good atmosphere in which the whole society respects heroes, learns from heroes, and strives to be heroes is increasingly formed; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Activities to create spiritual civilization such as civilized families and civilized campuses are carried out in depth, and the cultivation of respect for the elderly, love for the young, diligence and thrift, etc. The new trend of civilization rooted in traditional culture has blown into the hearts of the people, providing a steady stream of moral nourishment for the cause of socialism with Chinese characteristics...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core focuses on &quot;who to train&quot; and &quot;how to train&quot; People&quot;, leading batch after batch of new people of the era to strengthen their confidence, strengthen their consciousness, improve their quality, and devote themselves to the great cause of national rejuvenation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the fields, the &quot;new farmers&quot; work hard in the cold and summer, and work hard to keep China&#39;s rice bowl firmly in their hands; in the factory workshops, the new generation of workers work hard to practice their skills, strive for excellence, and work tirelessly to Study to make the &quot;golden business card&quot; of &quot;Made in China&quot; shine in the world; in sports arenas, athletes work hard and strive for great results, making the five-star red flag fly high again and again; on the front line of disaster relief, countless young faces are charging forward and marching against the trend. , saving the people in danger...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Promoting cultural prosperity and taking solid steps in building a socialist cultural power——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liangzhu, Yuhang, Zhejiang, &quot;a beautiful island in the water&quot; &quot;. Generations of archaeologists have worked hard here to explore the first traces of Chinese civilization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Liangzhu site is a holy place that demonstrates the five thousand years of Chinese civilization history.” In July 2003, Xi Jinping, then Secretary of the Zhejiang Provincial Party Committee, made an important conclusion on the historical status of the site. In 2016, General Secretary Xi Jinping issued important instructions on the application of the Liangzhu Ancient City Site as a World Heritage Site. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Three years later, the Liangzhu Ancient City ruins were selected into the World Heritage List. Foreign experts commented: &quot;Liangzhu has enabled us to understand China&#39;s early civilization more than a thousand years in advance.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core has strong cultural confidence and strong historical responsibility to inherit and inherit Carry forward the excellent traditional Chinese culture as a historic and strategic project, and lead the creative transformation and innovative development of Chinese culture. The &quot;Opinions on Implementing the Inheritance and Development Project of China&#39;s Excellent Traditional Culture&quot; was issued, which for the first time elaborated on the inheritance and development of China&#39;s excellent traditional culture in the form of a central document. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From the continuous advancement of Dunhuang cultural protection research work to the in-depth implementation of major projects such as the revolutionary cultural relics protection and utilization project; from the compilation and publication of &quot;Fuxing Library&quot; and &quot;Chinese Painting Series of Ancient Dynasties&quot; to the Chinese Communist Party History Exhibition Hall , the National Edition Museum of China and other cultural halls have been completed one after another... Under the care and promotion of General Secretary Xi Jinping, the &quot;pool of spring water&quot; of Chinese culture is full of vitality. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In today&#39;s China, the &quot;cultural museum craze&quot; is booming and the &quot;cultural and creative wind&quot; is blowing hard. The heritage displayed on the vast land and the words written in ancient books are coming to life. The excellent traditional Chinese culture is creatively transformed and innovated. Sexual development allows the cultural context to pass on the strings and songs endlessly and last for a long time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Literature and art are the clarion call for the advancement of the times. They can best represent the style of an era and best lead the ethos of an era. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;I look up at the starry sky you have seen, and the earth under my feet has changed time and space. The red color you left swaying in the wind is in my heart!&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shanghai Longhua Martyrs Cemetery, The tombs of the three martyrs - Chen Yannian, Chen Qiaonian and Zhao Shiyan - who are well-known for the TV series &quot;The Age of Awakening&quot;, are filled with letters to the martyrs. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One after another, powerful literary and artistic works play a heart-stirring voice of the times, the voice of patriotism, and the voice of the people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the literary and artistic field has blossomed with hundreds of flowers and achieved fruitful results: film and television works such as &quot;Changjin Lake&quot; and &quot;Mountains and Seas&quot; have both historical significance and realistic concern; &quot;The World&quot; and &quot;Snow Mountain Land&quot; Literary works such as &quot;The Party&#39;s Daughter&quot; and the dance drama &quot;The Eternal Wave&quot; and other innovative forms reproduce the heroic image...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Culture is not only the spiritual bond that unites people&#39;s hearts, but also the It is a key factor in improving people&#39;s livelihood and well-being. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking at the state, cultural projects to benefit the people are implemented in depth, various literary and artistic masterpieces continue to emerge, cultural tourism is deeply integrated, the cultural industry develops rapidly, cultural undertakings in the new era are full of vitality, and the cultural innovation and creativity of the entire nation are bursting out. The ancient oriental civilization has made great strides towards becoming a socialist cultural power. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tell China’s story well, the country’s cultural soft power and the influence of Chinese culture are increasing day by day——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In April 2023, Guangzhou was full of flowers in spring. Located at the foothills of Baiyun Mountain, the Pine Garden is surrounded by mountains and rivers and has a unique style. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping invited French President Macron to stroll through the Lingnan Gardens, sit by the water, and enjoy the scenery while sipping tea. The thousand-year-old guqin played a song &quot;Mountains and Flowing Waters&quot;, which the two heads of state enjoyed together. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“To understand today’s China, we must start by understanding China’s history.” General Secretary Xi Jinping discussed the past and present. “We are full of confidence in China’s development prospects.” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;In the past two days, our exchanges and friendship have been in-depth, which has enabled me to further appreciate China&#39;s long and splendid history and culture, and enhanced my understanding of modern China&#39;s governance concepts.&quot; Macron said deeply. explain. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The multilingual edition of &quot;Xi Jinping: The Governance of China&quot; has aroused enthusiastic responses overseas, opening windows for readers from all over the world to observe and perceive China;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The Historical Mission of the Communist Party of China&quot; and Action Value&quot;, &quot;China&#39;s New Party System&quot; white paper, &quot;China&#39;s Democracy&quot; white paper and other documents show the world a true, three-dimensional and comprehensive China; Performances continue to appear on the international stage, domestic film and television dramas are popular overseas, and dance, acrobatics, fine arts and folk literature and art have successively gone abroad;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Brand activities such as &quot;Perception of China&quot;, &quot;Happy Spring Festival&quot; and &quot;Spring Together&quot; are held nationwide. The world has set off an upsurge in the charm of Chinese culture;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Beijing Winter Olympics, Hangzhou Asian Games, and Chengdu Universiade stunned the world, showing the world that Chinese culture embraces all rivers and is inclusive of the world;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; A series of home diplomacy, such as the Forum on China-Africa Cooperation, the Shanghai International Import Expo, and the Conference on Dialogue of Asian Civilizations, tell the world China’s story and introduce China’s experience...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A China that is everlasting and ever-changing, is being open and inclusive. The mind and spirit of integrity and innovation are rooted in the land of China and displayed in front of the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sing the story of China with the voice of culture, build value consensus with the soul of culture, and promote the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind through mutual learning among civilizations... The radiance of the new era of Chinese culture has promoted the development of Chinese civilization and other countries. Civilizations share beauty and beauty and coexist harmoniously. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the new era, the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core has pointed out the direction for doing a good job in external publicity under the new situation, improving the country’s cultural soft power and the influence of Chinese culture, so that credible, lovable, and The respectable image of China is more real and palpable, playing a beautiful movement of peace, development, cooperation and win-win. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Aim high and look to the future, and build the modern civilization of the Chinese nation at a new historical starting point&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Yin Ruins in Anyang, Henan Province, the Huan River meanders, and the oracle bones are strange . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On October 28, 2022, less than a week before the conclusion of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping came here for an inspection. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Walking into the Yin Ruins Museum to view bronzes, jades, oracle bone inscriptions and other cultural relics, General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out the profound meaning of this visit: &quot;I have longed for the Yin Ruins. This time I came to learn more about Chinese civilization and use the past for the present. , to provide reference for better building the modern civilization of the Chinese nation.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Chinese civilization has a long history and has never been interrupted. It has shaped our great nation, and this nation will continue to be great.&quot; Looking across thousands of years, Xi Jinping The general secretary is full of confidence. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The prosperity of a country and a nation is always supported by cultural prosperity. The great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation requires the development and prosperity of Chinese culture. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With a deep sense of historical responsibility, in the first year of fully implementing the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping continues to deepen his concern and thinking about cultural prosperity and civilization innovation——&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;Inspect the National Edition Museum of China and the Chinese Academy of History to draw wisdom for the future from thinking about history; visit the ancient city of Suzhou to feel the abundant momentum that culture gives to economic development; enter the Shaanxi Hanzhong Municipal Museum to think about the importance of traditional culture Inheritance and innovation...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dip in the ink of history, continue to write new history. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“From now on, the central task of the Communist Party of China is to unite and lead the people of all ethnic groups in the country to comprehensively build a modern and powerful socialist country, achieve the second centenary goal, and comprehensively promote the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation with Chinese-style modernization. &quot;General Secretary Xi Jinping solemnly declared at the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese-style modernization is a modernization that harmonizes material civilization and spiritual civilization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Embarking on a new journey towards the second centenary goal, taking the unprecedented Chinese-style modernization path, how to better meet the people’s growing spiritual and cultural needs, continuously enhance the spiritual strength to realize the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation, and lay the foundation for Make new and greater contributions to human civilization? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Continuing to promote cultural prosperity, build a cultural power, and build the modern civilization of the Chinese nation from a new starting point is our new cultural mission in the new era.” General Secretary Xi Jinping set goals and clarified tasks. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Should the new mission and adhere to the spiritual character of self-confidence and self-reliance——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The roaring Yellow River will flow forever. Yuncheng, located at the southernmost tip of Shanxi Province, was called &quot;Hedong&quot; in ancient times and is one of the birthplaces of Chinese civilization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On May 16 this year, General Secretary Xi Jinping inspected the Shanxi Yuncheng Museum and emphasized: &quot;The museum has many precious cultural relics and even &#39;national treasures&#39;, which testify to my country&#39;s millions of years of human history and 10,000 years of human history. Cultural history and the history of civilization of more than 5,000 years, we must thoroughly implement the project of exploring the origins of Chinese civilization and lead in-depth research on the history of Chinese civilization.&quot; More than two months later, General Secretary Xi Jinping came to Guanghan, Sichuan Visited Sanxingdui and congratulated on the completion of the new Sanxingdui Museum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the exhibition hall, the General Secretary stopped frequently. Sometimes after seeing the front view, he would also walk slowly around the display cabinet to inspect the details of the cultural relics from different sides. He said with emotion: &quot;After seeing this, the national pride doubled. Five thousand years of Chinese history Civilization, and we are looking forward to the discovery and excavation of Chinese civilization in the future.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Confidence can lead to self-improvement. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The extensive and profound Chinese civilization has endured for thousands of years and endured many hardships. This is the miracle of human civilization and the basis for our self-confidence. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Based on the great historical practice and contemporary practice of the Chinese nation, use Chinese principles to summarize Chinese experience, upgrade Chinese experience into Chinese theory, and achieve spiritual independence.” Strengthen cultural confidence, we will make our own choices Walking high on the road. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shouldering new missions and adhering to a broad mind of openness and inclusiveness——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May this year, the ancient city of Xi’an welcomed guests and friends from all walks of life to attend the China-Central Asia Summit. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The bright and powerful ancient Yi dance, the gorgeous and graceful hibiscus flower dance... In front of Ziyun Tower, a generous, graceful and dreamlike traditional welcome ceremony of the Tang Dynasty showed the tolerance of Chinese culture A spiritual outlook that embraces all corners of the world and embraces all rivers. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Shaanxi is the eastern starting point of the ancient Silk Road and has witnessed the profound friendship between China and Central Asian countries for more than two thousand years. For thousands of years, China and the people of Central Asia have exchanged knowledge and learned from each other. It has created the glory of the ancient Silk Road and written a glorious chapter in the history of human civilization exchanges.&quot; General Secretary Xi Jinping said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The broad atmosphere of Chinese civilization benefits from the open attitude and inclusive mind of Chinese culture since ancient times. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To build the modern civilization of the Chinese nation, we must be more proactive in learning from all the outstanding civilizational achievements created by mankind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On September 14, the 2023 Beijing Cultural Forum opened. Chinese and foreign guests gathered together to gather wisdom and power to promote the common progress of human civilization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping sent a congratulatory letter and sincerely called for: &quot;Jointly promote cultural prosperity and development, cultural heritage protection, exchanges and mutual learning among civilizations, practice global civilization initiatives, and inject profound and lasting culture into the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind.&quot; Power.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the evening&#39;s literary evening, ballet and Chinese classical dance shared the same stage to interpret the common beauty, and ancient musical instruments from different civilizations played the sound of harmony together. The memories and pictures of civilizations in different countries were reflected in the Gathered on the land of China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ancient oriental power not only enlightens world civilization with its outstanding wisdom, but also embraces world civilization with an openness to all rivers. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We must expand our world vision, have a profound insight into the trend of human development and progress, actively respond to the common concerns of people of all countries, contribute to solving common problems facing mankind, and learn from and absorb all the outstanding achievements of human civilization with a broad mind that embraces all rivers. , and promote the construction of a better world.&quot; General Secretary Xi Jinping has a high position and interprets the overall pattern and atmosphere of Chinese civilization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We should shoulder the new mission and more consciously adhere to the &quot;two combinations&quot; -&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is no end to practice, and there is no end to theoretical innovation. It is the solemn historical responsibility of contemporary Chinese Communists to continue to write new chapters of the Sinicization of Marxism. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On June 30, the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee held its sixth collective study session on opening up a new realm of sinicizing Marxism in the times. General Secretary Xi Jinping made a profound statement:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The sinicization of Marxism in the era&quot; The important proposition of culturalization itself determines that we must not abandon the soul of Marxism and the root of China’s excellent traditional culture. Adhering to this soul and root is the basis and prerequisite for theoretical innovation.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;With a profound understanding of the role of culture in historical progress, a correct grasp of the spiritual characteristics and historical inheritance of culture, and the unremitting pursuit of cultural rejuvenation and civilization progress, Chinese Communists in the new era have opened up the basics of Marxism A new realm of combining principles with the excellent traditional Chinese culture. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the symposium on cultural inheritance and development, General Secretary Xi Jinping gave a profound and systematic explanation of &quot;two combinations&quot; - the premise of &quot;combination&quot; is mutual agreement, the result of &quot;combination&quot; is mutual achievement, &quot; &quot;Combining&quot; has laid a solid foundation for the road, &quot;combination&quot; has opened up the space for innovation, and &quot;combination&quot; has consolidated cultural subjectivity. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新征程上，要坚持“两个结合”的根本要求，继续推进实践基础上的理论创新，以真理之光照亮奋斗之路，以复兴之志凝聚磅礴之力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对历史最好的继承就是创造新的历史，对人类文明最大的礼敬就是创造人类文明新形态。面向未来，习近平总书记发出号召：“要坚定文化自信、担当使命、奋发有为，共同努力创造属于我们这个时代的新文化，建设中华民族现代文明。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;站上新起点，在以习近平同志为核心的党中央坚强领导下，在习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想科学指引下，宣传思想文化战线意气风发、昂首前行，踏上充满光荣和梦想的远征。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（新华社北京10月6日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;记者张晓松、朱基钗、王子铭、王思北、孙少龙、徐壮）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 05:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 消费需求旺  市场活力足（走进市场看信心·聚焦中秋国庆假期）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/07/nw.D110000renmrb_20231007_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月07日星期六&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;据测算，中秋国庆8天假期，国内旅游出游8.26亿人次，按可比口径同比增长71.3%、较2019年增长4.1%。全国各地，涌动着消费的活力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在四川成都春熙路步行街，游客熙熙攘攘。这个假期，“到成都街头走一走”活动预计接待国内游客超2500万人次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在宁夏银川文化园，马戏表演吸引了众多游客。看演出、逛展览、赏美景……仅假期第一天，宁夏接待国内游客45.05万人次，实现旅游收入3.25亿元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从逛街购物到观影赏戏，从餐饮住宿到旅游休闲，中秋国庆假期全国消费市场供需两旺，商品供应充足、价格总体平稳，假日消费需求充分释放。消费市场的蓬勃活力，印证我国经济韧性强、潜力大、活力足，为宏观经济持续恢复向好提供了有力支撑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;消费持续恢复&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;需求加快升级&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“趁着假期逛逛商场，给家里添置一些新物件。”10月6日，在北京朝阳区合生汇商场，前来购物的消费者李莉说。中秋国庆假期，北京市举办系列促消费活动，假期首日，全市60个重点商圈客流量近700万人次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据商务部商务大数据监测信息显示，中秋国庆假期消费市场持续恢复。假期前两天，全国示范步行街客流量同比增长68.6%；36个大中城市重点商圈客流量同比增长99.2%。假期前三天，重点监测零售和餐饮企业销售额同比增长8.3%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;销量增长的同时，消费升级趋势明显。个性化、多样化、品质化需求持续增加，实物消费和服务消费两翼齐飞，绿色、智能、健康等成为假日消费市场关键词。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;绿色产品销售较快增长。“新产品功能更加丰富，而且节能环保，还能享受优惠，真不错。”在江苏南京新街口苏宁易购门店，下单购买了全屋整套家电的市民郭斌说。苏宁易购数据显示，绿色家电销售火热，假期前三天，门店一级能效新风空调销量同比增长143%，节能热水器销量同比增长128%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;智能产品备受市场欢迎。“有了智能帮手，家务简单多了。”10月3日，在湖北武汉京东MALL商场，前来选购智能扫地机器人的消费者赵炜说。商务部商务大数据监测，假期前三天，智能家电、新型电子产品、新能源汽车等商品热销，重点监测家居卖场智能和定制家居产品销售额同比增长10%以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;服务消费预订持续火热。“每天下午4点就开始排队，一天可以翻台8次左右。”重庆叁步梯老火锅负责人说，这个假期客流量将近翻番。美团、大众点评数据显示，中秋国庆假期，餐饮、出行、住宿等服务消费势能强劲，全国服务零售日均消费规模较2019年同期增长153%，餐饮堂食消费规模较2019年同期增长254%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;创新业态场景&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;优化供给质量&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在浙江杭州武林银泰百货的亚运互动祝福墙旁，每天都有不少消费者前来体验，与打卡装置拍照互动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;紧跟不断升级的消费需求，各地区各部门持续深化供给侧结构性改革，提升、优化商品和服务供给的质量和结构，丰富消费新场景、新业态、新模式，形成节日消费市场的新增长点。不少商家积极打造更有趣味性、互动性、科技性的消费新场景，为人们假日休闲购物提供更多的好去处。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——新场景刷新体验。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“没想到，在成都街头就能遇见古蜀文明。”在成都高新区铁像寺水街“打卡”三星堆数字城市展，让北京游客戴女士欣喜不已。参观老茶馆、戏台子下喝杯茶、逛文艺展……中秋国庆假期，成都高新区在铁像寺水街精心打造多个文旅消费新场景，为市民和游客带来沉浸式、交互式、智能化的文旅消费新体验。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——新业态更加便利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“临出门发现孩子的洗发水用完了，下了一个即时配送订单，不到半小时就送来了。”即时零售，满足了北京朝阳区居民蔡佳出游前的需求。商务部发布的信息显示，以即时零售为代表的消费新业态为消费市场增添了新活力。京东到家数据显示，中秋国庆假期出行装备、个护用品的搜索量持续攀升，洗衣液旅行装、数据线、雨具等商品搜索量环比增长超过200%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——新模式带动销售。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有更多的游客通过短视频了解到我们，并在假期来旅游。”通过线上直播和短视频推广的新模式，新疆布尔津县禾木村知名度不断提升，在中秋国庆假期迎来旅游高峰。日前，文化和旅游部指导相关平台开展乡村旅游数字提升行动，开展美好乡村打卡点、乡村旅游直播等活动，助力乡村文旅发展。抖音数据显示，假期乡村景点打卡量超150万次，同比增长60%；乡村景点订单量环比增长176%，同比增长162%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;政策集中发力&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;激发市场活力&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“早想换辆新车，正好赶上假期促销活动，就下单了。”四川成都成华区居民罗华说。中秋国庆假期，成华区开展汽车消费促进活动，吸引了不少消费者参与。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个假期，宁夏组织开展各类促消费活动170多场次，发放6000余万专项促消费资金，精准发放消费券、惠民券等，让实惠直达消费者。全区重点商业综合体、商业街区、连锁超市、餐饮夜市延长营业时间，更好满足消费者多样化消费需求。宁夏车展上，多个汽车品牌携旗下新车型参展，吸引了众多观展者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“领到购物券，迫不及待来消费。”广州市民李悦领到“羊城欢乐购”消费券后，到附近的商场选购了一款枕头，用购物券优惠了100元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从9月27日开始，广州在各大商圈和百货商场、超市、家居家电卖场等，分批次发放总额为1.3亿元的政府消费券。广州广百百货北京路店相关负责人介绍，截至10月2日，门店客流超14万人次，同比增长超六成。受消费券带动，电器类产品消费涨幅同比上升超30%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政策集中发力，激发市场活力。据介绍，中秋国庆假期，商务部会同相关部门落实好前期已出台的家居、汽车、电子产品等领域促消费政策，确保政策落地见效。同时，还组织开展“全国一刻钟便民生活消费节”等重点活动，推出“情满中秋&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;礼迎国庆”“诚信兴商&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;信用惠民”等消费场景，活跃消费市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;消费一头连着宏观经济大盘，一头连着千家万户美好生活。商务部相关负责人表示，今年以来，各级商务主管部门深入组织开展“消费提振年”系列促消费活动，着力提振汽车、家居等大宗消费，推动消费持续恢复和扩大。接下来，将继续聚焦重点，多措并举，拓宽消费场景、营造消费氛围、改善消费条件，激发消费市场更大动能，推动经济持续恢复向好。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 05:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 李强将出席杭州第十九届亚洲运动会闭幕式并举行系列外事活动]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/07/nw.D110000renmrb_20231007_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月07日星期六&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;新华社北京10月6日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;外交部发言人汪文斌6日宣布：国务院总理李强将于10月8日出席杭州第十九届亚洲运动会闭幕式，并为来华出席闭幕式的外国领导人举行欢迎宴会和双边活动。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 05:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 中秋国庆假期国内旅游出游8.26亿人次（新数据 新看点）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/07/nw.D110000renmrb_20231007_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月07日星期六&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231007/1696621848037_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;数据来源：文化和旅游部&lt;BR/>;制图：张丹峰&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报北京10月6日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者王珂、郑海鸥）今年中秋国庆假期，文化和旅游行业恢复势头强劲，全国假日市场平稳有序。据文化和旅游部数据中心测算，8天假期国内旅游出游8.26亿人次，按可比口径同比增长71.3%、较2019年增长4.1%；实现国内旅游收入7534.3亿元，按可比口径同比增长129.5%、较2019年增长1.5%。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;群众假日出游意愿得到集中释放，中远程旅游实现较高增长，主要旅游目的地及热门景区消费活跃度持续高位运行。文化和旅游行业通过“旅游+”融合演艺、体育、非遗等，推出一系列活动和产品，为游客带来高质量的假日体验。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;文化和旅游活动精彩纷呈。文化和旅游部启动2023年“山河秋韵”全国旅游宣传推广，联动各地围绕金秋文旅推广季开展丰富多彩的活动，生动展示长城秋色、乡村秋景、民俗物候等金秋文旅魅力。江西南昌以“风景这边独好”为主题，举办烟花晚会，吸引市民和游客观看。河南焦作云台山景区游客传递巨幅国旗，共同唱响爱国歌曲。浙江推出亚运文旅精品线路，满足市民和游客的多元需求。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;文化和旅游活动深度融合成为亮点。多部优秀舞台艺术作品在北京、内蒙古、上海等地上演。山西、黑龙江、湖南、广东、海南、四川、陕西等地举办特色鲜明的赏灯观月、文艺表演、巡游等系列活动。智慧旅游沉浸式新产品新场景成为消费新热点，深受年轻游客喜爱。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;文化和旅游消费增长迅猛。文化和旅游部举办全国国庆文化和旅游消费月活动，推出149条乡村旅游精品线路和69家工业旅游示范基地。河北推出的“登山采摘乡村休闲之旅”，带领游客一起走进美丽乡村，赏秋景、享秋实。江苏、湖北、重庆、宁夏等地推出发放文旅消费券和门票特价等举措，激发游客消费热情。国家级夜间文化和旅游消费集聚区示范带动作用进一步体现，夜间消费活力进一步激发。根据中国联通数据监测，9月28日18时至10月6日6时，243个国家级夜间文化和旅游消费集聚区夜间客流量1.12亿人次，平均每个集聚区每夜5.76万人次，增幅明显。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 05:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 文旅热潮折射经济动能澎湃（今日谈）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/07/nw.D110000renmrb_20231007_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月07日星期六&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;徜徉美丽乡村，观秋景、品秋韵，亲近自然、放松心情；漫步休闲街区，尝美食、购好物，领略特色、体验风情；沉浸旅游景区，逛古镇、访名居，增长见识、开阔眼界……中秋国庆假期，许多人选择在旅游出行中欢度节日、享受生活。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;数据显示，8天假期，国内旅游出游8.26亿人次，按可比口径同比增长71.3%、较2019年增长4.1%；实现国内旅游收入7534.3亿元，按可比口径同比增长129.5%、较2019年增长1.5%。文旅市场热度攀升的背后，是持续释放的消费动能、不断提振的市场信心。一方面，新供给、新业态涌现，文旅产品与服务更能满足游客需求，为市场繁荣发展挖掘了强劲的新动力。另一方面，各地针对出游高峰加强预约、接待、安全等工作，让广大游客放心出行、舒心出游，为文旅市场持续升温提供保障。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;假日消费是观察经济的一扇窗口。中秋国庆假期的文旅热潮，正是中国经济动能澎湃的注脚。继续创新消费模式，延展消费空间，激发消费潜力，以高质量供给满足消费升级需求，必将激发更加强劲的消费势能，展现中国经济更加强大的韧性与活力。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 05:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 图片报道]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/07/nw.D110000renmrb_20231007_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月07日星期六&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231007/1696621840761_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;中国国家版本馆是国家版本资源总库和中华文化种子基因库，由中央总馆文瀚阁、西安分馆文济阁、杭州分馆文润阁、广州分馆文沁阁组成，全面履行国家版本资源保藏传承职责。图为位于燕山脚下的中国国家版本馆中央总馆。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;本报记者&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;陈&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;斌摄&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 05:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 中国工会十八大将于10月9日在北京开幕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/07/nw.D110000renmrb_20231007_7-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月07日星期六&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报北京10月6日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者刘博通）记者6日从中华全国总工会获悉：经党中央批准，中国工会第十八次全国代表大会将于10月9日在北京开幕。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;据了解，出席此次会议的共有来自全国各地工会，铁路、民航、金融工会，中央和国家机关工会联合会的35个代表团、2002名代表。此外，还将有约60名特邀代表、50名港澳来宾出席大会。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;中国工会十八大代表中，基层和一线职工代表占68.3%，工人代表占26.7%，比例较中国工会十七大时均有提高。一些快递员、外卖送餐员、网约车司机等新就业形态劳动者当选为代表，进一步增强了代表构成的广泛性、代表性。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;中国工会第十八次全国代表大会的主要任务是：高举中国特色社会主义伟大旗帜，以习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想为指导，全面贯彻落实党的二十大精神，贯彻落实习近平总书记关于工人阶级和工会工作的重要论述，全面总结新时代十年工会工作的成就和经验，系统总结工会十七大以来的工作，深刻把握以中国式现代化全面推进中华民族伟大复兴对党的工运事业和工会工作提出的新任务新要求，明确新时代新征程上工会组织肩负的历史使命和工会工作的目标任务，修改《中国工会章程》，选举产生中华全国总工会新一届领导机构。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;根据《中国工会章程》规定，中国工会全国代表大会每五年举行一次。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 05:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 铸就中华文化新辉煌]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/07/nw.D110000renmrb_20231007_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月07日星期六&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;一个民族的复兴，需要强大的物质力量，也需要强大的精神力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;党的十八大以来，以习近平同志为核心的党中央总揽全局，把宣传思想文化工作摆在重要位置，指引宣传思想文化事业在举旗定向、正本清源中取得历史性成就、发生历史性变革，在守正创新、开拓进取中展现新气象、迈向新征程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;高瞻远瞩、举旗定向，为新时代宣传思想文化事业发展指明前进方向&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;燕山脚下，国风浩荡，文脉不绝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023年6月1日，习近平总书记来到位于北京中轴线北延的中国国家版本馆中央总馆考察。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;走进国家书房，总书记的目光望向顶部中央藻井内的星空穹顶。穹顶上，宋代石刻天文图展现古人智慧，星汉灿烂、浩渺深邃；书房内，15组巨型书柜陈列近3万册新中国精品出版物，思想的星空蔚为大观。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文明生生不息，思想与时俱进。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;次日召开的文化传承发展座谈会上，习近平总书记深刻总结党的十八大以来在文化建设中提出的一系列新思想新观点新论断，并强调，这些重要观点是新时代党领导文化建设实践经验的理论总结，是做好宣传思想文化工作的根本遵循，必须长期坚持贯彻、不断丰富发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10年前的8月，党的十八大后首次全国宣传思想工作会议。习近平总书记的讲话语重心长：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我一直在思考一个问题……我们中国共产党人能不能在日益复杂的国际国内环境下坚持住党的领导、坚持和发展中国特色社会主义，这个还需要我们一代一代共产党人继续作出回答。做好意识形态工作，做好宣传思想工作，要放到这个大背景下来认识。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;清醒冷静的叩问，贯穿着对宣传思想文化事业的远虑深谋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是全新历史坐标下的重大命题：中国特色社会主义进入新时代，面对中华民族伟大复兴战略全局和世界百年未有之大变局相互交织、相互激荡、相互影响，应当如何凝心铸魂、高举旗帜？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是推进理论创新的时代呼唤：一个民族要走在时代前列，就一刻不能没有理论思维，一刻不能没有正确思想指引。想要不断推进马克思主义中国化时代化、不断攀登新的思想高峰，应当如何总结经验、把握规律？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是赓续历史文脉的高度自觉：没有高度的文化自信，没有文化的繁荣兴盛，就没有中华民族伟大复兴；没有社会主义文化繁荣发展，就没有社会主义现代化。推进社会主义文化强国建设，应当如何主动作为、再谱华章？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“意识形态工作是党的一项极端重要的工作，是为国家立心、为民族立魂的工作。”习近平总书记深刻指出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;紧扣时代脉搏，围绕中心工作，突出问题导向，宣传思想文化领域气象日新。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;正本清源，坚持和加强党对宣传思想文化工作的全面领导——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2013年11月，北京，党的十八届三中全会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这一正式开启新时代全面深化改革大幕的重要会议上，习近平总书记关于意识形态工作的一席话振聋发聩：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在集中精力进行经济建设的同时，一刻也不能放松和削弱意识形态工作，必须把意识形态工作的领导权、管理权、话语权牢牢掌握在手中，任何时候都不能旁落，否则就要犯无可挽回的历史性错误。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;意识形态关乎旗帜、关乎道路、关乎国家政治安全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着经济科技快速发展和社会格局深刻调整，拜金主义、享乐主义、极端个人主义和历史虚无主义等错误思潮不时出现，网络舆论乱象丛生，严重影响人们思想和社会舆论环境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;着力解决意识形态领域党的领导弱化问题，习近平总书记一锤定音：“要加强党对宣传思想工作的全面领导，旗帜鲜明坚持党管宣传、党管意识形态。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两度召开全国宣传思想工作会议，强调“做好宣传思想工作必须全党动手”“建设具有强大凝聚力和引领力的社会主义意识形态”；在文艺工作座谈会上指出“党的领导是社会主义文艺发展的根本保证”；在党的新闻舆论工作座谈会上强调“党和政府主办的媒体是党和政府的宣传阵地，必须姓党”；在网络安全和信息化工作座谈会上要求“群众在哪儿，我们的领导干部就要到哪儿去”；在哲学社会科学工作座谈会上指出“加强和改善党对哲学社会科学工作的领导，是繁荣发展我国哲学社会科学事业的根本保证”；在全国高校思想政治工作会议上强调“牢牢掌握党对高校工作的领导权”……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记就一系列根本性问题阐明原则立场，廓清了认识迷雾，校正了工作导向。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;方向明，则思路清。一项项针对性举措应运而生：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;确立和坚持马克思主义在意识形态领域指导地位的根本制度；制定意识形态工作责任制实施办法，以党内法规形式明确各级党委（党组）的责任；坚决反击各种歪曲丑化亵渎英雄烈士等历史虚无主义倾向，制定出台英烈保护法；重拳整治网络生态乱象，建立中央、省、市三级网信管理工作体系；制定第一部关于宣传工作的基础性、主干性党内法规《中国共产党宣传工作条例》，以刚性的法规制度为全党开展宣传工作提供有力指导和支撑……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;立破并举、激浊扬清，意识形态领域一度出现的被动局面从根本上得到扭转，意识形态领域形势发生全局性、根本性转变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;守正开新，鲜明提出“两个结合”重大论断——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国共产党为什么能，中国特色社会主义为什么好，归根到底是马克思主义行，是中国化时代化的马克思主义行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021年7月1日，天安门广场，庆祝中国共产党成立100周年大会隆重举行。习近平总书记话语铿锵：“坚持把马克思主义基本原理同中国具体实际相结合、同中华优秀传统文化相结合，用马克思主义观察时代、把握时代、引领时代，继续发展当代中国马克思主义、21世纪马克思主义！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是“两个结合”重大论断首次正式提出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此后，“两个结合”先后写入《中共中央关于党的百年奋斗重大成就和历史经验的决议》和党的二十大报告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在武夷山下的朱熹园表示“要把坚持马克思主义同弘扬中华优秀传统文化有机结合起来”，在殷墟强调“我们推进马克思主义中国化时代化的根本途径是&#39;两个结合&#39;”，在文化传承发展座谈会上深刻阐释“两个结合”的重大意义，指出“&#39;两个结合&#39;是我们取得成功的最大法宝”……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;持续深化对党的理论创新的规律性认识，习近平总书记对“两个结合”特别是“第二个结合”的论述不断深入，表明我们党对中国道路、理论、制度的认识达到了新高度，表明我们党的历史自信、文化自信达到了新高度，表明我们党在传承中华优秀传统文化中推进文化创新的自觉性达到了新高度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;固本培元，从赓续历史文化中坚定自信——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;四川眉山，三苏祠。百年银杏、千年黄葛，生机盎然。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022年6月8日，习近平总书记来到这里，实地考察千年古祠，深有感触地说：“一滴水可以见太阳，一个三苏祠可以看出我们中华文化的博大精深。我们说要坚定文化自信，中国有&#39;三苏&#39;，这就是一个重要例证。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;连续性、创新性、统一性、包容性、和平性——习近平总书记深刻总结中华文明的五个突出特性，指出“文化自信就来自我们的文化主体性”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在总书记心中，文化自信是一个国家、一个民族发展中最基本、最深沉、最持久的力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前往敦煌研究院主持召开座谈会，肯定“敦煌文化展示了中华民族的文化自信”；深入上海杨浦滨江，强调“保留城市历史文化记忆，让人们记得住历史、记得住乡愁，坚定文化自信，增强家国情怀”；在岳麓书院同师生亲切交流，勉励“当代学生在传承中华优秀传统文化的过程中一定要进一步坚定文化自信”；来到云冈石窟，指出“让旅游成为人们感悟中华文化、增强文化自信的过程”……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;党的十八大以来，习近平总书记将文化自信置于前所未有的高度，涵养全民族精神力量，为复兴伟业凝心聚力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纲举目张，为文化强国建设擘画蓝图路径——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文化兴国运兴，文化强民族强。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当代中国共产党人和中国人民应该而且一定能够担负起新的文化使命，在实践创造中进行文化创造，在历史进步中实现文化进步！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在党的十九大报告中，习近平总书记首次提出“新的文化使命”这一重大命题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;站在强国建设、民族复兴的高度，习近平总书记为建设社会主义文化强国指明前进方向：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;着眼新形势新任务新要求，明确提出宣传思想工作必须自觉承担起“举旗帜、聚民心、育新人、兴文化、展形象”的使命任务；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;培育积极健康、向上向善的网络文化，明确“互联网已经成为舆论斗争的主战场”，直言“过不了互联网这一关，就过不了长期执政这一关”；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;强调坚持以人民为中心的创作导向，时隔72年再度召开指引中国文艺前进方向的座谈会，指出“文艺创作方法有一百条、一千条，但最根本、最关键、最牢靠的办法是扎根人民、扎根生活”；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;心系文物保护利用和文化遗产保护传承，“文化足迹”遍及全国，考察文化地标、探寻文明根脉，对“要像爱惜自己的生命一样保护好城市历史文化遗产”念兹在兹；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;重视加快构建中国话语和中国叙事体系，要求“着力打造融通中外的新概念新范畴新表述，讲好中国故事，传播好中国声音”；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;着力推动文明交流互鉴，一次次在出访时做“文化代言人”，一次次在主场外交中展现中华文明博大胸怀，生动诠释“文明因交流而多彩，文明因互鉴而丰富”；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;党的十八大以来，习近平总书记以马克思主义政治家、思想家、战略家的历史主动精神、非凡理论勇气、卓越政治智慧、强烈使命担当，明确宣传思想文化工作使命任务，推动宣传思想文化建设掀开崭新篇章。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;以文化人、培根铸魂，推动宣传思想文化工作取得新成效&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;党的十八大以来，在以习近平同志为核心的党中央引领下，我国意识形态领域形势发生全局性、根本性转变，全党全国各族人民文化自信明显增强，全社会凝聚力和向心力极大提升，为新时代开创党和国家事业新局面提供了坚强思想保证和强大精神力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加强思想武装，党的创新理论深入人心——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;走进北京图书大厦，“学习贯彻习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想主题教育图书”专区前，《习近平著作选读》摆放在醒目位置，吸引了许多读者驻足阅读。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为深入学习贯彻党的创新理论的权威教材，今年4月3日，这部以中共中央文献编辑委员会名义编辑的习近平总书记重要著作，正式出版发行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同一天，主题教育工作会议在京召开，“一场新的学习竞赛”拉开帷幕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;站在实现中华民族伟大复兴的战略高度，以习近平同志为核心的党中央引领全党以理论大学习、思想大武装推进事业大发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从历次党内集中教育坚持把理论学习作为首要任务，到成立中央宣讲团开展基层宣讲，在习近平总书记亲自关心指导下，从中央到地方，理论学习氛围愈发浓厚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;深化理论研究，推进体系化、学理化建设，是加强党的理论武装的基本前提。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;步入新时代，马克思主义理论研究和建设工程等平台建设扎实推进，习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想研究中心成果丰硕，哲学社会科学界把握理论本质、探究精神内涵，对党的创新理论认识不断深化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2019年1月1日，一个功能强大、内容丰富的新思想学习平台——“学习强国”亮相，上线三个月注册用户就突破1亿人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《中国式现代化面对面》《百年大党面对面》等通俗理论读物让理论更加生动可感；新时代文明实践中心、县级融媒体中心等新载体新阵地助力党的创新理论不断深入基层；中央主要媒体推出的“第一观察”“一见”“时政新闻眼”等品牌栏目，让理论普及范围广度不断延伸……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;思想光芒照亮前路，学习热潮涌动神州。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如今，一堂堂大众理论公开课在年轻人中引发“追剧”效应，理论学习辅导读物上榜“农民喜爱的百种图书”，党的好声音化作社会最强音，直达人民心间、回响在中华大地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鼓舞精神士气，全国人民凝聚力和向心力极大提升——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021年7月1日，庆祝中国共产党成立100周年大会在天安门广场隆重举行。国之盛典，激发起亿万中华儿女爱党爱国的澎湃共鸣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;正如习近平总书记所说：“庆祝活动盛大庄严、气势恢宏，礼序乾坤、乐和天地”“起到了统一思想、凝聚力量、振奋人心、鼓舞士气的作用”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从纪念抗战胜利70周年、庆祝改革开放40周年，到庆祝新中国成立70周年、中国共产党成立100周年，宣传思想文化战线聚焦重要节点、重大活动，推动党心民心交融、国威军威彰显，汇聚起坚不可摧的磅礴伟力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;党的新闻舆论工作，事关全党全国各族人民凝聚力和向心力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2016年2月19日，习近平总书记用整整一天时间，前往人民日报社、新华社、中央电视台实地调研，并主持召开党的新闻舆论工作座谈会，提出了新的时代条件下党的新闻舆论工作的职责和使命：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“高举旗帜、引领导向，围绕中心、服务大局，团结人民、鼓舞士气，成风化人、凝心聚力，澄清谬误、明辨是非，联接中外、沟通世界。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3年后，2019年1月25日，习近平总书记带领十九届中央政治局同志，把集体学习的“课堂”从中南海搬到媒体融合发展第一线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;党的十八大以来，《关于推动传统媒体和新兴媒体融合发展的指导意见》《关于加快推进媒体深度融合发展的意见》先后出台，以融合发展为突破口，主流媒体在时代变革中“破茧蝶变”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;各大媒体“报网端微”百花齐放，文图音视竞相发力，通过创新手段、全媒呈现，记录下脱贫攻坚的感人瞬间、勾勒出全面小康的美丽画卷、展现出高质量发展的生动图景，以一件件精品力作，汇聚奋进力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人在哪，凝心聚力的重点就在哪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“网络空间已经成为人们生产生活的新空间，那就也应该成为我们党凝聚共识的新空间。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十多年来，无论是举办中国网络文明大会、世界互联网大会乌镇峰会等活动，还是开展“净网”“清朗”等专项治理行动，网络健康文化加速培育，不断汇聚向上向善的力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;坚定理想信念，堪当民族复兴重任的时代新人不断涌现——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022年4月25日，中国人民大学立德楼，一场以“传承中国共产党人精神谱系&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;做堪当民族复兴重任的时代新人”为主题的思政课正在进行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记走进教室，向老师和同学们招手致意，坐到了同学们中间，一同倾听讲授并参与讨论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在师生们热烈掌声中，总书记从中国走过的不平凡之路说起，讲到延安窑洞里的马克思主义、新中国成立之初的一穷二白、改革开放的惊雷划空……他勉励同学们在全面建设社会主义现代化国家新征程中勇当开路先锋、争当事业闯将。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从脱贫攻坚精神、抗疫精神，到新时代北斗精神、丝路精神……弘扬以伟大建党精神为源头的中国共产党人精神谱系，一座座精神丰碑，为时代新人成长提供坚实支撑；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从《新时代公民道德建设实施纲要》《新时代爱国主义教育实施纲要》先后印发，到“时代楷模”“中国好人”不断涌现……社会主义核心价值观广泛传播，爱党、爱国、爱社会主义成为时代强音；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从《关于新时代加强和改进思想政治工作的意见》印发，到全方位提升思政课建设水平、创新方式方法……基层思想政治工作质量不断提升，思想政治工作体系日益完善；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;设立烈士纪念日，颁授“七一勋章”“共和国勋章”，建立健全党和国家功勋荣誉表彰制度……全社会敬仰英雄、学习英雄、争做英雄的良好氛围日益形成；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文明家庭、文明校园等精神文明创建活动深入开展，尊老爱幼、勤俭节约等植根于传统文化的文明新风吹进百姓心田，为中国特色社会主义事业提供源源不断的道德滋养……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以习近平同志为核心的党中央聚焦“培养什么人”“怎样培养人”，引领一批又一批时代新人坚定信心、强化自觉、提升素质，投身民族复兴伟业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在田间地头，“新农人”们寒耕暑耘、精耕细作，努力把中国饭碗牢牢端在自己手中；在工厂车间，新一代工人苦练本领、精益求精，以不懈钻研让“中国制造”的“金色名片”闪耀世界；在体育赛场，运动健儿们顽强拼搏、争创佳绩，让五星红旗一次次高高飘扬；在救灾一线，无数年轻面孔冲锋在前、逆行出征，救人民群众于危难之间……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;推动文化繁荣，社会主义文化强国建设迈出坚实步伐——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;浙江余杭良渚，“美丽的水中之洲”。几代考古学家在这里孜孜以求，探寻中华文明的最初印记。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“良渚遗址是实证中华五千年文明史的圣地”，2003年7月，时任浙江省委书记习近平对遗址的历史地位作出重要论断。2016年，习近平总书记又对良渚古城遗址申遗作出重要指示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3年后，良渚古城遗址入选《世界遗产名录》。外国专家评价：“良渚让我们对中国早期文明的认识提前一千多年。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以习近平同志为核心的党中央以坚定的文化自信、强烈的历史担当，把传承弘扬中华优秀传统文化作为一项历史性工程、战略性工程来抓，引领中华文化创造性转化、创新性发展。《关于实施中华优秀传统文化传承发展工程的意见》印发，第一次以中央文件的形式专题阐述中华优秀传统文化传承发展工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从敦煌文化保护研究工作持续推进，到革命文物保护利用工程等重大工程深入实施；从《复兴文库》、“中国历代绘画大系”编纂出版，到中国共产党历史展览馆、中国国家版本馆等文化殿堂相继落成……在习近平总书记关心推动下，中华文化的“一池春水”生机勃勃。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今日之中国，“文博热”火爆、“文创风”劲吹，陈列在广阔大地上的遗产、书写在古籍里的文字活起来，中华优秀传统文化创造性转化、创新性发展，让文脉传承弦歌不辍、历久弥新。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文艺是时代前进的号角，最能代表一个时代的风貌，最能引领一个时代的风气。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我仰望你看过的星空，脚下大地已换了时空，你留在风中摇曳的那抹红，在心中！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上海龙华烈士陵园，因电视剧《觉醒年代》而广为人知的3位烈士——陈延年、陈乔年、赵世炎墓前，放满了写给先烈们的信。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一部部充满力量的文艺作品，奏响一曲曲荡气回肠的时代之声、爱国之声、人民之声。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;党的十八大以来，文艺园地百花齐放、硕果累累：影视作品《长津湖》《山海情》等兼具历史厚重感和现实关怀；《人世间》《雪山大地》等文学作品展现波澜壮阔的社会变迁；复排歌剧《党的女儿》、舞剧《永不消逝的电波》等创新形式再现英雄形象……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文化既是凝聚人心的精神纽带，又是增进民生福祉的关键因素。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;放眼神州，文化惠民工程深入实施，各类文艺精品不断涌现，文化旅游深度融合，文化产业快速发展，新时代文化事业生机盎然，全民族文化创新创造活力竞相迸发，东方文明古国阔步迈向社会主义文化强国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;讲好中国故事，国家文化软实力和中华文化影响力日益提高——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023年4月，春天的广州，繁花似锦。坐落在白云山麓的松园依山傍水，别有风情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记邀请法国总统马克龙漫步岭南园林，临水而坐，观景品茗。千年古琴奏出一曲《高山流水》，两国元首一起欣赏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“了解今天的中国，要从了解中国的历史开始”，习近平总书记纵论古今，“我们对中国发展前景充满信心”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这两天里，我们的交流友好深入，使我进一步领略了中国悠久灿烂的历史文化，增进了对现代中国治国理政理念的了解。”马克龙深有感触地说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《习近平谈治国理政》多语种版在海外引发热烈反响，为各国读者开启一扇扇观察和感知中国的窗口；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《中国共产党的历史使命与行动价值》、《中国新型政党制度》白皮书、《中国的民主》白皮书等文献向世界展示真实、立体、全面的中国；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;京剧、昆曲等洋溢着“中国风”的演出不断亮相国际舞台，国产影视剧海外热播，舞蹈、杂技、美术以及民间文艺接连走出国门；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“感知中国”“欢乐春节”“四海同春”等品牌活动在全世界掀起中华文化魅力热潮；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京冬奥会、杭州亚运会、成都大运会惊艳世界，向全球展现中华文化兼纳百川、包容四海的雍容气度；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中非合作论坛、上海进博会、亚洲文明对话大会等一系列主场外交向世界讲述中国故事、介绍中国经验……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个亘古亘今、日新月异的中国，正以开放包容的胸怀、守正创新的精神，扎根于中华大地、展现在世界面前。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以文化之声唱响中国故事、以文化之魂凝聚价值共识、以文明互鉴推动构建人类命运共同体……中华文化绽放出的新的时代光芒，推动中华文明与各国文明美美与共、和谐共生。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;进入新时代，以习近平同志为核心的党中央为在新形势下做好外宣工作，提高国家文化软实力、中华文化影响力指明了方向，让可信、可爱、可敬的中国形象更加真实可感，奏响了和平、发展、合作、共赢的华美乐章。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;矢志远大、放眼未来，在新的历史起点上建设中华民族现代文明&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;河南安阳殷墟，洹河蜿蜒，甲骨呈奇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022年10月28日，党的二十大闭幕不到一周，习近平总书记来到这里考察。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;步入殷墟博物馆，观摩青铜器、玉器、甲骨文等文物，习近平总书记点明此行深意：“殷墟我向往已久，这次来是想更深地学习理解中华文明，古为今用，为更好建设中华民族现代文明提供借鉴。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中华文明源远流长，从未中断，塑造了我们伟大的民族，这个民族还会伟大下去的。”目光穿越千年，习近平总书记充满自信。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个国家、一个民族的强盛，总是以文化兴盛为支撑，中华民族伟大复兴需要以中华文化发展繁荣为条件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;怀着深沉的历史责任感，在全面贯彻落实党的二十大精神开局之年，习近平总书记持续加深对文化繁荣、文明创新的关切和思考——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;考察中国国家版本馆、中国历史研究院，从对历史的思考中汲取走向未来的智慧；到访古城苏州，感受文化赋予经济发展的充沛动能；走进陕西汉中市博物馆，思考传统文化的传承创新……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蘸满历史的笔墨，继续书写新的历史。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“从现在起，中国共产党的中心任务就是团结带领全国各族人民全面建成社会主义现代化强国、实现第二个百年奋斗目标，以中国式现代化全面推进中华民族伟大复兴。”党的二十大上，习近平总书记庄严宣告。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国式现代化，是物质文明和精神文明相协调的现代化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;踏上第二个百年奋斗目标新征程，走前无古人的中国式现代化道路，如何更好满足人民日益增长的精神文化需求，不断增强实现中华民族伟大复兴的精神力量，为人类文明百花园作出新的更大贡献？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在新的起点上继续推动文化繁荣、建设文化强国、建设中华民族现代文明，是我们在新时代新的文化使命。”习近平总书记标定目标，明确任务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;肩负新使命，坚守自信自立的精神品格——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;滔滔黄河，万古奔流。位于山西最南端的运城，古称“河东”，是中华文明的发源地之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年5月16日，习近平总书记考察了山西运城博物馆，强调：“博物馆有很多宝贵文物甚至&#39;国宝&#39;，它们实证了我国百万年的人类史、一万年的文化史、五千多年的文明史，要深入实施中华文明探源工程，把中国文明历史研究引向深入。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2个多月后，习近平总书记来到四川广汉三星堆考察，祝贺三星堆博物馆新馆落成使用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;展厅里，总书记频频驻足，有时看完正面，还缓步绕着展柜，察看文物的不同侧面细节，感慨道：“看过以后民族自豪感倍增，五千年中华文明啊，而且更期待着更长的中华文明的发现发掘。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自信，才能自强。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;博大精深的中华文明历经数千年而绵延不绝、迭遭忧患而经久不衰，这是人类文明的奇迹，也是我们自信的底气。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“立足中华民族伟大历史实践和当代实践，用中国道理总结好中国经验，把中国经验提升为中国理论，实现精神上的独立自主。”坚定文化自信，我们在自己选定的路上昂首阔步。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;肩负新使命，坚持开放包容的博大胸襟——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年5月，古城西安迎来参加中国—中亚峰会的各方宾朋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;明快有力的古代佾舞、绚丽婀娜的芙蓉花舞……紫云楼前，一场大度雍容、如梦如幻的唐朝传统迎宾礼，展现出中华文化包容四海、兼纳百川的精神风貌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“陕西是古丝绸之路的东方起点，见证了中国同中亚国家两千多年的深厚友谊。千百年来，中国同中亚人民互通有无、互学互鉴，创造了古丝绸之路的辉煌，书写了人类文明交流史上的华章。”习近平总书记说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中华文明的博大气象，得益于中华文化自古以来开放的姿态、包容的胸怀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;建设中华民族现代文明，要更加积极主动地学习借鉴人类创造的一切优秀文明成果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;9月14日，2023北京文化论坛开幕，中外嘉宾汇聚一堂，为促进人类文明共同进步汇聚智慧力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记发来贺信，真诚呼吁：“共同推动文化繁荣发展、文化遗产保护、文明交流互鉴，践行全球文明倡议，为推动构建人类命运共同体注入深厚持久的文化力量。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当晚的文艺晚会上，芭蕾舞与中国古典舞同台诠释美美与共，来自不同文明的古老乐器共同奏响和谐之音，不同国度的文明记忆、文明图景，在华夏大地上汇集。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;古老的东方大国不仅以卓越的智慧启迪世界文明，更以海纳百川的气度拥抱世界文明。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们要拓展世界眼光，深刻洞察人类发展进步潮流，积极回应各国人民普遍关切，为解决人类面临的共同问题作出贡献，以海纳百川的宽阔胸襟借鉴吸收人类一切优秀文明成果，推动建设更加美好的世界。”习近平总书记高屋建瓴，诠释出中华文明的大格局大气象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;肩负新使命，更加自觉坚持“两个结合”——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;实践没有止境，理论创新也没有止境。不断谱写马克思主义中国化时代化新篇章，是当代中国共产党人的庄严历史责任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6月30日，中央政治局就开辟马克思主义中国化时代化新境界进行第六次集体学习，习近平总书记语重心长：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“马克思主义中国化时代化这个重大命题本身就决定，我们决不能抛弃马克思主义这个魂脉，决不能抛弃中华优秀传统文化这个根脉。坚守好这个魂和根，是理论创新的基础和前提。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以对文化在历史进步中的地位作用的深刻认识，以对文化的精神特质和历史传承的正确把握，以对文化复兴和文明进步的不懈追求，新时代中国共产党人开辟了马克思主义基本原理同中华优秀传统文化相结合的新境界。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在文化传承发展座谈会上，习近平总书记对“两个结合”进行了深刻系统阐释——“结合”的前提是彼此契合、“结合”的结果是互相成就、“结合”筑牢了道路根基、“结合”打开了创新空间、“结合”巩固了文化主体性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新征程上，要坚持“两个结合”的根本要求，继续推进实践基础上的理论创新，以真理之光照亮奋斗之路，以复兴之志凝聚磅礴之力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对历史最好的继承就是创造新的历史，对人类文明最大的礼敬就是创造人类文明新形态。面向未来，习近平总书记发出号召：“要坚定文化自信、担当使命、奋发有为，共同努力创造属于我们这个时代的新文化，建设中华民族现代文明。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;站上新起点，在以习近平同志为核心的党中央坚强领导下，在习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想科学指引下，宣传思想文化战线意气风发、昂首前行，踏上充满光荣和梦想的远征。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（新华社北京10月6日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;记者张晓松、朱基钗、王子铭、王思北、孙少龙、徐壮）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 05:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 为绘好共建“一带一路”工笔画增添江苏色彩（共建“一带一路”·权威访谈）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/07/nw.D110000renmrb_20231007_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月07日星期六&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;江苏处于丝绸之路经济带和21世纪海上丝绸之路的交汇点上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;江苏省委常委、常务副省长马欣在接受新华社记者采访时说，共建“一带一路”倡议提出十年来，江苏始终牢记习近平总书记殷殷嘱托，集全省之力推动“一带一路”交汇点建设，努力为绘好共建“一带一路”工笔画增添江苏色彩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;夯基垒台，推动全方位高水平对外开放&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在阿联酋，中阿产能合作示范园正火热建设，已签约项目23个、入园项目15个；在哈萨克斯坦，16个重点项目签约，拓展了多领域合作新空间；在沙特阿拉伯，东方盛虹与沙特企业签订重大项目合作框架协议……“&#39;一带一路&#39;倡议已成为深受欢迎的国际公共产品。”马欣表示，近日到阿联酋、沙特阿拉伯参观访问，真切感受到我国与相关国家经贸往来持续扩大，交流合作更加紧密。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以“一带一路”交汇点建设为总揽，江苏在形成《关于高质量推进“一带一路”交汇点建设的意见》《江苏省“十四五”高质量推进“一带一路”交汇点建设规划》的基础上，实施国际综合交通体系拓展、国际产能合作深化、“丝路贸易”促进、重点合作园区提升、人文交流品牌塑造等“五大计划”专项行动，推动全方位高水平对外开放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年1月至9月，江苏共开行中欧（亚）班列1667列，同比增长13.4%。马欣介绍，江苏稳定开行24条中欧（亚）班列线路，覆盖欧亚20多个国家；累计建成亿吨大港10个，港口综合通过能力超过23亿吨。十年来，江苏对“一带一路”合作伙伴进出口年均增长7.2%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;双向交流，多维互动。马欣表示，江苏的国际产能合作持续深化，培育了红豆集团等一批国际产能合作龙头企业，搭建了中国—中东欧国家技术转移中心等合作平台；人文交流日益密切，与共建“一带一路”国家缔结友城146对，数量居全国前列，“一带一路”青年体育交流周等已成为人文交流重要品牌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;发挥优势，建设国内国际双循环重要通道&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一带一路”交汇点建设，对江苏来说是贯穿历史、现实和未来的重大命题。江苏充分发挥区位特征、资源禀赋等优势，不断推动“一带一路”交汇点建设走深走实。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沿海构筑国际合作蓝色海洋经济带，沿江构筑国际合作绿色低碳发展带……马欣介绍，承东启西，建设具有国际影响力的“一带一路”交汇点，江苏促进共建“一带一路”、长江经济带发展、长三角区域一体化发展深度融合，着力推动东西双向开放互济，人流、物流、数据流和经贸往来深度交汇，不断推动形成全省开放发展新布局。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为新亚欧大陆桥东端起点，随着中欧班列密集开行，连云港已成为中亚地区最便捷的出海口。陆海统筹，共建新亚欧陆海联运通道，江苏大力发展多式联运，努力打造内外联通的战略通道。中哈（连云港）物流合作基地与“霍尔果斯—东大门”无水港共同构成新亚欧陆海联运通道上的“双枢纽”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;江苏发挥园区经济优势，共建全面开放新高地，积极探索境外合作园区“重资产投资运营”和“轻资产管理输出”模式，努力打造对接国际规则、深化产能合作、促进产业转型升级的重要平台和空间载体。目前，7家境外园区入园企业达350家，为当地创造近6万个就业岗位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;江苏成功举办中欧班列国际合作论坛，为共建国家进一步畅通国际物流大通道、强化产业链供应链合作提供平台和凝聚共识；发挥科教人文优势，共筑民意相通新局面，精心打造全球滨海论坛、世界运河城市论坛等品牌活动，影响力不断增强。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;服务全局，建设具有世界聚合力的双向开放枢纽&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“发挥枢纽作用、支撑作用、示范引领作用，是江苏服务全国构建新发展格局的使命任务。”马欣表示，江苏将完整、准确、全面贯彻新发展理念，更加注重绿色低碳、共建共享、民心相通和风险防范，高质量建设“一带一路”交汇点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新亚欧陆海联运通道东连日韩、东盟，西接中亚、欧洲，横贯我国中西部地区众多城市群。马欣说，江苏将立足“一带一路”交汇点区位优势，以项目为载体不断深化东中西开放合作，充分发挥连云港海铁联运、徐州公铁水联运优势，共同建设中欧班列集结中心，放大通道的辐射带动作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以境内外产业园区为载体，深入推进产业链补链固链强链，打造国际产能合作示范区。江苏正鼓励苏南地区对标高标准国际经贸规则，创造更多可复制可推广经验，不断推动形成高水平制度型开放新优势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以港口城市为载体，建设长江经济带上的“一带一路”战略支点。深化陆海统筹、江海联动、港产城融合，服务畅通国内国际双循环。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以世界自然遗产和历史文化名城为载体，建设国际人文交流高地。江苏将进一步探索人与自然和谐共生、传统与现代交相辉映的高质量发展路径，打造丝绸之路上的生态和人文交流品牌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马欣说，江苏将进一步深入贯彻落实习近平总书记重要指示精神，秉持共商共建共享原则，深入实施“五大计划”专项行动，打造更有针对性的市场化、法治化、国际化一流营商环境，建设具有世界聚合力的双向开放枢纽。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（新华社南京10月6日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;记者凌军辉、陈刚）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 05:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[03版要闻 - 农技合作，开拓乌干达农民脱贫新路径]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/07/nw.D110000renmrb_20231007_1-03.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月07日星期六&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231007/1696622038078_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;在乌干达东部城市金贾举办的乌干达第二十九届全国农业展上，中国专家向参观者介绍优质农作物品种。&lt;BR/>;新华社记者聂祖国摄&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;在乌干达首都坎帕拉市郊的乌干达水产研究与发展中心的示范基地，阳光洒在水面，鲇鱼在鱼塘里畅游。从2012年开始，中国在联合国粮食及农业组织（联合国粮农组织）南南合作框架下向乌干达派遣农业专家和技术人员，积极向当地农民分享知识和技术，助力提升当地农业生产能力。截至目前，中国—联合国粮农组织—乌干达南南合作项目已执行至第三期，为当地农民开拓了脱贫新路径。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌干达副总统阿卢波表示，60多年来，乌中双方在基础设施建设、贸易、投资、农业等领域加强合作，为乌经济社会转型发展创造了条件，乌方对此表示衷心感谢。她高度肯定前两期合作项目富有成效，希望并相信第三期合作项目将助力乌中农业合作再创佳绩，推动乌干达实现可持续发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“鱼苗成活率从36%提高到81%”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌干达水产研究与发展中心是中乌友谊农业技术示范中心合作项目。去年11月，9名中国农业专家来到乌干达，开始执行为期3年的第三期合作项目。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者在现场采访时，正赶上中国专家向当地渔民示范科学投喂饵料的方法。56岁的中国水产专家陈太华耐心讲解：“鱼塘养殖要注意控制饵料投喂方式方法，投喂量要根据鱼的种类、尺寸、数量以及水质等因素来调节……”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;示范基地有10个鱼塘。几个月来，中国专家向当地渔民传授鲇鱼的人工繁殖、种苗选育、饲养管理和疾病防治等知识，手把手演示鱼塘清理、水质监测和饵料投喂等基本操作，同时帮助渔民开发出两种价格实惠的饲料。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在我们的饲料大多就地取材，一种由玉米粉、麸皮、鱼骨粉等制成，另一种由蚯蚓、昆虫、螺蚌等组成。不仅鲇鱼爱吃，价格还便宜。”当地渔民坎尼斯一边投喂饵料，一边向记者介绍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;提起中国技术给鱼塘带来的变化，坎尼斯有切身感受。他说：“中国专家带来的鱼苗孵化、饲料加工技术和排灌系统，让我们的鱼苗成活率从36%提高到81%。掌握增产的科学方法，对我们来说太重要了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;排灌系统是鱼塘的重要组成部分，规划建设的好坏直接影响养殖效果。中国农业专家组组长张小强介绍，这里的排灌系统通过在高地开挖总渠，将水分流至不同鱼塘，实现“自动流灌”，节省了用水和劳力，“这是中国传统的&#39;筑坝分水，修渠引水&#39;水利工程技术在当地的灵活运用”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据介绍，在第三期合作项目中，中国专家计划帮助当地养殖1000多万尾鱼，生产15吨以上鱼饲料，建立34个稻鱼共生示范点，同时为养殖户提供技术支持等。乌干达水产研究与发展中心下设的渔业资源研究所水产养殖研发中心负责人蒂本达表示：“中国专家的技术指导和经验传授为乌干达渔民带来了增产增收的希望。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“多亏了中国专家，果园产量有了大幅提高”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;微风和煦，51岁的果农爱德华走进果园，树上挂满苹果。“今年又是个好收成！”爱德华摘下果子，轻轻放入篮中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;爱德华的果园位于乌干达卡贝拉镇附近，面积不大。“以前，结出的苹果个头小、水分少，口感不好，产量也低，还容易遭受病虫害。”爱德华眼睁睁地看着忙活了一年的果园收成欠佳。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我努力找过不少解决办法，但效果都不太好。最终，中国专家带来的苹果砧木良种繁育技术改变了这一切。”爱德华说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;苹果砧木良种繁育是指在苹果树的砧木部分进行育种选种，培育出的新品种具有抗病虫害能力强、产量高等特性。在中国专家的指导下，爱德华选用了适合自家果园的砧木品种，并将其应用到苹果树的种植和管理中。经过实践，他发现果树的生长状况良好，果子的品质和产量也明显提高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现在，爱德华的果园收益成倍增长，日子越过越好，家里不仅翻新了房子，还添置了电视机、电冰箱等电器。“中国专家手把手指导我们，他们为乌干达果树种植业发展作出的贡献令人敬佩！”看着果园的丰收景象，爱德华满脸笑容。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在2012—2014年、2016—2018年两期合作项目推动下，中国苹果砧木良种繁育技术在乌干达进入大规模推广阶段，数量目前已达到150万株。据乌干达媒体报道，仅在卡贝拉项目点，就有数千名果农受益。经过中国专家技术指导后，卡贝拉项目点果农的收益总体比之前增加了5倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;针对乌干达缺乏储水装备和技术的现状，中国专家还开发了“坡改梯”，并建设天然集雨工程，改造面积达4000平方米。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国粮农组织公布的报告显示，在中国专家指导下建设的示范果园，优质苹果占比高达90%，不仅单枚苹果的重量增加了，整体品质也大大提升。“多亏了中国专家，果园产量有了大幅提高！”当地果农约瑟夫的开心溢于言表。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“吸引更多农业企业到乌干达投资兴业”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在距离坎帕拉北部近3小时车程的卢韦罗区，一大早，当地农户詹姆斯匆匆吃过早饭，便拿上纸笔，出门赶往水稻旱育秧技术培训活动现场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当天，南南合作项目卢韦罗驻点的中国专家讲解了节水抗旱水稻新品种WDR—73：“与传统水稻相比，WDR—73在有水灌溉的高产田可节水50%以上。在低投入情况下，WDR—73也比当地品种高产30%以上。”詹姆斯把专家提到的方法和数据认真地记录下来。“中国专家从我们的实际需要出发，真心实意帮助我们。改良后的新水稻品种将带来更大丰收。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年1月，由第二期合作项目筛选的WDR—73在卢韦罗中乌农业合作产业园喜获丰收，沉甸甸的稻穗压弯了稻秆。目前，中国专家正继续开展水稻新品种WDR—57的相关研究。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌干达农业、畜牧业和渔业部数据显示，乌干达70%以上的人口以农业为生。前两期南南合作项目切实提高了当地农业、畜牧业和渔业产量。第三期合作项目乌干达协调员彼得·穆因博介绍，项目旨在将农业生产商业化，目标是增加乌干达农产品对海外市场的出口。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张小强表示，第三期合作项目主要借助中乌友谊农业技术示范中心、中乌农业合作产业园两大平台，更大范围推广中国技术。“希望这一期项目能够进一步推动中乌农业贸易和投资合作，将乌干达优良农产品更多推向国际市场，同时也吸引更多农业企业到乌干达投资兴业。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联合国粮农组织副总干事贝丝·贝克多对中方多年来向南南合作项目提供的大力支持表示感谢。她强调，该南南合作项目的成功经验在于，中乌两国政府对项目高度重视并予以大力支持，在实施过程中主动同两国发展目标对接，极大促进了乌干达经济社会发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 05:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[03版要闻 - 传递中国经济向好发展的信心和力量（和音）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/07/nw.D110000renmrb_20231007_2-03.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月07日星期六&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;繁荣的假日经济是中国经济持续向好的见证，向世界传递出中国经济稳定发展的信心和力量&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;今年中秋国庆假期，景区排长队、电影院和餐厅爆满、出行人数再创新高，流动的中国到处生机勃勃。“机票和火车票提前售罄，酒店一房难求。对世界第二大经济体来说，这是一个强大的推动力”“中国国内消费猛增，乘坐火车出行的人数维持在高位，这些都提振了中国经济”“假日消费彰显中国经济的强劲动力”……连日来，国际舆论高度关注中国中秋国庆假期，认为繁荣的假日经济是中国经济持续向好的见证，向世界传递出中国经济稳定发展的信心和力量。&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;今年以来，面对复杂的外部环境，中国经济顶住压力、持续恢复，稳住了规模、提升了质量，经济增速在全球主要经济体中名列前茅。最新公布的数据显示，今年9月，随着政策效应不断累积，经济运行中积极因素不断增多，中国制造业采购经理指数（PMI）、非制造业商务活动指数和综合PMI产出指数分别为50.2%、51.7%和52%，三大指数均位于扩张区间，显示经济景气水平有所回升。花旗银行近日上调中国今年经济增长预期。联合国贸易和发展会议秘书长格林斯潘表示，中国有很大的财政空间，有办法实现反弹并支持经济。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;超大规模市场的需求是中国经济发展的重要优势之一。中秋国庆假期8天，中国国内旅游出游8.26亿人次，实现国内旅游收入7534.3亿元，按可比口径分别同比增长71.3%、129.5%，较2019年分别增长4.1%、1.5%，再次向世界展现了中国市场的韧性和活力。中国有14亿多人口和4亿以上中等收入群体，是全球第二大消费市场、第一大网络零售市场和新兴的中高端市场，也是全球最具潜力的大市场。随着恢复和扩大消费措施的实施，中国消费潜力将进一步得到释放，消费拉动经济增长的作用将进一步增强。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;中国稳步扩大开放，市场吸引力越来越大。近期，中国就进一步优化外商投资环境、加大吸引外商投资力度出台了一系列针对性举措。如今，中国一般制造业领域已实现全面开放，自贸试验区负面清单制造业条目全面清零。中国贸促会发布的《2023年第二季度中国外资营商环境调研报告》显示，近九成受访外资企业对在华获取经营场所、纳税、市场准入、跨境贸易、促进市场竞争等指标评价“满意”以上，超九成受访外资企业对2022年四季度以来中央出台的外资政策评价“满意”以上。今年前8个月，中国新设立外商投资企业33154家，同比增长33%。跨国公司在华积极投资，展现对中国市场和中国经济发展的信心。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;中国是全球开放合作的坚定支持者，中国经济向好发展是世界的重要机遇。从扩大面向全球的高标准自贸区网络到高质量实施《区域全面经济伙伴关系协定》，从不断壮大共建“一带一路”朋友圈到积极推进加入《全面与进步跨太平洋伙伴关系协定》，中国不断深化双多边经贸合作，促进互利共赢、共同发展。本月，中国将在北京举办第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛，已经有130多个国家的代表和很多国际组织代表确认参会。“&#39;一带一路&#39;倡议是一个雄心勃勃的经济合作大项目，不仅谋求振兴古老的丝绸之路，还致力于在区域和全球层面促进经济要素有序自由流动、资源高效配置和市场深度融合。”智利智中商会主席胡安·埃斯特万·穆萨莱姆撰文指出，中国作为一个永不停止的经济引擎，一直在为全球发展作出贡献，一如过去40年发生的那样。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;中秋国庆假期充满活力的中国市场，是中国经济韧性强、潜力大、活力足的明证。随着加快建设全国统一大市场，进一步巩固中国超大规模经济体的优势，更大激发市场活力和社会创造力，不断扩大高水平对外开放，中国将继续是世界经济发展的重要支撑，为各国发展提供更多机遇。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 07 Oct 2023 05:26:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>