<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 把广大民营经济人士更加紧密地团结在党的周围 不断开创工商联事业发展新局面]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/25/nw.D110000renmrb_20231025_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 25, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Congratulatory letter&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;On the occasion of the 70th anniversary of the establishment of the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce , on behalf of the Party Central Committee, I would like to extend warm congratulations to you! I would like to extend my sincere greetings to all the cadres and workers of the Federation of Industry and Commerce system and the vast number of private economic people across the country! &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The work of the Federation of Industry and Commerce is an important part of the party’s united front work and economic work. Over the past 70 years, the Federation of Industry and Commerce has always adhered to the party&#39;s leadership, focused on serving the party and the country&#39;s central work, and made important contributions in the great practice of building a new China, advancing reform and opening up, and forging ahead into a new era. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;We hope that the Federation of Industry and Commerce will thoroughly study and implement the Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era and the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, earnestly shoulder the mission and tasks entrusted by the Party in the new era and new journey, and strengthen ideological and political guidance and promote non-public ownership. The healthy development of the economy and the healthy growth of people in the non-public sector of the economy, solid efforts to promote the high-quality development of the private economy, boost confidence, unite people&#39;s hearts, unite the majority of private economic people more closely around the party, and constantly create a new situation for the development of the Federation of Industry and Commerce . It is hoped that the majority of private economic professionals will effectively implement the new development concept, vigorously promote entrepreneurship, strive to be a model of patriotism, dedication, law-abiding business, entrepreneurship and innovation, and return to society, and contribute to the comprehensive construction of a modern socialist country and the comprehensive promotion of the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;October 24, 2023&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>; (Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 24) &amp; nbsp; , President Xi Jinping, Chairman of the Central Military Commission, sent a congratulatory letter, extending warm congratulations on behalf of the Party Central Committee, and extending sincere greetings to all cadres and workers in the Federation of Industry and Commerce system and the vast number of private economic people across the country. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out in his congratulatory letter that the work of the Federation of Industry and Commerce is an important part of the party’s united front work and economic work. Over the past 70 years, the Federation of Industry and Commerce has always adhered to the party&#39;s leadership, focused on serving the party and the country&#39;s central work, and made important contributions in the great practice of building a new China, advancing reform and opening up, and forging ahead into a new era. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping hopes that the Federation of Industry and Commerce will thoroughly study and implement the Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era and the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Party, earnestly shoulder the mission and tasks entrusted by the Party in the new era and new journey, and strengthen ideological and political guidance and promote non-governmental organizations. We must work hard to promote the healthy development of the public economy and the healthy growth of people in the non-public economy, and solidly promote the high-quality development of the private economy, boost confidence, unite people&#39;s hearts, unite the majority of private economic people more closely around the party, and constantly create new developments in the development of the Federation of Industry and Commerce. situation. It is hoped that the majority of private economic professionals will effectively implement the new development concept, vigorously promote entrepreneurship, strive to be a model of patriotism, dedication, law-abiding business, entrepreneurship and innovation, and return to society, and contribute to the comprehensive construction of a modern socialist country and the comprehensive promotion of the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation. (The full text of the congratulatory letter will be issued separately)&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The 70th anniversary celebration meeting of the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce was held in Beijing on the 24th. Wang Huning, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Chairman of the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference, attended and delivered a speech. He said that General Secretary Xi Jinping specially sent a congratulatory letter to the 70th anniversary of the establishment of the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce, affirming the important contributions made by the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce, clarifying the significance, direction, theme and tasks of the work of the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce, and raising ardent hopes for the majority of private economic people. and clear requirements, which provide a fundamental basis for doing a good job in the work of the Federation of Industry and Commerce in the new era and promoting the healthy development of the private economy. We must study and understand it carefully and implement it well. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Wang Huning said that the Federation of Industry and Commerce is a people&#39;s organization and chamber of commerce organization led by the party, and the cause of the Federation of Industry and Commerce is an important part of the cause of the party and the country. On the new journey, the Federation of Industry and Commerce must be guided by Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, fully implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, firmly grasp the central tasks of the party and the country in the new era and new journey, and adhere to trust, unity, service, and guidance. , education policy, closely focus on the work of promoting &quot;two health&quot;, perform duties and responsibilities for the comprehensive construction of a modern socialist country. It is necessary to strengthen ideological and political guidance, guide the majority of private economic professionals to unswervingly listen to and follow the Party, consciously be models of patriotism, dedication, law-abiding business, entrepreneurship and innovation, and return to society, and become qualified builders of socialism with Chinese characteristics. It is necessary to promote the high-quality development of the private economy, guide private enterprises to completely, accurately and comprehensively implement the new development concept, actively participate in building a new development pattern, stick to the main business and strengthen the industry. It is necessary to guide the majority of private economic professionals to practice people-centered development ideas and promote private enterprises to fulfill their social responsibilities and better benefit the people. It is necessary to adhere to political construction, unite to establish the association, serve to rejuvenate the association, reform and strengthen the association, always maintain and enhance the political, advanced and mass nature, and better play the role of bridge and assistant of the Federation of Industry and Commerce. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Shi Taifeng, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and director of the United Front Work Department of the CPC Central Committee, read Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter at the meeting. Hao Mingjin, Vice Chairman of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress and Chairman of the Central Committee of the Democratic National Construction Association, and Xu Liuping, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and First Secretary of the Secretariat of the All-China Federation of Trade Unions, successively delivered congratulatory messages on behalf of the central committees of democratic parties and people&#39;s organizations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Liu Guozhong, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Vice Premier of the State Council, Zheng Jianbang, vice chairman of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress and chairman of the Central Committee of the Kuomintang, and Wang Yong, vice chairman of the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference, attended the conference. Gao Yunlong, Vice Chairman of the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference and Chairman of the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce, presided over the conference. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The conference commended the advanced collectives and advanced workers of the Federation of Industry and Commerce system. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Before the meeting, Wang Huning and other leading comrades met with members of the leadership team of the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce, as well as commended advanced collective representatives and advanced workers of the Federation of Industry and Commerce system. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Responsible comrades of relevant departments of central and state agencies and relevant people&#39;s organizations, central leaders of all democratic parties, relevant responsible comrades and representatives of the Federation of Industry and Commerce system, commended advanced collective representatives and advanced workers of the Federation of Industry and Commerce system, Representatives of private economic persons attended the conference. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平向纪念亲诚惠容周边外交理念提出10周年国际研讨会发表书面致辞]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/25/nw.D110000renmrb_20231025_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 25, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 24th&amp;nbsp; Delivered a written speech at the International Symposium on the 10th Anniversary of the Concept of Comprehensive Neighborhood Diplomacy. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that the basic policy of China&#39;s peripheral diplomacy is to adhere to the principle of being good to and partner with its neighbors, adhering to amity, security and prosperity, and highlighting the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness. Over the past 10 years, China has actively practiced the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness, and comprehensively developed friendly and cooperative relations with neighboring countries. Political mutual trust between the two sides has been continuously enhanced, and the integration of interests has continued to deepen, and has embarked on a bright road of good-neighborliness, friendship, and win-win cooperation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that in the new era, we will give new connotation to the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness, carry forward Asian values ​​with peace, cooperation, tolerance and integration as the core, and contribute to regional unity, openness and progress. Provide new assistance. We will promote the new development of the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness, so that Chinese-style modernization will benefit more neighboring countries, and jointly promote the modernization process in Asia, so that China&#39;s high-quality development and a good surrounding environment will promote and complement each other. China will continue to practice the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness, work with regional countries to build an Asian homeland of peace, tranquility, prosperity, beauty, and friendship and coexistence, and jointly write a new chapter in promoting the construction of a community with a shared future for Asia and a community with a shared future for mankind! &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;An international seminar to commemorate the 10th anniversary of the proposal of the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness in neighboring diplomacy was held in Beijing on the same day, with the theme of &quot;Amity, Sincerity, Benefit and Inclusion: New Connotation&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;New Development&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;New Vision&quot;. It is jointly organized by the Foreign Affairs Office of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the Ministry of Foreign Affairs. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 在全面推进强国建设民族复兴伟业中奋勇担当]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/25/nw.D110000renmrb_20231025_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 25, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;“We must adhere to the fundamental policy of relying wholeheartedly on the working class, fully mobilize the enthusiasm, initiative, creativity, and enthusiasm of the broad masses of workers. Dedicate ourselves to comprehensively advancing the great cause of building a strong country and rejuvenating the nation.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On October 23, General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech during a collective talk with members of the new leadership team of the All-China Federation of Trade Unions pointed out the new era. The direction of trade union work has strengthened the confidence and determination of the majority of trade union cadres to do a good job. The majority of trade union cadres and employees expressed that they should follow the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech and strive to create a new situation for the party’s labor movement and trade union work with a more heroic attitude and a courageous and responsible spirit. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping’s full affirmation of the work of the trade union has inspired the majority of trade union cadres. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen Huixia, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Executive Vice Chairman of the Hubei Provincial Federation of Trade Unions, said that since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the party’s labor movement has made historic achievements and the trade union work has achieved all-round progress. The fundamental reason is that General Secretary Xi Jinping The guiding orientation is guided by the scientific guidance of Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era. The cohesion and centripetal force of the majority of employees have been further enhanced, the reform of the trade union system has continued to deepen, and the role of trade union work in the overall work of the party and the country has been further demonstrated. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is the political responsibility of trade union organizations to guide the workers and staff to listen to and follow the Party, and to consolidate the class foundation and mass foundation of the Party&#39;s governance. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We must always adhere to the party’s overall leadership over the trade unions, maintain the correct political direction of the trade union work, and use greater efforts and more practical measures to demonstrate the vitality of the trade unions in striving to achieve Chinese-style modernization.” Fujian Province Wang Xuemin, member of the Standing Committee of the Xiamen Municipal Party Committee and chairman of the Xiamen Federation of Trade Unions, said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhao Hao, Party Secretary and Vice Chairman of the Federation of Trade Unions of Nanyang City, Henan Province, said that the trade union is a mass organization of the working class under the leadership of the Communist Party of China. It has a history of organizing and mobilizing workers to unite and fight to complete the central tasks of the party. mission. On the new journey, we must be loyal to the party&#39;s cause, serve the employees wholeheartedly, have the courage to take on responsibilities, forge ahead, and strive to write a new chapter in the party&#39;s labor movement. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new era requires hard work, innovation and development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Just after attending the 18th National Congress of the Chinese Trade Union in Beijing, Mu Yongqi, the main shield driver and senior technician of the China Railway Tunnel Bureau Group, rushed back to the construction site in Tibet and continued to lead the team to focus on key technical problems in shield construction. Scientific research. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The General Secretary pointed out that we must speed up the construction of an army of knowledge-based, skilled and innovative industrial workers, and cultivate and create more craftsmen and highly skilled talents in the country. As a tunnel worker, we must do a line of work, We will love our work and be good at it, continue to overcome the difficulties in the operation of shield machines on the plateau, and make greater contributions to the construction of the &#39;Sky Road&#39; on the plateau.&quot; He said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized “carry out various forms of labor and skills competitions extensively and deeply to stimulate the enthusiasm and creative potential of employees, and give full play to the main role in all walks of life and fields”, so that the majority of employees can The confidence and energy of the masses have doubled. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Lei, winner of the National May 1st Labor Medal and a relay protection engineer at Guizhou Liupanshui Power Supply Bureau of China Southern Power Grid, has been on the front line for 23 years and has independently innovated and developed more than 30 new professional equipment and tools. After studying the General Secretary’s important speech, he felt deeply: “The General Secretary’s important speech made me more deeply aware of the value and strength of workers. I will continue to work hard in my job, and I will also give full play to the role of leading the new with the old. role in stimulating the wisdom and strength of young workers to make contributions, innovate and create.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After carefully studying General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s important speech, Wang Zhenhua, deputy director of the Standing Committee of the People&#39;s Congress of Fengtai District, Beijing and chairman of the District Federation of Trade Unions, deeply feels the responsibility major. He said: &quot;We must deeply understand the spirit of the General Secretary&#39;s important speech and convey the spirit to every employee and every position.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The trade union is the representative and defender of the interests of employees and the representative of employees. &quot;My mother&#39;s family&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Zhe, a Meituan takeout delivery worker in Zhangwu County, Fuxin City, Liaoning Province and a &quot;post-90s&quot; young man, said that General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized the importance of safeguarding the legitimate rights and interests of workers in the new employment form, so that as a takeaway rider, He felt deeply warm. &quot;At work, the enterprise trade union is like a link, strengthening democratic consultation and equal communication between the enterprise and the riders, so that we can gain a sense of accomplishment in ordinary positions.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The General Secretary emphasized that the trade union must Earnestly fulfill the basic responsibilities of rights protection services and strive to solve practical problems related to the vital interests of employees. As a member of the grassroots trade union, I will further focus on the needs of employees in future work, strive to help employees solve urgent, difficult and anxious problems, and make employees more aware of their needs. I really feel the warmth of the trade union family.&quot; said Tang Ju, winner of the May 1st Labor Medal in Luoyang City, Henan Province and chairman of the trade union of the Hanzhong Industrial Park Project of China Railway 15th Bureau. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trade union reform is an important part of my country&#39;s comprehensive deepening of reform and an inexhaustible driving force for the innovation and development of trade union work. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized the need to continue to deepen the reform and construction of trade unions. As a trade unionist, I deeply feel that the mission is glorious and the responsibility lies on my shoulders.” Chen Hongbing, deputy secretary of the Party Committee and chairman of the trade union of China Silian Instrument Group He said that we must not forget our original aspirations and keep our mission in mind, continue to promote the establishment of strong associations, safeguard the rights and interests of employees, promote democratic management of enterprises, fully stimulate the enthusiasm of front-line workers for innovation and creation, focus on key core technologies, and let more innovative results emerge. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Geng Xiaoli, Party Secretary and Vice Chairman of the Taizhou Federation of Trade Unions in Jiangsu Province, was deeply impressed by the words of General Secretary Xi Jinping in his important speech: &quot;We must innovate working methods and strive to provide precise and considerate services to employees.&quot; He told reporters that in recent years, trade union organizations such as the Taizhou Online Ride-hailing Industry Trade Union Federation and the Express Delivery and Food Delivery Industry Trade Union Federation have been established one after another. In the future, trade unions at all levels should take the General Secretary&#39;s important speech as a guide, deeply understand the needs and expectations of workers in the new employment form, and solve their &quot;key issues&quot; with heart and soul, so that &quot;work&quot; services can better benefit employee production. Life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 24)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 李强抵达比什凯克出席上海合作组织成员国政府首脑（总理）理事会第二十二次会议并对吉尔吉斯斯坦进行正式访问]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/25/nw.D110000renmrb_20231025_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 25, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231025/1698180021901_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;At the invitation of Prime Minister Zhaparov of the Kyrgyz Republic, Premier Li Qiang of the State Council left Beijing on a chartered flight on the afternoon of October 24 and went to the Kyrgyz Republic to attend the 22nd Meeting of the Council of Heads of Government (Prime Ministers) of the Shanghai Cooperation Organization Member States and to pay an official visit to the Kyrgyz Republic. On the afternoon of the 24th local time, Li Qiang’s charter flight arrived at Bishkek Manas International Airport. This is a grand welcome ceremony held by Zhaparov for Li Qiang at the airport. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Yin Bogu&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Bishkek of this newspaper on October 24 Japan News &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (Reporter Wang Di) At the invitation of Prime Minister Zhaparov of the Kyrgyz Republic, Premier Li Qiang left Beijing on a chartered flight on the afternoon of October 24 and went to the Kyrgyz Republic to attend the Council of Heads of Government (Prime Ministers) of the Member States of the Shanghai Cooperation Organization 22nd meeting and an official visit to the Kyrgyz Republic. State Councilor and Secretary-General of the State Council Wu Zhenglong and other accompanying personnel left Beijing on the same plane. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of the 24th local time, Li Qiang’s charter flight arrived at Bishkek Manas International Airport. Prime Minister Zhaparov and senior government officials went to the airport to greet him. Chinese Ambassador to Kyrgyzstan Du Dewen also went to the airport to greet him. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhaparov held a grand welcome ceremony for Li Qiang at the airport. The military band played the national anthems of China and Kyrgyzstan. Li Qiang, accompanied by Zhaparov, reviewed the guard of honor. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later, Li Qiang held a brief meeting with Zhaparov. Li Qiang said that since the establishment of diplomatic relations, China and Kyrgyzstan have persisted in working together, helping each other, and achieving mutual benefit and win-win results. Cooperation in various fields has yielded fruitful results, and international cooperation has been close and efficient. China and Kyrgyzstan are truly good neighbors, good friends, good partners, and good brothers. My visit to Kyrgyzstan this time is to enhance mutual trust, expand cooperation, deepen friendship and promote peace. China is willing to work with Kyrgyzstan to fully implement the important consensus reached by the two heads of state, continuously deepen political and strategic mutual trust, create more new highlights and new benchmarks for cooperation, and give China-Kyrgyzstan friendship more contemporary connotations. China also looks forward to working with SCO member states to carry forward the &quot;Shanghai Spirit&quot; and inject new momentum into regional peace, stability and development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhaparov warmly welcomed Li Qiang’s visit to Kyrgyzstan, spoke highly of the positive development momentum of Kyrgyz-China relations, and expressed that Kyrgyzstan is willing to strengthen exchanges with China in various fields, promote the joint construction of the “Belt and Road”, and promote the comprehensive strategies of the two countries. The partnership continues to reach new heights and jointly promotes stability and development in Central Asia. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wu Zhenglong attended the meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 十四届全国人大常委会第六次会议在京闭幕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/25/nw.D110000renmrb_20231025_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 25, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;This newspaper, Beijing, October 24th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Huang Qingchang) The Sixth Session of the Standing Committee of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress The meeting concluded on the afternoon of the 24th at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing. After voting, the meeting passed the newly revised Marine Environmental Protection Law and the Patriotism Education Law; it was decided to remove Li Shangfu from the posts of State Councilor and Minister of National Defense, remove Qin Gang from the posts of State Councilor, and remove Wang Zhigang from the posts of Minister of Science and Technology. , appointed Yin Hejun as Minister of Science and Technology, removed Liu Kun from the post of Minister of Finance, and appointed Lan Fo&#39;an as Minister of Finance. President Xi Jinping signed Presidential Orders No. 12, 13, and 14 respectively. Chairman Zhao Leji presided over the closing meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;162 members of the Standing Committee attended the meeting, and the number of attendees met the quorum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The meeting voted to adopt the National People’s Congress Standing Committee’s resolution approving the State Council’s issuance of additional treasury bonds and the 2023 central budget adjustment plan, and the 14th National People’s Congress Standing Committee’s resolution authorizing the State Council to issue some new local government debt limits in advance. Decide. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The meeting voted to adopt the decision of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress on ratifying the Treaty between the People&#39;s Republic of China and the Republic of Colombia on the Transfer of Sentenced Persons, the decision on ratifying the Extradition Treaty between the People&#39;s Republic of China and the Republic of Mauritius, Decision to ratify the Protocol against the Illicit Manufacturing of and Trafficking in Firearms, Their Parts and Components and Ammunition, supplementing the United Nations Convention against Transnational Organized Crime, ratification of the Secretariat of the Conference on Interaction and Confidence-Building Measures in Asia and its personnel, and the privileges of representatives of member states and the Immunity Convention, and the decision to join the International Convention on Aids to Navigation and Navigation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The meeting voted and approved the proposals submitted by representatives of the Supervisory and Judicial Committee, the Financial and Economic Committee, the Environment and Resources Protection Committee, and the Social Construction Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress respectively regarding the presidium of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress for deliberation. Report on the results of the review. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The meeting voted to remove Li Shangfu from his position as a member of the Central Military Commission. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The meeting voted to appoint Liu Shaoyun as the president of the Chinese People&#39;s Liberation Army Military Court. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The meeting also voted on other appointments and dismissals. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vice Chairman of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress Li Hongzhong, Wang Dongming, Xiao Jie, Zheng Jianbang, Ding Zhongli, Hao Mingjin, Cai Dafeng, He Wei, Wu Weihua, Tiening, Peng Qinghua, Zhang Qingwei, Luosang Jiangcun, Xue Keleti Zha Kerr and Secretary-General Liu Qi attended the meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vice Premier of the State Council Zhang Guoqing, President of the Supreme People&#39;s Court Zhang Jun, responsible comrades of the National Supervisory Commission and the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, members of the special committees of the National People&#39;s Congress, responsible comrades of the Standing Committees of the People&#39;s Congresses of various provinces, autonomous regions and municipalities, some deputy provincial governors The main responsible comrades of the Standing Committee of the Municipal People&#39;s Congress, some National People&#39;s Congress deputies, and responsible comrades of relevant departments attended the meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the closing meeting, the Standing Committee of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress held the seventh special lecture, chaired by Chairman Zhao Leji. Li Chunlin, member of the Party Leadership Group and Deputy Director of the National Development and Reform Commission, gave a lecture titled &quot;Accelerating the Planning and Construction of a New Energy System Guided by Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 中国经济具有巨大韧性和潜力]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/25/nw.D110000renmrb_20231025_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 25, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;A correct understanding of the current economic situation is the foundation for us to do a solid job in economic work. Recently, the economic data for the third quarter were released, which showed that China&#39;s economic recovery has become more obvious. The main engine of world economic growth is strong and resilient. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our economy has huge development resilience and potential”, “the fundamentals of long-term good development have not changed, and the development prospects are bright” and “China’s economic ship will continue to move forward despite the wind and waves.” Since the beginning of this year, Comrade Xi Jinping has been the leader. The core Party Central Committee has made a series of strategic judgments on my country&#39;s economic situation, which plays an important guiding role in our comprehensive, dialectical and accurate understanding of the general trend of economic development. It also conveys to the world China&#39;s firm confidence in united struggle and courageous advancement. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Confidence comes from a dialectical understanding of economic fundamentals. To objectively look at the overall situation of China&#39;s economic operation, we must look at both speed and quality. Since the beginning of this year, our country’s economy has withstood the downward pressure brought by external risk challenges and multiple domestic factors, and its growth has stabilized and rebounded. In the first three quarters, my country&#39;s GDP grew by 5.2% year-on-year, ranking among the best among the world&#39;s major economies. It is particularly important to point out that the year-on-year growth rate in the third quarter was 4.9%, which was slightly lower than that in the second quarter. This was mainly affected by the base number last year. If the base effect is deducted, the two-year average growth rate in the third quarter of this year is 4.4%, which is 1.1 percentage points faster than the two-year average growth rate in the second quarter. In addition, the quarter-on-quarter growth rate in the third quarter was also 0.8 percentage points faster than that in the second quarter. There is inertia in the economic operation, and we believe that the trend of stabilization and recovery will remain in the fourth quarter. While growth continues to recover, my country&#39;s prices are generally stable, the employment situation has improved, foreign trade is better than expected, corporate profit growth has improved, and high-quality development has been solidly advanced. Facts have proved that in the complex and severe external environment of sluggish world economic recovery and still high global inflation, the Chinese economy has demonstrated strong resilience, potential and vitality, and remains the ballast and stabilizer of global economic growth. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Confidence comes from an accurate grasp of the laws of development. It is advisable to take a long-term view and observe the Chinese economy, which is inseparable from historical thinking and historical perspective. Judging from international experience, after the economy reaches a certain scale, industrial upgrading and transformation and development are generally accompanied by a slowdown in growth. As the world&#39;s second largest economy, China&#39;s total economic output exceeded 120 trillion yuan last year, and the increment corresponding to each one percentage point increase is roughly equivalent to 2.1 percentage points 10 years ago. From the perspective of development history, China&#39;s economy has always developed by overcoming challenges, grown by ups and downs, and grown stronger by going through trials. Especially since the new era, in the face of the dangers of fording the beach, the difficulties of climbing mountains, and the difficulties of breaking through obstacles, we have responded calmly and worked hard. The cause of the party and the country has made historic achievements and undergone historic changes, and has made strides forward in high-quality development. , my country’s economic strength achieved a historic leap. As General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized, &quot;When are there no difficulties? One by one, every year is good, and every year is good. This has been the case for the Chinese nation for more than 5,000 years. The key to overcoming obstacles is to boost confidence.&quot;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;Confidence comes from a deep insight into the superiority of the system. Since the beginning of this year, under the strong leadership of the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping at its core, all regions and departments have better coordinated domestic and international situations, better coordinated epidemic prevention and control and economic and social development, and better coordinated development and security. We have created The most populous country in the history of human civilization has successfully emerged from the miracle of the epidemic. my country&#39;s economy is developing in waves and twists and turns, with obvious momentum of consumption upgrading, enhanced regional coordination momentum, and continuous release of innovation vitality. This fully demonstrates that the decision-making and deployment of the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core on economic work is completely correct, and fully demonstrates our party’s superb wisdom and skillful ability to control the socialist market economy in a complex and changeable situation. Facing the future, we must fully, accurately and comprehensively implement the new development concept, firmly grasp the primary task of high-quality development and the strategic task of building a new development pattern, proactively adapt to and lead a new round of scientific and technological revolution and industrial transformation, and accelerate the realization of high-level scientific and technological progress. Being self-reliant and self-reliant, and implementing a series of strategic deployments of the Party Central Committee on scientific and technological innovation, we are fully capable of continuously shaping new drivers of development and new advantages, and firmly grasping the initiative in development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unity is strength, and confidence is worth more than gold. The fundamentals of China&#39;s long-term economic growth have not changed and will not change. Strengthening self-confidence, cultivating a normal mind, stimulating enterprising spirit, and concentrating on doing our own things well are the keys to overcoming various risks and challenges. Accurately grasp the analysis and judgment of the Party Central Committee on the current economic situation, invigorate our spirits, unite our efforts, continue to climb over obstacles, overcome difficulties, muster the spirit of entrepreneurial spirit, and form a good situation in which we will pay close attention to implementation. China&#39;s economic giant is set for Able to cut through waves and travel steadily and far. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 韩正会见不丹外交大臣丹迪·多吉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/25/nw.D110000renmrb_20231025_7-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 25, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 24th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;On October 24th, Vice President Han Zheng met in Beijing with Dandi Dorje, Minister of Foreign Affairs of Denmark. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Han Zheng said that China and Bhutan are friendly neighbors connected by mountains and rivers. Although the two countries have not established diplomatic relations, they have maintained friendly exchanges for a long time. In recent years, the two sides have taken the resumption of boundary negotiations as a symbol and relied on the boundary negotiation mechanism to promote positive progress in China-Bhutan relations. Strengthening friendship and expanding cooperation between China and Africa is in line with the fundamental interests of both countries and the expectations of the two peoples. China will, as always, respect the independence, sovereignty and territorial integrity of Bhutan, and is willing to strengthen mutual visits and exchanges with Bhutan at all levels and in all fields, expand practical cooperation in economy, trade, culture, tourism and other fields, accelerate the process of demarcation and establishment of diplomatic relations between China and Bhutan, and better Benefit both countries and peoples. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Tandy Dorji said that the Bhutanese government attaches great importance to developing relations with China and firmly adheres to the one-China principle. Both sides have the sincere desire and firm determination to realize demarcation and establish diplomatic relations at an early date. Bhutan is willing to maintain the good momentum of cooperation in various fields with China and promote greater development of bilateral relations. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 携手构建和平安宁、繁荣美丽、友好共生的亚洲家园]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/25/nw.D110000renmrb_20231025_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 25, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;On October 24, President Xi Jinping issued a written statement to the international seminar commemorating the 10th anniversary of the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness in neighboring diplomacy. The speech summarized the fruitful results of China&#39;s active implementation of the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness, clarified the new connotation and new development of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness, outlined a new vision for the future common development of China and neighboring countries, and provided a basis for the development of bilateral relations in the new era. Important to follow and point out the way forward. International people interviewed by this reporter believed that China has always followed the path of peaceful development, pursued the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness, and worked hand in hand with regional countries on the journey of modernization to better benefit Asian countries with its own development and contribute to regional and even global prosperity and stability. strength. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; “Playing an important role in the prosperity and stability of the Asian region”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The basic policy of China’s peripheral diplomacy is to persist in being good friends and partners with its neighbors. Adhere to the principle of good-neighborliness, security and prosperity, and highlight the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness. President Xi Jinping emphasized in his speech that over the past 10 years, China has actively practiced the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness and comprehensively developed friendly and cooperative relations with neighboring countries. Political mutual trust between the two sides has been continuously enhanced, and the integration of interests has continued to deepen, creating a path of good neighborliness, friendship, and win-win cooperation. The bright road. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sujata Koirala, former deputy prime minister and foreign minister of Nepal, told this reporter that the speech reflected President Xi Jinping’s emphasis on and persistence in the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness. As a major country in Asia, China has always treated neighboring countries as equals, shared development dividends with neighboring countries, and made important contributions to Asia&#39;s prosperity and stability. The joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative embodies the concepts of openness, inclusiveness, mutual benefit and win-win, is in line with the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness, and has injected strong impetus into the economic development of Nepal and other South Asian countries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zemir Awan, founding chairman of the Global Silk Road Research Alliance, a Pakistani think tank, said that China has the most neighbors in the world. The development of friendly and cooperative relations between China and neighboring countries is of great significance and is a blessing to the region and the world. &quot;Under the guidance of the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness put forward by President Xi Jinping, China&#39;s relations with neighboring countries have developed steadily, and economic and trade cooperation has become increasingly close. Neighboring countries have boarded China&#39;s express train of development, and everyone can live a good life together and play an important role in the prosperity and stability of the Asian region. &quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chaogtbaatar, former Foreign Minister of Mongolia and member of the State Great Hural, believes that President Xi Jinping&#39;s concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness highlights China&#39;s willingness to achieve win-win cooperation with neighboring countries. China must be true to its words and resolute in its deeds, and has shown the world with practical actions that China always respects its neighboring countries and regards them as friends and partners. This has enhanced the trust and confidence of neighboring countries in China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kazbek Megeldinov, a member of the Kurultai State Council under the President of Kazakhstan, said that China practices the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness in its interactions with neighboring countries, and is committed to mutual respect, openness and inclusiveness. Mutually beneficial cooperation has been carried out on the basis of cooperation and enhanced trust with neighboring countries. At the same time, China and neighboring countries have strengthened dialogue and collaboration on international affairs. For example, Kazakhstan and China actively collaborate within multilateral mechanisms such as the United Nations, the Shanghai Cooperation Organization, and the Conference on Interaction and Confidence Building Measures in Asia, making important contributions to regional and world peace and stability. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“Bringing confidence in peace and development to neighboring countries”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping emphasized that in the context of the new era, we will endow ourselves with amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness. The new connotation of the concept promotes Asian values ​​with peace, cooperation, tolerance and integration as the core, and provides new impetus for regional unity, openness and progress. We will promote the new development of the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness, so that Chinese-style modernization will benefit more neighboring countries, and jointly promote the modernization process in Asia, so that China&#39;s high-quality development and a good surrounding environment will promote and complement each other. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The &quot;Asian values ​​of peace, cooperation, tolerance and integration as the core&quot; mentioned in President Xi Jinping&#39;s speech deeply impressed Virun Phi Chaowongpakdi, director of the Thailand-China &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; Research Center. &quot;This discussion reflects President Xi Jinping&#39;s latest thinking on neighborhood diplomacy.&quot; He said that Thailand and China are one family, and the friendly relations and close cooperation between the two countries embody the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness. Thailand and other Southeast Asian countries look forward to continuing to develop friendly relations and mutually beneficial cooperation with China. They hope that Chinese-style modernization will benefit more neighboring countries and jointly promote the modernization process in Asia. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;President Xi Jinping reiterated in his speech that China will continue to practice the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness and bring confidence in peace and development to neighboring countries.&quot; said Yoganathan, Charge d&#39;Affaires of the Embassy of Sri Lanka in China. , over the past 10 years, this concept has promoted friendly cooperation between neighboring countries and China, and also brought development opportunities to neighboring countries. The &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative proposed by China has well implemented the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness. &quot;Colombo Port City and a number of jointly built &#39;Belt and Road&#39; projects have promoted Sri Lanka&#39;s connectivity and economic and social development, and the beautiful vision of &#39;rich neighbors&#39; is being realized. Sri Lanka looks forward to continuing to work together with China for common development.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>; Cai Dequan, a researcher at the &quot;Integrated Development Research Center&quot;, a Philippine think tank, said that President Xi Jinping&#39;s speech is far-sighted and &quot;promotes new development of the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness, so that Chinese-style modernization can benefit more neighboring countries.&quot; This discussion reflects China&#39;s commitment to safeguarding Sincerity and goodwill for peace and prosperity in the surrounding areas. Cai Dequan said that in the past 10 years, the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness has promoted good-neighborly friendship and win-win cooperation between China and neighboring countries. Chinese-style modernization is a modernization that takes the road of peace. China&#39;s development will inject inexhaustible impetus into regional unity and cooperation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Veronica, head of the China Research Department of the Indonesian Center for International Strategic Studies, said that China is promoting Chinese-style modernization and promoting high-quality development. While Indonesia and China are deepening cooperation in traditional fields, they are also constantly exploring new areas. Cooperate in emerging industries such as energy vehicles, digital economy, and photovoltaics to actively cultivate more growth points. China has sincerely shared development dividends and carried out pragmatic cooperation through the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, and neighboring countries such as Indonesia have benefited a lot. It is believed that driven by the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness, Chinese-style modernization will benefit more countries and people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“Promote the realization of the beautiful vision of building a community with a shared future for mankind”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping emphasized that China will continue to practice the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness, and work with regional countries Let us work together to build an Asian homeland of peace, tranquility, prosperity, beauty, and friendly coexistence, and jointly write a new chapter in promoting the construction of a community with a shared future for Asia and a community with a shared future for mankind. International people believe that President Xi Jinping&#39;s speech injects confidence and impetus into promoting the construction of a community with a shared future for Asia and a community with a shared future for mankind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jin Ping, director of the Institute of International Relations of the Royal Academy of Cambodia, said that as a member of the Asian family and a responsible major country, China attaches great importance to neighborhood diplomacy, always puts its neighbors at the forefront of the overall diplomatic situation, and is always committed to promoting regional peace, stability, development and prosperity. China continues to practice the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness and will further promote the construction of a community with a shared future for Asia and a community with a shared future for mankind. Jin Ping said: &quot;In the past 10 years, the joint construction of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; has made great contributions to Cambodia&#39;s economic and social development. The Cambodian people believe even more that cooperation with China will bring them hope of development.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asia-Pacific &quot;One Belt&quot; Weng Shijie, chairman of the &quot;One Road&quot; Joint Strategy Committee, said that this year marks the 10th anniversary of the concept of amity, sincerity, mutual benefit and inclusiveness, and China&#39;s will to adhere to peaceful development has always been consistent. Under the framework of the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, landmark projects such as the China-Laos Railway and the Jakarta-Bandung High-Speed ​​Railway have been realized, and many &quot;small but beautiful&quot; people&#39;s livelihood projects have widely benefited Southeast Asian countries.习近平主席还提出三大全球倡议，将中国与周边国家的友好合作提升到更高层次。翁诗杰说：“亲诚惠容理念符合地区繁荣与和平的需要。通过发展追求持久和平和繁荣，中国为全球治理提出了新方案，将推动实现构建人类命运共同体的美好愿景。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;柬埔寨亚洲愿景研究院湄公河战略研究中心主任林明和表示，当今世界充满不确定性、不稳定性，这进一步凸显了构建人类命运共同体的必要性。柬中关系充分体现了亲诚惠容理念，共建“一带一路”倡议与该理念相辅相成。 “金港高速公路、新金边国际机场、暹粒吴哥国际机场等一大批共建&#39;一带一路&#39;项目给柬埔寨增添发展动力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现场与会的日本前首相福田康夫表示，随着中国国力不断增强，更多国家从中国的发展中受益。实现发展进步，建设亚洲家园，需要各国共同努力。各国应自发践行亲诚惠容理念，让发展成果惠及周边，推动全球发展进步，走向更加繁荣美好的未来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（本报北京、伊斯兰堡、阿斯塔纳、雅加达10月24日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;记者杨讴、龚鸣、赵益普、郭梓云、程是颉、李强、李培松）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - “泰中两国合作前景广阔”（共建“一带一路”·高端访谈）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/25/nw.D110000renmrb_20231025_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月25日星期三&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;“今年是习近平主席提出共建&#39;一带一路&#39;倡议10周年。这一倡议通过加强基础设施建设、贸易投资、文化交流和人员往来等，将许多国家紧密联系在一起，成为造福全人类的重要倡议。”泰国总理赛塔日前在来华出席第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛并进行正式访问期间接受了本报记者专访。他高度评价泰中两国合作取得丰硕成果，表示在共建“一带一路”框架下，“泰中两国合作前景广阔”。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;赛塔表示，习近平主席在本届高峰论坛开幕式上的主旨演讲传递了中国坚持和平发展、扩大开放的信号。“习近平主席温文尔雅、平易近人，对邻国以诚相待，让人感觉十分暖心。”赛塔认为，共建“一带一路”倡议已成为连接全球不同国家的纽带。本届高峰论坛上，多国领导人齐聚一堂，阐述各自国家发展计划，展现了各方继续携手共建“一带一路”的承诺和决心。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;赛塔说，中国是泰国最大的贸易伙伴，共建“一带一路”对于泰中经贸合作十分重要。赛塔今年9月就任泰国总理后，曾前往泰国东北部廊开地区考察泰中老三国铁路连接情况。他认为，经由泰中老铁路连接获得的中转地位，将极大推动廊开发展。他还以泰中铁路建设为例说，这条铁路是两国务实合作的旗舰项目，铁路建成后将推动区域互联互通，增强企业对泰国投资环境信心。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;随着共建“一带一路”不断推进，许多中国新能源汽车企业前往泰国投资建厂。赛塔认为，这将助力泰国实现全球电动汽车制造中心的愿景。在他看来，泰中两国在农业领域也拥有巨大合作潜力。他以榴莲出口为例说：“我知道很多中国民众喜欢吃榴莲，将来泰国可以向中国出口更多、更高品质的榴莲。”&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“泰中友好源远流长，两国人民像亲友一样互相支持。”赛塔表示，中国是泰国最大的游客来源国，从9月25日起，泰国政府面向中国游客实施为期约5个月的免签政策。“免签等政策有助于促进泰中民间交往，为两国进一步深化务实合作打下坚实基础。”&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;出席高峰论坛相关活动期间，赛塔还与多位中国企业负责人洽谈。“我这次来就是向中国传递一个信号：泰国已准备好迎接来自中国的投资者。”赛塔表示，“中国市场广阔，潜力巨大，泰国具有良好的营商环境，希望与更多中国企业合作共建&#39;一带一路&#39;项目。泰中合作大有可为。”&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 纪念亲诚惠容周边外交理念提出10周年国际研讨会开幕式在京举行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/25/nw.D110000renmrb_20231025_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月25日星期三&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报北京10月24日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者龚鸣、赵益普、郭梓云）纪念亲诚惠容周边外交理念提出10周年国际研讨会24日在京举行。中共中央政治局委员、中央外办主任王毅首先宣读了习近平主席书面致辞。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;王毅说，10年前，习近平主席提出亲诚惠容周边外交理念。 10年来，亲诚惠容从理念到行动，从愿景到现实，思想内涵不断丰富，实践效果持续显现，为亚洲友好合作、团结振兴注入了强大动力，为构建人类命运共同体提供了有益镜鉴。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;王毅强调，亚洲的未来，关键在做好自己的事情。亚洲的振兴，关键在地区国家团结奋斗。中国正在以中国式现代化全面推进中华民族伟大复兴，必将为世界各国特别是亚洲邻国带来持久红利，提供更多机遇，注入不竭动力。中方将秉持亲诚惠容理念，深化同周边国家友好合作和利益融合，共同构建和平安宁、繁荣美丽、友好共生的亚洲家园，为构建亚洲命运共同体和人类命运共同体贡献更多智慧和力量。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;王毅就此提出四点建议：一是坚持共商共建共享，打造“一带一路”示范区。二是坚持共谋发展，打造全球发展倡议先行区。三是坚持和衷共济，打造全球安全倡议实验区。四是坚持亚洲价值，打造全球文明倡议首善区。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;研讨会由中央外办、外交部共同举办。巴基斯坦参议院主席桑吉拉尼、蒙古国总理奥云额尔登、尼泊尔总理普拉昌达、柬埔寨副首相孙占托、日本前首相福田康夫、韩国前总理李海瓒、吉尔吉斯斯坦前总理博罗诺夫、上海合作组织秘书长张明等以线下或线上方式出席。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;开幕式前，王毅集体会见了出席研讨会的外方嘉宾。各方表示，面对当前地缘政治、应对气变、卫生环境等各种全球性挑战，周边国家更需要加强团结合作。各国愿同中国一道，坚持睦邻友好、互利共赢，共同维护地区和平稳定和发展繁荣。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;研讨会当日还发布了《新时代中国的周边外交政策展望》文件。 &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 统筹推进履约监管与资源可持续利用]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/25/nw.D110000renmrb_20231025_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月25日星期三&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;国务院新闻办公室24日发布《中国的远洋渔业发展》白皮书，全面介绍了中国远洋渔业的发展理念、原则立场、政策主张和履约成效，分享中国远洋渔业管理经验，促进远洋渔业国际合作与交流。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国是世界渔业大国。中国远洋渔业发展情况、重点监管措施和成效如何？如何强化科技支撑？中国远洋渔业对世界渔业有哪些贡献？记者采访了有关负责人和专家，详解公众关心的问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;中国统筹推进资源养护和可持续利用&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白皮书指出，中国坚持在发展中保护、在保护中发展，实施公海自主休渔等重要举措，不断强化渔业资源养护，加强生态系统管理，重点关注气候变化与生物多样性养护，推进渔业资源长期可持续利用取得显著成效。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国政府采取了比区域渔业管理组织更为严格的措施。”上海海洋大学教授刘小兵举例说，中国政府决定自2024年起所有中国远洋渔船必须每天报送电子渔捞日志。这一措施比大西洋、印度洋和东太平洋的渔捞日志年报的区域管理措施更为严格，有利于获得实时的渔船生产信息，及时了解捕捞配额/限额使用情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上海海洋大学海洋科学学院院长陈新军说，为了确保公海鱿鱼资源的可持续利用和科学开发，中国政府对三个国际上没有国际组织管理的公海鱿鱼作业海域进行了自主休渔制度，这是中国政府负责任捕捞的体现和担当。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据了解，中方远洋渔业作业海域中，所有目前尚无区域性渔业管理组织的公海海域均已纳入自主休渔范围。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;中国严格实施远洋渔业监管&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;强化远洋渔业科技支撑&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国远洋渔业的持续发展与不断强化的监管措施密不可分。中国渔业主管部门不断强化监管、完善机制、提升能力，促进远洋渔业持续健康发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国远洋渔业协会会长张显良说，中国实施全球最严格的远洋渔船船位监控措施；从2020年开始全面实施远洋渔业公海转载自主监管，落实所有公海转载活动提前申报和事后报告程序，为公海转载运输船逐步配备观察员或安装视频监控系统；严格实施水产品进出口监管，积极履行市场国义务；建立远洋渔业企业履约评估制度，对远洋渔业企业捕捞活动实施严格监管，坚持对违规行为“零容忍”，积极采取立法、行政等措施打击违规捕捞行为，规范企业生产经营活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白皮书指出，中国通过开展公海渔业资源科学调查、参与区域渔业管理组织相关研究、改善升级渔船和捕捞装备等举措，不断加强科技创新，促进渔业提质增效、转型升级和高质量发展。《“十四五”全国渔业发展规划》提出，渔业科技进步贡献率努力从2020年的63%提高到2025年的67%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈新军说，科学研究是渔业管理决策和渔业治理的基础。我国开展了公海鱿鱼资源评估、鱿钓渔业观察员覆盖率、鱿钓渔业捕捞努力量等方面的研究工作，为公海渔业治理贡献中国智慧和中国方案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们将信息技术、人工智能等现代新技术、新成果应用于公海渔业治理。研发、推广电子渔捞日志系统。”陈新军说，截至2022年底，600多艘鱿钓渔船安装了电子渔捞日志系统并试运行，实现了生产数据从大洋到陆地的实时传输，极大提高了履约能力和时效；研发电子监控系统并开展了船端测试，为“电子观察员”登临远洋鱿钓渔船打下了基础。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;深化国际渔业合作&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;推动全球渔业可持续发展&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国渔业发展极大促进了国际交流与合作。据统计，2022年中国水产品进出口总量1023万吨，总额467亿美元，进出口总额再创历史最高，与200多个国家和地区有水产贸易往来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白皮书说，“十四五”期间及今后一段时期，中国将继续以推动远洋渔业全产业链集聚发展，健全远洋渔业发展支撑体系，提升远洋渔业综合治理能力，加大远洋渔业发展保障力度为重点任务，通过优化产业结构，强化科技支撑，提升监管能力，深入参与国际渔业治理，完善政策体系，努力实现远洋渔业高质量发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张显良说，中国渔业发展对全球渔业资源科学养护和可持续利用作出了重要贡献。中国积极发展水产养殖，同时，大力实施减船转产，全面实施海洋渔业资源总量管理制度，实现内陆七大流域、四大海域休禁渔制度全覆盖，实施长江“十年禁渔”，建设海洋牧场和水生生物保护区，养护水生生物资源和生态系统，保护濒危物种，维护世界水生生物多样性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张显良说，经过30多年的发展，中国远洋渔业取得了令人瞩目的发展成就。未来，中国远洋渔业将继续坚持绿色可持续发展道路，优化产业结构，推进转型升级，提高质量效益，严控发展规模，强化规范管理，打击非法捕捞，致力于科学养护和可持续利用渔业资源，努力实现远洋渔业高质量发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（新华社北京10月24日电）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 25 Oct 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>