<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 坚定不移走中国特色社会主义妇女发展道路 组织动员广大妇女为中国式现代化建设贡献巾帼力量]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/31/nw.D110000renmrb_20231031_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, October 31, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-10/31/01/rmrb2023103101p24_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;October 30, CCP Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, President of the State, and Chairman of the Central Military Commission, held a collective conversation with members of the new leadership team of the All-China Women&#39;s Federation in Zhongnanhai and delivered an important speech. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Ju Peng&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;■&amp;nbsp;Comprehensive advancement of modernization in Chinese style The great cause of building a strong country and rejuvenating the nation requires the united struggle of all people, and the role of women is irreplaceable. We must unswervingly follow the path of socialist women&#39;s development with Chinese characteristics, encourage women to have self-esteem, self-confidence, self-reliance and self-reliance, forge ahead on a new journey, build a new era, and contribute women&#39;s wisdom and strength to Chinese-style modernization&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■&amp;nbsp; Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the Party Central Committee has comprehensively strengthened its leadership on women&#39;s work, promoted the reform of the Women&#39;s Federation, continuously improved the legal system for the protection of women&#39;s rights and interests, continued to optimize the development environment for women, and promoted historic achievements in women&#39;s causes. In the past five years, women&#39;s federations at all levels have conscientiously implemented the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, effectively fulfilled their responsibilities of leadership, service, and contact, and mobilized and organized women to promote high-quality development, win a decisive victory in building a moderately prosperous society in all respects, fight against poverty, fight against the COVID-19 epidemic, and promote science and technology. We have fought bravely on the main battlefields of innovation and rural revitalization, innovatively promoted the construction of family education and family tradition, provided rights protection and care services with heart and soul, continued to deepen the reform of the Women&#39;s Federation, continuously enhanced its political nature, advanced nature, and mass character, and further played its role as a bridge and link. The Party Central Committee fully affirms the work of the Women&#39;s Federation and has high expectations for the new leadership of the All-China Women&#39;s Federation&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■&amp;nbsp;Women&#39;s cause and the work of the Women&#39;s Federation must always adhere to the correct political direction and work together with the Party. We must uphold the party&#39;s overall leadership, resolutely safeguard the authority and centralized and unified leadership of the Party Central Committee, and always maintain a high degree of consistency with the Party Central Committee. We must always maintain political sobriety and determination, firmly grasp the political nature of my country&#39;s women&#39;s cause and the political positioning of women&#39;s federations, strengthen women&#39;s ideological and political guidance, and persist in using the thoughts of socialism with Chinese characteristics for a new era to guide the majority of women. Unswervingly listen to the Party and follow the Party&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■&amp;nbsp;We must closely focus on implementing the strategic deployment of the 20th National Congress of the Party, identify the focus of work, and translate the decisions and deployments of the Party Central Committee into the work of the Women&#39;s Federation specific tasks. It is necessary to encourage women to play their own advantages and active roles in implementing new development concepts, building a new development pattern, promoting high-quality development, achieving high-level scientific and technological self-reliance, and comprehensively promoting rural revitalization&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■&amp;nbsp;Family Harmony , With good family education and correct family traditions, children can grow up healthily and society can develop healthily. Doing a good job in women&#39;s work is not only related to women&#39;s own development, but also related to family harmony, social harmony, national development and national progress. It is necessary to tell good family tradition stories, guide women to play their unique role in carrying forward the traditional virtues of the Chinese nation, establish good family traditions, and create a new trend of family civilization. It is necessary to actively cultivate a new culture of marriage and childbearing, strengthen guidance on young people&#39;s views on marriage, childbirth, and family, promote the improvement and implementation of fertility support policies, improve the quality of population development, and actively respond to the aging population&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■&amp;nbsp ; Protecting the legitimate rights and interests of women and children, promoting equality between men and women, and the all-round development of women and children are important elements of Chinese modernization. Women&#39;s federations at all levels should take proactive actions and strive to solve outstanding problems that affect and infringe on the rights and interests of women and children. It is necessary to care for and assist low-income women, elderly women, disabled women and other women in need, and cooperate with relevant departments to provide caring services for migrant children and left-behind children. The work of safeguarding the rights and interests of women and children must be done on a daily basis, on a regular basis, and at the grassroots level&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■&amp;nbsp;The Women&#39;s Federation is the bridge between the party and the government and the women. We must focus on maintaining and enhancing the political, advanced and mass nature of the Women&#39;s Federation, continue to deepen the organizational reform of the Women&#39;s Federation, focus on making up for shortcomings, strengthen weak areas, lay the foundation and increase vitality, and comprehensively strengthen the construction of the Women&#39;s Federation Party. It is necessary to establish a clear direction of focusing on the grassroots, conduct in-depth investigations and studies, understand the thoughts and expectations of grassroots women and the urgent needs of women&#39;s work, and promote more resources and services to be tilted towards the grassroots. It is necessary to increase efforts to establish women&#39;s federation organizations in new fields such as new economic organizations, new social organizations, and new employment groups to achieve full coverage, follow the online mass line, and consolidate the women&#39;s mass foundation for the party&#39;s governance. It is necessary to strengthen the construction of a team of high-quality and professional women&#39;s federation cadres, and continuously enhance the ability to promote the high-quality development of women&#39;s causes, serve the broad masses of women, and prevent and resolve risks in the women&#39;s field&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■&amp;nbsp;Party committees at all levels must adhere to the party&#39;s management of women Working principles, implement the basic national policy of gender equality, strengthen leadership over the work of the Women&#39;s Federation, promptly study and solve important issues in the work of the Women&#39;s Federation, and provide support and create conditions for the Women&#39;s Federation to carry out its work. The women and children working committees of governments at all levels must effectively play their functional roles, strengthen organization, coordination, guidance and supervision, and implement the various decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee on the development of women and children&#39;s undertakings&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency Beijing, October 30th Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, President of the State, and Chairman of the Central Military Commission, held a collective conversation with members of the new leadership team of the All-China Women&#39;s Federation in Zhongnanhai on the afternoon of the 30th and delivered an important speech. Xi Jinping emphasized that comprehensively promoting the construction of a strong country and the great cause of national rejuvenation through Chinese-style modernization requires the united struggle of all people, and the role of women is irreplaceable. We must unswervingly follow the path of socialist women&#39;s development with Chinese characteristics, encourage women to have self-esteem, self-confidence, self-reliance and self-improvement, forge ahead on a new journey, build a new era of success, and contribute women&#39;s wisdom and strength to China&#39;s modernization drive. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cai Qi, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and secretary of the Secretariat of the CPC Central Committee, participated in the collective conversation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping first said that since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the Party Central Committee has comprehensively strengthened its leadership on women&#39;s work, promoted the reform of the Women&#39;s Federation, continuously improved the legal system for the protection of women&#39;s rights and interests, continued to optimize the development environment for women, and promoted the achievements of women&#39;s causes. A historic achievement. In the past five years, women&#39;s federations at all levels have conscientiously implemented the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, effectively fulfilled their responsibilities of leadership, service, and contact, and mobilized and organized women to promote high-quality development, win a decisive victory in building a moderately prosperous society in all respects, fight against poverty, fight against the COVID-19 epidemic, and promote science and technology. We have fought bravely on the main battlefields of innovation and rural revitalization, innovatively promoted the construction of family education and family tradition, provided rights protection and care services with heart and soul, continued to deepen the reform of the Women&#39;s Federation, continuously enhanced its political nature, advanced nature, and mass character, and further played its role as a bridge and link. The Party Central Committee fully affirms the work of the Women&#39;s Federation and has high expectations for the new leadership team of the All-China Women&#39;s Federation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that women’s causes and the work of the Women’s Federation must always adhere to the correct political direction and work together with the party. We must uphold the party&#39;s overall leadership, resolutely safeguard the authority and centralized and unified leadership of the Party Central Committee, and always maintain a high degree of consistency with the Party Central Committee. We must always maintain political sobriety and determination, firmly grasp the political nature of my country&#39;s women&#39;s cause and the political positioning of women&#39;s federations, strengthen women&#39;s ideological and political guidance, and persist in using the thoughts of socialism with Chinese characteristics for a new era to guide the majority of women. Unswervingly listen to and follow the Party. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that it is necessary to closely focus on the implementation of the strategic deployment of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, identify the focus of work, and translate the decisions and deployments of the Party Central Committee into specific tasks for the work of the Women&#39;s Federation. It is necessary to encourage women to play their own advantages and active roles in implementing new development concepts, building a new development pattern, promoting high-quality development, achieving high-level scientific and technological self-reliance, and comprehensively promoting rural revitalization. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that only by having a harmonious family, good upbringing, and a correct family tradition can children grow up healthily and society develop healthily. Doing a good job in women&#39;s work is not only related to women&#39;s own development, but also related to family harmony, social harmony, national development and national progress. It is necessary to tell good family tradition stories, guide women to play their unique role in carrying forward the traditional virtues of the Chinese nation, establish good family traditions, and create a new trend of family civilization. It is necessary to actively cultivate a new culture of marriage and childbearing, strengthen guidance on young people&#39;s views on marriage, childbirth, and family, promote the improvement and implementation of fertility support policies, improve the quality of population development, and actively respond to the aging of the population. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that protecting the legitimate rights and interests of women and children, promoting equality between men and women, and the all-round development of women and children are important contents of Chinese-style modernization. Women&#39;s federations at all levels should take proactive actions and strive to solve outstanding problems that affect and infringe on the rights and interests of women and children. It is necessary to care for and assist low-income women, elderly women, disabled women and other women in need, and cooperate with relevant departments to provide caring services for migrant children and left-behind children. The work of safeguarding the rights and interests of women and children must be done on a daily basis, on a regular basis, and at the grassroots level. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that the Women&#39;s Federation is a bridge between the party and the government and the women. We must focus on maintaining and enhancing the political, advanced and mass nature of the Women&#39;s Federation, continue to deepen the organizational reform of the Women&#39;s Federation, focus on making up for shortcomings, strengthen weak areas, lay the foundation and increase vitality, and comprehensively strengthen the construction of the Women&#39;s Federation Party. It is necessary to establish a clear direction of focusing on the grassroots, conduct in-depth investigations and studies, understand the thoughts and expectations of grassroots women and the urgent needs of women&#39;s work, and promote more resources and services to be tilted towards the grassroots. It is necessary to increase efforts to establish women&#39;s federation organizations in new fields such as new economic organizations, new social organizations, and new employment groups to achieve full coverage, follow the online mass line, and consolidate the women&#39;s mass foundation for the party&#39;s governance. It is necessary to strengthen the construction of a team of high-quality and professional women&#39;s federation cadres, and continuously enhance the ability to promote high-quality development of women&#39;s causes, serve the broad masses of women, and prevent and resolve risks in the women&#39;s field. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that party committees at all levels must adhere to the principle of party management of women&#39;s work, implement the basic national policy of gender equality, strengthen leadership over the work of the Women&#39;s Federation, promptly study and solve important issues in the work of the Women&#39;s Federation, and provide information for the Women&#39;s Federation to carry out their work. Support and create conditions. The women and children working committees of governments at all levels must effectively play their functional roles, strengthen organization, coordination, guidance and supervision, and implement various decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee on the development of women and children&#39;s undertakings. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;On behalf of the new leadership team of the All-China Women&#39;s Federation, Chen Yiqin, Chairman of the All-China Women&#39;s Federation, reported on the relevant situation of the 13th China Women&#39;s Congress and the considerations for the next step. Vice-chairmen of the All-China Women&#39;s Federation Huang Xiaowei, Meng Man and Wang Yaping made speeches. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Shi Taifeng, Li Ganjie, Li Shulei, Chen Wenqing and Liu Jinguo participated in the conversation. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 05:56:09 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 第三季度规上工业企业利润同比增7.7%（新数据 新看点）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/31/nw.D110000renmrb_20231031_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, October 31, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, October 30th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Liu Zhiqiang and Wang Yunshan) The National Bureau of Statistics recently released data showing that In the third quarter, the profits of industrial enterprises nationwide increased by 7.7% year-on-year, showing an accelerating recovery trend. Since the beginning of this year, profits of industrial enterprises above designated size have rebounded quarter by quarter. In September, the profits of industrial enterprises nationwide increased by 11.9% year-on-year, achieving double-digit growth for two consecutive months. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;As market demand continues to recover, the prices of industrial products have gradually recovered, and the revenue of industrial enterprises has improved significantly. In the first three quarters, the operating income of industrial enterprises above designated size was flat year-on-year, and the growth rate increased by 0.4 and 0.5 percentage points respectively from the first half of the year and the first quarter. Among them, the operating income of industrial enterprises above designated size increased by 0.3% year-on-year in the third quarter. Looking at the monthly basis, the operating income of industrial enterprises above designated size increased by 1.2% year-on-year in September, increasing for two consecutive months, and the growth rate accelerated by 0.4 percentage points compared with August. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In the third quarter, manufacturing profits increased by 11.8% year-on-year; profits from the electricity, heat, gas and water production and supply industry increased by 44.5% year-on-year, and the growth rate accelerated by 10.6 percentage points from the second quarter. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Benefiting from factors such as the continued recovery of the economy and the continued effects of policies to expand domestic demand, consumer demand continues to pick up, and profits in the consumer goods industry have improved significantly. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 05:56:09 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 以新气象新作为推动高质量发展取得新成效]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/31/nw.D110000renmrb_20231031_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, October 31, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Strengthening in response to challenges will further demonstrate the resilience of China&#39;s development; moving forward in the wind and rain, we must especially take advantage of the situation. determination. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;At the reception celebrating the 74th anniversary of the founding of the People&#39;s Republic of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized the need to &quot;strive to increase macro-control, expand domestic effective demand, stimulate the vitality of business entities, and continuously promote the continued improvement of economic operations. Endogenous power continues to strengthen, social expectations continue to improve, we must effectively prevent and resolve major risks, and strive to achieve the economic and social development goals for the year.&quot; This has pointed out the direction of our efforts and provided important guidelines for our current economic work. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Since the beginning of this year, in the face of the stormy international environment and the arduous and arduous tasks of domestic reform, development and stability, the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core has united and led hundreds of millions of people to face the difficulties and advance despite them. , my country&#39;s economy has generally recovered and is improving, laying a good foundation for achieving the annual economic and social development goals. However, we must also be soberly aware that the world economic recovery lacks momentum and domestic cyclical structural contradictions are intertwined and superimposed. The economic recovery after the epidemic prevention and control has stabilized is a process of wave-like development and tortuous progress. The more we climb uphill and overcome difficulties, the more we must firm up our confidence and determination, maintain the persistence of &quot;holding firm on the green mountain and never let go&quot;, strengthen the determination of &quot;still calmly flying through the chaotic clouds&quot;, and inspire &quot;the more difficult and dangerous it is, the more we move forward&quot; &quot;Entertainment and strive to achieve the annual economic and social development goals. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;We have the foundation to achieve the annual economic and social development goals. When observing China&#39;s economy, we must not only look at the &quot;shape&quot; of short-term fluctuations, but also the &quot;trend&quot; of long-term development. Since the beginning of this year, some indicators in economic operation have experienced short-term fluctuations, but macroeconomic policies have taken the lead and coordinated efforts, and the overall recovery trend of economic recovery has become more obvious. People&#39;s lives continue to improve, and the overall social situation remains stable. Facts have proved that the economy always operates in fluctuations. We must not only see short-term fluctuations and take effective measures to continuously promote the continued improvement of economic operations, but also correctly understand that the long-term positive development trend of our economy has not changed, seize strategic opportunities, and accelerate Build a new development pattern, continuously strengthen our country&#39;s economic strength, scientific and technological strength, and comprehensive national strength, and enhance our country&#39;s viability, competitiveness, development, and sustainability. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;We are confident to achieve the annual economic and social development goals. To observe the Chinese economy, we must not only read the &quot;surface&quot; of current profits and losses, but also the &quot;inside&quot; of endogenous driving forces. Overcoming the impact of natural disasters such as the rare &quot;bad rain&quot; in the Huanghuai River, my country&#39;s grain production is expected to have another bumper harvest throughout the year; despite the lack of momentum for world economic recovery, my country&#39;s economic growth has stabilized and rebounded, and the growth rate ranks among the best among major economies; facing the energy crisis and other global challenges, our country has built the world&#39;s largest power supply system and clean power generation system...to better coordinate domestic and international situations, to better coordinate epidemic prevention and control and economic and social development, to better coordinate development and security, my country&#39;s innovation Momentum continues to increase, high-quality development is solidly advanced, and the economy&#39;s ability to withstand stress and risks is stronger. From its incremental scale and trade scale to its contribution to carbon reduction and science and technology, China&#39;s economy remains the &quot;ballast&quot; for world economic growth, the &quot;engine&quot; for global innovation and prosperity, and the &quot;booster&quot; for win-win cooperation among all countries. Facing the future, we must focus closely on the primary task of high-quality development and the strategic task of building a new development pattern, continue to consolidate the good momentum of economic recovery with greater intensity and more practical measures, and promote high-quality development with new atmosphere and new actions. Achieve new results. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;We have the conditions to achieve the annual economic and social development goals. Institutional advantages provide the confidence for China&#39;s economy to overcome difficulties. Since the beginning of this year, from the release of plans to stabilize growth in 10 key industries, to the acceleration of the implementation of 31 policies and 28 measures to promote the development and growth of the private economy, to the continuation, optimization and improvement of a number of tax and fee reduction related policies... Macroeconomic policies It is powerful and effective in promoting the continuous recovery of my country&#39;s economic operation, and the accumulation of positive factors has increased. At present, there are many tools in my country&#39;s policy &quot;toolbox&quot;. We must make good use of policy space, find the right direction, organically combine the implementation of the strategy of expanding domestic demand with deepening supply-side structural reform, continue to deepen reform and opening up, and effectively prevent and resolve risks in key areas. We will surely be able to continue to promote the continued improvement of economic performance, the continuous enhancement of endogenous power, the continuous improvement of social expectations, and the continuous resolution of hidden risks, so as to promote the effective improvement of the quality of the economy and reasonable growth of the quantity. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: &quot;On the new journey, our future is bright, but the road under our feet will not be smooth.&quot; There is only struggle in the long journey. Unite more closely around the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core, fully implement Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, unify thoughts and actions with the Party Central Committee’s analysis and judgment on the economic situation, and implement the Party Central Committee to the letter By making decisions and arrangements, maintaining strategic focus, strengthening confidence and determination, working together in the same boat, and uniting as one, we will be able to make a good start in building a modern socialist country in an all-round way with new results in high-quality development. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 05:56:09 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 韩正会见美国飞虎队代表团]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/31/nw.D110000renmrb_20231031_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, October 31, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 30 (Reporter Zhu Chao) Vice President Han Zheng was in Beijing on the 30th Met with the American Flying Tigers delegation. Han Zheng said that President Xi Jinping recently personally responded to a letter from the chairman of the US-China Aviation Heritage Foundation and a veteran of the Flying Tigers. The Chinese people will always remember the heroic deeds of the Flying Tigers and will never forget their old friends. More than 80 years ago, China and the United States fought side by side to fight fascism. The story of the Flying Tigers carries the profound friendship forged with the lives and blood of the two peoples. Many major challenges in today&#39;s world still require cooperation between China and the United States to face them together. The two countries should adhere to mutual respect, peaceful coexistence and win-win cooperation, and make greater contributions to world peace and development. I hope the spirit of the Flying Tigers can be passed down from generation to generation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Green, chairman of the U.S.-China Aviation Heritage Foundation, and Flying Tigers veterans Moyer and McMullen said they were very honored to receive President Xi Jinping’s reply letter and visit China, and would be committed to inheriting and carrying forward the Flying Tigers. spirit and enhance the friendship between the people of the United States and China. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 05:56:09 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 黑龙江奋力开创高质量发展新局面（高质量发展调研行）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/31/nw.D110000renmrb_20231031_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, October 31, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;On both sides of the Songhua River, there are thousands of miles of fertile fields and golden land. Heilongjiang welcomes another bumper grain harvest. In recent years, Heilongjiang&#39;s annual grain output has stabilized at more than 150 billion jin, and its three major indicators of total output, commodity volume, and transfer volume rank first in the country. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Heavy machine tools roar, precision instruments operate, innovation vitality bursts, and old industrial bases glow with new vitality. The &quot;Guohe No. 1&quot; nuclear reactor pressure vessels participated in the research and development by China First Heavy Industry Group Co., Ltd. were all independently designed and manufactured locally. The world&#39;s largest single-unit capacity of one million kilowatt hydroelectric generator set, which Harbin Electric Group Co., Ltd. participated in the development of, is at the Baihetan Hydropower Station. Successful operation...Technological innovation leads Heilongjiang to accelerate its revitalization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In September this year, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized during an inspection in Heilongjiang that we must firmly grasp the strategic positioning in the overall development of the country, grasp the primary task of promoting high-quality development, and implement the Party Central Committee’s instructions on promoting Northeast China Decision-making and deployment of comprehensive revitalization, utilizing strengths to offset weaknesses, transforming resource advantages, ecological advantages, scientific research advantages, industrial advantages, and location advantages into new momentum and new advantages for development, and building and strengthening the country&#39;s important commodity grain production base, heavy equipment production and manufacturing base, and important Energy and raw material base, northern ecological security barrier, and new highland for opening up to the north, actively perform their duties in safeguarding national defense security, food security, ecological security, energy security, and industrial security, and strive to create Heilongjiang in the comprehensive revitalization and all-round revitalization. A new situation of high-quality development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Keeping in mind General Secretary Xi Jinping’s earnest instructions, the cadres and masses of Heilongjiang work together to forge ahead and strive to create a new situation of high-quality development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Science and technology innovation cluster activates new momentum for development&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the sound of operation, the first hydraulic press forging plant of China First Heavy Industry Group Co., Ltd. independently developed and manufactured in China The 15,000-ton free forging hydraulic press started working, and the surface temperature of the circular forging reached more than 1,200 degrees Celsius... In the past 70 years, China First Heavy Industry Group Co., Ltd. has developed a total of 421 new products, filling 475 domestic industrial product technology gaps. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Heilongjiang strives to put the basis of revitalization and development on innovation. In the past five years, the province&#39;s R&amp;D investment has increased at an average annual rate of 5%, and the turnover of technology contracts has increased at an average annual rate of 28.5%. In the first half of this year, the province realized the transformation of 278 new major scientific and technological achievements, generating economic benefits of approximately 3.04 billion yuan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In June this year, my country&#39;s first flat-panel new system low-orbit broadband communication test satellite &quot;Longjiang-3&quot; was successfully launched. &quot;Longjiang-3&quot; was jointly developed by Harbin Institute of Technology and Harbin Institute of Technology Satellite Technology Co., Ltd., and broke through key technologies such as regenerative low-orbit satellite-to-ground high-speed communications and flat-panel satellite platforms. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Harbin Institute of Technology Satellite Technology Co., Ltd. is a satellite manufacturing enterprise incubated by Harbin Institute of Technology and located in Harbin New District. More than 40 companies related to the space and satellite field have gathered here, driving the rapid development of the satellite industry chain. &quot;Using the role of technological innovation as an incrementer, we are fully committed to building a satellite industry cluster in Heilongjiang Province.&quot; said Shao Gang, a member of the Party Working Committee of Harbin New District. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The number of state-certified high-tech enterprises in Heilongjiang has increased from 929 in 2017 to the current 3,605. Last year, the revenue of five strategic emerging industries including aerospace, electronic information manufacturing, and new materials all achieved double-digit growth. In the first half of this year, the added value of the aerospace vehicle and equipment manufacturing industry increased by 24.2%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Innovation empowers, and the advantages of traditional industries continue to be consolidated. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the &quot;Heilongjiang Province Digital (Intelligent) Demonstration Workshop&quot; of Harbin Xinha Precision Bearing Co., Ltd., intelligent high-speed bearing production lines, automatic adjustment electrical systems, CNC machine tools and other intelligent equipment are all available. “New product R&amp;D and design all use digital tools, and the digitalization rate reaches 100%.” said Zhang Li, the person in charge of the company. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Currently, Heilongjiang Province has certified 279 provincial-level digital (intelligent) demonstration workshops and smart factories. In Xiangfang District, Harbin City, an old industrial area, the added value of industrial enterprises above designated size increased by 9.2% year-on-year in the first half of this year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Modern agriculture cultivates new competitive advantages&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the golden autumn, 531,000 acres of rice in Fujin City have gradually entered the mature harvest period. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fujin Chang&#39;an Town is a typical low-lying town that is prone to waterlogging all year round. “This year’s harvest will be great, and the rice yield per mu can reach 1,000 kilograms.” Liu Chun, a villager in Dongbei Village, Chang’an Town, said that this is due to the construction of high-standard farmland and the repair of “sewers”, which can be irrigated during droughts and drained during floods. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hide food in the ground, and hide food in technology. Heilongjiang Province has built more than 100 million acres of high-standard farmland, and the province&#39;s comprehensive mechanization rate for crop cultivation and harvesting has stabilized at over 98%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With full pods, soybeans in Hailun City, Suihua City are ushering in a bumper harvest. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Only by strengthening the ‘seed chip’ can we secure the ‘Chinese rice bowl’.” In the test field of the Hailun Agricultural Ecological Experiment Station of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, scientific researcher Li Yanhua has been engaged in soybean breeding research in cold black soil areas for more than 30 years. 17 new varieties of the &quot;Dongsheng&quot; series have been introduced, which have been promoted to a total of 50 million acres, increasing production by 2 billion jin, and increasing benefits by 4 billion yuan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, Heilongjiang has vigorously implemented seed industry revitalization actions, built a national-level cold-land crop germplasm resource bank, launched the construction of a national-level soybean seed base, and has reached 19 national seed-producing counties and regional improved seed breeding bases. , and built 16 expert breeding bases. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Yi&#39;an County, Qiqihar City, Shang Wenhui, general manager of North Latitude 47 Green Organic Food Co., Ltd., said that the company produced more than 100,000 tons of fresh corn last year, with an output value of about 180 million yuan. &quot;This year, we have planted more than 250,000 acres of fresh corn, providing 4,500 jobs for farmers, which can increase income by about 60 million yuan.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Small corn has become a big industry, reflecting the large agricultural base of Heilongjiang , large enterprises and large industries are accelerating their development. At present, the number of designated agricultural product processing enterprises in the province has grown to 2,045, and the agricultural product processing conversion rate has reached 65%. The provincial-level high-quality agricultural brand &quot;Black Soil Premium&quot; has gone nationwide. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Vigorously promote the high-quality development of agriculture, the province strives to cultivate and expand advantageous industries such as high-quality grain, modern animal husbandry, forest food, cold area fruits and vegetables, cold-water fisheries and specialty agriculture, and strives to create a pioneer in practicing the big food concept Land.&quot; said Li Wende, deputy director of the Heilongjiang Provincial Department of Agriculture and Rural Affairs. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Green development highlights a beautiful new look&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Standing at the observation deck of Feicui Lake Mine Forest Park, Baoqing County, Shuangyashan City, you can see that the oval lake is like a star. Blue gems are embedded in the forest. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This used to be an abandoned open-pit mine.” Zhao Zhenping, deputy director of the Natural Resources Bureau of Baoqing County, said that the county has promoted the implementation of mine restoration projects and restored green water through dangerous rock cleaning, soil reconstruction, and vegetation restoration. The original appearance of Qingshan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The abandoned mine has been transformed into a forest park and has become an emerging country tourism and vacation destination integrating wedding photography base, impression light show, wild camping and other functions. Since its opening to the public in October last year, the park has received tens of thousands of tourists and generated tourism revenue of 12 million yuan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Heilongjiang Province has resolutely built an ecological security barrier in the north of the motherland, coordinated and promoted the management of mountains, rivers, forests, farmlands, lakes, grass and sand systems, and created a total of 6.357 million acres of forest in the past five years. In 2022, 12,000 sewage outlets into rivers and lakes will be renovated, and the proportion of days with excellent air quality in the province will reach 95.9%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In autumn, the forest sea in Daxing&#39;an Mountains is dyed in layers. In Jianan Village, Jiagedaqi District, Daxinganling Region, villager Li Wei returned to his hometown to establish a professional cooperative for the cultivation of traditional Chinese medicinal materials. He transferred more than 5,000 acres of land and built a provincial-level breeding base for improved varieties of traditional Chinese medicinal materials. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Planting more than 30 varieties such as red peony root and saposhnikovia, etc., has made Jianan Village a famous flower sea check-in place.” Li Wei has the determination and confidence to promote the integration of medicine and tourism. “The cooperative employs more than The number of tourists exceeded 20,000, and the per capita monthly income was more than 4,500 yuan; the Flower Sea sightseeing tour drove 60 villagers to sell agricultural and sideline products, and the per capita annual income increased by 20,000 yuan.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Accelerate the development of green energy and create &quot;Harbin-Daqi&quot; &quot;New energy industry belt; explore the establishment of an ecological product value realization mechanism, and promote the transformation of ecological product value pilot results in the Daxinganling... With large forests, prairie, large wetlands, large lakes, large boundary rivers, large ice and snow, Heilongjiang strives to achieve green development The road makes green mountains always exist, green water always flows, and the air always fresh. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 05:56:09 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 第三届世界华侨华人工商大会开幕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/31/nw.D110000renmrb_20231031_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, October 31, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, October 30 (Reporter Yang Hao) The Third World Overseas Chinese Business Conference Opening in Beijing on October 30th. Shi Taifeng, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and director of the United Front Work Department of the CPC Central Committee, attended the opening ceremony and delivered a speech. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Shi Taifeng pointed out that since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core has accurately grasped the general trend of domestic and international development, united and led the people across the country to overcome various risks and challenges, and China&#39;s economic and social development has achieved historic achievements. Historical changes have taken place and we have embarked on a new journey of comprehensively promoting the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation with Chinese-style modernization. Since the beginning of this year, in the face of a complex external environment, China has introduced a series of policies and measures to stabilize growth and promote the continued recovery of the national economy. Facts have proven that China&#39;s economy is highly resilient, has great potential, and is full of vitality, and its long-term positive fundamentals have not changed. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Shi Taifeng said that the vast number of Chinese businessmen have footprints all over the world and have strong economic strength, rich intellectual resources, extensive business networks, and deep personal connections. They are helping China promote high-quality development and build a new development pattern with high-level opening up to the outside world. has unique advantages. I hope that everyone will grasp the development trend of the times, comply with the requirements of the development situation, strengthen confidence in development, actively participate in Chinese-style modernization, promote high-quality joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, promote exchanges and mutual learning between Chinese and foreign civilizations, and strive to become a leader of the overseas Chinese business community in the new era. Outstanding representative. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Gao Yunlong, Vice Chairman of the National Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference and Chairman of the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce, attended the opening ceremony. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;This conference is co-sponsored by the Overseas Chinese Affairs Office of the State Council, the All-China Federation of Returned Overseas Chinese, and the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce. More than 400 overseas Chinese representatives from more than 100 countries and regions around the world attended. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 05:56:09 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 第十届北京香山论坛开幕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/31/nw.D110000renmrb_20231031_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, October 31, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, October 30th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Jin Zhengbo) The 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum on the 30th Opening at the Beijing International Convention Center. Zhang Youxia, Vice Chairman of the Central Military Commission, attended the opening ceremony and delivered a keynote speech. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Zhang Youxia said that the Chinese military looks forward to working with all parties to continue to deepen security mutual trust, jointly improve the security architecture, work together to strengthen security governance, pragmatically promote security cooperation, and implement global development initiatives and global security. Initiative and the Global Civilization Initiative to jointly build a community of human security and inject more certainty, stability and positive energy into a world intertwined with chaos. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Zhang Youxia said that in the face of a world intertwined with events, all countries share weal and woe and share risks. We must adhere to win-win cooperation and symbiosis to promote lasting peace, respect each other&#39;s sovereignty and territorial integrity, respect each other&#39;s core interests and major concerns, respect the development path and social system independently chosen by the people of each country, pay attention to and accommodate the legitimate concerns of all countries, and insist on adopting To resolve differences through dialogue and consultation, we must not impose our will on others, place our own interests above others, base our own security on the insecurity of others, let alone deliberately provoke other countries on major and sensitive issues. The Taiwan issue is at the core of China&#39;s core interests. The one-China principle is the general consensus of the international community. No matter who wants to separate Taiwan from China in any form, the Chinese military will never agree or show mercy. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Liu Zhenli, Chief of Staff of the Joint Staff Department of the Central Military Commission, attended the opening ceremony. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The theme of the 10th Beijing Xiangshan Forum is &quot;Common Security, Lasting Peace&quot;. There are 99 official delegations, defense ministers of 19 countries, military chiefs (commanders of national defense forces) of 14 countries, and representatives of 6 international organizations. More than 1,800 guests, including experts, scholars and observers from various countries, attended the event. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The forum welcome dinner was held in Beijing on the 29th. Zhang Youxia attended and delivered a speech. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 05:56:09 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 首届“一带一路”科技交流大会将在重庆举行（权威发布）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/31/nw.D110000renmrb_20231031_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, October 31, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;The first “Belt and Road” Science and Technology Exchange Conference will be held in Chongqing from November 6th to 7th. On October 30, the State Council Information Office held a press conference to introduce the relevant situation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The first &quot;Belt and Road&quot; science and technology exchange conference has the theme of &quot;jointly building a road to innovation and jointly promoting cooperative development&quot;, focusing on intergovernmental scientific and technological cooperation, scientific and cultural exchanges, industrial innovation and development, scientific research paradigm changes, and the future On topics such as medicine, open science and big data, there are five major sections and 10 main activities: the opening ceremony and plenary session, the “Belt and Road” Science and Technology Innovation Ministers’ Meeting, theme activities, roundtables and results presentations. The conference adheres to the Silk Road spirit of peace and cooperation, openness and inclusiveness, mutual learning, and mutual benefit. It will release important results reports, launch important measures to promote the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; scientific and technological innovation cooperation, and send out a common aspiration of open cooperation and joint development. . &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Vice Minister of Science and Technology Zhang Guangjun said that scientific and technological innovation, as a key force in promoting economic development, improving people&#39;s livelihood and responding to global challenges, is a key area in the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and a key direction of common concern for all countries. . It is hoped that by holding the first “Belt and Road” science and technology exchange conference, focusing on the action of “promoting scientific and technological innovation”, we can jointly review the progress and results of scientific and technological innovation cooperation with co-building countries, jointly explore the trends and directions of scientific and technological innovation development, and jointly discuss the promotion of the Silk Road of Innovation. Key measures for high-quality development. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Chongqing Vice Mayor Zhang Anjiang introduced that more than 300 foreign guests from more than 70 countries and international organizations have been invited to attend, including Nobel Prize winners, foreign academicians, experts and scholars, and presidents of well-known foreign universities. Nearly 40 people. At the same time, domestic academicians, university presidents, representatives of scientific research institutions, and key enterprises will also attend the conference to actively carry out in-depth all-round and multi-field exchanges. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In the 10 years since the “Belt and Road” initiative was proposed, what progress and results have been achieved in scientific and technological innovation cooperation? Zhang Guangjun introduced that with the joint participation and promotion of all parties, the scientific and technological cooperation mechanism has been continuously deepened over the past 10 years, the exchanges of scientific researchers have become closer, and the achievements of scientific and technological cooperation have become increasingly fruitful. Up to now, China has signed intergovernmental scientific and technological cooperation agreements with more than 80 co-building countries, jointly building an all-round, multi-level, and wide-ranging scientific and technological cooperation pattern, and yielding solid and heavy &quot;fruits&quot; of cooperation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In terms of jointly promoting people-to-people and cultural exchanges, China and co-building countries have deepened all-round scientific and technological exchanges. China has supported more than 10,000 young scientists from co-building countries to come to China for short-term work and exchanges; cumulative training has been provided to co-building countries in science and technology and 16,000 management personnel. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In terms of jointly improving scientific research capabilities, China and co-building countries have implemented many batches of joint research plans and jointly built more than 50 research institutions in agriculture, medical care, information, new energy, basic research and other fields. The “Belt and Road” joint laboratory has established 10 overseas science and education cooperation centers. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In terms of jointly serving the improvement of people&#39;s livelihood, China and co-building countries support the construction of a number of public health science and technology cooperation centers, agricultural technology demonstration centers, Juncao technology demonstration centers, mariculture research centers, and mountain disaster research centers. The cooperation platform has also implemented a number of &quot;small but beautiful&quot; cooperation projects to promote scientific and technological achievements and benefit more people. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;在共同支撑产业发展方面，中国与共建国家推进科技园区合作和多领域技术转移示范，中国面向东盟、阿拉伯国家、非洲等区域建设了9个跨国技术转移平台，与各国共建覆盖广泛的技术转移网络，服务各国产业升级。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;在共同助力文明传承方面，中国与共建国家开展联合考古和文物保护等科研合作，在探寻丝绸之路多元灿烂历史面貌的同时，展现出文明互鉴的和美诗篇。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;张广军表示，未来，中方期待与共建国家继续深入实施“一带一路”科技创新行动计划，以开放创新汇合作之力，以共商共建谋发展之路，共同促进更加开放包容、互惠共享的国际科技合作和交流。 &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 05:56:09 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 神十六飞船顺利撤离空间站组合体]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/31/nw.D110000renmrb_20231031_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月31日星期二&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报北京10月30日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者刘诗瑶、谷业凯）10月30日20时37分，神舟十六号载人飞船与空间站组合体成功分离。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;据中国载人航天工程办公室介绍，分离前，神舟十六号航天员乘组与神舟十七号航天员乘组开展了工作交接，完成了在轨工作经验交流、上行物资及下行样品转移安装等工作。分离后，神舟十六号航天员手持高清相机，通过飞船绕飞完成了以地球为背景的空间站组合体全景图像拍摄。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;后续，神舟十六号载人飞船返回舱将在地面指令控制下择机再入返回，在中国空间站出差的航天员景海鹏、朱杨柱、桂海潮即将踏上回家之旅。 &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 05:56:09 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 我国划定城镇开发边界]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/31/nw.D110000renmrb_20231031_5-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月31日星期二&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报北京10月30日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者常钦）记者从自然资源部获悉：根据“三区三线”划定工作的统一部署，各省（区、市）按照自上而下、自下而上相结合的工作方式，统筹划定了城市、镇以及各类开发区的城镇开发边界，倒逼各地节约集约利用资源，加大存量用地盘活力度，促进发展方式绿色转型。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;据介绍，划定过程坚持区域统筹，在优先划好划足耕地和永久基本农田保护红线、应划尽划生态保护红线的前提下，各省份按不超过2020年现状城镇建设用地总规模的1.3倍控制城镇开发边界范围，给予各省份统筹指导市县划定城镇开发边界的自主权。 &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 05:56:09 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 办好更加公平、更高质量的基础教育（政策解读）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/31/nw.D110000renmrb_20231031_6-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月31日星期二&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;建设教育强国，基点在基础教育。为切实办好更加公平、更高质量的基础教育，教育部、国家发展改革委、财政部联合印发《关于实施新时代基础教育扩优提质行动计划的意见》（以下简称《意见》）。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“《意见》致力于深化基础教育供给侧改革，进一步做大优质教育资源&#39;蛋糕&#39;，加快构建幼有优育、学有优教的高质量基础教育体系，解决优质教育资源总体不足与人民群众期望&#39;上好学&#39;的矛盾，增强人民群众教育获得感、幸福感、安全感。”教育部基础教育司司长田祖荫表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;深化基础教育供给侧改革&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;党的十八大以来，我国基础教育政策制度体系进一步健全，基础教育取得历史性成就，为实现“幼有所育、学有所教”“建成世界上规模最大的教育体系”“教育普及水平实现历史性跨越”发挥了重要作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022年，全国学前三年毛入园率89.7%，比2012年提高25.2个百分点，普惠性幼儿园覆盖率89.6%。九年义务教育巩固率达到95.5%，比2012年提高了3.7个百分点，适龄残疾儿童入学率超过95%。高中阶段教育毛入学率91.6%，比2012年提高6.6个百分点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前，我国基础教育普及水平总体达到世界中上行列，在此基础上，《意见》提出新的目标：到2027年，适应新型城镇化发展和学龄人口变化趋势的城乡中小学幼儿园学位供给调整机制基本建立，优质教育资源扩充机制更加健全，学前教育优质普惠、义务教育优质均衡、普通高中优质特色、特殊教育优质融合发展的格局基本形成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;具体而言，学前教育阶段，公办园在园幼儿占比力争达到60%以上；义务教育阶段，扩增一批新优质学校，优质学位供给大幅增加；高中教育阶段，培育一批优质特色高中，普通高中多样化发展扎实推进，高中阶段毛入学率持续提升；特殊教育方面，特教学校在20万人口以上的县基本实现全覆盖，适龄残疾儿童义务教育入学率保持在97%以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;扩大优质教育资源供给&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022年，广东省深圳市龙岗、坪山、光明区，9所高中学校拔地而起。面对公办普通高中学位短缺的难题，深圳实施大规模高中学校建设计划。一批现代化、高颜值的校园，成为深圳市一道亮丽的风景线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“2020年至2023年，全市共新改扩建41所公办普高、新增9万个公办普高学位，2023年全市普高录取率超过70%。未来两年，还将新增2万个以上公办普高学位，公办普高录取率将持续保持稳定。”深圳市教育局局长郑秀玉说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;深圳市不断加大投入力度、增加学位供给，是扩大优质教育资源供给、构建优质均衡基本公共教育服务体系的举措之一。为解决普通高中多样发展不充分、部分县中水平不高以及群众职普分流焦虑问题，通过加大投入力度“新建一批”、创新办学机制“帮扶一批”、多样化发展“提升一批”、有序增加招生计划“扩容一批”，促进普通高中内涵建设。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，在学前教育方面，《意见》主要解决学前教育保障机制不健全、优质普惠性资源不足问题，明确公办园公用经费标准，提出“各地公办园生均公用经费标准原则上应于2024年达到600元/年·人”。在义务教育方面，主要解决义务教育阶段优质教育资源总量不足、城乡校际差距大问题，制定区域优质学校成长发展规划，倾斜支持帮扶有一定基础的学校，办好“家门口”的每所学校。在特殊教育方面，鼓励20万人口以上的县办好一所达到标准的特殊教育学校，20万人口以下的县因地制宜设立特教班。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;提升基础教育育人水平&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;漆画挂上教学楼走廊，纸艺、绳艺成为拿手绝活，架子鼓队在舞台上绽放光彩……得益于上海实施的“新优质学校”项目，地处杨浦、宝山、虹口三区交界的三门中学，发展势头一年比一年好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“坚持回归教育本原，为了每一个学生的健康快乐成长，通过深度调研、案例解析、互动培训、交流分享、立体宣传，我们打造了100多所因材施教、百姓满意的家门口好学校。”上海市教委副主任杨振峰说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，我国基础教育质量稳步提升，德智体美劳五育并举大力推进，素质教育深入实施，课堂教学改革不断深化。部分省份连续几次参加国际学生评估项目（PISA）测试，阅读、数学、科学等科目成绩名列前茅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;提升教育质量，师资是重要因素。《意见》提出，实施高素质教师队伍建设行动，提高师资保障水平。田祖荫表示，“要完善义务教育学校教师&#39;县管校聘&#39;管理机制，立足学区内、集团内和城乡间为主实施骨干教师交流轮岗计划，加快实现县域内师资均衡配置；支持开展团队式交流，加快提升薄弱学校、农村学校办学水平；加强县域统筹，促进思想政治、科学、体育、艺术、心理健康等紧缺学科教师校际共享。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;提升教育质量，应以数字化赋能。《意见》要求，提升国家中小学智慧教育平台建设应用水平，完善国家基础教育管理服务平台。据了解，目前国家中小学智慧教育平台汇集了德育、课程教学、体育、美育、劳动教育、课后服务、家庭教育、教改等十多个板块，共53个栏目，资源总量达5.04万条。平台大幅提高了师生的信息素养，为优化教育资源配置发挥了重要作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据悉，教育部将指导地方明确责任分工，建立健全推进机制，确保各项要求落到实处。同时加强学龄人口变化预测前瞻性研究以及城乡学校布局合理性研究，不断提高工作科学化水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 31 Oct 2023 05:56:09 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>