<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/<item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平会见斯里兰卡总统维克拉马辛哈]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/21/nw.D110000renmrb_20231021_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, October 21, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-10/21/01/rmrb2023102101p25_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the morning of October 20, President Xi Jinping met at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing with Sri Lankan President Wickramasinghe, who was in China to attend the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Liu Weibing&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, October 20th&amp;nbsp ;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Wang Hailin) ​​On the morning of October 20, President Xi Jinping met at the Great Hall of the People with Sri Lankan President Wickremesinghe, who was in China to attend the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that the people of China and Sri Lanka have long-term friendship, learn from each other, help each other, and strengthen themselves through unity. Sri Lanka is one of the first countries to welcome and join the Belt and Road Initiative. China attaches great importance to the development of China-Sri Lanka relations and is willing to work with Sri Lanka to consolidate political mutual trust, jointly build the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; with high quality, promote China-Sri Lanka strategic cooperative partnership of sincere mutual assistance and ever-lasting friendship to continuously achieve new progress, and better benefit the two peoples. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that China firmly supports Sri Lanka in adhering to strategic independence and safeguarding national sovereignty, independence and national dignity. China is willing to expand imports of Sri Lanka&#39;s advantageous and characteristic products, encourage Chinese enterprises to invest and start businesses in Sri Lanka, and help Sri Lanka achieve economic transformation, upgrading and sustainable development. It hopes that Sri Lanka will provide an open and transparent business environment for Chinese enterprises. China is willing to continue to provide assistance to Sri Lanka without political strings attached to help Sri Lanka cope with the difficulties it faces in the field of social and people&#39;s livelihood. Both sides should make every effort to promote the Colombo Port City and Hambantota comprehensive development projects and turn them into flagship projects of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; jointly built by China and Sri Lanka. China is happy to see Sri Lanka become a commercial center in the Indian Ocean. The two sides must also strengthen coordination on international and regional affairs, oppose the politicization of human rights issues, oppose the creation of confrontation between camps, and safeguard the common interests of the two countries and developing countries. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Wickramasinghe expressed congratulations to China on successfully hosting the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. Sri Lanka has attached great importance to and actively participated in the joint construction of the “Belt and Road” from the beginning, and is optimistic about its potential and prospects. The joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, especially the &quot;21st Century Maritime Silk Road&quot;, has greatly promoted Sri Lanka&#39;s economic and social development and is conducive to enhancing Sri Lanka&#39;s unique influence in the region. Sri Lanka hopes to cooperate more closely with China in the future, and China can become Sri Lanka&#39;s realization An important partner in modernization. Sri Lanka firmly adheres to the one-China policy, hopes to learn from China&#39;s development experience, welcomes Chinese enterprises to invest in Sri Lanka, and is willing to provide a good business environment for this purpose. Sri Lanka believes that the Indian Ocean should be open. Sri Lanka is willing to strengthen communication with China in regional affairs and support unity and cooperation among developing countries. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cai Qi and Wang Yi attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 08:26:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平会见越南国家主席武文赏]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/21/nw.D110000renmrb_20231021_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, October 21, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-10/21/01/rmrb2023102101p24_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the morning of October 20, President Xi Jinping met at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing with President Vu Van Thang of Vietnam, who was in China to attend the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. &lt;BR/>;Photographed by Xinhua News Agency reporter Zhai Jianlan&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, October 20th&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;(Reporter Wang Hailin) ​​On the morning of October 20, President Xi Jinping met at the Great Hall of the People with President Vu Van Thang of Vietnam, who was in China to attend the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that China and Vietnam support each other in striving for their respective national liberation causes and have forged a profound friendship of &quot;comrades and brothers&quot;. Both China and Vietnam are advancing their respective socialist modernization causes, both regard China-Vietnam relations as the priority direction of their respective foreign policies, and both regard the other&#39;s development as an opportunity for their own development. Faced with the ever-changing international situation and the arduous and arduous domestic development tasks, the two countries must not forget the original intention of traditional friendship, keep in mind the common ideals and missions, work together to follow the path of socialism, build a community of shared future with strategic significance, and ensure that the relations between the two countries always move forward. On the fast track of mutual benefit, win-win and joint development. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that both China and Vietnam adhere to the people-centered development concept. The two sides must maintain strategic communication, learn from each other, and promote strategies for rejuvenating the country and a path to strengthening the country that are suitable for their own national conditions. Both sides should adhere to the principle of extensive consultation, joint contribution and shared benefits, give full play to the advantages of geographical proximity and industrial complementarity, accelerate the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative and the &quot;Two Corridors and One Ring&quot;, focus on promoting cooperation in strategic areas such as interconnection, and strengthen e-commerce and other areas. Cooperation in emerging areas, China is willing to continue to expand imports of high-quality Vietnamese products. The two sides should continue to bring closer the friendly feelings between the people and localities of the two countries, especially the younger generation, so that the traditional friendship between the two countries can be passed down from generation to generation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Wu Wenshang expressed his warm congratulations to China for successfully hosting the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. Representatives from more than 150 countries attended the forum, which fully reflected the international community’s affirmation and support for the “One Belt, One Road” initiative. After 10 years of development, the “Belt and Road” has become an open, inclusive, high-quality and important international cooperation platform, which has effectively promoted the development of countries and the friendship between peoples. President Xi Jinping&#39;s speech at the opening ceremony of the forum was far-sighted and included both strategic planning and specific measures. It demonstrated the responsibility of China&#39;s major party and country and will surely have an important impact on leading future international cooperation and global development. Vietnam admires the great achievements made by the Communist Party of China in theoretical and practical innovation. General Secretary Xi Jinping’s thoughts on state governance are very inspiring to the Vietnamese party and government. Vietnam has always regarded China&#39;s development as an opportunity, supported socialist China in continuing to grow and develop, and achieve its goal of becoming a powerful country as scheduled. It believes that China will make greater contributions to promoting world peace and development. Vietnam firmly adheres to the one-China policy and is willing to intensify high-level strategic communication with China, enhance the positioning of Vietnam-China relations, and continuously enrich the connotation of the Vietnam-China comprehensive strategic cooperative partnership under the new situation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cai Qi and Wang Yi attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 08:26:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平会见老挝人民革命党中央总书记、国家主席通伦]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/21/nw.D110000renmrb_20231021_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, October 21, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-10/21/01/rmrb2023102101p18_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the morning of October 20, General Secretary of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and President Xi Jinping met at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing with General Secretary of the Central Committee of the Lao People&#39;s Revolutionary Party and President Thongloun Sisoulith, who was in China to attend the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum and pay a working visit. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Liu Weibing&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, October 20th&amp;nbsp ;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Wang Hailin) ​​On the morning of October 20, General Secretary of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and President Xi Jinping met at the Great Hall of the People with the Central Committee of the Lao People&#39;s Revolutionary Party, who was in China to attend the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum and pay a working visit. General Secretary and President Thongloun Sisoulith. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that over the past 10 years, the construction of a community with a shared future between China and Laos has continued to make important progress. In the context of the intertwined chaos of today&#39;s world and the accelerating evolution of century-old changes, the construction of a China-Laos community with a shared future has more contemporary value and strategic significance, and has a positive demonstration and leadership role. China and Laos should start by signing a new five-year action plan to build a community with a shared future for China and Laos, give new connotation to the relations between the two parties and the two countries, and inject new momentum into regional and even world peace, stability, development and prosperity. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that adhering to the leadership of the party and adhering to the direction of socialism are the essential characteristics of China-Laos relations. The two parties of China and Laos should continue to deepen political mutual trust, improve governance capabilities, and strengthen communication and cooperation in the fields of politics, law enforcement, and security. It is necessary to deeply tap the potential of the China-Laos railway, focus on the development along the railway, steadily promote the construction of the China-Laos economic corridor, actively promote the concept of regional connectivity development, and create a model for &quot;Belt and Road&quot; cooperation in the region. China is willing to continue to provide assistance within its capacity to the economic development of Laos, encourage more Chinese companies to invest in Laos, import more high-quality agricultural products from Laos, and expand China-Laos cooperation in energy, mining and other fields. Laos will serve as the rotating chair of ASEAN next year, and China is willing to support Laos in playing a greater role in regional and international affairs. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Thongloun Sisoulith expressed congratulations to China for successfully hosting the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. This summit forum highlights the important results achieved by the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative in the past 10 years, especially Comrade General Secretary Xi Jinping The eight actions proposed to support the joint construction of the “Belt and Road” have injected new impetus into the high-quality construction of the “Belt and Road”. At present, cooperation between Laos and China in all aspects is progressing smoothly, and Laos sincerely thanks China for its long-term valuable assistance to Laos’ economic and social development. The completion and smooth operation of the Laos-China Railway have greatly promoted the economic development of Laos and brought positive changes to the lives of the Lao people. The new five-year action plan to build a community with a shared future between Laos and China to be signed this time will further consolidate the friendly cooperative relations between Laos and China and the two parties and countries. Laos is willing to strengthen high-level interactions with China, deepen exchanges of experience in state governance, promote practical cooperation such as the Laos-China Economic Corridor, strengthen coordination and cooperation on ASEAN-China relations and regional issues, and promote new development of Laos-China relations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;After the meeting, Xi Jinping and Thongloun Sisoulith jointly signed the &quot;Action Plan of the Communist Party of China and the Lao People&#39;s Revolutionary Party on Building a China-Laos Community with a Shared Future (2024-2028)&quot; and jointly witnessed the signing of the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; , digital economy, news, culture, tourism, health, customs inspection and quarantine and other fields. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cai Qi and Wang Yi participated in the above activities. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 08:26:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平会见巴西众议长里拉]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/21/nw.D110000renmrb_20231021_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, October 21, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-10/21/01/rmrb2023102101p21_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the morning of October 20, President Xi Jinping met with Brazilian Speaker of the House of Representatives Lira at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing. &lt;BR/>;Photographed by Xinhua News Agency reporter Zhai Jianlan&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, October 20th&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;(Reporter Wang Hailin) ​​On the morning of October 20, President Xi Jinping met with Brazilian Speaker of the House of Representatives Lira at the Great Hall of the People. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that President Lula paid a successful state visit to China this spring. He and I held a fruitful meeting and reached important consensus on leading China-Pakistan relations to usher in a new era. China and Brazil are the largest developing countries in the Eastern and Western Hemispheres respectively, and are emerging powers with global influence. In the face of a world intertwined with events, China and Pakistan should firmly support and respond to each other. The &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; initiative is highly consistent with Brazil&#39;s &quot;re-industrialization&quot; and the new version of its &quot;Accelerated Growth Plan&quot;, and can fully achieve synergy to boost their respective modernization processes. China supports Brazil in hosting the G20 Leaders&#39; Summit next year and the Conference of the Parties to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change the year after that, and is willing to strengthen coordination and cooperation with Brazil. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that this year marks the 30th anniversary of the establishment of strategic partnership between China and Pakistan, and next year will celebrate the 50th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations. The relations between the two countries have great potential in building on the past and opening up the future. The Brazilian Congress is an important driving force for the development of China-Brazil relations. I hope that Mr. Speaker of the House of Representatives and all members of the Congress will actively promote exchanges and cooperation between China and Brazil and contribute to the better development of China-Brazil relations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Lilla said that it is an honor to lead a delegation to China for the first time as the Speaker of the Brazilian House of Representatives. We would like to congratulate China on successfully hosting the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. Brazil-China relations are developing well, and cooperation with China has effectively promoted Brazil&#39;s economic and social development and increased Brazil&#39;s employment and production capacity. China&#39;s success is of great significance to the world, and China has always been an important partner for Brazil&#39;s development. Brazil hopes to strengthen the docking of development strategies with China, and the Brazilian Congress is willing to strengthen exchanges with the National People&#39;s Congress of China and take the 50th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between the two countries next year as an opportunity to elevate Brazil-China relations to a new height. As the rotating chair of the G20 next year, Brazil is willing to communicate closely with China and play its due role, and looks forward to welcoming President Xi Jinping to visit then. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cai Qi and Wang Yi attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 08:26:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 共建“一带一路”汇集着人类共同发展的最大公约数]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/21/nw.D110000renmrb_20231021_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, October 21, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Ten years of wind and rain, ten years of spring and autumn. At the opening ceremony of the 3rd Belt and Road International Cooperation Summit Forum, President Xi Jinping delivered a keynote speech and profoundly pointed out that &quot;the joint construction of the Belt and Road Initiative adheres to extensive consultation, joint contribution and shared benefits, and transcends differences in different civilizations, cultures, social systems and development stages. , opened up a new path for exchanges between countries, built a new framework for international cooperation, and brought together the greatest common denominator for the common development of mankind.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the 10 years since the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative was proposed, all parties have adhered to their original aspirations, worked hand in hand, and launched thousands of practical cooperation projects, promoting the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; international cooperation from scratch to flourishing. Real and heavy results were harvested. More than 150 countries and more than 30 international organizations have signed cooperation documents on the Belt and Road Initiative, held three Belt and Road International Cooperation Summit Forums, established more than 20 multilateral cooperation platforms in professional fields, and launched a large number of landmark projects and benefits. &quot;Small but beautiful&quot; projects for people&#39;s livelihood have taken root. Consultation, co-construction and sharing, openness, greenness and cleanliness, high standards and sustainability for people&#39;s livelihood have become important guiding principles for high-quality joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. Today, extending from the Eurasian continent to Africa and Latin America, moving from the &quot;big freehand&quot; stage to the &quot;meticulous painting&quot; stage, and expanding from hard connectivity to soft connectivity, the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; cooperation has injected new momentum into world economic growth and opened up new opportunities for global development. Space creates a new platform for international economic cooperation and paints a magnificent picture of connecting the world and sharing beauty and beauty. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The key to jointly building the “Belt and Road” is connectivity. In the 10 years since the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative was proposed, all parties have worked together and helped each other to promote the ancient Silk Road that has lasted for thousands of years to rejuvenate in the new era. Build a global interconnection network led by economic corridors, with large channels and information highways as the skeleton, and relying on railways, highways, airports, ports, and pipeline networks, covering land, sea, space, and the Internet, effectively promoting the commodity exchanges of various countries. , capital, technology, and personnel, making running trains, speeding cars, fast and convenient digital e-commerce, etc. become the bells and sails of international trade in the new era, making hydropower stations, wind power stations, photovoltaic power stations, and oil pipelines Gas pipelines have become oases and beacons of sustainable development in the new era, while modern airports and terminals, smooth roads, and rising economic and trade industrial cooperation parks have become business avenues and stations in the new era. Exciting cultural years, art festivals, fairs, exhibitions, unique cultural exchange projects such as Luban Workshop, &quot;Silk Road Family&quot;, &quot;Bright Journey&quot;, and continuously deepening exchanges between non-governmental organizations, think tanks, media, and youth , playing the Silk Road movement of the new era. After the outbreak of the COVID-19 epidemic, the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; has become a road to life and health. Ten years of practice have fully demonstrated that the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; draws on the ancient Silk Road, takes interconnection as the main line, strengthens policy communication, facility connectivity, unimpeded trade, financial integration, and people-to-people bonds with other countries, and builds a road to peace, prosperity, and prosperity. The road, the road of openness, the road of green, the road of innovation, the road of civilization, continue to realize the desire of people of all countries for civilized exchanges, the hope for peace and tranquility, the pursuit of common development, and the yearning for a better life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping emphasized: &quot;The joint construction of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; originates from China, and the results and opportunities belong to the world.&quot; From strengthening bilateral or multilateral communication and consultation, jointly exploring and pioneering the establishment of many cooperation mechanisms, to fully Explore and give full play to the development potential and comparative advantages of all parties, jointly create new opportunities for development, seek new driving forces for development, expand new space for development, and then seek for convergence of interests and the greatest common denominator of cooperation to achieve shared development opportunities and results for all parties... …In the past 10 years, the Belt and Road Initiative has adhered to the principle of extensive consultation, joint contribution, shared cooperation, guided by the Silk Road spirit of peace and cooperation, openness and inclusiveness, mutual learning, and mutual benefit, and has been committed to high standards, benefiting people’s livelihood, and Sustainable cooperation goals have become a common cause for partners. Facts have fully proved that the fruitful results achieved by the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; did not fall from the sky, nor were they given by anyone, but were achieved by the hard work, wisdom and courage of the governments, enterprises and people of the countries participating in the joint construction; The circle of friends in jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; is getting bigger and bigger, there are more and more good partners, the quality of cooperation is getting higher and higher, and the development prospects are getting better and better. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Only by embracing the world can we embrace tomorrow; by working together can we achieve steady and long-term progress. The joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; pursues development, advocates win-win results, and delivers hope. The successful practice of the past 10 years has proved that the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; follows the trend, wins the hearts of the people, benefits people&#39;s livelihood, and benefits the world. It brings together the greatest common denominator for the common development of mankind. It is a sunshine avenue for China to share opportunities and seek common development with the world. It is a road of opportunity leading to common prosperity, a big stage for common development of all countries, and a practical platform to promote the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind. It has strong resilience and strong vitality. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Throughout the history of human development, only through continuous self-improvement and unremitting struggle can we reap abundant fruits and establish long-term achievements that will benefit the future and benefit all people. The joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; has gone through its first decade of prosperity and is at its peak. Standing at a new historical starting point, adhering to the original intention of cooperation, keeping in mind the development mission, building on the past and forging ahead with courage, the high-quality joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; will surely be more innovative, dynamic, open and inclusive. With the joint efforts of all parties, Head towards the next golden decade and create a better future for mankind! &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 08:26:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 国家主席习近平任免驻外大使]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/21/nw.D110000renmrb_20231021_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, October 21, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 20th&amp;nbsp; Decided to appoint and remove the following ambassadors abroad:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1. Remove Chai Wenrui from the post of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the People&#39;s Republic of China to Mongolia;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Appoint Shen Minjuan (female) as the Ambassador of the People&#39;s Republic of China to Mongolia Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2. Remove Xiao Jianguo from the post of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the People&#39;s Republic of China to the Democratic Republic of East Timor; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Appoint Wang Wenli (female) as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the People&#39;s Republic of China to the Democratic Republic of East Timor. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3. Remove Ma Fulin from the post of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the People&#39;s Republic of China to the Republic of Congo; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Appoint Li Yan (female) as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the People&#39;s Republic of China to the Republic of Congo. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4. Remove Ren Yisheng from the post of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the People&#39;s Republic of China to the Republic of Liberia;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Appoint Yin Chengwu as the Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the People&#39;s Republic of China to the Republic of Liberia. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5. Remove Sun Lijie from the post of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the People&#39;s Republic of China to the Slovak Republic; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Appoint Cai Ge as the Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the People&#39;s Republic of China to the Slovak Republic. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6. Remove Chen Bo (female) from the post of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the People&#39;s Republic of China to the Republic of Serbia; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Appoint Li Ming as Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the People&#39;s Republic of China to the Republic of Serbia. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7. Removing Wu Haitao from the posts of Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the People&#39;s Republic of China to the Kingdom of Spain and Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the People&#39;s Republic of China to the Principality of Andorra; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Appointing Yao Jing as the Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary of the People&#39;s Republic of China to the Kingdom of Spain Ambassador Plenipotentiary and Ambassador Extraordinary and Plenipotentiary to the Principality of Andorra. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 08:26:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 中国共产党和老挝人民革命党关于构建中老命运共同体行动计划（2024—2028年）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/21/nw.D110000renmrb_20231021_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, October 21, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Part One&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Preface&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China and Laos Mountains We share the same blood and water, and we are friendly socialist neighbors with a shared future and a shared destiny. In April 2019, the top leaders of the two parties and the two countries signed the &quot;Action Plan of the Communist Party of China and the Lao People&#39;s Revolutionary Party on Building a Community with a Shared Future for China and Laos&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Action Plan&quot;), which determined the promotion of strategic communication, mutual trust, and pragmatism within five years. The &quot;five actions&quot; of cooperation and connectivity, political security and stability, people-to-people exchanges and tourism, and green and sustainable development have opened a new chapter in the construction of a China-Laos community with a shared future. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past five years, under the strategic guidance of the top leaders of the two parties and two countries, the two sides have sought common development through mutual trust and cooperation, met challenges with sincere assistance, and effectively implemented the spirit of a community with a shared future. In the face of the epidemic of the century that is raging around the world, the two sides have supported each other, overcome the difficulties together, and taken practical actions to protect the lives and health of the two peoples. In the face of the common expectations of the two peoples, the two sides have worked together to open up a new pattern of high-quality cooperation between the two countries, especially to build the China-Laos railway into a road of happiness, development and friendship for the people of China and Laos, and for the peace and prosperity of the two countries. It has brought great benefits to the two peoples. In the face of the complex international environment, the two sides have closely coordinated, united and cooperated, firmly supported each other on issues involving each other&#39;s core interests, and set an example for building a new type of international relations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The practice of building a community with a shared future for China and Laos has proved that the destiny of mankind shares weal and woe and the interests of all countries are closely connected. Building a community with a shared future for mankind is the future of the people of all countries in the world. Today&#39;s world is intertwined with chaos and changes that have occurred over the past century are accelerating. Human society is facing unprecedented challenges. In the face of changes in the world, the times, and history, both sides agreed that we should persist in cooperation and not engage in confrontation, adhere to openness and not engage in closure, adhere to mutual benefit and win-win, not engage in zero-sum games, and resolutely oppose all forms of hegemony doctrine and power politics, and oppose the &quot;new cold war&quot;, interference in other countries&#39; internal affairs, double standards, and formation of camps and exclusive circles targeting specific countries. The two sides are willing to work together to implement the global development initiative, global security initiative, and global civilization initiative, work together to promote the common values ​​of peace, development, fairness, justice, democracy, and freedom for all mankind, jointly explore the path of human modernization, and continuously create a better future for mankind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In order to plan the principles and direction for the development of relations between the two parties and two countries in the next stage, and promote the steady and long-term construction of a community with a shared future between China and Laos, the two sides unanimously agreed to renew and implement a new five-year action plan, adhering to the political We should respect and trust each other, be mutually beneficial economically, help each other in security, understand each other culturally, and coexist and govern ecologically. We should work together to build a high-standard, high-quality, and high-level China-Laos community with a shared future, and make active efforts to build a community with a shared future for mankind. and demonstration. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Part 2&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Cooperation in various fields&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1. Political field&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the top leaders of the two parties and two countries Guided by the important consensus, we should deepen political mutual trust, strengthen strategic communication, and intensify coordination and cooperation in international and regional affairs to promote greater development of China-Laos relations in the new era. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1. Give play to the leading role of high-level officials, strengthen high-level exchanges between the two parties and two countries, especially strategic communication between the top leaders, through bilateral exchanges of visits, video calls, exchange of letters, meetings on multilateral occasions, etc., and timely discuss bilateral issues. They exchanged in-depth views on major issues of concern and international and regional situations, and firmly grasped the direction of China-Laos relations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2. Implement the bipartisan cooperation plan from 2021 to 2025, and prepare and implement the bipartisan cooperation plan from 2026 to 2030. Plan and implement counterpart exchanges and cooperation between the two parties’ central committees in the fields of comprehensive coordination, policy research, cadre organization, and public opinion propaganda, and promote the expansion of exchanges and cooperation between the two parties at local, grassroots, and mass organizations. Continue to hold theoretical seminars between the two parties and conduct in-depth exchanges on a series of major theoretical and practical issues in socialist construction. Improve the quality of cadre training cooperation and provide a solid talent reserve for the long-term governance and development of the two parties. Utilize the training resources of Yunnan, Hunan, Guangxi and other provinces (regions) to promote the in-depth development of cadre training cooperation between the two parties. Implement the &quot;Cooperation Agreement between the International Department of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the International Department of the Central Committee of the Lao People&#39;s Revolutionary Party&quot; and the annual meeting mechanism between the heads of the International Department of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the Lao People&#39;s Revolutionary Party, and promote the coordination of matters related to exchanges and cooperation between the two parties. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3. Continue to strengthen exchanges and cooperation in the field of discipline inspection and supervision. Jointly promote the integrity construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and establish and improve the long-term mechanism for the integrity construction of the China-Laos railway during the operation period. Deepen anti-corruption law enforcement cooperation in the pursuit of fugitives and stolen property, and work together to combat cross-border corruption crimes. Strengthen communication and coordination in multilateral mechanisms such as the United Nations Convention against Corruption and China-ASEAN to jointly safeguard the interests of developing countries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4. Deepen the friendly exchanges and cooperation between the National People&#39;s Congress of China and the National Assembly of Laos, the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference and the Central Committee of the Lao National Construction Front, maintain the momentum of high-level exchanges of visits, and learn from each other&#39;s useful experiences. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5. Continue to implement the Agreement between the Ministries of Foreign Affairs of China and Laos on Strengthening Cooperation under the New Situation, maintain a regular exchange mechanism between the two ministries, intensify communication and collaboration at all levels, and expand diplomatic talent training channels. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6. Continue to firmly support each other and safeguard their respective core interests. China firmly supports Laos in safeguarding national sovereignty, security and development interests, and supports Laos in adhering to the party&#39;s leadership and following the socialist path. Laos firmly adheres to the one-China principle and recognizes that there is only one China in the world, that the government of the People&#39;s Republic of China is the only legal government representing the whole of China, and that Taiwan is an inalienable part of China&#39;s territory. We oppose any words or deeds that undermine China&#39;s sovereignty and territorial integrity, oppose any form of &quot;Taiwan independence&quot; separatist activities, oppose external forces interfering in China&#39;s internal affairs under any pretext, and support all efforts made by China to achieve national reunification. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7. Strengthen coordination and cooperation within regional mechanisms such as Lancang-Mekong Cooperation and China-ASEAN Cooperation, practice open regionalism, promote the construction of a closer community of a shared future for Lancang-Mekong countries, and deepen China-ASEAN cooperation. Comprehensive strategic partnership and work together to build the &quot;Five Homes&quot; of peace, tranquility, prosperity, beauty and friendship. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;8. Strengthen cooperation within the framework of the United Nations, maintain close communication and cooperation on international and regional issues of common concern, insist on practicing and respecting true multilateralism, promote the democratization of international relations, and jointly safeguard the international Fairness and justice promote the development of global governance in a more fair and reasonable direction. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;9. Actively implement the global development initiative, global security initiative, and global civilization initiative, advocate common values ​​​​for all mankind, jointly respond to global challenges, promote regional security, stability, development and prosperity, inclusiveness and harmony, and promote the construction of humankind. A community of shared future. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2. Economic field&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Strengthen strategic alignment, take the construction of the China-Laos Economic Corridor as the main axis, take the cooperation on large projects such as the China-Laos railway and power grid as the backbone, and comprehensively implement the principle of mutual benefit and reciprocity. Carry out in-depth practical cooperation in various fields to bring tangible benefits to the people of the two countries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1. Follow the principle of extensive consultation, joint contribution and shared benefits, orderly promote the alignment between the “Belt and Road” initiative and Laos’ strategy of “turning a land-locked country into a land-linked country”, and implement the key projects and task lists of the joint construction of the “Belt and Road”, Promote the effectiveness of the cooperation plan outline of the two countries in jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. Laos actively supports and participates in the “Belt and Road” International Cooperation Summit Forum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2. Steadily implement the &quot;Cooperation Framework on Jointly Building the China-Laos Economic Corridor (2019-2030)&quot;, give full play to the role of the China-Laos Economic Corridor Cooperation Joint Committee mechanism, and rely on the China-Laos Railway. Make overall plans to promote practical cooperation between China and Laos in areas such as transportation, production capacity, agriculture, culture and tourism, and social and people&#39;s livelihood. Promote the operation, maintenance and development of the China-Laos railway with high quality, strive to realize the early connection of the China-Laos railway and the Thai railway with standard gauges, and advance the development concept of China-Laos and Thailand connectivity. Continue to carry out production capacity and investment cooperation in accordance with the principles of &quot;enterprise entities, market orientation, commercial operations, and international practices&quot;, do a good job in connecting the construction of economic corridors, development along the China-Laos railway and production capacity cooperation, and build a cooperation platform for enterprises and financial institutions of the two countries. Promote the implementation of more pragmatic cooperation projects. We will successfully operate key projects such as the Saisettha Comprehensive Development Zone, steadily promote the construction of the China-Laos Mohan-Boten Economic Cooperation Zone, and pragmatically carry out cross-border industrial cooperation. Actively expand practical cooperation between China and Laos in emerging fields such as digital economy and green development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3. Give full play to the role of China-Laos Economic, Trade and Technical Cooperation Committee, Production Capacity and Investment Cooperation, China-Laos Investment Cooperation Working Group and other mechanisms, strengthen policy communication and experience exchange, make overall plans for bilateral economic and trade cooperation, and promote China-Laos economic and trade cooperation. Healthy and sustainable development of economic and trade relations. Jointly implement the zero-tariff arrangement for 98% of Laos’ tax items exported to China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4. Timely start negotiating and signing the new &quot;Five-Year Plan for China-Laos Economic and Trade Cooperation&quot;, improve trade infrastructure, strengthen port construction, actively explore innovative management and inspection models for China-Laos ports, promote port customs clearance convenience, and promote Economic and trade development cooperation and personnel exchanges in border areas. Deepen customs inspection and quarantine cooperation, accelerate animal and plant quarantine (SPS) consultations, facilitate the export of more Lao goods to China, and continue to improve the level of passenger and freight supervision services on the China-Laos railway. Promote e-commerce cooperation and expand bilateral trade between China and Laos. China is willing to actively promote trade in agricultural products between the two countries, support Laos in participating in the China International Import Expo, and continuously expand exports of Laos&#39; high-quality agricultural and food products to China. Guide and encourage each other&#39;s companies to invest and start business in each other&#39;s countries, improve the business environment, provide cooperation convenience, and promote the healthy development of investment cooperation between the two sides. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5. Actively carry out the negotiation and signing of the protocol of the China-Laos International Road Transport Agreement and promote the implementation of bilateral international road transport cooperation. Promote the construction of logistics infrastructure for the China-Laos Economic Corridor in an orderly manner, promote the stable operation of international trains on the China-Laos Railway, and ensure the safety and smoothness of the China-Laos logistics transportation channel. Operate the Vientiane-Vang Vieng Expressway well and promote the implementation of the remaining section of the China-Laos (Boten-Vientiane) Expressway Project. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6. Promote extensive exchanges in the field of information and communications, and actively promote pragmatic cooperation between enterprises of the two countries in areas such as new communications infrastructure and cross-border optical cables. Deepen cooperation between the radio authorities in China and Laos to further ensure the safety of radio frequency use on China-Laos railways. Give full play to the advantages of the &quot;Laos 1&quot; communication satellite and focus on cultivating Lao satellite measurement and control and satellite application talents. China will use aerospace technology to help Laos&#39; national economic and social development and improvement of people&#39;s livelihood. Explore the establishment of a Laos National Satellite Application Center, build a satellite remote sensing application cooperation platform, and promote cooperation in surveying and mapping geoinformation technology between China and Laos, including helping to establish and improve databases on Laos&#39; agriculture, land, forests, minerals, etc. Promote the application of aerospace technology, including satellite communications, remote sensing and navigation, and promote Laos&#39; economic and technological progress. China helps Laos cultivate scientific research talents, improve its scientific research capabilities and levels, and promote the application of scientific and technological achievements in Laos&#39; national development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7. Deepen the strategic partnership between China and Laos for power cooperation, accelerate China-Laos power interconnection, and strengthen exchanges on power policies and planning. Support enterprises in accelerating the implementation of China-Laos power interconnection projects in accordance with commercial principles and increase the scale of power grid interconnection and power mutual aid between the two countries. Support enterprises from both sides to cooperate in operating the Lao National Transmission Network Company (EDL-T), share power development experience, promote the sustainable development of Laos&#39; power grid, cooperate to promote the development, utilization and transmission of clean energy in Laos, and cooperate to improve the stable power supply guarantee of the Laos section of the China-Laos Railway level, cooperate to carry out power grid interconnection between Laos and neighboring countries, and create a model for all-round power cooperation in the Lancang-Mekong region. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;8. Deepen bilateral local currency cooperation, further promote trade and investment facilitation between the two sides, and create a good policy environment for bilateral local currency settlements. China provides Laos with intellectual support for financial reform within its capacity. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;9. Strengthen experience exchanges and cooperation in the field of poverty reduction and rural revitalization, rely on China-ASEAN, ASEAN and China, Japan and South Korea, Lancang-Mekong Cooperation and other platforms to strengthen experience exchanges and actively promote the second phase of the East Asia Poverty Reduction Demonstration Cooperation Project launch and implementation to support personnel capacity building in the field of poverty reduction in Laos. Comprehensively implement eight major aid projects to Laos, continue to carry out a series of livelihood projects such as East Asia poverty reduction demonstrations and rural poverty alleviation facility construction, support the improvement of people&#39;s livelihood in northern Laos, benefit more local people, and jointly promote global development initiatives to achieve positive results in Laos. Promote the implementation of ten schools and education projects aiding Laos, including the Railway Vocational and Technical College. Give full play to the role of hospitals assisting the elderly and carry out innovative hospital management cooperation. Promote the construction of more vocational and technical schools that meet Laos’ development needs. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10. Further deepen cooperation in agricultural and rural areas, improve working mechanisms, and focus on crop planting, livestock and aquaculture, agricultural product quality and safety, agricultural product processing, warehousing and logistics, digital technology application, rural e-commerce, rural areas Continue to cooperate in industrial development and other fields, continuously improve the quality of agricultural practitioners, and promote sustainable agricultural development and agricultural and rural modernization. Strengthen agricultural economic, trade and investment cooperation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;11. Strengthen exchanges and cooperation between small and medium-sized enterprises. Strengthen exchanges between the two sides on policies and measures to promote the development of small and medium-sized enterprises, and promote exchanges and cooperation in key areas such as technological innovation, trade and investment, and industrial docking. China supports Lao companies to participate in the China International Small and Medium Enterprises Expo. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;12. China encourages relevant provinces (autonomous regions and municipalities) to give full play to their location and resource advantages and form a good situation in which each can demonstrate its strengths and complement each other in cooperation with Laos. Relying on platforms and mechanisms such as the Lancang-Mekong Cooperation, the China-ASEAN Expo, and the China Yunnan-Laos Northern Cooperation Working Group, efforts will be made to build Yunnan, Hunan, Guangxi, Guangdong and other provinces (regions) into highlands for cooperation with Laos. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;13. Further deepen cooperation within China-ASEAN (10+1), ASEAN and China, Japan and South Korea (10+3) cooperation, Lancang-Mekong Cooperation, East Asia Summit and other regional mechanisms, as well as the Asian Infrastructure Investment Bank coordination and cooperation within the framework.加强政策协调，共同高质量实施《区域全面经济伙伴关系协定》（RCEP）、中国—东盟自贸区相关协定。积极推动中国—东盟自贸区3.0版谈判早日取得成果，做好协定后续生效实施工作，推进区域经济一体化。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三、安全领域&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加强沟通协作，深化中老防务、执法、政治安全等合作，切实维护两国各自的安全、稳定和发展利益。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1.深化防范抵御“颜色革命”双边协作，拓展合作内容，丰富交流形式，重点在理论研究、经验分享、情报交流、案件协查等方面加强务实合作，坚决防范应对“颜色革命”威胁。推动政治安全、反恐、海外利益保护、打击跨国犯罪等领域合作走深走实，切实维护两国共同利益。中方继续帮助老方提升维护国内稳定和应对外部渗透能力，共同维护各自安全稳定，防止外部势力介入。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2.进一步深化两军合作。保持两军高层领导会晤，加强战略沟通。用好两军合作协调委员会会议机制，统筹协调两军各领域交往合作事项。深化两军政工领域务实交流，拓展两军联演联训，协商签署后勤保障协议。办好边境国防友好交流活动，共同维护边境安全稳定。抓好老挝空军航校、热带传染病防控实验室、军事测绘导航等重点项目建设，继续开展院校交流、人才培养、中青年军官互访、学术研究等领域合作。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3.加强两国执法安全合作，继续开展在打击跨境犯罪，打击各种形式的人口拐卖、电信网络诈骗、偷越国边境，湄公河联合执法，共建“一带一路”合作项目安保等领域合作，支持中老警务合作中心建设和运行，建立和加强中央、地方警务定期会晤机制。深化反恐怖合作，加强打击国际恐怖组织的情报信息交流、案件协查和行动协调，相互交流经验以及分享最佳实践和能力建设措施。中方支持老方做好铁路安保工作，共同维护中老铁路运营安全。中方加强对老方执法安全类援助和培训，与老挝共建“平安城市”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4.加大保护在本国工作、生活的对方国家公民生命、财产安全及双方重大合作项目安全。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5.加强移民和边防出入境管理领域合作。接续和完善中老边境三级代表联系机制，强化打击非法入境、非法居留、非法就业活动力度，深化在边境管控、出入境边防检查、非法移民遣返和外国人管理等方面合作。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6.加强在东盟打击跨国犯罪部长级会议机制、东盟地区论坛等地区多边安全对话合作机制中的协调与配合。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;四、人文领域&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;深化人文领域交流合作，赓续传统友谊，巩固中老友好的社会基础和民意基础，推动中老关系亲上加亲、好上加好。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1.深化人文交流与合作，推动两国地方特别是边境地区缔结和发展更多友好城市关系，夯实中老友好的社会民意基础。通过双、多边机制，维护和密切双方友好组织和人员往来，丰富交流内容，凝聚友好共识，增进中老民相亲、心相通。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2.加强群团（工会、青年、妇女）组织、企业、中央及地方行业协会间友好交流合作。深化两国青少年和儿童交往，办好中老铁路青年友谊工程，共同培养中老友谊接班人。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3.加强教育政策对话沟通，拓展双方在教育领域交流与合作。中方欢迎老挝优秀学生来华留学。开展职业教育合作办学，服务中老大项目建设。加强中老语言文化教学合作，促进文化交流。推进教育数字化转型，促进数字资源共建共享。深化双方高校、智库合作。进一步加强人力资源开发合作，中方愿根据老方需要，提供多双边培训名额及在职学历学位教育名额。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4.加强卫生健康领域交流与合作，开展医疗服务、传统医学、热带病等传染病防控领域的交流合作。鼓励双方更多医疗机构加入中国—东盟医院合作联盟，利用联盟资源，促进双方医疗机构管理体制完善和能力提升。中方支持老挝热带病防治联合实验室能力建设，共同助力提升澜湄区域热带病防控能力。继续在老开展“光明行”白内障复明等国际公益活动，共同维护两国民众健康。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5.积极开展文化和旅游交流与合作。推动商签新一期文化和旅游合作执行计划。推动两国各层级人员往来，支持文化和旅游机构开展交流合作。积极参加在对方国家举办的重大文化和旅游活动，中方为老方在华开展旅游推介提供便利。围绕中老铁路，支持优质文化和旅游线路与产品开发、推动开展品牌塑造和营销推介。加强人力资源建设，共同策划各类培训项目。老方支持中国文化中心等中国在老挝文化和旅游机构运作。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6.巩固和提升在退役军人工作领域的交流合作，进一步推动双方在退役军人的管理服务、抚恤优待、就业培训、创业扶持、社会融合、褒扬纪念等领域的政策制度分享与工作经验交流。共同做好中国在老烈士陵园修缮和维护工作，发挥好其在弘扬中老传统友好关系上的宣传教育作用。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7.深化在新闻、影视、出版领域交流合作。利用好双多边媒体交流合作机制，开展联合采访、联合制作、人员互访与培训等合作。中方向老方介绍电影制作和发行经验。深入开展中老经典著作互译出版项目，推动两国出版机构在内容生产、翻译出版、发行推广等建立常态化合作机制。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;五、生态领域&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;推动生态环境领域全方位合作，倡导绿色低碳循环发展，共谋生态文明建设，以生态环境合作促进两国民生福祉。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1.深化生态环境领域合作，加强生态环保理念和法规标准研讨交流，中方支持老方在气候变化、污染治理、环境管理、生态保护等领域人员能力建设。进一步支持中国—老挝应对气候变化南南合作低碳示范区建设，发挥示范区在应对气候变化、助力绿色低碳发展过程中的示范作用。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2.加强双边和澜湄合作机制下水资源领域合作，推动续签部门间水资源合作谅解备忘录，就水资源开发利用、水文信息、防灾减灾、能力建设、人员培训等领域开展合作，共同提升水资源集约安全利用水平。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3.中方应用航天技术助力老方农林资源规划、水资源管理、环境保护、洪涝灾害防灾减灾等。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4.利用好中国—东盟、澜湄以及“一带一路”绿色发展国际联盟等平台，推动双方环境政策对话和技术合作等活动，就双方共同关注的地区和全球环境议题开展沟通和协调。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5.积极开展在野生动植物特别是药用植物保护领域的合作，加强在政府间协议、国际公约等多边场合的立场沟通和协商。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;第三部分&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;落实机制&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中老双方有关部门和地方根据实际情况，细化落实本《行动计划》涉及本单位内容。双方分别由两党中联部作为落实《行动计划》牵头部门，负责沟通协调、监督实施、总结评估、对外宣介等工作。在执行过程中出现的问题，双方应通过友好协商解决。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本《行动计划》于二〇二三年十月二十日在北京签署，一式两份，每份均用中文和老挝文写成，两种文本具有同等效力。本《行动计划》有效期五年，自二〇二四年一月一日起生效。期满后，双方视情签署新的行动计划。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国共产党&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;老挝人民革命党&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中央委员会总书记&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;中央委员会总书记&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;通伦·西苏里&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（新华社北京10月20日电）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 08:26:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 二〇二三年深入学习贯彻习近平生态文明思想研讨会举行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/21/nw.D110000renmrb_20231021_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月21日星期六&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;新华社长沙10月20日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者明星、高敬）10月19日至20日，2023年深入学习贯彻习近平生态文明思想研讨会在湖南长沙举行。研讨会主题为“深入学习贯彻习近平生态文明思想，以美丽中国建设全面推进人与自然和谐共生的现代化”。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;生态环境部党组书记孙金龙表示，新时代我国生态文明建设从理论到实践都发生了历史性、转折性、全局性变化。新征程上，要坚持以习近平生态文明思想为指引，深刻理解和贯彻坚持人与自然和谐共生的基本原则、为了人民依靠人民的宗旨要求、以高品质生态环境支撑高质量发展的重要任务、系统思维全局观念的工作方法、推进生态环境治理现代化的改革目标、加强党的全面领导的根本保证，努力绘就美丽中国的更新画卷。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;中国法学会副会长甘藏春在发言中说，党的十八大以来，用最严格制度最严密法治保护生态环境取得显著成效。生态文明建设必须紧紧抓住法治建设这个“牛鼻子”，要坚持推进生态环境科学立法，坚持推进生态环境严格执法，坚持推进生态环境公正司法，坚持推进生态环境全民守法。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;湖南省政协副主席、湘潭大学校长潘碧灵表示，高校应当在生态文明建设上发挥积极作用，承担好推进生态文明教育、研究、实践的应有责任。高校要成为学习贯彻习近平生态文明思想的教育高地、研究高地、实践高地。要从学科专业建设、人才队伍培养、科技创新协同等方面践行习近平生态文明思想，为生态文明建设提供强有力的人才和科技支撑。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;此次研讨会由习近平生态文明思想研究中心主办，生态环境部环境与经济政策研究中心、湖南省委宣传部、湖南省生态环境厅、湘潭大学承办，设主论坛和4个平行分论坛。 &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 08:26:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 中华人民共和国和斯里兰卡民主社会主义共和国联合声明]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/21/nw.D110000renmrb_20231021_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月21日星期六&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;一、应中华人民共和国主席习近平邀请，斯里兰卡总统拉尼尔·维克拉马辛哈于2023年10月16日至20日来华出席第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;二、访问期间，习近平主席同维克拉马辛哈总统举行会见，国务院副总理丁薛祥会见维克拉马辛哈总统。两国领导人在亲切友好的气氛中，就深化中斯传统友谊、扩大两国互利合作以及共同关心的国际地区问题深入交换意见，达成广泛共识。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三、两国元首一致对1957年建交以来两国关系的发展表示满意。66年来，两国始终弘扬《米胶协定》精神，坚持独立自强、团结互助，始终在涉及彼此核心利益和重大关切的问题上相互坚定支持，共同应对包括自然灾害、新冠疫情、经济困难在内的风险挑战，不断巩固战略互信，弘扬传统友谊。中斯真诚互助、世代友好的战略合作伙伴关系已经成为大小国家友好相处、互利合作的典范，对两国均具有特殊重要意义。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;四、双方同意保持高层交往势头，扩大两国政府和其他利益攸关方交流合作，在和平共处五项原则、《联合国宪章》宗旨和原则及睦邻友好原则基础上，加强战略沟通，为两国关系未来发展明确重点和方向。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;五、双方重申在涉及彼此核心利益和重大关切问题上相互支持。斯方重申坚定奉行一个中国原则，中华人民共和国政府是代表全中国的唯一合法政府，台湾是中国领土不可分割的一部分，支持中国政府为维护主权和领土完整所作的一切努力，反对任何形式的“台湾独立”。斯方重申决不允许利用斯领土从事任何反华分裂活动。中方重申将继续坚持亲诚惠容和与邻为善、以邻为伴周边外交方针，坚定支持斯里兰卡维护国家独立、主权和领土完整，尊重和支持斯方自主选择符合本国国情的发展道路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;六、斯方赞赏近年来在习近平主席英明领导下中国经济社会发展取得的成就。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;七、斯方对新冠疫情期间和2022年斯方经济危机期间中方提供的宝贵支持表示感谢。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;八、2023年3月，中方已及时向斯方出具融资支持文件，帮助斯顺利获得国际货币基金组织贷款。9月下旬，中国进出口银行作为官方债权人，已同斯方就涉华债务处置初步达成一致。中方将继续支持本国金融机构同斯方开展友好商谈，尽快达成斯涉华债务处置方案，愿同有关国家和国际金融机构一道，继续为斯方应对当前困难、缓解债务负担、实现可持续发展发挥积极作用。斯方赞赏中方为其金融纾困提供的支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;九、在两国领导人共同引领和推动下，中斯共建“一带一路”合作取得丰硕成果。斯方重申愿积极参与中方提出的“一带一路”倡议。双方同意签署《中华人民共和国国家发展和改革委员会与斯里兰卡民主社会主义共和国财政、经济稳定和国家政策部关于共同加快编制共建“一带一路”合作规划的谅解备忘录》《中华人民共和国国家发展和改革委员会与斯里兰卡民主社会主义共和国财政、经济稳定和国家政策部合作谅解备忘录》《中华人民共和国国家发展和改革委员会与斯里兰卡民主社会主义共和国财政、经济稳定和国家政策部关于绿色低碳发展合作的谅解备忘录》《援斯里兰卡首都科伦坡低收入人群保障住宅项目实施协议》等文件，交流发展经验，对接发展战略，统筹推进合作，为两国高质量共建“一带一路”打造新亮点、注入新动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十、斯方欢迎中国企业在斯国家建设中发挥的积极作用，欢迎更多中国企业赴斯投资，愿为其创造良好投资和经营环境。中方将继续鼓励有实力的中国企业赴斯投资，开展互利合作。科伦坡港口城和汉班托塔港项目是双方共建“一带一路”的标志性项目。斯方欢迎中国企业加大投资力度，愿为港口城提供有利投资环境，包括出台必要法律措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十一、双方对两国经贸合作成果表示满意，同意尽快达成全面的自贸协定，以加强双边贸易和经济合作。双方将在市场化、自主化、法治化的基础上开展金融领域务实合作，进一步提升金融服务水平，促进双边经贸发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中方愿继续支持斯具有优势的产业与中国相关进出口商协会建立联系，为斯出口企业来华参加中国国际进口博览会、中国进出口商品交易会、中国—南亚博览会、中国国际供应链促进博览会等会展提供便利和支持，推动双方企业在互利共赢基础上深化合作，促进斯对华出口。双方同意签署《中华人民共和国海关总署与斯里兰卡民主社会主义共和国种植工业部关于斯里兰卡锡兰肉桂输华植物检疫要求议定书》《中华人民共和国海关总署与斯里兰卡民主社会主义共和国渔业部关于斯里兰卡输华野生水产品的检验检疫和兽医卫生要求议定书》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十二、双方同意加强两国中小企业交流合作，鼓励双方中小企业、服务机构、行业协会、科研院所等加强沟通联系，搭建产业对接、科技研发、电子航务、人才培训等方面的合作平台，创新合作模式，拓宽合作渠道，丰富合作内容。中方欢迎斯里兰卡中小企业参加中国国际中小企业博览会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十三、中斯农业合作交流密切、互动良好。中方愿聚焦双边农业合作重点和关切，在热带作物生物技术、育种栽培、水产养殖、农产品加工、市场开发及农业现代化等领域与斯方开展技术交流和培训合作，帮助斯方提升农业综合生产能力。中方欢迎斯里兰卡扩大优质农产品输华。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十四、双方充分肯定教育交流对增进两国了解与友谊的重要作用，将进一步加强教师、学生和研究人员的交流。双方同意继续加强科教领域合作，鼓励两国教育机构开展合作研究、联合培养。双方同意继续支持“中国—斯里兰卡联合科教中心”的建设和发展。双方同意签署援斯里兰卡普通教育数字化转型项目可研换文。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十五、双方积极评价两国文化和旅游领域合作取得的进展。双方将继续鼓励两国公民赴对方国家旅游，为对方开拓旅游市场提供协助。双方同意鼓励两国加强航空互联互通。斯方愿继续出台更多旅游便利化政策。中方愿为斯方在河南洛阳白马寺修建斯里兰卡佛殿提供便利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十六、双方同意继续深化友好城市和人文交流合作。双方愿以中国（重庆）—斯里兰卡减贫与发展合作圆桌会为起点，通过搭建平台、组织培训、智库交流等加强减贫经验交流。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十七、双方愿在气候变化适应和可持续发展领域开展更紧密的合作，强调共同实施绿色措施是减缓气候变化影响的有效途径。双方愿加强协作，深化防灾减灾、海上救护救援与研究、人才培养和能力建设方面交流与合作，进一步探索蓝色经济合作。双方同意签署《“中国—斯里兰卡水技术研究与示范联合中心”三方运行管理协议》。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十八、双方重申坚定致力于促进真正的多边主义，推进国际关系民主化，推动全球治理朝着更加公正合理的方向发展。双方同意在联合国等多边机制内加强合作，维护广大发展中国家的共同利益，支持多边贸易体制，反对保护主义，推动经济全球化朝着开放、包容、普惠、平衡、共赢方向发展，构建人类命运共同体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;斯方坚定支持并积极参与中方提出的全球发展倡议、全球安全倡议和全球文明倡议。中方愿同斯方深入探讨落实上述倡议的具体举措，共同致力于推进全球与地区的和平、安全、发展与繁荣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十九、维克拉马辛哈总统感谢中华人民共和国政府和人民对他本人及斯里兰卡代表团的热情友好接待，并邀请中国领导人访问斯里兰卡。中国领导人对此表示感谢，双方将通过外交渠道保持沟通。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（新华社北京10月20日电）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 08:26:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 王毅同马来西亚外长赞比里通电话]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/21/nw.D110000renmrb_20231021_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月21日星期六&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;新华社北京10月20日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;10月20日，中共中央政治局委员、外交部长王毅同马来西亚外长赞比里通电话。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;赞比里祝贺中方成功举办第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛，表示“一带一路”倡议有利于促进地区互联互通、巩固国际贸易纽带、给地区和世界发展带来更多机遇。马方是最早加入“一带一路”倡议的国家之一，始终支持这一重要倡议，将继续与中方加强对接合作。马方期待与中方共同庆祝明年马中建交50周年，推动两国关系进一步发展。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;王毅赞赏马方为第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛成功举办作出的贡献，表示今年是中马建立全面战略伙伴关系10周年，明年两国将迎来建交50周年。中方愿同马方共同开展系列友好庆祝活动，深化高质量共建“一带一路”合作，推动中马命运共同体建设走深走实。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;双方就巴以冲突交换意见。赞比里表示，马方赞赏中方促进停火止战、保护无辜平民、推动对话和谈的努力，支持中方关于确保人道救援顺利抵达、尽快落实“两国方案”、实现中东持久和平的立场。期待中方为推动冲突双方尽快回到谈判桌前发挥重要作用。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;王毅表示，我们今天在这里享受和平，但是这个世界并不安宁，也不公平，还有很多无辜民众正被死亡和苦难的阴影所笼罩。在巴以冲突问题上，中方始终站在和平一边，站在国际法一边，站在广大阿拉伯和伊斯兰国家正当诉求一边。中方反对一切袭击伤害无辜平民和违反国际法的行为。中方支持东盟—海合会峰会刚刚就加沙地带局势发表的声明。我们呼吁，在战争与和平面前，各方应摒弃一切地缘政治考虑，坚守人类良知，形成国际共识，尽快停火止战，防止发生更大规模人道主义灾难。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;王毅指出，巴以冲突的根源在于巴勒斯坦的土地被不断侵占，巴勒斯坦人民建国的要求被长期忽视。解决巴以冲突的根本之策是落实“两国方案”，实现巴勒斯坦和以色列和平共处。中方支持恢复巴勒斯坦民族的合法权利，期待巴勒斯坦问题重新回到政治解决的轨道上来，切实落实联合国安理会多次就此通过的决议。中方愿同马方及所有爱好和平的国家加强沟通，为中东和平继续作出努力。 &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 08:26:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 中华人民共和国和巴基斯坦伊斯兰共和国联合新闻声明]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/21/nw.D110000renmrb_20231021_5-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月21日星期六&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;1.应中华人民共和国主席习近平邀请，巴基斯坦伊斯兰共和国总理安瓦尔·哈克·卡卡尔于2023年10月16日至20日来华出席第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2.在北京期间，习近平主席会见卡卡尔总理。李强总理，中共中央政治局常委、中央纪委书记李希同卡卡尔总理举行会见。两国领导人在亲切友好的气氛中，就深化中巴全天候战略合作伙伴关系、各领域务实合作以及共同关心的国际地区问题深入交换意见，达成广泛共识。双方重申，相互信任是中巴关系的核心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3.双方一致认为，中巴两国是全天候战略合作伙伴和“铁杆”兄弟，两国友谊历久弥坚、牢不可破。中方重申将中巴关系作为中国外交的优先方向。巴方强调，巴中关系是巴基斯坦外交政策基石。双方将继续从战略和长远角度看待中巴关系，在发展道路上携手前行，加快构建新时代更加紧密的中巴命运共同体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4.双方重申在涉及彼此核心利益和重大关切问题上相互支持。巴方重申坚定奉行一个中国原则，台湾是中国领土不可分割的一部分，巴方坚定支持中国政府为实现国家统一所作努力，反对任何形式的“台湾独立”。巴方在南海、涉港、涉疆和涉藏等问题上坚定支持中国。中方重申支持巴方捍卫国家主权、民族独立和领土完整，支持巴方走符合本国国情的发展道路并实现经济稳定，支持巴方打击恐怖主义，支持巴方在国际和地区事务中发挥更大作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5.巴方热烈祝贺中方成功举办第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛。中方赞赏巴基斯坦长期支持和参与共建“一带一路”倡议。双方一致认为，“一带一路”倡议为世界经济增长提供强劲动力，为国际经济合作搭建平台，为全球共同发展开辟空间，成为广受欢迎的国际公共产品，是构建人类命运共同体的重大实践。双方同意继续加强合作，推动高质量共建“一带一路”，共同开辟和平、发展、合作、共赢的美好未来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6.双方一致认为，中巴经济走廊是共建“一带一路”先行先试项目，启动10年来取得丰硕成果，进入高质量发展新阶段。双方决心共同建设增长走廊、民生走廊、创新走廊、绿色走廊、开放走廊，将中巴经济走廊打造成高质量共建“一带一路”的示范性工程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7.双方认为，瓜达尔港是地区互联互通的重要节点，同意加快推进瓜达尔港配套设施建设。双方满意地回顾了瓜达尔港海水淡化厂、瓜达尔港新国际机场、中巴友谊医院等项目进展情况，重申将瓜达尔港建设成为高质量港口、地区贸易中心和互联互通枢纽。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;8.双方认为，巴基斯坦1号铁路干线升级改造项目是中巴经济走廊框架下重要项目，对巴基斯坦经济社会发展意义重大，同意按照两国领导人共识早日推进实施。双方满意地回顾了中巴喀喇昆仑公路（雷克特—塔科特）改线项目前期工作取得的重要进展，同意予以加快推进。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;9.双方决心共同推动开展DI汗—兹霍布公路项目前期准备工作，为在中巴经济走廊框架下增进巴基斯坦互联互通和社会经济发展增添动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10.中方赞赏巴方大力发展包括光伏在内的可再生能源项目的努力，认为这契合绿色、低碳、环保能源发展方向。双方鼓励中资企业以商业方式参与相关项目的开发和建设，实现双赢。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;11.双方同意积极推进落实《中巴产业合作框架协议》，支持巴基斯坦工业化发展，鼓励中国公司在巴设立制造业企业。双方重申，中巴经济走廊是开放包容、合作共赢的平台，欢迎第三方从产业、农业、信息技术、科技等中巴经济走廊优先合作领域投资中受益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;12.双方同意加强中巴矿业合作，加强地质调查、地矿联合研究、人才培训、矿业产业园区规划等领域合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;13.双方认为，中巴农业合作富有潜力，作物育种、病虫害防治等中巴经济走廊框架下农业合作等项目进展良好。双方同意在农作物种植、动植物疫病防控、农业机械化、农业技术交流、农产品贸易等方面加强合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;14.双方同意在中巴信息技术产业联合工作组框架下加强交流合作，共同提高数字基础设施建设管理水平、高新技术合作和信息技术服务能力，推动数字经济高质量发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;15.双方满意地回顾了两国在中巴经济走廊社会民生工作组框架下取得的积极成效。巴方感谢中方为巴洪灾灾后重建和恢复提供援助。中方愿继续支持巴方改善社会民生和灾后重建，优先实施民生领域援助项目，基于“共同富裕”理念帮助最不发达地区和脆弱人群改善经济社会发展条件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;16.中方愿在中巴自贸协定框架下积极支持巴方扩大对华出口，将通过经验分享、专题研究、专家交流、人员培训等方式帮助巴方提升出口能力。巴方欢迎更多中国企业赴巴投资，愿为其创造良好营商环境。巴方向中方介绍了近期改善投资环境、推出投资鼓励措施以及设立特别投资促进委员会的努力。中方赞赏巴方为促进两国投资和经贸合作所作努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;17.双方注意到近期两国商业交流的增长势头，决定进一步促进商贸往来。双方同意努力提升双边人员往来便利化水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;18.双方注意到，今年以来，两国签署了关于巴基斯坦熟制牛肉、干辣椒输华的议定书，实现了巴基斯坦鲜食樱桃对华准入，并就巴基斯坦乳制品、动物皮对华出口达成一致。中方欢迎更多巴方优质产品和符合条件的企业进入中国市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;19.双方认为，红其拉甫公路口岸在促进中巴经贸往来和人文交流等方面发挥着重要作用。双方宣布红其拉甫口岸常年开放，同意加强边境口岸基础设施建设和管理，改善口岸通行条件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;20.双方对两国本币互换协议、人民币结算清算等合作进展表示满意，一致同意进一步加强两国金融业和银行业合作。巴方感谢中方在财政金融等方面提供的宝贵支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;21.双方表达了通过深化交流、调配资源和合作创新加强长期空间合作的坚定决心，以推动空间科学、空间技术和空间应用领域的重大进展。双方赞赏两国航天机构签署关于国际月球科研站等合作文件，同意进一步探索外层空间，推动两国在前沿空间任务中发挥带头作用，开创一个科学突破和空前发现的时代，以造福人类，促进文明进步。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;22.巴方向中方介绍了查谟和克什米尔地区形势。中方重申，克什米尔问题是历史遗留下来的长期争议，应根据《联合国宪章》和安理会有关决议以及双边协议，以和平方式加以妥善解决。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;23.双方谴责一切形式的恐怖主义。中方肯定巴方为打击恐怖主义作出的贡献和牺牲。双方同意进一步加强反恐合作，促进世界的和平与安全。巴方再次承诺全力保障所有在巴中方人员、项目和机构安全，并将涉华恐袭案件中对中方人员施袭的凶手缉拿归案、绳之以法，中方对巴方作出的巨大努力表示赞赏。双方对双边层面开展的安全合作感到满意，同意继续加强此类合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;24.双方高度评价在“中巴旅游交流年”举办过程中，两国文化交流合作得到加强，双方赞赏在故宫博物院成功举办的“譬若香山：犍陀罗艺术展”，并对“犍陀罗艺术展”在中国继续巡展表示欢迎。巴方欢迎中国文化和旅游部将巴基斯坦列入出境团队游国家名单。双方一致同意继续加强双方旅游业界交流。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;25.双方对两国军队之间的密切合作、信任和沟通表示满意。强调更强的中巴战略防务安全合作是本地区和平与稳定的重要因素，同意保持两军高层交流互访势头，深化军事训练、联合演习、军事技术等领域合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;26.双方重申坚持《联合国宪章》宗旨和原则，维护以联合国为核心的国际体系，维护以国际法为基础的国际秩序，维护以联合国宪章宗旨和原则为基础的国际关系基本准则，维护国际社会团结合作，反对霸权主义和强权政治，坚持建设性和包容性的多边主义，弘扬和平、发展、公平、正义、民主、自由的全人类共同价值。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;27.巴方坚定支持中国领导人在开放、区域互联互通、经济一体化和技术分享方面的远见卓识。巴方将继续支持中方提出的全球发展倡议、全球安全倡议、全球文明倡议，高度赞赏中方为维护发展中国家可持续发展权利所作的努力。上述倡议呼吁国际社会重视发展问题，重振全球发展合作伙伴关系，强调应秉持共同、综合、合作、可持续的安全观，强调尊重世界文明多样性，坚持文明平等、互鉴、对话、包容。双方同意围绕上述倡议加强合作，共谋发展、共筑安全、共兴文明，合力为构建人类命运共同体作出贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;28.双方同意加强在阿富汗问题上的沟通协调，共同维护地区和平稳定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;29.双方对本轮巴以冲突和暴力升级深表关切，呼吁立即停火止战，尽最大努力保护平民，防止加沙发生更大的人道主义灾难。双方重申，解决冲突的根本出路在于落实“两国方案”，建立独立的巴勒斯坦国。国际社会应当以更大的紧迫感增加对巴勒斯坦问题的投入，为推动尽快重启巴以和谈付出更大努力，实现持久和平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;30.卡卡尔总理衷心感谢中国领导人和中国人民给予的热情友好接待，代表巴基斯坦政府和人民盛情邀请习近平主席早日访问巴基斯坦。双方将通过外交渠道就此保持沟通。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;31.访问期间，双方签署20项合作协议，涵盖共建“一带一路”、基础设施、矿产开发、产业合作、绿色低碳发展、健康、航天合作、数字经济合作、发展合作、巴农产品输华等领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（新华社北京10月20日电）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 21 Oct 2023 08:26:02 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>