<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平同俄罗斯总统普京分别向中俄执政党对话机制第十次会议致贺信]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/21/nw.D110000renmrb_20231121_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, November 21, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 20th&amp;nbsp; The meeting was held via video. General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee and President Xi Jinping and President of the Russian Federation Vladimir Putin sent congratulatory messages to the meeting respectively. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In his congratulatory letter, Xi Jinping expressed warm congratulations on the convening of the meeting. He said that at present, changes in a century are accelerating and the world has entered a new period of turbulence and change. Sino-Russian relations have withstood the severe test of the changing international situation and have always maintained high-level development, setting a model for a new type of major-country relations and emphasizing its strategic value in achieving global stable development. Next year marks the 75th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and Russia. China is willing to work with Russia to seize the historical trend and firmly develop China-Russia relations featuring permanent good-neighborly friendship, comprehensive strategic coordination, and mutually beneficial cooperation, so as to effectively promote the development and revitalization of both countries and inject more into the world. Stability and positivity. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that exchanges and cooperation between the Communist Party of China and the United Russia Party are an important part of China-Russia relations in the new era. The dialogue mechanism between the ruling parties of China and Russia has developed into a unique channel and platform for the two countries to consolidate political mutual trust, intensify strategic coordination, and promote mutually beneficial cooperation. It is hoped that the two parties will take the 10th meeting of the dialogue mechanism as an opportunity to demonstrate the responsibilities of major powers and major parties, enrich the connotation of exchanges in the new era, create a new situation of institutionalized exchanges and cooperation, and promote the continuous development of China-Russia relations in the new era, safeguard international fairness and justice, and promote Contribute more to building a community with a shared future for mankind. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Putin said in his congratulatory letter that the Russia-China comprehensive strategic partnership of coordination is at an all-time high. The two countries are jointly promoting many large-scale cooperation projects in the fields of economy, transportation, energy, people-to-people and cultural exchanges, coordinating positions and solving major international issues through bilateral channels and multilateral mechanisms such as the Shanghai Cooperation Organization and BRICS, and promoting the construction of a more just and democratic international order. United Russia and the Communist Party of China, as the ruling parties of Russia and China, carry out high-level and constructive interactions, promoting the rapid development of cooperation between the two countries in various fields. The central agencies and local agencies of the two parties have maintained institutionalized exchanges, exchanged useful experiences in the fields of party building, legislation and society, and conducted in-depth discussions on a series of practical issues on the bilateral and international agenda. It is believed that the dialogue held at the 10th meeting of the dialogue mechanism between the Russian and Chinese ruling parties will be rich in content and constructive, and will further promote and deepen the fruitful cooperation between Russia and China. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平同法国总统马克龙通电话]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/21/nw.D110000renmrb_20231121_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, November 21, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 20th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;On the afternoon of November 20th, President Xi Jinping met with French President Marc Long talks on the phone. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that since Mr. President’s successful visit to China in April this year, exchanges between China and France at all levels have rapidly resumed, cooperation in various fields has been solidly advanced, and many achievements have been achieved. In 2024, we will celebrate the 60th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between the two countries. Both sides should pass on the baton of history, adhere to the original intention of establishing diplomatic relations, continue traditional friendship, and push China-France relations to a new level. China is willing to maintain high-level exchanges with France, successfully hold a new meeting of the China-France high-level people-to-people and cultural exchange mechanism, promote new progress in cooperation in education, culture, scientific research and other areas, and promote friendly exchanges between the two peoples. China appreciates France&#39;s active participation in the 3rd &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum and the 6th China International Import Expo. It is happy to see more French products entering the Chinese market, welcomes more French companies to invest in China, and hopes that France will contribute to China&#39;s France provides a fair and non-discriminatory business environment for enterprises to invest. China is willing to strengthen cooperation with France in multilateral institutions such as the United Nations. This year marks the 20th anniversary of the establishment of a comprehensive strategic partnership between China and the EU. Facing the current chaotic world, China and the EU should remain partners of mutually beneficial cooperation. It is hoped that France will play a constructive role in promoting the positive development of China-EU relations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that China and France have good cooperation in addressing climate change. The 28th Conference of the Parties to the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change to be held in Dubai will take stock of the Paris Agreement for the first time, summarize and evaluate implementation progress, and guide the future global climate governance process. The institutional framework of the Paris Agreement should be maintained, especially the principle of common but differentiated responsibilities and the autonomy of national contributions. China is willing to work with France to send a strong signal to the outside world that China and France are working together to address climate change and promote the success of the United Nations Climate Change Conference in Dubai. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Macron said that I still remember my successful visit to China in April this year and am satisfied with the recent maintenance of exchanges and dialogue between the two countries at all levels. Under the current international situation, it is of great significance for France and China to maintain strategic communication and cooperation. France is willing to take the 60th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between France and China next year as an opportunity to intensify high-level exchanges with China and deepen exchanges and cooperation in the fields of economy, trade, aviation, people-to-people and cultural exchanges. France hopes to communicate closely with China on the United Nations Climate Change Conference in Dubai and continue to cooperate to address global issues such as climate change and biodiversity protection. France is willing to promote the EU and China to further develop a comprehensive strategic partnership in the spirit of mutual respect and mutually beneficial cooperation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The two heads of state exchanged views on the Palestinian-Israeli conflict. The two heads of state believe that the top priority is to prevent the Palestinian-Israeli situation from deteriorating further, especially from a more serious humanitarian crisis. The &quot;two-state solution&quot; is the fundamental way to resolve the cycle of Palestinian-Israeli conflicts. Both sides agreed to continue to maintain communication on international and regional issues of common concern and contribute to maintaining world peace and stability. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平将出席金砖国家领导人巴以问题特别视频峰会]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/21/nw.D110000renmrb_20231121_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, November 21, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 20th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Foreign Ministry Spokesperson Hua Chunying announced on the 20th: In response to South Africa’s At the invitation of President Ramaphosa, President Xi Jinping will attend the BRICS Leaders&#39; Special Video Summit on the Palestinian-Israeli Issue in Beijing on the evening of November 21 and deliver an important speech. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 发挥独特优势  坚定前行信心（全面辩证长远看待当前经济形势·记者观察）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/21/nw.D110000renmrb_20231121_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, November 21, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;To see the trend clearly and identify the general trend, you might as well start by seizing the advantages. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We have the strong leadership of the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core, the institutional advantages of the socialist market economy, the demand advantages of a super-large market, the supply advantages of a complete industrial system, and a large number of high-end products. Talent advantages of quality workers and entrepreneurs. This is the logical starting point for a correct understanding of our country&#39;s economic situation, and it is also the confidence for us to resist risks and overcome challenges. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taking the demand advantage as an example, we have the largest and most potential market in the world. This advantage is scarce around the world. Precisely because of this advantage, we can completely overcome the periodic impact of insufficient aggregate demand. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Great consumption potential. In the first ten months of this year, my country’s domestic sales of new energy vehicles were 6.285 million units, a year-on-year increase of 31.4%. It should also be noted that my country’s automobile consumption still has considerable room for improvement. Overall, my country&#39;s consumption scale still maintains a continuous growth trend, with huge potential and abundant stamina. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The investment space is wide. The high-end, intelligent, and green development of the manufacturing industry has given rise to a large demand for investment in technological transformation and nurtured many new industrial growth points; the steady advancement of new urbanization and agricultural modernization has also provided opportunities for upgrading and accelerating construction of infrastructure. A vast stage. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We will unswervingly implement the strategy of expanding domestic demand, transform the demand advantages of the ultra-large-scale market into a realistic driving force for economic growth, and resolve the phased problem of insufficient total demand. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition to its demand advantage, my country also has the largest and most complete manufacturing system in the world, with solid supply advantages. Coordinating the expansion of domestic demand and deepening supply-side structural reforms will create a higher-level dynamic balance in which demand drives supply and supply creates demand, which will help the national economy achieve a virtuous cycle and continue to recover. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Let’s look at talent advantages. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the reform and opening up, we have relied on the demographic dividend to achieve rapid economic growth as a large country. Today, the demographic dividend tends to decline, but the quality dividend is emerging. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One decrease and one increase coincide with the needs of industrial transformation and upgrading. Looking at a spinning production line, the traditional model requires 50 people to spin 10,000 spindles of yarn, while the smart factory only requires 10 people, but the skill requirements have increased significantly. Looking at the quality of the labor force, the average number of years of education for my country&#39;s new workforce has risen to 14 years, the number of people receiving higher education has reached 240 million, the number of R&amp;D talents ranks first in the world, and the total number of skilled talents exceeds 200 million. These factors are synchronously upgrading, interacting positively, and developing together, and new development advantages are being formed at an accelerated pace. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The vast number of entrepreneurs are deeply involved in industry, the leading scientific researchers are immersed in tackling key problems, and the craftsmen of great countries are concentrating on research. Based on the advantages of talents and seizing development opportunities, we are fully capable of continuously opening up new fields and tracks of economic development and shaping new momentum and new development momentum. Advantage. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The most important thing is that we have the strong leadership of the Party Central Committee and the advantages of the socialist system. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On October 17, the Jakarta-Bandung high-speed railway was officially opened for operation. This is the first time that the entire system, all factors, and the entire industrial chain of China&#39;s high-speed railway have been implemented overseas. It has once again attracted widespread social attention to the achievements of China&#39;s high-speed railway. By the end of 2022, my country&#39;s high-speed rail mileage will reach 42,000 kilometers. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Socialism with Chinese characteristics is the only way to realize the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation. The leadership of the party is the greatest advantage of the socialist system with Chinese characteristics. China&#39;s high-speed rail, which leads the world, is the fruit of integrated innovation in all aspects of my country&#39;s economy, science and technology, and is also a vivid manifestation of the socialist system&#39;s concentrated efforts to achieve great things. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking back at history, from the early days of the founding of the People&#39;s Republic of China, it overcame all difficulties to establish an independent industrial system; to the 1960s and 1970s, when it successfully developed &quot;two bombs and one satellite&quot; under extremely difficult circumstances; In the new era, many problems that have long been wanted to be solved but have not been solved have been solved, and many major things that have been wanted to be done in the past have been accomplished. In just a few decades, our country has transformed from a &quot;latecomer to modernization&quot; to a &quot;country late to modernization&quot;. &quot;The visual center of modernization&quot; relies on the centralized and unified leadership of the party and the advantages of the system. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This advantage has been tested and matured day by day. In the face of major changes unseen in a century, looking at the new journey of building a strong country and national rejuvenation, understanding and grasping the advantages, and giving full play to our respective advantages in the overall situation, opportunities and comparisons, we can effectively deal with the external environment. In the face of uncertainty, we should put the development of the country and the nation on the basis of our own strength, and push our country&#39;s economy to ride the wind and waves and move forward to a higher level. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 李强主持召开中央金融委员会会议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/21/nw.D110000renmrb_20231121_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, November 21, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 20th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee, Premier of the State Council, and Director of the Central Financial Commission Li Qiang presided over a meeting of the Central Financial Committee on November 20 to thoroughly study and implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech at the Central Financial Work Conference, and review plans for the division of labor related to key tasks related to promoting high-quality financial development. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The meeting pointed out that General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech at the Central Financial Work Conference provided fundamental compliance and action guidelines for promoting high-quality financial development in the new era and new journey. It is necessary to thoroughly study and understand the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech, deeply understand the significance of taking the road of financial development with Chinese characteristics, effectively enhance the sense of responsibility and mission to do a good job in financial work in the new era, and work hard and effectively with an enterprising spirit and solid and effective work. measures to fully implement the deployment of the Central Financial Work Conference, accelerate the construction of a financial power, and better serve and support China-style modernization. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The meeting reviewed and approved the division of labor plan for key tasks related to promoting high-quality financial development. The meeting emphasized that efforts should be made to improve the quality of financial services for economic and social development. On the basis of maintaining the stability of monetary policy, we should increase support for major strategies, key areas and weak links, and focus on doing a good job in science and technology finance, green finance, and universal finance. We will publish five major articles on welfare finance, pension finance, and digital finance, and promptly study and introduce specific policies and work measures, grasp the timing, rhythm, and intensity, solidly promote the opening up of the financial industry, and promote the steady and long-term development of the financial industry, and promote the better development and growth of the financial industry. It is necessary to comprehensively strengthen financial supervision, tighten financial risk disposal responsibilities, strengthen department coordination and linkage between departments, while continuing to increase efforts to resolve existing risks, strengthen source control, deepen reforms in relevant fields, and improve risk prevention, early warning and disposal mechanisms , and jointly carry out the task of preventing and resolving risks. It is necessary to uphold the party&#39;s overall leadership over financial work, effectively strengthen party building in the financial system, give full play to the role of party organizations at all levels as a fighting bastion, strengthen the construction of a team of high-quality cadres, strictly perform duties and responsibilities in accordance with the requirements of the division of labor plan, and make every effort to promote the implementation of various tasks Effective. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;He Lifeng and Wu Zhenglong attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 丁薛祥同俄罗斯第一副总理别洛乌索夫共同主持中俄投资合作委员会第十次会议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/21/nw.D110000renmrb_20231121_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, November 21, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 20 On the same day, he co-chaired the 10th meeting of the China-Russia Investment Cooperation Committee with Russian First Deputy Prime Minister Belousov in Beijing. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Ding Xuexiang said that since the beginning of this year, the heads of state of China and Russia have met twice, drawing a blueprint for the development of bilateral relations and cooperation in various fields in the future. China is willing to work with Russia to fully implement the important consensus reached by the two heads of state, give full play to the coordinating role of the China-Russia Investment Cooperation Committee, continue to tap the potential of investment cooperation between the two countries, promote practical cooperation to achieve new results, and continuously enrich the new era of China and Russia. The connotation of the comprehensive strategic partnership of coordination will better benefit the two countries and the two peoples. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Ding Xuexiang put forward four suggestions on deepening Sino-Russian investment cooperation. First, jointly plan a new future for investment cooperation, strengthen planning guidance, and provide guidance for the deepening and solidification of investment cooperation between the two countries. The second is to jointly promote new progress in cooperation in key areas, strengthen support and guidance for enterprises of the two countries, and encourage enterprises that are willing, qualified and capable to strengthen cooperation. The third is to jointly create a new situation for local cooperation, promote regional complementarity, better coordinate trade, investment, channel and platform construction, and deepen practical cooperation in agricultural cooperation demonstration zones, transportation infrastructure and other fields. The fourth is to jointly develop a new vision for long-term cooperation, continue to strengthen docking and coordination, create a good environment, and promote bilateral investment cooperation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Belousov said that the Russia-China comprehensive strategic partnership of coordination for a new era is at an unprecedented high level. Russia is willing to work with China to implement the important consensus reached by the two heads of state, strengthen strategic alignment, give full play to the role of the Russia-China Investment Cooperation Committee, promote practical cooperation between the two sides to produce more fruits, and assist the development and revitalization of both countries. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 韩正集体会见阿拉伯、伊斯兰国家外长联合代表团]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/21/nw.D110000renmrb_20231121_7-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, November 21, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 20th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Vice President Han Zheng met with a group of Saudi Arabian diplomats in Beijing on the 20th A joint delegation of foreign ministers from Arab and Islamic countries led by Minister Faisal, the foreign ministers of Jordan, Egypt, Palestine, Indonesia and the Secretary-General of the Organization of Islamic Cooperation attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Han Zheng said that China highly appreciates the peace efforts and calls for justice of the Special Arab-Islamic Countries Summit, and supports the summit’s joint ministerial follow-up committee to play a greater role. China is deeply concerned about the extremely serious humanitarian situation in Gaza and is accelerating emergency supplies and cash assistance to Gaza. As the rotating chair of the Security Council this month, China is willing to continue to work with Arab and Islamic countries to promote the comprehensive implementation of relevant resolutions of the United Nations General Assembly and the Security Council, and make unremitting efforts to achieve a ceasefire and end of war, ease the humanitarian situation, and return to the &quot;two-state solution.&quot; &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Faisal and others expressed their gratitude to China for its leadership in promoting the adoption of important resolutions by the UN General Assembly and the Security Council. Arab and Islamic countries highly appreciate China&#39;s adherence to principles and upholding justice, and hope to work with China to promote an immediate ceasefire, increase humanitarian assistance, and effectively implement the &quot;two-state solution.&quot; &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 文化企业营收同比增长百分之七点七（新数据 新看点）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/21/nw.D110000renmrb_20231121_8-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, November 21, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/21/01/rmrb2023112101p11_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;Data source: National Bureau of Statistics &lt;BR/>;Drawing: Shen Yiling&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, November 20th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (Reporter Liu Zhiqiang) Data recently released by the National Bureau of Statistics shows that according to a survey of 72,000 cultural and related industrial enterprises above designated size (hereinafter referred to as &quot;cultural enterprises&quot;), in the first three quarters of this year, cultural enterprises achieved operating income of 9.1619 billion yuan, based on comparable In caliber calculation, the year-on-year growth was 7.7%. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The scale of the new cultural format industry continues to grow, and the proportion of operating income continues to increase. In the first three quarters, 16 sub-categories with obvious new cultural business formats achieved operating income of 3.687 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 15.2%, 7.5 percentage points faster than all cultural enterprises above designated size. The operating income of the new cultural business industry accounted for 40.2% of the operating income of all cultural enterprises above designated size, accounting for 2.6 percentage points higher than the same period last year. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The cultural service industry has maintained rapid growth, and the cultural wholesale and retail industries, as well as the cultural manufacturing industry, have shown positive changes. In the first three quarters, the cultural service industry achieved operating income of 4,758.8 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 14.6%, and the growth rate was significantly faster than the overall level of service industry enterprises above designated size. The operating income of the cultural service industry accounted for 51.9% of the cultural enterprises above designated size, accounting for 3.1 percentage points higher than the same period last year. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The total profits of cultural enterprises have grown rapidly, and their efficiency levels have steadily improved. In the first three quarters, the total profit of cultural enterprises above designated size was 750.8 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 31.4%. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 图片报道]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/21/nw.D110000renmrb_20231121_9-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, November 21, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231121/1700508319414_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/ TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;In recent years, Lingshui Li Autonomous County, Hainan Province has focused on the development of rural industries, actively promoted the in-depth integration of &quot;agriculture, fishery + tourism&quot; and other industries, and expanded rural areas New forms of tourism can help people increase their income and become rich. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The picture shows that recently, tourists from many places came to the Xincun Fishing Port in Xincun Town, Lingshui Li Autonomous County for sightseeing and purchasing aquatic products. People and boats came and went, making it a busy scene. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Photographed by Liu Guoxing (Image China)&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https: //feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color :orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 加快发展5G+工业互联网  更好助力推进新型工业化]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/21/nw.D110000renmrb_20231121_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, November 21, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Wuhan, November 20th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The 2023 China 5G+ Industrial Internet Conference opened in Wuhan on the 20th. Zhang Guoqing, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Vice Premier of the State Council, attended the opening ceremony and delivered a speech. He emphasized that it is necessary to thoroughly implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions on new industrialization, implement the deployment of the National New Industrialization Promotion Conference, accelerate the development of 5G+ industrial Internet, and provide solid support for promoting new industrialization and building a modern industrial system. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Zhang Guoqing pointed out that the industrial Internet is an important infrastructure for new industrialization. Under the strong leadership of the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core, my country&#39;s industrial Internet development has achieved remarkable results in recent years. On the new journey, we must thoroughly implement the industrial Internet innovation and development strategy, promote the deep integration of the digital economy and the real economy, and drive the transformation and upgrading of industrial digitalization, networking, and intelligence. It is necessary to further improve network infrastructure, build a solid foundation for key technologies, accelerate the popularization of industry applications, optimize the industrial development ecology, strengthen network security management, and promote the high-quality development of the industrial Internet. We must keep a close eye on the trend of global technology industry changes, and continue to build new competitive advantages and strengthen new development momentum through openness and cooperation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;On the night of arriving in Hubei on the 19th, Zhang Guoqing went directly to the grassroots fire rescue station to inspect the emergency duty situation on site. He stressed that it is necessary to faithfully implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important precepts, focus on the needs of comprehensive rescue for all disasters and major emergencies, strictly carry out professional training and joint prevention and joint training, continue to improve the team’s combat effectiveness and rescue and response efficiency, and maintain emergency preparedness for rapid response at all times. state, and better fulfill the responsibilities and missions of ensuring people&#39;s safety and benefiting the people. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 住房公积金办理更方便（政策解读）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/21/nw.D110000renmrb_20231121_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, November 21, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;In order to better meet the needs of the people for handling housing provident fund-related business in other places, the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development proposed to rely on the national housing provident fund public service The platform and the National Housing Provident Fund Supervision Service Platform integrate personal certification matters such as employee payment certificates, off-site loan payment and deposit use certificates, and loan settlement certificates, and promote &quot;clear codes to handle&quot;. This is the second step in the &quot;trans-provincial handling&quot; of housing provident funds. Another convenient measure for the future. How exactly does the “clear code can be applied for” method provide convenience? What other services can the housing provident fund bring to the people? The reporter recently conducted an interview. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Starting from August next year, “you can check your housing provident fund by showing your electronic code” for personal certification matters.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; It is really convenient to provide information such as deposits and withdrawals in other places instead of paper certificates.&quot; Ding Jiashan, who works in Shanghai, recently bought a house in his hometown of Chuzhou, Anhui, and came to the local housing provident fund management center to handle loan business. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Yanmei, a staff member of the Chuzhou Housing Provident Fund Management Center, said that in the past, off-site loan applications required people to submit paper materials to apply at the loan location after issuing a certificate at the place of deposit. After promoting the &quot;inter-provincial service&quot; of high-frequency housing provident fund services in 2020, people can apply directly at the place where the loan was taken, and the housing provident fund management center of the loan place will contact the place of deposit to verify the payment status, eliminating the need to travel between the two places, but it is difficult to real-time Handle business. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“‘Light the Code to Apply’ improves the convenience of business processing. You don’t have to worry about the expiration of certificates, and also effectively prevents the risk of fake paper certificates. The ‘Light the Code to Apply’ function will be launched on August 2 , as of the end of October, our center had handled more than 670 transactions,&quot; Zhang Yanmei said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development proposed that by the end of August this year, relevant functions will be launched online on the National Housing Provident Fund Public Service Platform and the National Housing Provident Fund Supervision Service Platform, and the &quot;clear code can be processed&quot; will be promoted and used. The original paper The certification and issuance methods will be used in parallel and valid at the same time, with a transition period of one year; starting from August 2024, personal certification matters for housing provident funds will be fully implemented &quot;clear codes can be processed&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Currently, provident fund centers in various regions are accelerating the streamlining and integration of certification materials, adjusting certificate issuance methods, unblocking window inspection functions, and optimizing business processing processes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Promote service matters to be &quot;online, mobile, nearby, and one-time processing&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shanghai promotes the automatic processing of mortgage cancellation of housing provident fund loans, allowing payment &quot;Zero movement&quot; of deposited employees; the Chongqing Housing Provident Fund Management Center promotes data sharing with market supervision, public security, civil affairs, real estate and other departments, and handles many housing provident fund matters online and on the phone... In recent years, the housing provident fund has accelerated the overall The system has developed digitally and built a new digital service model to make service matters easier to handle &quot;online, on the mobile phone, nearby, and at once&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Relying on digital technology, more high-frequency housing provident fund service matters have been &quot;transformed across provinces&quot;. As of the end of 2022, 3,423 offline special windows and 1,043 online special areas have been set up across the country for the &quot;inter-provincial universal service&quot; business. At the same time, functions are constantly being enriched. As of September this year, a total of 120 million depositors have used the national housing provident fund public service platform, a total of 740 million inquiries about personal housing provident funds have been made, and a total of 5.11 million transfers and renewals have been processed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;This year, we continue to expand the scope of the &#39;inter-provincial universal service&#39; service and promote the realization of &#39;inter-provincial universal service&#39; for two service matters such as &#39;rental housing provident fund withdrawal&#39; and early retirement housing provident fund withdrawal&#39;. The number of housing provident fund &#39;inter-provincial services&#39; has increased to 13, allowing more data to go around and less errands for the masses,&quot; said the relevant person in charge of the Housing Provident Fund Supervision Department of the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Optimize policies and give better play to the role of the housing provident fund system&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After more than 30 years of development, the housing provident fund system is helping depositors solve basic housing problems and promote It has played an important role in realizing a place to live. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to statistics, in 2022, the housing provident fund loan interest rate will be 0.9 to 1.35 percentage points lower than the loan market quotation rate (LPR) in the same period. During the repayment period, it can save approximately 208.9 billion yuan in interest expenses for loan employees, with an average of 208.9 billion yuan per loan. This loan can save approximately 84,300 yuan in interest expenses; support 15.3787 million people to withdraw 152.137 billion yuan of housing provident funds for rental housing; as of the end of 2022, the housing provident fund has provided a total of more than 651.8 billion yuan in supplementary funds for the construction of public rental housing (low-rent housing). &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, various regions have continued to explore and optimize housing provident fund policies to more specifically solve the housing problems of young people and new citizens. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After graduating from university, Ms. Zhang, who rented an affordable rental housing in Guangzhou under the &quot;Monthly Payment of Rent&quot; pilot project, said: &quot;The monthly housing provident fund payment is more than 3,000 yuan, and the rent is about 3,000 yuan. Apply for it. After the &#39;monthly rent payment&#39; business, automatic deductions are made every month, as well as deposit exemption and rent discounts, which alleviates the pressure of renting.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, the Guangzhou Housing Provident Fund Management Center has gradually increased rental withdrawals quota, continue to promote the new model of &quot;monthly rent payment&quot;, and explore pilot projects in market-based rental projects to build a multi-level housing provident fund rental payment system covering public rental housing, affordable rental housing, market-based rental housing, etc. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Unexpectedly, individual industrial and commercial households can also enjoy the housing provident fund, apply for low-interest housing loans, and buy a house in the city to settle down.” 35-year-old Zhu Yinlong opened a small barber shop in Yancheng, Jiangsu, and applied for it two years ago As a flexible employee who contributes to the housing provident fund, each person must deposit 2,000 yuan per month. The government will provide subsidies at a rate of 5% of the deposit amount, with a maximum subsidy of 100 yuan per person per month. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the beginning of this year, Zhu Yinlong and his wife took a fancy to a house of more than 90 square meters in the city, with a total price of more than 800,000 yuan. All the 400,000 yuan other than the down payment used a housing provident fund personal housing loan. In 2021, Yancheng launched a program to allow flexibly employed people to participate in the housing provident fund system. As of the first half of this year, 42,500 flexibly employed people have paid into the housing provident fund. Among them, 1,192 families with flexible employment have applied for housing provident fund personal housing loans to purchase houses. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Dalian, Liaoning Province, implements a housing provident fund loan interest discount policy for low-income people, and the maximum annual discount for a single loan is 8,000 yuan; Qingdao, Shandong Province implements a housing provident fund support policy for families with multiple children, allowing families with multiple children to purchase their first self-occupied house , the loan limit of the household housing provident fund will increase by 20%...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The relevant person in charge of the Housing Provident Fund Supervision Department of the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development said that in the next step, in order to better play the role of the housing provident fund system, it is necessary to cooperate with the housing market , housing security and other related policies to form a synergy to continuously amplify the &quot;multiplier effect&quot; of the system; at the same time, vigorously promote the participation of flexible employment personnel in the housing provident fund system, realize the housing provident fund &quot;pay all the contributions, and pay if you are willing to pay&quot;, so that the system benefits more people widely. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 21 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>