<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/<item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 武汉加快建设具有全国影响力的科技创新中心]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/27/nw.D110000renmrb_20231027_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, October 27, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;The technical team of Huazhong University of Science and Technology successfully achieved the overall magnetization of the rotor of the world&#39;s largest single-machine power wind turbine; the research team of Wuhan University revealed The secret of opening a black hole&#39;s accretion magnetic field... Recently, a number of scientific research results have emerged one after another, highlighting the innovative vitality of the city of Wuhan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In June 2022, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized during an inspection in Wuhan, Hubei: “We must completely, accurately and comprehensively implement the new development concept, deeply implement the innovation-driven development strategy, and firmly grasp the lifeblood of science and technology. In our own hands, we will make greater progress in self-reliance and self-reliance in science and technology, continuously improve our country’s development independence, independence, and security, spawn more new technologies and new industries, open up new fields and new tracks for economic development, and form new advantages in international competition. ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The cadres and the masses in Wuhan have kept in mind General Secretary Xi Jinping’s earnest instructions, insisted on taking innovation as the leading strategy for urban development, strengthened research on key core technologies, accelerated the construction of a scientific and technological innovation center with national influence, and created a surge of innovation. The new era hero city. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Build a high-energy innovation platform and enhance innovation source capabilities&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In mid-October, the construction site of Wuhan New City Optics Valley Science Island project was busy, with more than a thousand people The builders accelerated the curtain wall installation of the first phase of the Science and Technology Innovation Center project and the main construction of the second phase. Next year, a large scientific device pre-research platform and a technology sharing service platform will be built here. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Less than 500 meters away, the Wuhan Artificial Intelligence Computing Center and the Wuhan Supercomputing Center stand side by side. &quot;Since the Wuhan Artificial Intelligence Computing Center was put into operation for more than two years, it has provided inclusive computing services to more than 300 companies and universities.&quot; Chen Bin, the head of operations of the computing center, said that the center recently completed the third phase of expansion. The force size doubled. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Wuhan Supercomputing Center will be officially put into operation in November 2022. It is the country&#39;s first diversified cloud service computing power cluster integrating artificial intelligence and supercomputing. &quot;Relying on the &#39;dual centers&#39;, Wuhan can not only use &#39;intelligent computing&#39; to achieve fast and good calculations, but also use &#39;supercomputing&#39; to calculate accurately.&quot; said Li Deren, an academician of the Chinese Academy of Sciences and the Chinese Academy of Engineering. In recent years, Wuhan has been approved to build a national new-generation artificial intelligence innovation and development pilot zone and a national artificial intelligence innovation and application pilot zone. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Focusing on scientific and technological innovation, the &quot;Key Points of Wuhan&#39;s Scientific and Technological Innovation Work in 2023&quot; focuses on building major scientific and technological infrastructure clusters, high-level laboratory construction clusters and national-level industrial innovation platform clusters, and accelerating the cultivation of strategic scientific and technological forces. Since the beginning of this year, Wuhan New City has started construction with the goal of creating a world-class scientific and technological innovation source highland, and a number of large-scale scientific installations such as deep geotechnical disturbance simulation and national major scientific and technological infrastructure have started one after another. Currently, five major scientific installations have landed in Wuhan New City. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, Hubei has focused on major national strategic needs and has successively constructed 10 Hubei laboratories including Optics Valley, Luojia, and Hongshan in the fields of optoelectronics science, aerospace technology, and biological breeding. Many of them are in Wuhan. These laboratories are led by universities, institutions or enterprises to carry out interdisciplinary and cross-field collaborative innovation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Rich scientific and educational resources are an advantage for Wuhan’s development, and they are also the basis for Wuhan to contribute to the country’s high-level scientific and technological self-reliance.” said Guo Yuanqiang, member of the Standing Committee of the Hubei Provincial Party Committee and Secretary of the Wuhan Municipal Party Committee. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Relying on rich scientific and educational resources such as 92 universities and 101 scientific research institutes, Wuhan is accelerating the construction of a major innovation platform. Currently, the city has 155 national-level innovation platforms, 34 national (national) key laboratories, and more than 500 industry-university-research cooperation carriers at or above the municipal level. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Create a first-class innovation ecology and cultivate high-level innovation entities&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Last year, the ‘Guangguang Innovation Forum’ held by the Enterprise Services and Key Project Promotion Bureau of Wuhan East Lake High-tech Zone At Guzao&#39;s special supply and demand docking meeting, through the help of government departments, this chip process heat treatment equipment RTP (infrared rapid annealing furnace) successfully entered the main supply chain of local leading optical communication companies. From January to September this year, sales increased by more than 60% year-on-year. %.&quot; Mao Xin, director of the operation service center of Wuhan Jiayitong Technology Co., Ltd. introduced. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the two years since its launch, the &quot;Made in Optics Valley&quot; supply and demand matching activity has served more than 1,500 high-tech zone companies, matched 237 intended cooperation projects, and helped companies obtain financing worth hundreds of millions of yuan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Stimulating innovation vitality and optimizing the ecological environment for innovation and entrepreneurship are key. Wuhan strives to create a first-class innovation ecology with diverse symbiosis of innovation entities, multi-dimensional fusion of innovation elements, and multi-chain integration of innovation services, cultivate high-level innovation entities, strengthen innovative industrial clusters, and accelerate the transformation of scientific and educational talent advantages into innovation and development advantages. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the production workshop of Huagong Technology Intelligent Manufacturing Industrial Park, R&amp;D personnel from Huagong Technology Industry Co., Ltd. and Wuhan Huazhong CNC Co., Ltd. are jointly testing the technical performance of the products. &quot;If Party A and Party B develop separately, they will not understand each other&#39;s technical processes, and it will be difficult to match.&quot; Chen Jihong, chairman of Huazhong CNC, introduced that since 2022, Huazhong CNC has cooperated with Huagong Technology, the &quot;chain master&quot; unit of Wuhan&#39;s laser industry, to carry out collaboration tackle key problems and help Huagong Technology launch the country&#39;s first three-dimensional five-axis laser cutting equipment intelligent manufacturing production line, increasing production efficiency by 200%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since this year, Wuhan has insisted on deploying innovation chains around the industrial chain and arranging industrial chains around the innovation chain, focusing on advantageous industrial fields such as optoelectronic information, new energy and intelligent connected vehicles, life and health, high-end equipment, and Beidou. Establish a number of industrial technology innovation consortiums - &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Led by Huazhong CNC, together with 12 enterprises and scientific research institutes including Wuzhong, the Hubei Province high-end CNC system industry technology innovation consortium was established; led by YOFC , and 9 units including Fiberhome Communications, jointly built the Hubei Province Optical Fiber and Cable Advanced Manufacturing and Application Industry Technology Innovation Consortium; the Three Gorges Group took the lead in establishing the Hubei Province Smart Integrated Energy Industry Technology Innovation Consortium... These consortiums are to solve key commonalities in the industry Targeting technical issues, we will drive a group of upstream and downstream enterprises in the industrial chain to jointly innovate and promote the common development of industrial clusters. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The innovation environment continues to be optimized, and Wuhan’s industrial innovation capabilities continue to increase. In 2022, Wuhan will have 158 new &quot;little giant&quot; enterprises that specialize in new technologies, and a net increase of 3,503 high-tech enterprises, setting a new record high. The total number will reach 12,654, and the added value of high-tech industries will account for 28.2% of the regional GDP. %; In the first half of this year, 10,345 technology-based small and medium-sized enterprises in Wuhan were evaluated and included in the database, a year-on-year increase of 67.12%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Break up scientific research supply and market demand, and promote the transformation of high-efficiency achievements&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tang Xinfeng, a professor at the State Key Laboratory of New Materials Composite Technology at Wuhan University of Technology, introduced that relying on domestic The first pilot platform for semiconductor thermoelectric chips. The performance of the semiconductor thermoelectric chips developed by the project team has reached the level of internationally renowned companies. Since it was fully operational at the beginning of this year, it has received small batch orders from well-known domestic optical module manufacturers. &quot;Thanks to Minister Liu&#39;s connection, the project can be successfully implemented and transformed.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Minister Liu mentioned by Tang Xinfeng is Liu Yuanlin, deputy director of the Comprehensive Coordination Department of Wuhan Municipal Science and Technology Achievements Transformation Bureau. In recent years, Wuhan has explored the implementation of a &quot;scientific and technological achievements transformation liaison officer&quot; system, selecting more than 300 liaison officers who understand technology, are familiar with the market, and negotiate projects to go to colleges and universities to &quot;find partners&quot; for their scientific and technological achievements. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Wuhan University of Technology has more than 10,000 invention patents alone. At the beginning, we were not sure which ones were suitable for transformation.” Liu Yuanlin and his colleague Hu Wenli served as the first batch of liaison officers for the transformation of scientific and technological achievements. Wuhan University of Technology and Central China Normal University. By visiting a team of academicians and experts, they carefully screened valuable scientific and technological achievements, and organized scientific research teams to connect with enterprises, financial institutions, technology transfer service agencies, etc., and gradually found out the &quot;doorway.&quot; Over the past two years, more than 20 university scientific research projects, such as &quot;semiconductor thermoelectric chip pilot platform&quot; and &quot;preparation and industrial application of special coatings&quot;, have been successfully transformed in Wuhan. The city’s 320 scientific and technological achievement transformation liaison officers have facilitated the implementation and transformation of more than 150 projects. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On September 21, the Wuhan Municipal Science and Technology Major Project &quot;Research on Key Technologies for Ultimate Energy Efficiency and Carbon Reduction in the Ironmaking Process&quot; was launched. The project is led by Wuhan Iron and Steel Co., Ltd., and nine leading universities and enterprises in the field, including Huazhong University of Science and Technology, Wuhan University of Science and Technology, and MCC South, jointly &quot;unveiled the list&quot; and will focus on the core ironmaking process of reducing emissions in the steel industry to carry out key technological research. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This is the twentieth major science and technology project that our bureau has organized and implemented in the form of ‘unveiling the list’ with the goal of breaking through the technological bottleneck of industrial development.” The relevant person in charge of the Wuhan Science and Technology Bureau said that the overall project The funding is 90 million yuan, of which 30 million yuan is government funding, and the first 6 million yuan has been received. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, Wuhan has actively explored the use of the &quot;unveiling the list and taking command&quot; mechanism to organize the research on key core technologies in the industry and the transformation of major scientific and technological achievements, and achieved breakthroughs in a number of key core technologies. Through the &quot;unveiling of the list&quot;, an innovation consortium composed of technology companies and universities and colleges &quot;took the lead&quot; to conduct scientific research on the production line and seek transformation in the laboratory. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By promoting new project management systems such as &quot;unveiling the list&quot; and &quot;directed entrustment&quot;, Wuhan has connected scientific research supply and market demand and promoted the transformation of high-efficiency results. In the first half of this year, the city’s technology contract turnover was 100.406 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 35.36%. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 《深入学习习近平关于民政工作的重要论述》出版发行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/27/nw.D110000renmrb_20231027_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, October 27, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 26th&amp;nbsp; The book &quot;Important Discussion&quot; was recently published by the People&#39;s Publishing House and distributed nationwide. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;This book is guided by Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, and explains the great significance, rich connotation, core essence, spiritual essence, and practical requirements of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important exposition on civil affairs work by topic. Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping has delivered important speeches on civil affairs work many times and made a series of important instructions. He profoundly pointed out that civil affairs work is related to people&#39;s livelihood and connected with people&#39;s hearts, and emphasized that civil affairs work is the bottom-up and basic work of social construction. , clearly requires civil affairs departments at all levels to better perform their duties such as basic people&#39;s livelihood protection, grassroots social governance, and basic social services, and profoundly clarifies a series of directional, fundamental, overall, and strategic issues related to the development of civil affairs. General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important exposition on civil affairs work systematically answers a series of major theoretical and practical issues concerning the reform and development of civil affairs in the new era and new journey. It is a concrete embodiment of the party’s innovative theory in the field of civil affairs and has a strong political and ideological nature. , guiding and targeted, pointing out the direction and providing fundamental guidelines for promoting high-quality development of civil affairs in the process of Chinese modernization. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 中国经济大船将乘风破浪持续前行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/27/nw.D110000renmrb_20231027_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, October 27, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Only by accumulating energy and strength can we climb the slope and overcome the obstacles; only by taking advantage of the momentum and sailing can we move forward through the waves. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out: “China has the institutional advantages of a socialist market economy, the demand advantage of a very large market, the supply advantage of a complete industrial system, and the talent advantage of a large number of high-quality workers and entrepreneurs. &quot;These &quot;four major advantages&quot; profoundly reveal the solid support for my country&#39;s development to remain invincible in the fierce international market competition and the strategic game of major powers. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Those who observe the situation are wise, and those who control the situation win. At present, many contradictions are superimposed and risks and challenges have increased significantly. my country&#39;s development is facing an unprecedentedly complex environment. At the same time, we must note that our country has entered a stage of high-quality development and has many advantages and conditions for continued development. The times and trends are on our side. This is where our strength and confidence lie, as well as our determination and confidence. China&#39;s economy is a giant ship that can withstand storms and tests. By enhancing our awareness of opportunities and risks, accurately identifying changes, responding scientifically, and proactively seeking change, and by pooling our development advantages and enhancing our momentum for development, we are fully confident, confident, and capable of writing a new chapter of the &quot;Two Miracles.&quot; &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Institutional advantages are a country’s greatest advantage and the fundamental guarantee for forming a powerful force to overcome difficulties together. Since the beginning of this year, Shenzhou 16 and Shenzhou 17 have been successfully launched, continuing to write the &quot;Flying Legend&quot;; more than 20,000 national high-tech enterprises have supported the international science and technology innovation center and created &quot;Shenzhen Speed&quot; again; the 19th Hangzhou The Asian Games made a stunning appearance and were praised by the Olympic Council of Asia as &quot;an unprecedented success&quot;; the national autumn grain harvest has exceeded 80%, and the &quot;Chinese rice bowl&quot; is firmly in hand... my country&#39;s socialist market economic system is more systematic, complete, mature and stereotyped , showing extraordinary organizational mobilization capabilities, overall coordination capabilities, and implementation capabilities, providing important institutional guarantees for us to deal with uncertainty. By giving full play to our institutional advantages, we can seize the opportunity to take the strategic initiative to turn danger into safety and crisis into opportunity. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The market is the scarcest resource in the world, and my country is the most potential large-scale market in the world. With a population of more than 1.4 billion, a per capita GDP of over US$12,000, and a middle-income group of over 400 million people, my country has strong capabilities for rapid recovery, innovation leadership, and risk resistance. my country remains the world&#39;s second largest consumer market, the largest online retail market, and the world&#39;s second largest import market for 14 consecutive years. Especially since the beginning of this year, under the influence of a series of policy measures to expand domestic demand and boost confidence, domestic demand has continued to expand, positive factors have accumulated, and the advantages of the ultra-large market remain obvious. Adhering to a people-centered approach will enable the middle-income group to exceed 800 million in the next 15 years and promote the continuous development of ultra-large-scale markets, which will create favorable conditions for the continued improvement of economic operations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;A complete industrial system is my country’s outstanding supply advantage. General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: &quot;Industrial and supply chains must not be disrupted at critical moments. This is an important feature that a large country&#39;s economy must have.&quot; my country&#39;s manufacturing industry has ranked first in the world for 13 consecutive years. In August this year, my country ranked first in global automobile exports. A big country. As the only country in the world that has all industrial categories in the United Nations industrial classification, my country has a complete industrial system, strong industrial organization capabilities and strong supply chain resilience, and occupies an important position in the global industrial division of labor system and supply chain system. Deepening the supply-side structural reform, continuing to focus economic development on the real economy, improving the stability and modernization of industrial and supply chains, and creating a modern industrial system that is independent, controllable, safe, reliable, and highly competitive, we can provide Provide strong material support for economic and social development. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Human resources are an important strength and significant advantage of our country in the fierce international competition. Our country has become a country with the largest and most complete human resources in the world. The total number of human resources has reached 220 million. The total number of R&amp;D personnel ranks first in the world. The demographic dividend still exists, and the new advantages of the talent dividend are emerging. At the same time, a large number of courageous and innovative entrepreneurs in our country have thrived, forming a team of Chinese entrepreneurs with distinctive characteristics of the times, national characteristics, and world standards. They are striving to build a new development pattern, build a modern economic system, and promote the new era. A new force for high-quality development. By thoroughly implementing the strategy of strengthening the country through talent in the new era and accelerating the construction of an important talent center and innovation highland in the world, the land of China is becoming a hot land with great potential and achievements for all kinds of talents. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out that &quot;China&#39;s economic ship will continue to move forward despite the wind and waves.&quot; At present, my country&#39;s economic recovery speed is in a leading position among the world&#39;s major economies, its long-term positive fundamentals have not changed, and its development prospects are bright. By taking advantage of the situation and taking advantage of it, and firmly grasping the institutional advantages of the socialist market economy, the demand advantages of the ultra-large-scale market, the supply advantages of a complete industrial system, and the talent advantages of a large number of high-quality workers and entrepreneurs, China&#39;s economic ship will surely be able to break the waves. Move forward and set sail. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 李强出席上海合作组织成员国政府首脑（总理）理事会第二十二次会议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/27/nw.D110000renmrb_20231027_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, October 27, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231027/1698352337481_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the morning of October 26, local time, the Premier of the State Council Li Qiang attended the 22nd meeting of the Council of Heads of Government (Prime Ministers) of the Shanghai Cooperation Organization member states in Bishkek. &lt;BR/>;Photographed by Xinhua News Agency reporter Yue Yuewei&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Bishkek of our newspaper on October 26 (Reporter Wang Di) On the morning of October 26, local time, Premier Li Qiang attended the 22nd meeting of the Council of Heads of Government (Prime Ministers) of the Shanghai Cooperation Organization member states in Bishkek. Prime Minister of Kazakhstan Smailov, Prime Minister of Russia Mishustin, Prime Minister of Tajikistan Rasulzoda, Prime Minister of Uzbekistan Aripov, First Vice President of Iran Mukhbel, Foreign Ministers of India and Pakistan and Prime Minister of Belarus Go Lovchenko, Mongolian Prime Minister Oyun Erden and others attended the meeting, and Kyrgyzstan Prime Minister Zhaparov presided over the meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Qiang said in his speech that the SCO Summit in July this year further reached important consensus and clarified key tasks on carrying forward the &quot;Shanghai Spirit&quot; and building a closer SCO community with a shared future. China is willing to Work with all parties to implement the spirit of the heads of state meeting. Looking back at the original intention of the SCO, the reason why we have come together is to ensure that regional affairs are decided and handled by regional countries themselves without interference from countries outside the region. At last year&#39;s Samarkand Summit, President Xi Jinping emphasized the need to uphold political mutual trust, mutually beneficial cooperation, equal treatment, openness and inclusiveness, and fairness and justice. This is the key to the success of the SCO&#39;s development and growth. Looking to the future, we must keep in mind our original aspiration and mission, adhere to the path to success, and, guided by the concept of building a community with a shared future for mankind, we must meet each other halfway and achieve mutual success, solidly advance cooperation in various fields, and inject more certainty into the peace and development of the region and the world. and positive energy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Qiang put forward four suggestions on deepening SCO cooperation: First, jointly build a strong regional security barrier, resolutely resist external interference, improve the organization&#39;s response to security threats and challenges as soon as possible, and severely crack down on the &quot;three evil forces&quot; and transnational organized crime. The second is to jointly promote accelerated economic recovery, cooperate to build a safe and efficient transportation system, continue to promote trade and investment liberalization and facilitation, and maintain smooth and smooth industrial and supply chains. The third is to jointly promote the construction of the “Belt and Road”. The third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum was successfully held. In the past 10 years, the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; has become the most popular international public product and the largest international cooperation platform in the world today. It is necessary to strengthen the connection between high-quality joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and the development strategies of various countries, further promote the construction of important economic corridors, and establish the SCO Development Bank. The fourth is to jointly promote mutual understanding and mutual understanding among the people and continuously deepen cooperation in education, culture, tourism, sports and other areas. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Parties participating in the meeting stated that the SCO is committed to promoting the &quot;Shanghai Spirit&quot; and has continued to grow and develop since its establishment 22 years ago, with its international influence increasing day by day. It is necessary to implement the consensus of the Council of Heads of State, jointly combat the &quot;three evil forces&quot; and transnational organized crime, strengthen cooperation in the fields of economy and trade, transportation, agriculture, energy, finance, high-tech, ecological environmental protection, green development and other fields, and promote the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, Improve infrastructure connectivity and deepen people-to-people and cultural exchanges such as tourism and education. All parties agreed to strengthen the institutional building of the SCO, practice true multilateralism, work together to safeguard regional security, promote regional prosperity, and promote the development of the international system in a more inclusive and sustainable direction. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Qiang signed and issued a joint communique with the leaders of the participating member states, approving a number of SCO cooperation documents and resolutions on economy, trade, railways, and mechanism building. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wu Zhenglong attended the meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 神舟十七号载人飞船发射取得圆满成功]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/27/nw.D110000renmrb_20231027_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, October 27, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Jiuquan, October 26, this newspaper&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Liu Shiyao and Gu Yekai) According to the China Manned Space Engineering Office According to the news, at 11:14 on October 26, Beijing time, the Long March 2F Yao-17 carrier rocket carrying the Shenzhou 17 manned spacecraft was ignited and launched from the Jiuquan Satellite Launch Center. About 10 minutes later, the Shenzhou 17 manned spacecraft The spacecraft and rocket successfully separated and entered the predetermined orbit. The astronaut crew was in good condition and the launch was a complete success. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;This mission is the second manned mission for my country’s manned space project to enter the space station application and development stage. It is the thirtieth launch mission since the project was established and implemented. It is also the first launch mission of the Long March series of launch vehicles. Flight 493. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;After entering orbit, the Shenzhou 17 manned spacecraft successfully docked at the forward port of the Tianhe core module of the space station at 17:46 on October 26, Beijing time. The entire docking process lasted about 6.5 hours. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;After the manned spacecraft and space station combination successfully achieved autonomous rapid rendezvous and docking, the Shenzhou 17 astronaut crew entered the orbital module from the spacecraft return capsule. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;At 19:34 on October 26, Beijing time, the Shenzhou 16 astronaut crew successfully opened the &quot;door&quot; and welcomed the Shenzhou 17 astronaut crew from afar to settle in the &quot;Tiangong&quot;. Later, Shenzhou 16 astronauts Jing Haipeng, Zhu Yangzhu, Gui Haichao and Shenzhou 17 astronauts Tang Hongbo, Tang Shengjie, and Jiang Xinlin took a &quot;family photo&quot; to jointly report safety to the people of the country. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In the future, the two astronaut crews will rotate in orbit on the space station. During this period, the six astronauts will work and live together on the space station for about 4 days to complete various scheduled tasks. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;While working and living on the space station, the Shenzhou 17 astronaut crew will conduct multiple extravehicular activities and carry out activities involving basic microgravity physics, space material science, space life science, aerospace medicine, aerospace technology, etc. Conduct a large number of space science experiments in the field, and complete various tasks such as installation, commissioning, maintenance and repair of equipment inside and outside the cabin. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;(For relevant reports, see pages 10 and 19)&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 韩正会见日本前首相福田康夫]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/27/nw.D110000renmrb_20231027_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, October 27, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 26th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Vice President Han Zheng met with former Japanese Prime Minister Fukuda in Beijing on the 25th Yasuo. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Han Zheng said that this year marks the 45th anniversary of the signing of the Treaty of Peace and Friendship between China and Japan. Peaceful coexistence and ever-lasting friendship between China and Japan are in line with the fundamental interests of the two countries and their peoples, and are of great significance to Asia and the world. The people-to-people friendship between China and Japan has a deep foundation and the interests are deeply integrated. The two sides should further strengthen communication and exchanges, deepen practical cooperation in various fields, and achieve mutual learning, mutual benefit and win-win results. China appreciates the unremitting efforts and important contributions made by Mr. Yasuo Fukuda and friendly people in the Japanese cultural circles to promote people-to-people and cultural exchanges between China and Japan. It is hoped that the two sides will strengthen cooperation and play a greater role in improving and developing relations between the two countries and enhancing friendly feelings between the people. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Yasuo Fukuda said that friendly exchanges between Japan and China have a long history and their real interests are closely linked. Carrying out people-to-people and cultural exchanges will help enhance mutual understanding and trust between the two peoples. We are willing to work together to continue to promote cooperation in various fields including cultural exchanges. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 杭州亚残运会赛事精彩纷呈]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/27/nw.D110000renmrb_20231027_7-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, October 27, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Our newspaper, Hangzhou, October 26th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Sun Longfei, Li Yang, Tao Xiangan) October 26th It is the fourth competition day after the opening of the Asian Paralympic Games in Hangzhou. Since the start of this Asian Paralympic Games, the events have been brilliant. Athletes from 44 countries and regions in Asia have pursued their dreams in life, shown their self-improvement, and shared unity and friendship in Hangzhou, Zhejiang. As of 22:00 on October 26, the Hangzhou Asian Para Games has produced 359 gold medals, 356 silver medals, and 430 bronze medals, and a total of 31 sports delegations have won medals. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The Chinese sports delegation achieved great results at this Asian Para Games. The athletes had the courage to challenge and surpass themselves, showing the spirit of continuous improvement and tenacity, which left a deep impression on the audience. As of October 26, the Chinese sports delegation had won 157 gold medals, 128 silver medals, and 108 bronze medals. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The Organizing Committee of the Hangzhou Asian Paralympic Games held a press conference on the morning of the 26th. The person in charge of the relevant parties introduced the development of the cause of persons with disabilities at this Asian Paralympic Games. The preparation and hosting of the Hangzhou Asian Para Games have effectively promoted the development of the cause of disabled people in my country. In the past five years, the development of the cause of disabled people in China has achieved new results and shown a new look. The health level of disabled people has been further improved. The goals of equality, integration and sharing of disabled people have been better realized, and the comprehensive development of disabled people has a more solid foundation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The reporter learned from the media briefing on the preparations for the closing ceremony of the Hangzhou Asian Paralympic Games held on the afternoon of the 26th: The closing ceremony will have the theme of &quot;Flying on the Dream&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Meet Again&quot; and will focus on &quot;ceremony. The three key words of &quot;rhyme&quot; and &quot;emotion&quot;, through the narration of three performance chapters and three short films, show the memory of Hangzhou, the heart of China and the friendship of Asia. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;(Special reports on the Hangzhou Asian Para Games are available on page 5)&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx .best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 绘就全面推进乡村振兴壮美画卷（全面推进乡村振兴）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/27/nw.D110000renmrb_20231027_8-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, October 27, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Wuyuan County, Jiangxi Province is busy in the autumn sun, with newly harvested red peppers, yellow corn, and the white walls of the village The blue tiles, blue sky and white clouds interweave into a beautiful and colorful picture. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The beautiful Zijing Village in Yuhang District, Hangzhou City, Zhejiang Province is very popular. Tourists come one after another to experience making and playing bamboo flutes. The bamboo flute plays music to enrich the people. Last year, the village&#39;s bamboo flute industry had an annual output value of 340 million yuan, and the per capita annual income of villagers reached 53,000 yuan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On October 11, when General Secretary Xi Jinping inspected Shimen Natural Village, Wangcun, Qiukou Town, Wuyuan County, Jiangxi Province, he cordially said to the villagers: “Chinese-style modernization requires both urban modernization and Agricultural and rural modernization, I am very concerned about rural revitalization.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If the nation is to rejuvenate, the countryside must be revitalized. The 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China proposed for the first time the implementation of the rural revitalization strategy, &quot;prosperous industries, livable ecology, civilized rural customs, effective governance, and prosperous life&quot;. The 20 words outline a beautiful picture of the future countryside. The report of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China proposed to comprehensively promote rural revitalization, emphasizing the need to &quot;accelerate the construction of an agricultural power and solidly promote the revitalization of rural industries, talents, culture, ecology, and organizations.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping is obsessed with rural revitalization. During his first domestic inspection after the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping came to Yan&#39;an, Shaanxi, and emphasized &quot;comprehensively promote rural revitalization, implement policies to enrich the people one by one, accelerate the modernization of agriculture and rural areas, and make the lives of the villagers more and more prosperous.&quot; &quot;. In May this year, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized “expanding channels for farmers to increase their income and become rich” when listening to the work report of the Shaanxi Provincial Party Committee and Provincial Government. In June this year, General Secretary Xi Jinping asked to “promote the high-quality development of agriculture and animal husbandry” during an inspection in Inner Mongolia. In September this year, when General Secretary Xi Jinping chaired a symposium on promoting the comprehensive revitalization of Northeast China in the new era in Harbin, Heilongjiang Province, he emphasized that “guaranteing national food security must always be the first priority”...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Regions and departments have put Sincere instructions have been turned into resolute actions, anchoring the goal of building an agricultural power, comprehensively promoting rural revitalization, farmers&#39; income has continued to grow, the rural appearance has been significantly improved, agricultural and rural modernization has reached a new level, and the fields of hope are flourishing. On the new journey, the comprehensive promotion of rural revitalization has been vigorous, providing strong support for high-quality development in the first year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Adhere to promoting agriculture through industry, quality and green agriculture, and build agriculture into a big industry&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Industrial revitalization is the top priority of rural revitalization . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized during his inspection in Jiangxi that “firmly guard the bottom line of food security, promote agricultural industrialization, and promote the integrated development of rural primary, secondary, and tertiary industries” and “adhere to the development of agriculture through industry, quality, and green development.” Agriculture and build agriculture into a big industry.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping attaches great importance to the development of rural industries in terms of the development of local dialects in the fields and the revitalization of farmyards. In April this year, at the lychee garden in Baiqiao Village, Genzi Town, Gaozhou City, Maoming City, Guangdong Province, the General Secretary emphasized that “developing characteristic industries is an important way to achieve rural revitalization. Promote the comprehensive revitalization of rural areas.&quot; In September this year, in Zaozhuang City, Shandong Province, the General Secretary pointed out, &quot;We must build a good brand, improve quality, extend the industrial chain, enhance industrial market competitiveness and comprehensive benefits, and drive more villagers to get rich together.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For China to be strong, agriculture must be strong. Since the beginning of this year, various regions and departments have vigorously promoted the revitalization of rural industries, made every effort to increase grain production capacity, strengthen leaders, supplement chains, develop business types, build brands, and promote high-quality and efficient development of agriculture. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Build a “big granary” and lay a solid foundation for food security in all aspects. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the fields of Xiaolongma Township, Yongnian District, Handan City, Hebei Province, corn harvesters, balers, and planters take turns to advance the autumn harvest and autumn sowing and cropping. &quot;With the help of large agricultural machinery, the implementation of new technologies, and the persistence of field management, the corn yield this year has increased by nearly 100 kilograms compared with last year.&quot; Cuiye family farmer Wang Yafei is working hard. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secure the initiative on food security. Since the beginning of this year, all regions and departments have strictly implemented the joint responsibilities of the party and government for food security, stabilized area, increased yields, increased efficiency, and implemented the strategy of storing grain in the ground and storing grain in technology in the fields. my country has built a total of 1 billion acres of high-standard farmland with guaranteed yields despite droughts and floods, and the comprehensive mechanization rate of crop cultivation and harvesting exceeds 73%. This year&#39;s summer grain output reached 292.3 billion jin, ranking the second highest in history. At present, the autumn grain harvest has exceeded 80%, and a bumper harvest is in sight. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Promote “local specialties” and accelerate the upgrading of the entire chain of rural industries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lush fruit forests stretch along the mountains, cold chain trucks drive on the winding mountain road, and crisp plums in Quanfa Village, Quchi Township, Wushan County, Chongqing usher in a bumper harvest. &quot;Cui Li &#39;lives in the refrigerator&#39; and takes a plane to enter the supermarket. Logistics costs are reduced by 10%. High-quality fruits are sold for more than 15 yuan per catty, and the income has increased a lot.&quot; Sun Zuyong, secretary of the village party branch, said. Wushan Crispy Plums are distributed in 222 villages in Wushan County and have become a &quot;rich fruit&quot; for more than 200,000 farmers. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Luochuan apples, Gannan navel oranges, Zhashui fungus... all regions rely on unique resources to make great efforts to make &quot;local specialties&quot; a big deal, upgrading the entire chain of rural industries and increasing value in all links. Up to now, a total of 180 advantageous and characteristic industrial clusters have been built across the country, with the output value of the entire industry chain exceeding 4.6 trillion yuan, radiating and driving more than 10 million farmers. 300 modern agricultural industrial parks, 1,509 strong agricultural industry towns, and 1,952 national key leading enterprises have effectively promoted the improvement of quality and efficiency of rural industries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Play a good “quality card” and promote high-quality and efficient development of agriculture. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We use organic fertilizer and water from mountain springs. The rice is fragrant and of good quality. We planted 12 acres of terraced rice this year, and the yield per mu reached 1,000 kilograms. The purchase price per kilogram is higher than that of ordinary rice. Quite a bit.&quot; Zou Xunping, a villager in Zhuxi Village, Zhutian Town, Suichuan County, Jiangxi Province, was particularly happy about the bumper rice harvest. Relying on its ecological advantages, Suichuan County has built a green, ecological, and organic rice planting base, and its &quot;terraced ecological rice&quot; sign has become brighter and brighter. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since this year, all regions and departments have insisted on focusing on quantity, quality, and production ecology, and accelerated the comprehensive green transformation of agriculture. The amount of agricultural chemical fertilizers used nationwide has maintained a downward trend for seven consecutive years, the supply of green and high-quality agricultural products has continued to increase, and the total number of valid products with green food and organic agricultural products exceeds 60,000. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Making the countryside more beautiful, making life happier and happier as time goes by&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Livable, workable and beautiful countryside is an important part of building a powerful agricultural country. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On October 11, in Shimen Natural Village, Wangcun, Wuyuan County, Jiangxi Province, General Secretary Xi Jinping urged that &quot;the beautiful natural environment itself is a high-quality resource for rural revitalization&quot; and &quot;make the countryside more beautiful and make life more beautiful.&quot; The more you go, the happier and happier you become.” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For China to be beautiful, the countryside must be beautiful. Various regions and departments have carried out solid rural construction actions to build a livable, industrial and beautiful countryside, and more and more villagers are living a happy pastoral life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Protect green waters and green mountains, making the environment more beautiful and comfortable. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Sunjiagang Village, Qixingtai Town, Zhijiang City, Hubei Province, we are treating sewage, clearing sludge, creating an ecological park, and following the path of integrated development of agriculture and tourism. &quot;Longxugou&quot; has transformed into a scenic spot. The scenery of Shuimei Village is new, and the villagers&#39; &quot;tourist rice&quot; becomes more and more delicious. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The mountains become greener, the water becomes clearer, and the villages become more beautiful. This year, the central government has allocated 7.4 billion yuan in incentives and subsidies for the implementation of the toilet revolution in the whole village. It has arranged 3 billion yuan of investment within the central budget to support the construction of rural residential environment infrastructure, and coordinated the promotion of rural domestic sewage and garbage management. Each village has become more and more beautiful. Pretty. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Improve infrastructure and make rural areas more livable and workable. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Whenever we use water, we have enough water and less scale.” said Ding Jin’e, a villager in Caizhang Village, Shangtang Town, Qingyun County, Shandong Province. By stabilizing water sources, laying water pipes, and improving water quality, the county&#39;s rural tap water penetration rate has reached 100%, and the urban and rural water supply integration rate has reached 100%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking across the country, the completeness of rural infrastructure is gradually improving, the penetration rate of tap water is close to 88%, and the bus access rate of towns and incorporated villages has reached 99.8% and 99.7% respectively. The Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs guides various localities to prepare rural construction task lists, promotes the establishment of county-level rural construction project databases, and continuously improves and upgrades rural water, electricity, gas and telecommunications and other infrastructure. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Optimize public services and make life happier and more comfortable. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The nursing home has activity areas, a medical room, three dishes and one soup for lunch, and life is quite comfortable.” said Xie Shichang, an elderly person living in a nursing home in Lingbei Town, Yudu County, Jiangxi Province.于都县完善养老服务体系建设，不断丰富老年人的晚年生活。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;公共服务更加便利。我国加快建设县乡村三级养老服务网络，紧密型县域医共体建设全面推开，截至去年底，农村义务教育阶段本科以上学历专任教师比例达76.01%，比上年增长3.78个百分点。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 生活富裕、精神富足，广大农民共享改革发展成果&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;生活富裕是乡村振兴的题中应有之义。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记在江西考察时强调，“巩固拓展脱贫攻坚成果，要更多依靠产业发展，不断增强内生发展动力”“确保老区人民共享改革发展成果，过上幸福生活，是推进全体人民共同富裕的底线任务”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国要富，农民必须富。今年以来，各地区各部门继续加大强农惠农富农力度，千方百计拓宽农民增收致富渠道，不断丰富乡亲们的精神文化生活。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——守底线，巩固拓展脱贫攻坚成果。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;帮扶不断档，接力加油干。广西南宁市城厢镇香泉村第一书记黎庆华驻村以来，请专家、跑市场忙个不停，让村里的新产业青木瓜种植渐成规模。 “新产业带来好收入，日子越过越红火。”脱贫户李章年说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巩固拓展脱贫攻坚成果是全面推进乡村振兴的底线任务。壮大产业，稳定就业，精准帮扶，目前全国每个脱贫县都形成了2至3个特色主导产业，7月末全国脱贫人口务工规模3274万人，超过3000万人的目标任务。全国约64%的监测对象消除了返贫风险，其余也都落实了相应帮扶措施，没有发生规模性返贫。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——富口袋，不断拓宽农民增收渠道。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一块地，既有租金又有薪金，每月能挣2000多元，挣钱顾家都不耽误，这日子有奔头。”甘肃省成县二郎乡武坝村村民刘董芳说。乡里通过“党支部+公司（基地）+农户”产业发展模式，把村民紧紧“链”在特色产业上，带动全乡450余人就地务工增收。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;干活有劲头，生活有奔头。今年上半年，全国建设50个国家现代农业产业园、40个优势特色产业集群、200个农业产业强镇，更多农民在家门口发展产业、稳定就业。农村居民人均可支配收入10551元，实际增长7.2%，高于城镇居民2.5个百分点。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——富脑袋，不断提升农民精神风貌。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;河南省封丘县潘店镇南老庄村的农家书屋里，一排排图书整齐摆放，村委会主任王福生说：“农家书屋成了乡亲们的&#39;文化粮仓&#39;，很多村民来查资料、学技术，孩子来这里写作业、看故事书。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前，全国所有行政村都有了农家书屋、电子阅览室和文化活动室。各地区各部门不断健全公共文化体系，大力培育文明乡风、良好家风、淳朴民风，农民文化生活更加丰富多彩，农民精神面貌焕然一新。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乡村振兴潜力无限、大有可为。奋进新征程，让我们更加紧密地团结在以习近平同志为核心的党中央周围，认真学习贯彻习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想，撸起袖子加油干，全面推进乡村振兴，加快建设农业强国，共建越来越多宜居宜业的和美乡村。 &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 追逐梦想  激扬风采（今日谈）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/27/nw.D110000renmrb_20231027_9-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月27日星期五&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;“我真的很喜欢游泳，这种快乐无与伦比”，中国游泳运动员蒋裕燕连续刷新亚洲纪录；“一定要坚持到越过终点线”，中国田径运动员刘盼盼意外摔倒后重新坐上轮椅坚持完赛；“举重让我获得鲜花和掌声，更让我找到了自己”，叙利亚体育代表团运动员努拉·巴杜尔的热爱始终不变……连日来，杭州亚残运会比赛正酣，参赛运动员以拼搏的身姿、灿烂的笑容和积极的心态，展现出自强不息的生命力。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;心相约，梦闪耀。残疾人体育事业是展现精神与品格、凝聚信心与力量、充满关爱与希望的事业。本届亚残运会运动员参赛规模再创新高。这是展示竞技水平和精神风貌的平台，也是彰显生命价值和人生精彩的舞台。北京冬残奥会、杭州亚残运会等赛事的举行，将和平、友谊、关爱的种子播撒在更多人的心中，助力越来越多残疾人追逐梦想、激扬风采。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;习近平总书记强调：“健全人可以活出精彩的人生，残疾人也可以活出精彩的人生。我们每个人都要珍惜生命、追求健康，努力创造无愧于时代的精彩人生。”杭州亚残运会正在进行，一场场奋勇争先的精彩赛事，背后是一个个点燃希望、成就梦想的感人故事。赛场内，奏响生命强音；赛场外，创造精彩人生。勇于挑战、超越自我，每个人都可以取得不俗成绩，书写不凡篇章。 &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 为推动两国关系健康稳定发展发挥建设性作用]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/27/nw.D110000renmrb_20231027_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月27日星期五&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;10月25日，国家主席习近平向美中关系全国委员会年度颁奖晚宴致贺信。接受本报记者采访的中美人士认为，习近平主席的贺信对于引领中美关系健康发展具有重要意义，中美关系的重要性早已超越了两国本身，对于世界的和平与繁荣都意义深远&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10月25日，国家主席习近平向美中关系全国委员会年度颁奖晚宴致贺信。习近平主席指出，作为两个世界大国，中美能否确立正确相处之道，攸关世界和平发展和人类前途命运。 China is willing to adhere to the three principles of mutual respect, peaceful coexistence, and win-win cooperation to promote mutually beneficial cooperation with the United States, properly manage differences, and work together to respond to global challenges, achieve mutual success and common prosperity, and benefit both countries and the world. It is hoped that the National Committee on U.S.-China Relations and friends from all walks of life will continue to care and support Sino-U.S. relations and play a constructive role in promoting the healthy and stable development of bilateral relations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;接受本报记者采访的中美人士认为，习近平主席的贺信对于引领中美关系健康发展具有重要意义，中美关系的重要性早已超越了两国本身，对于世界的和平与繁荣都意义深远。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“体现了中方对中美关系的高度重视”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国驻美国大使谢锋表示，习近平主席的贺信深刻阐明了中美确立正确相处之道的必要性和重要性，鲜明表达了中方推动中美关系健康稳定发展的良好意愿。中方始终认为两国应该是伙伴而不是对手，始终相信中美应该互利共赢而不是零和博弈，始终期待中美关系稳下来、好起来而不是滑向冲突对抗。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国艾奥瓦州马斯卡廷中国友好委员会主席丹·斯泰恩说，习近平主席的贺信对引领两国关系发展具有重要意义。 “当前世界上存在很多需要解决的问题，如果美国和中国能够保持合作，将让世界变得更美好。”斯泰恩说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国新墨西哥州立大学教授肯尼思·哈蒙德表示，习近平主席在贺信中强调了相互尊重的重要性。当今世界面临许多严峻挑战，包括气候变化、局部冲突、发展问题等，这促使各国必须团结起来寻找解决途径。在此背景下，美中两国加深理解与合作显得尤为重要。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“习近平主席的贺信，体现了中方对中美关系的高度重视。”外交学院副院长高飞对记者表示，习近平主席强调，中美关系基础在民间，希望在人民，未来在青年，活力在地方。美中关系全国委员会长期以来为促进两国人民相互了解发挥了建设性作用。高飞说，习近平主席在贺信中再次重申了相互尊重、和平共处、合作共赢三原则，“为推动中美关系健康稳定发展指明了方向，也展现了中方对美政策始终保持连续性和稳定性”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; “两国关系对于彼此及世界的和平繁荣至关重要”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国库恩基金会主席罗伯特·劳伦斯·库恩说：“两国关系对于彼此及世界的和平繁荣至关重要。”库恩表示，当今世界充满各种各样的挑战，美中两国应坚持相互尊重，坚持和平共处。双方应积极寻找能够开展有效合作、实现互利共赢的领域，例如应对气候变化等。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国丹佛大学国际关系学院教授兼美中合作中心主任赵穗生表示，近期美中关系出现止跌企稳势头，表明两国都意识到稳定双边关系的重要性。作为从事中美关系研究的学者，他希望两个大国能够找到和平相处之道，“美中两个大国的合作不一定能解决世界上所有的问题，但是没有这两个大国的合作，这些问题的解决肯定很难取得进展。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;复旦大学国际问题研究院院长吴心伯说，习近平主席的贺信一方面体现了中方对中美关系持积极和建设性姿态，希望与美国社会的积极力量一道改善中美关系。另一方面，习近平主席在贺信中指出两国要“相互成就、共同繁荣，造福两国，惠及世界”。事实上，这是中方处理中美关系的一贯原则。中美关系不仅关系到两国利益，而且关系到全人类的前途命运。看待中美关系要有大格局和大胸怀，不能只盯着一个国家的利益，这一点非常重要。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; “找到一条通往更美好明天的合作共赢之路”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美中关系全国委员会会长欧伦斯说，美中关系近来获得改善，两国民间纽带依然牢固。在美中关系面临挑战时，更应看到两国关系中“光明的一面”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界粮食奖基金会荣誉主席、美国前驻柬埔寨大使肯尼斯·奎因表示，美国和中国作为两个大国、世界前两大经济体，在应对人类社会面临的重大挑战方面展开合作，将发挥巨大潜力。例如，双方可以为维护世界粮食安全、促进非洲发展等开展合作。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哈蒙德认为，中国一直主张通过合作来解决美中之间的许多问题。过去几十年来，中国实现了数亿人摆脱贫困，中国人民的生活水平显著提高，经济社会快速发展，中国成为全球事务中重要的、负责任的参与者。他期待美中能相向而行，“找到一条通往更美好明天的合作共赢之路”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;赵穗生说，从习近平主席贺信中可以看出，中国领导人对中美合作的重要性有着深刻认识。两国关系保持稳定，世界才会稳定，两国合作对于世界来说都是利好。美中关系的过去表明，民间交往对促进两国关系发展起了重要积极作用。 “脱钩断链”、相互制裁，都是损人不利己的行为。当前，美中两国需要作出更大努力，通过各界参与支持，加强沟通、促进理解、寻找共赢之道。 &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 李强会见蒙古国总理奥云额尔登]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/27/nw.D110000renmrb_20231027_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月27日星期五&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-10/27/02/rmrb2023102702p12_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;当地时间10月26日下午，国务院总理李强在比什凯克出席上海合作组织成员国政府首脑（总理）理事会第二十二次会议期间会见蒙古国总理奥云额尔登。 &lt;BR/>;新华社记者殷博古摄&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;本报比什凯克10月26日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者王迪）当地时间10月26日下午，国务院总理李强在比什凯克出席上海合作组织成员国政府首脑（总理）理事会第二十二次会议期间会见蒙古国总理奥云额尔登。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李强表示，中蒙两国山水毗邻，友好与合作一直是双边关系的主基调。习近平主席同呼日勒苏赫总统前不久在北京举行富有成果的会晤，就推进中蒙命运共同体建设、深化共建“一带一路”合作等达成一系列重要共识，为双边关系健康稳定发展提供了战略引领。中方愿同蒙方落实好两国元首共识，始终做可以信赖和倚重的好邻居、好兄弟，以明年两国建交75周年和建立全面战略伙伴关系10周年为契机，弘扬友好传统，筑牢政治互信，加强各领域交流合作，为各自发展振兴提供更多动力，为两国人民创造更多福祉。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李强指出，中方愿同蒙方坚定支持彼此维护主权、独立和领土完整，在涉及彼此核心利益和重大关切问题上坚定相互理解和支持。双方要继续深化互利合作，巩固好存量，谋划好增量，加强口岸互联互通、经贸、绿色发展等领域合作，进一步做大共同利益蛋糕，更好实现共赢。中方愿同蒙方加强在上合组织等多边框架内合作，更好维护两国共同利益，推动构建人类命运共同体。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥云额尔登表示，近年来，蒙中全面战略伙伴关系不断深化，两国高层交往密切，相互了解不断加深，经贸合作迅速发展。蒙方坚定恪守一个中国原则，反对外部势力干涉中国内政，愿同中方一道，不断增进政治互信和相互支持，紧密对接双方提出的发展战略和倡议，加强边境口岸能力建设和互联互通，推进共建“一带一路”，深化贸易、铁路、绿色、旅游、文化等领域合作，密切多边协作，把蒙中关系推向更高水平。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wu Zhenglong attended the meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 27 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>