<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 欢度国庆佳节  阔步迈向未来（国家繁荣富强 人民幸福安康）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/04/nw.D110000renmrb_20231004_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 4, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;“Unity is strength, confidence is stronger than gold.” At the reception celebrating the 74th anniversary of the founding of the People’s Republic of China, President Xi Jinping The secretary emphasized that &quot;we must strengthen our confidence, inspire our spirits, and work together in unity&quot;, inspiring and motivating hundreds of millions of people to forge ahead on a new journey and build a new era of success. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Celebrate the National Day and stride towards the future. In the past few days, various regions have held various activities to demonstrate development achievements and strengthen confidence in moving forward; various regions have intensified efforts to ensure the supply and stable prices of people&#39;s livelihood commodities. During the holidays, cultural tourism and catering consumption are in strong demand, boosting market confidence; people enjoy green waters and lush mountains. Enjoy the beauty of nature, go into the fields and share the joy of harvest, and the land of China is full of new vitality. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Achievements are exciting&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Goals are inspiring&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; During the National Day holiday, various places continue to hold The series of activities make people deeply feel that achievements are exciting and goals are inspiring. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Hangzhou, Zhejiang, the Qiaoxi historical and cultural district beside the canal has been renovated, and Asian Games mascots and other Asian Games logos have given the old district new vitality. On the occasion of the National Day, the interactive intangible cultural heritage experiences such as tea ordering skills and guqin playing, as well as neighborhood cultural festival activities such as comic book reading and bamboo weaving experience, attracted enthusiastic participation from Chinese and foreign tourists and athletes. &quot;During the National Day holiday, our family not only watched the Asian Games and admired the canal, the holiday was very meaningful.&quot; Hangzhou citizen Zhang Fan said, &quot;I hope that through the Asian Games, China&#39;s development achievements can be shown to the world, and I also hope that the athletes will spend their time in the poetic and picturesque Zhejiang.&quot; Live an unforgettable time.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the farm bookstore of Xiaolu Village, Chengnan Street, Rugao City, Jiangsu Province, Jiang Feng, an instructor from the High-tech Zone Police Station of the Rugao City Public Security Bureau who visited the area during the National Day holiday, sat in front of the screen with the villagers Watch Asian Games games. &quot;To share the glory of the Asian Games, we must not only cheer for the athletes, but also learn from their fighting spirit, enhance their skills in daily duty training, and protect the safety of people&#39;s lives and property,&quot; Jiang Feng said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the comprehensive training hall of the Sports School of Xiangtan City, Hunan Province, gymnastics coach Wang Tianhao gathered the young athletes and cheered for the Asian Games athletes in front of the TV. 7-year-old gymnast Jiang Honghui was very inspired: &quot;My brothers and sisters&#39; technical movements are very standardized and their performance is very stable. I will train harder in the future and strive to one day participate in the Asian Games and get on the podium!&quot;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;On October 3, at the Square of the Miners’ Movement Memorial Hall on Anyuan Road, Pingxiang City, Jiangxi Province, tourists followed the lead reciter to read Comrade Fang Zhimin’s “Lovely China”. Young pioneers wearing red scarves, art enthusiasts wearing red long skirts, and tourists holding red flags merged into a sea of ​​red on Anyuan Mountain. &quot;A series of activities such as Singing Anyuan and Reading Red are held here, allowing us to deeply feel the ideals and beliefs of the revolutionary martyrs and the great achievements made by the country today, which strengthens our confidence and determination to work hard,&quot; said college student Zhong Jiani. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the National Day holiday, cultural venues and scenic spots across Ningxia closely adhere to the National Day theme and launch a series of colorful celebration activities to express their good expectations for the country&#39;s development and create a warm and festive festival atmosphere. At the Pedestrian Street of Xinhua Business District in Yinchuan City, a thousand-person chorus event with the theme of &quot;Celebrating the Beautiful Mountains and Rivers, Singing Together for the Birthday&quot; was very lively. People from all walks of life sang affectionately, praising development achievements and expressing their patriotism. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Consumption continues to heat up&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Market vitality is released&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This year’s Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holidays overlap, creating an even more festive atmosphere The consumption enthusiasm of people in various places continues to heat up. Market sentiment is strong, and colorful new scenes and new business formats stimulate new vitality in consumption, effectively boost market confidence, reflect the huge potential of the consumer market, and also bear witness to the strong endogenous power of China&#39;s economy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Qingdao City, Shandong Province, major scenic spots are crowded with people, and consumer places such as restaurants and supermarkets are booming. According to statistics, in the three days before the holiday, Laoshan Scenic Area received 130,300 tourists. Among them, the average daily number of visitors to many attractions such as Polar Ocean World and Wheat Island exceeded the level of the same period in 2019. &quot;The active market has driven peak passenger flow, the popularity has continued to rise, and consumer demand has been further released.&quot; said Hu Shengrui, director of the Laoshan District Culture and Tourism Bureau. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At 11 a.m., a long queue formed in front of a restaurant in the scenic area of ​​Huangyao Ancient Town, Zhaoping County, Hezhou City, Guangxi. “There are so many customers, so busy!” In addition to allowing tourists to taste local specialties such as steamed pork ribs with black bean sauce, stuffed bamboo shoots, and rice dumplings, restaurant operator Gu Juan also made special pickles that are easy to pack and carry. “We prepared 200 bottles Already sold out.&quot; On that day, Huangyao Ancient Town Scenic Area received 14,830 tourists, a year-on-year increase of 284.60%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trendy consumption scenarios are becoming more and more common, providing young consumer groups with a more distinctive and interesting consumption experience during the National Day holiday. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rappers, skateboarders...the naive pandas are assigned different roles in the illustrations. This creative and diverse exhibition was created by Chongqing Impression City in Yuzhong District, Chongqing, attracting many citizens and Tourists come to &quot;check in&quot;. Mr. Hu, a citizen, said: &quot;Children especially like rich and diversified cultural and artistic experiences, and their holidays are more colorful.&quot; Lang Mingyong, the person in charge of Chongqing Impression City, said that the exhibition has accumulated popularity with its unique style and is welcomed by consumers. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The trumpet is playing loudly and loudly, and an art exhibition is being held at the Jibenggang Art Center in Lhasa, Tibet. The cafes and cultural and creative product exhibition stands here are also very lively. The person in charge of the art center said: &quot;The continued heating up of the tourism market has not only increased the income of businesses, but also expanded the audience and influence of the cultural industry, injecting more confidence and power into development.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Motivated to work hard&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Promote rural revitalization&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Extend industrial chains in various regions, connect agriculture, culture and tourism, and promote the overall development of rural industries Chain upgrade. During the National Day holiday, more small villages became popular tourist destinations, more &quot;local specialties&quot; made &quot;big articles&quot;, the rural environment became more beautiful, farmers&#39; pockets were bigger, development prospects were broad, and they were full of motivation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Judging from online reservations, the number of tourists traveling to rural areas during the holidays will exceed 30,000,” said Ma Yongqi, Party branch secretary of Lingyan Village, Wande Street, Changqing District, Changqing District, Jinan, Shandong Province. Changqing District holds the &quot;Golden Autumn Tourism Festival&quot; event during the holidays to attract more tourists to relax in the countryside. &quot;We will vigorously promote party building to lead the integrated development of agriculture, culture and tourism and promote the revitalization of rural industries.&quot; said Liu Zhenqiang, member of the Standing Committee of the Changqing District Committee of Jinan and director of the Organization Department. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On October 3, in the Sunshine Orchard of Xijiqi Village, Jindegu Township, Nanle County, Puyang City, Henan Province, the pear branches were lush and the growers were busy picking pineapples. &quot;My pears are of high quality and very popular in the market. They can be sold for more than 4 yuan per pound this year!&quot; Guo Zhenqi, a farmer, said with a smile on his face. In recent years, Nanle County has developed high-quality fruit planting according to local conditions and cultivated characteristic forest and fruit planting bases to increase farmers&#39; income and become rich. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Grabbing rice with her left hand and wielding a sickle with her right hand, citizen Zhao Jing came from Kunming City, Yunnan Province to the Maihe Rice Field Cultural and Creative Farm in Dacun Community, Wuhua District, to experience what it’s like to do farm work. “You can experience both traditional farming and Culture, and you can also have a cup of coffee in a coffee house in the field. It feels great.&quot; During the National Day holiday, the Harvest Festival with the theme of &quot;Celebrating Harvest and Promoting Harmony and Beauty&quot; was held in Dacun Community. Tourists walked through the golden fields. Take photos to record the beautiful scenery and share the joy of harvest. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; During the National Day holiday, at the &quot;Huanxi Premium Alliance Exhibition Hall&quot; in Huanxi Town, Jin&#39;an District, Fuzhou City, Fujian, there is a dazzling array of specialty agricultural products such as Guling sweet potatoes, jasmine black tea, chestnut pumpkins, etc., attracting many citizens and tourists. purchase. Not far away, at the 100-acre goose-bill radish demonstration base in Ebi Village, grower Huang Xuekui is busy debugging drip irrigation equipment. &quot;Orders are scheduled until the end of the year! Taking advantage of the good weather, we will speed up the renovation of the mountain fields and strive to achieve radish production this year.&quot; 400,000 kilograms.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Comprehensive reports from our reporters Dou Hanyang, Bai Guangdi, Wang Yunna, Yang Yanfei, Liu Feng, Hou Linliang, Zheng Yi, Jiang Feng, Xu Yuyao, Wang Zhe, Ye Chuanzeng, and Liu Xiaoyu)&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target= &quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx. best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 05:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平致电祝贺穆伊兹当选马尔代夫总统]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/04/nw.D110000renmrb_20231004_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 4, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 3&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;On October 3, President Xi Jinping called Mohammed Mui I would like to congratulate him on his election as President of the Maldives. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that China and the Maldives have a long history of friendly exchanges. China and Malaysia are not only friends who sincerely trust each other and help each other, but also partners who work together for development and common prosperity. I attach great importance to the development of China-Malaysia relations and am willing to work with President-elect Muiz to carry forward traditional friendship, deepen practical cooperation, and promote the future-oriented comprehensive friendly cooperative partnership between the two countries to continuously achieve new progress. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 05:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 坚定信心，振奋精神，团结奋斗]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/04/nw.D110000renmrb_20231004_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 4, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Contemporary China has magnificent mountains and rivers, heroic people and a bright future. At the reception celebrating the 74th anniversary of the founding of the People’s Republic of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: “We must strengthen our confidence, inspire our spirit, work together, continue to climb over obstacles and overcome difficulties, and unswervingly move towards the goal of building a strong country and rejuvenating the nation. March forward bravely with the ambitious goal!&quot;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The vast fields are filled with joy, and various regions have fought hard to win the autumn grain harvest. Grain production throughout the year is expected to have another bumper harvest; corporate workshops are in full swing, and more than 60% of the world&#39;s new energy vehicles are manufactured by Produced and sold in China, the installed capacity of industrial robots accounts for more than 50% of the world&#39;s total. China&#39;s economy is achieving greater breakthroughs and moving to a higher level; the land of China is connected in all directions, and the Guinan High-speed Railway, the Shanghai-Nanjing Coastal High-speed Railway, and the Fuzhou-Xiamen High-speed Railway are now in operation. The mobile China is full of vitality; the sports venues are exciting, and our athletes have achieved great results in the Chengdu Universiade and the Hangzhou Asian Games, inspiring the high enthusiasm of Chinese people at home and abroad... Since this year, under the strong leadership of the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping at the core Under the leadership of the Communist Party of China, hundreds of millions of people have overcome difficulties and fought tenaciously, writing their glory and dreams on the new journey of building a strong country and national rejuvenation, and engraved them in the common memory of hard work and united struggle. A bright future is ahead. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: &quot;The reason why a great cause is great is not only because it is just and grand, but also because it is not smooth sailing.&quot; At present, our country&#39;s development has entered a strategic opportunity A period in which risks and challenges coexist and uncertainties and unpredictable factors increase. To forge ahead on a new journey, we must calmly examine the profound and complex changes in the international situation, comprehensively grasp the arduous and arduous tasks of reform, development and stability, and make long-term and unremitting efforts. We must never imagine that we can achieve our goals smoothly and smoothly with gongs and drums. In the face of the dangers of wading on the beach, the difficulties of climbing, and the difficulties of overcoming obstacles on the way forward, we must strengthen our confidence, inspire our spirits, work together, muster up the courage to overcome difficulties and overcome them, and inspire high-spirited and enterprising people. We must work hard to overcome seemingly insurmountable difficulties and obstacles, continue to create more impressive miracles on earth, and constantly push forward the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Confidence is better than gold, only by self-confidence can we strengthen ourselves. Today, innovation increases ambition, struggle strengthens backbone, and development adds confidence. “The Chinese people can do it, and China can do it.” Looking at history and culture, &quot;Chinese civilization has endured for thousands of years and endured many hardships. This is the miracle of human civilization and the basis for our self-confidence.&quot; Looking at the current economy, &quot;China&#39;s economy is highly resilient and has great potential. , full of vitality, and the long-term good fundamentals will not change&quot;; looking at the future prospects, &quot;with the people in our hearts, the truth in our hands, and the right path of the world, we are full of confidence and strength&quot;... Times and trends are on our side, Strengthen strategic self-confidence, maintain the belief in victory, put the development of the country and the nation on the basis of our own strength, and firmly control the destiny of China&#39;s development and progress in our own hands. No force can shake the status of our great motherland, and no force can Block the progress of the Chinese people and the Chinese nation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;If people have no spirit, they will not stand up, and if a country has no spirit, it will not be strong. Today, not only are there tall buildings all over the land of China, but the building of the Chinese national spirit has also stood tall. In the fight against poverty and backwardness, we worked hard and historically solved the problem of absolute poverty; in the fight against the COVID-19 epidemic, we united as one and withstood an arduous historical test; in the fight against corruption, we fought hard and every step of the way. , promote the anti-corruption struggle to achieve an overwhelming victory and comprehensively consolidate it... Fully understand the long-term, complex, and arduous nature of the great struggle on the road ahead, carry forward the spirit of responsibility and struggle, do not believe in evil, be afraid of ghosts, or be afraid of pressure, dare to fight, If you dare to win, take the initiative in the face of opportunities, rise to the challenge in the face of difficulties, actively respond to risks, and always maintain a high-spirited and enterprising spirit, you will be able to overcome all difficulties and obstacles on the way forward. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Unity is strength, and struggle creates the future. The strongest unity is the unity formed around a clear goal of struggle, and the most powerful struggle is the struggle based on close unity. We must adhere to the principle that &quot;the people&#39;s yearning for a better life is our goal&quot;, firmly &quot;improve and develop the socialist system with Chinese characteristics, promote the modernization of the national governance system and governance capabilities&quot;, and work vigorously to comprehensively build a modern socialist country and comprehensively promote the development of the Chinese nation. We must unite and struggle for the great rejuvenation... Seize the historical initiative, anchor the goal of struggle, and move forward bravely in the right direction. We are even more convinced that as long as we move forward in unison under the banner of the party and move forward unitedly under the goal of the party, Under the strong leadership of the party, we can move forward with confidence, think in one place, work hard in one place, and form a strong synergy to realize the Chinese dream together. We will surely be able to turn the grand blueprint into a beautiful reality. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The journey is like a rainbow, and we are moving forward with great strength. The baton of building a strong country and rejuvenating the nation has historically fallen on our generation. This is a great era for the Chinese people and the Chinese nation to forge ahead into a new era and write a new glorious chapter for Chinese civilization! Let us unite more closely around the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core, fully implement Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, strengthen our confidence, inspire our spirit, work together, and create worthy achievements on the new journey of building a strong country and rejuvenating the nation. The party, the people, and the times are worthy of their new achievements. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 05:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 客流高位运行  运输平稳有序（新数据 新看点）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/04/nw.D110000renmrb_20231004_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 4, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Our newspaper, Beijing, October 3&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Han Xin, Li Xinping, Qiu Chaoyi) Reporter 10 On March 3, we learned from the Ministry of Transport: As the Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday enters its fifth day, the country’s railways, highways, waterways, and civil aviation are expected to carry a total of 53.539 million passengers, a year-on-year increase of 52.5%. Road passenger flow remains high, and transportation is safe, stable, and orderly. . &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Looking at highways, on October 3, highways are expected to carry 33.629 million passengers, a year-on-year increase of 21.8%; highway traffic is expected to be 59.62 million vehicle trips, a year-on-year increase of 55.4%, and a year-on-year increase of 20.2%. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Looking at the railway, on October 3, railway passenger flow will continue to operate at a high level. The railway is expected to carry 16.35 million passengers, a year-on-year increase of 167.1% and an increase of 20.3% over the same period in 2019. It is planned to operate 11,190 passenger trains. Among them, 889 additional trains were opened. The Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway, the Shanghai-Nanjing Riverside High-speed Railway, and the Fuzhou-Xiamen High-speed Railway that were newly opened before the holiday have become the first choice for people traveling along the lines, and passenger flow continues to rise. According to data from China Railway Group, the Guangzhou-Shantou High-speed Railway, which was put into operation on September 26, operates an average of 59 multiple trains every day, carrying a total of 238,000 passengers; the Fuzhou-Xiamen High-speed Railway, which opened on September 28, operates 23 multiple trains every day. , sending a total of 108,000 passengers. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Looking at civil aviation, in the five days before the Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday, civil aviation is expected to send a total of 10.4142 million passengers, with an average daily number of 2.0828 million passengers, an increase of 10.73% compared with the daily average of the five days before the National Day holiday in 2019, and compared with last year An increase of 196.53% over the same period. Data from the Civil Aviation Administration of China shows that in the first five days of the holiday, the civil aviation market operated smoothly and orderly, with 82,875 flights expected, an increase of 114.65% and 2.45% respectively compared to the same periods during the holidays in 2022 and 2019. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 05:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 礼赞劳动美 致敬奋斗者（今日谈）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/04/nw.D110000renmrb_20231004_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 4, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Every holiday, there are always people on duty. The builders of major projects are racing against time, the couriers rushing through the streets and alleys, the drivers and flight attendants on the front line of passenger transportation provide enthusiastic services... Countless people stick to ordinary posts and create extraordinary things in their persistence, interpreting responsibility and responsibility, and serving the people. People can fully enjoy the happy holiday time and contribute. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The struggle is the most touching. General Secretary Xi Jinping spoke highly of the strivers, emphasizing many times that “the journey is long but the only solution is struggle”, encouraged model workers to “inspire more people with your energy, enterprising spirit and perseverance”, and hoped that the broad masses of working people would “rely on the creation of labor to make solid progress” Chinese-style modernization will give full play to the main force role in the new journey of building a strong country and rejuvenating the nation”... The new era is the era of strivers. The great achievements in the new era are the result of the hard work, hard work and struggle of the party and the people, and we must rely on hard work to create a better future. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;There is such an exciting scene - in July this year, General Secretary Xi Jinping inspected Jiangsu. In the intelligent manufacturing production area of ​​a company, he asked the company employees gathered around: &quot;Everyone has the next step.&quot; Are you going to work hard for the goal?&quot; &quot;Yes!&quot; Everyone&#39;s firm and powerful answers made people feel full of confidence and motivation. Let us cheer for labor, pay tribute to the strugglers, roll up our sleeves and work hard, forge ahead and set off again, gathering the majestic power of united struggle and courage to move forward, playing the melody of forge ahead and achieving countless achievements on the new journey. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 05:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 图片报道]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/04/nw.D110000renmrb_20231004_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 4, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231004/1696361066507_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;National Day holiday, Fengnan District, Tangshan City, Hebei Province The Hetou Old Street Scenic Area is full of splendor, and citizens and tourists come to enjoy the scenery and celebrate the festival. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Liu Mancang (Photo China)&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align= &quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231004/1696361073602_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR >;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>; During the National Day holiday, workers at the ±800 kV UHV Yanmenguan Converter Station in Shuozhou City, Shanxi Province stayed at their posts and performed maintenance operations. &lt;BR/>;Photographed by Shi Jiamin (Photo China)&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;&lt;/P>;&lt;!-- /enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 05:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 送电器进农家  看市场谈变化（经济新方位）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/04/nw.D110000renmrb_20231004_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 4, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;&quot;How much is the subsidy for this TV?&quot; &quot;If I buy two more, can the subsidy be stacked?&quot;...Mid-Autumn Festival The festival coincides with the market day. At around 8 a.m., Xingjing Town, Xixia District, Yinchuan City, Ningxia is already busy with traffic. A store at the corner of the street has a small store, but it is fully equipped with home appliances and has an endless stream of customers. According to this year&#39;s policy on home appliances going to the countryside, villagers can enjoy a &quot;500 back for purchases over 5,000&quot; subsidy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since this year, the Ministry of Commerce, the National Development and Reform Commission and other departments have successively issued documents proposing to &quot;solidly promote green smart home appliances to the countryside&quot; and &quot;continue to promote home appliances to the countryside.&quot; Recently, reporters followed delivery trucks as they visited villages and households to hear what dealers, deliverymen and consumers said about the new trend of home appliances going to the countryside and the new changes in rural consumption. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Distributor Li Yiha:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“The subsidy method has changed, but the consumption momentum has not diminished”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; When going to the market in Xingjing Town, you must go to Lao Li’s house to buy electrical appliances. &quot;Our store has been open for almost 15 years and is recognized by people from all over the country.&quot; Li Yiha, the 55-year-old operator, is busy arranging truck loading and delivery. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the early years, Li Yiha once set up a stall in the market to sell radios and cassette players. At the end of 2008, the policy of sending home appliances to the countryside was promoted nationwide. He borrowed more than 20,000 yuan to open a store, paid off the loan in the first year, and saved more than 60,000 yuan. &quot;At that time, I bought a second-hand small truck, and I kept the store during the day and delivered goods at night.&quot; During the peak period in my memory, I could sell more than 20 major appliances a day, and the sales subsidy was more than 100,000 yuan a month. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Back then, it was a &quot;buy first, pay later&quot; approach: villagers relied on their household registration books, ID cards, etc. to buy at subsidized prices. Li Yiha went to the town finance office once a month to receive subsidies for home appliances sold. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Customers can now click on their mobile phones.&quot; Li Yiha took out his mobile phone to demonstrate: &quot;Open the &#39;My Ningxia&#39; APP and click on the &#39;500 back for every 5,000&#39; coupon to directly deduct the price of electrical appliances.&quot; He is optimistic about the rural home appliance market. In recent years, he has opened another branch, rented a 500-square-meter warehouse, and bought a new truck. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The home appliance business in the store has been booming. &quot;The subsidy method has changed, but the consumption momentum has not diminished.&quot; Li Yiha told reporters that in recent years, villagers have been pursuing high quality and convenience when purchasing electrical appliances. The store&#39;s business grew, and he hired a delivery boy. Not only were they delivered to your door, but they were also installed for free. Lao Li’s family became even more famous, and villagers from other places often came to buy them. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ma Mei, a staff member of the Xixia District Commerce Bureau, told reporters that since the launch of home appliances to the countryside, the penetration rate of white home appliances such as color TVs and refrigerators in rural Xixia District has increased from about 20% to more than 90%; local consumption promotion , Subsidy measures to benefit people&#39;s livelihood are introduced from time to time, and holidays such as the Spring Festival and Mid-Autumn Festival usually set off a boom in rural home appliance consumption. During this year’s Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday, Xixia District issued consumer coupons to benefit the people and carried out activities including full discounts on smart home appliances and gas stoves. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Deliveryman Ma Zhixiao: &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“Major appliances are sold more and more, but delivery is easier”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;After counting the goods, loading and fixing the truck, confirming the delivery address, and calculating the route, Ma Zhixiao jumped on the truck and prepared to set off. &quot;Come back and hand over the car before 11pm!&quot; He rolled down the window and shouted towards Li Yiha at the door of the warehouse. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;It&#39;s already afternoon. Can this big truck be delivered today?&quot; In the cab, watching Xiao Ma holding the steering wheel with a relaxed expression, the reporter was a little unconvinced - the big truck carries 6 tons. , there are about ten pieces of home appliances installed in the carriage, and some of them have to be sent to the neighboring districts, counties and rural areas. They are delivered to your door and installed. I am afraid that there is not enough time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Don&#39;t worry, the rural roads are much smoother now, and you have plenty of time to have dinner.&quot; Ma Zhixiao lightly stepped on the accelerator to accelerate, and the truck left the township and sped along the wide intercity expressway. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;33-year-old Ma Zhixiao has been working as a delivery boy at Li Yiha store for 8 years. He has traveled to various townships and villages and is very familiar with the roads in this area. In the early years, poor road conditions were his biggest headache: “In the past, let alone village roads, even the roads out of the town were sandy roads. At that time, you had to leave at 5 a.m. to deliver a truck of goods, and you could deliver it before 12 o’clock at night. It&#39;s good after all.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What&#39;s more difficult is gravel roads and mud roads. &quot;Driving is like sailing a boat. It only hurts your butt if you bump it, but it&#39;s troublesome if you bump the cargo.&quot; One day in 2017 , Ma Zhixiao went to the village to deliver refrigerators. Because he was in a hurry, he drove a little faster and the journey was bumpy. After it was delivered and opened, the buyer happily stretched out his hand to touch it when there was a &quot;crash&quot; and the tempered glass door of the refrigerator shattered to the ground. Xiao Ma and the buyer looked at each other. In the end, I had to go through the after-sales process and get a new one. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As we were talking, we arrived at Xingyuan Village, Liangtian Town, Jinfeng District, Yinchuan City. Entering the village along the four-lane asphalt road, you will see pleasant autumn scenery. Ripe corns are taller than people, and their ears are densely packed on both sides of the road. The truck sped forward, and soon turned onto the cement-hardened entrance road, heading straight to the door of the villagers&#39; homes. &quot;In the past, the journey to the village took half an hour, but today it takes less than five minutes,&quot; Ma Zhixiao said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I took out the delivery note and compared it. It was a side-by-side refrigerator with a capacity of 560 liters. &quot;This model costs just over 6,000 yuan. It has a large freezer space and can freeze half a sheep. It is very popular in rural areas. I have delivered more than 10 units this month.&quot; Xiao Ma recalled that when he first started working as a deliveryman, the villagers bought the most The one is a small three-door refrigerator of 200 liters. Nowadays, large double-door refrigerators are increasingly becoming the first choice. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The life in the countryside is becoming more and more beautiful. In the past, villagers bought electric fans in summer, but now they buy air conditioners. The popularity of water purifiers and range hoods is also not low.&quot; Ma Zhixiao jumped into the truck and sighed. , &quot;More and more major appliances are sold, and delivery is easier.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Consumer Yu Jianfa:&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Smart home appliances The Internet is very convenient.&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At 9 o&#39;clock in the evening, the delivery trip came to the last store. The full moon, like a silver plate, hung on the treetops, complementing the village street lights. The truck stopped at the door of Yu Jianfa, a villager in Xigan Village, Xingjing Town. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The TV I ordered at the town market in the morning was delivered in the evening!” Yu Jianfa saw the reporter rolling up his sleeves to help, so he quickly stopped him, “Xiao Ma and I can carry it into the house! I bought it at the beginning of the year He delivered all our refrigerators, washing machines and air conditioners, and we had a tacit understanding of carrying things together.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This 65-inch ultra-thin color TV is not heavy, and Ma Zhixiao finally carried it into the house alone. . &quot;The TV cabinet is so beautiful!&quot; Xiao Ma exclaimed, making the reporter notice that the TV cabinet in the living room occupies the entire wall. The exquisite wood carvings and meticulous workmanship are pleasing to the eye. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;I saved some money by raising cattle and growing crops, renovated the room, and moved into a new house for the holidays.&quot; After installation and commissioning, Yu Jianfa turned on the new TV, &quot;In 2019, fiber will be introduced into the village, and the income will be With more than 100 channels, this large-screen style is perfect for watching high-definition TV programs.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The early TV signal device used by Lao Yu’s family, the tic-tac-toe antenna, is still lying in the grocery store. &quot;It was originally installed on the roof outdoors. When it was windy or rainy, it had to be specially fixed to barely have a signal.&quot; Later, the villagers also used the &quot;Household Communication&quot; signal receiver, which can receive more than 50 stations, but it still needs Placed in the open air, it is also susceptible to weather effects. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Continuously improving hardware facilities have greatly improved the experience of using home appliances in rural areas. &quot;Tap water was connected to the village at the beginning of 2015. Before that, to wash clothes in a washing machine, you had to fetch water from a well and then pour it in.&quot; Yu Jianfa pointed to a closed wellhead in the courtyard and said that at that time, it took three buckets of water to wash a tank of clothes. , &quot;There is small sand in the well water, which cannot be shaken off after washing, and makes the body very scratchy when worn.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Since the beginning of the fight against poverty, the appearance of the village has become worse day by day!&quot; In Lao Yu&#39;s words Chen Hongxia, the village party secretary who visited her home, said that in recent years, hardened roads have been built, running water has been opened, and wireless networks have become popular. Everyone has made a good living by growing vegetables, and more and more electrical appliances they use are smart models. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yu Jianfa’s washing machine has been replaced by a fully automatic drum type, which can also be operated remotely with a mobile phone. &quot;Nowadays, every household is equipped with wireless network, and smart home appliances are connected to the Internet, which is very convenient!&quot; Lao Yu said while opening various APPs and showing his operation records. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Next time you come to deliver the goods at noon and have a light meal, I will show you how the smart appliances in the kitchen listen to the instructions of the mobile phone!&quot; Yu Jianfa said when leaving. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Coordinator of this issue: Lu&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Li&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 05:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 绿色智能家电下乡如何走深走实（延伸阅读）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/04/nw.D110000renmrb_20231004_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 4, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This year’s Central Government Document No. 1 proposed to encourage qualified regions to carry out new energy vehicles and green smart home appliances to the countryside. Driven by relevant departments, various localities, industry associations, and enterprises have cooperated to promote green smart home appliances in rural areas. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The continued release of policy dividends, the gradual deepening of green, low-carbon, smart, and fashionable consumption concepts, and the new demands of rural consumers for comprehensive upgrades in function, form, and experience of home appliances have provided a platform for the circulation of home appliances. It will bring new opportunities to manufacturers and promote the consumption of high-quality home appliances in county and township markets. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In the first half of the year, sales of green smart home appliances going to the countryside on major e-commerce platforms increased by 12.7% year-on-year. Pinduoduo data shows that in the first half of the year, smart home appliances were favored by consumers in most rural areas, with sales of air fryers increasing by more than 200% year-on-year; small smart home appliances ushered in a sales boom, with sales of electric toothbrushes, fascia guns, health pots, etc. increasing by more than 200% year-on-year. times. Currently, JD.com has opened more than 17,000 home appliance stores in 25,000 towns and 600,000 administrative villages. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“From a market perspective, the youthful trend of home appliance consumption has been further highlighted, and the proportion of the post-90s and post-95s generation in the consumer population has increased significantly.” Xu Dongsheng, vice chairman of the China Household Electrical Appliances Association, said that young people in rural areas Consumers prefer smart and high-end home appliances, and some also pursue personalized and customized products. Judging from some e-commerce platforms, among the information home appliances category, sales of smartphones and tablets worth more than 4,000 yuan have increased slightly in rural areas. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“To promote high-quality green smart home appliances to the countryside, we need to increase high-quality supply and improve consumption conditions.” Xu Dongsheng believes that on the one hand, we must create more marketable and good products. Home appliance manufacturers should focus on the characteristics of the rural market and consumer demand, accelerate the research and development and promotion of products that are cost-effective, easy to operate, and of high quality. On the other hand, it is necessary to weave a dense marketing network and improve the service system. Guide home appliance production, sales, repair, recycling enterprises and e-commerce platforms to sink channels, and set up direct stores, experience stores, service outlets, recycling sites, and front-end warehouses at the county and township levels; improve distribution, installation, repair, and old dismantling , transportation and other integrated services make rural residents happy to buy, use smoothly and worry-free in exchange. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 05:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 扎实推进“一带一路”核心区高质量发展取得新进展新成效（共建“一带一路”·权威访谈）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/04/nw.D110000renmrb_20231004_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 4, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Opening words&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jointly build the “Belt and Road”, follow the trend of the times, and fulfill the destiny of mankind The concept of community adheres to the concept of extensive consultation, joint contribution and shared benefits, practices the concepts of openness, greenness and integrity, and is committed to high standards, sustainability and people&#39;s livelihood goals. It provides Chinese solutions for the reform of the global governance system and has become the most popular international public products and the largest international cooperation platform. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In order to further publicize and interpret General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important exposition on the joint construction of the “Belt and Road” and publicize the rich connotation, core concepts and significance of the joint construction of the “Belt and Road” initiative, from now on, this newspaper will open a &quot; The column “Co-building ‘Belt and Road’·Authoritative Interviews”, through exclusive interviews with responsible comrades from relevant provinces, autonomous regions, municipalities, ministries and commissions, comprehensively describes the characteristics, highlights and experiences and practices of various departments in various places that are deeply integrated into the construction of “One Belt and One Road”, and fully demonstrates the joint construction of “One Belt and One Road”. &quot;One Road&quot; has achieved great achievements and far-reaching influence in the past ten years. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the new era, the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative proposed by General Secretary Xi Jinping has created a new pattern of my country&#39;s opening up to the outside world and has also provided Xinjiang with unprecedented development opportunities. opportunity. Yusu Fujiang Maimati, member of the Standing Committee of the Party Committee of the Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region and Vice Chairman of the People&#39;s Government, recently accepted an exclusive interview with a reporter from Xinhua News Agency and said that after ten years of exploration and practice, Xinjiang has continuously promoted the construction of &quot;one port, two districts, five major centers, and port economic belts&quot; Make new breakthroughs. Embarking on a new journey, Xinjiang will continue to expand the breadth and depth of its opening up to the outside world, and solidly promote the high-quality development of the core areas of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; to achieve new progress and new results. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; core area has achieved fruitful results&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past ten years, Xinjiang has made great achievements in policy communication, facility connectivity, unimpeded trade, financial integration, and people-to-people bonds. We will continue to make efforts to promote the construction of the core area to achieve solid and substantial results. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The “circle of friends” for external exchanges continues to expand. Yusu Fujiang Maimaiti said that Xinjiang enterprises have invested overseas in more than 60 countries and regions, built 4 overseas economic and trade cooperation parks, held 7 China-Eurasia Expo, and nearly 50 Xinjiang commodity exhibitions in neighboring countries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This year, we have increased our efforts to ‘go out and invite in’. The party and government leaders of the autonomous region have intensively held many foreign affairs meetings, received delegations from more than 50 countries, reached a series of cooperation in many fields, and expanded international exchanges and cooperation. New space.&quot; He said that Xinjiang has also strengthened cooperation with Hong Kong and Macao, signed strategic cooperation agreements with Gansu, Qinghai, Ningxia, Tibet and other provinces to jointly promote the opening to the west. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The achievement of building the “Asia-Europe Golden Channel” has been outstanding. At present, Xinjiang has opened 118 bilateral international road transport lines, the Xinjiang-Europe highway has been fully connected, 10 highway ports have been paved with secondary roads, and the second railway with Kazakhstan has been completed and operational. A number of interconnection projects, such as the addition of a second line on the Jinghe-Alataw Pass section of the Lanzhou-Xinjiang Railway and the reconstruction and expansion of Urumqi Airport, are being accelerated. A number of comprehensive capacity improvement projects for logistics hubs such as Alashankou, Horgos and Kashgar are also being implemented intensively. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As of the end of August, there were 70,000 China-Europe (Central Asia) trains passing through Xinjiang, accounting for more than 57% of the country; 8,024 international trains had departed, with an average annual growth of 50.4%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;People-to-people and cultural exchanges with countries co-building the “Belt and Road” have continued to deepen and become more substantial. “Xinjiang has established a cross-border telemedicine service platform with 24 large foreign hospitals. Its foreign scientific and technological cooperation covers 45 countries and regions and more than 400 scientific research institutions. It has signed more than 230 inter-school exchange and cooperation agreements with 25 countries and regions, and has cultivated a total of 95个国家近1.2万名留学生。”玉苏甫江·麦麦提表示，核心区民意基础不断夯实。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;优势产业为核心区高质量发展赋能&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为“一带一路”核心区，新疆具有独特的区位、政策、资源等优势。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“国家延续优化了西部大开发、新疆困难地区、劳动密集型产业等的优惠政策，不断加大对新疆商贸、物流、农业、能源等领域支持力度。”玉苏甫江·麦麦提说，还批复设立一批国家级重点开放平台，出台系列政策支持新疆优势产业加快转型升级、提质增效，为“一带一路”核心区高质量发展提供新动能。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前，新疆正加快形成以油气生产加工、煤炭煤电煤化工、绿色矿业、粮油、棉花和纺织服装、优质畜产品、绿色有机果蔬、新能源新材料等“八大产业集群”为支撑的现代化产业体系。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“三基地一通道”建设全面提速，西气东输一、二、三线和疆电外送第一、二通道相继运行，疆煤外运规模稳步提升，光伏硅基产业不断壮大……玉苏甫江·麦麦提介绍，近年来新疆加快融入新发展格局，不断增强国内国际“两个市场、两种资源”联动效应，为优势产业集聚发展提供强有力支撑。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，新疆还大力发展边民互市贸易、市场采购贸易、跨境电子商务、二手车出口试点等新模式新业态，培育建设了一批进出口产品加工基地，吸引劳动密集型产业集聚，为口岸城市经济社会发展持续注入活力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;在共建“一带一路”中更好造福人民&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“实践证明，新疆开放发展有基础、有优势、有潜力，只要坚持把发展成果落到惠及民生、凝聚人心上，激发出各族干部群众同心同向的奋斗豪情、汇聚起众志成城的磅礴力量，就一定能够实现追赶跨越、后发赶超。”玉苏甫江·麦麦提说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他介绍，目前新疆建成投运民用运输机场达25个，所有地州市开通高速公路，全部县（市、区）实现通二级及以上公路，所有乡镇和具备条件的建制村全部通硬化路。此外，新疆还开通了和田—喀什—乌鲁木齐集拼集运货运班列、喀什至巴基斯坦卡拉奇国际定期货运航线，支持南疆农副产品、电子产品等打通外销渠道，助力南疆稳就业、稳外贸、稳增长、巩固脱贫攻坚成果。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;迈上新征程，共建“一带一路”面临新形势新任务新要求。玉苏甫江·麦麦提表示，新疆将锚定在全面建设社会主义现代化强国中的战略定位，以“一港”（乌鲁木齐国际陆港区）、“两区”（喀什、霍尔果斯经济开发区）、“五大中心”（交通枢纽中心、商贸物流中心、医疗服务中心、文化科教中心、区域金融中心）、“口岸经济带”（沿边开放口岸）建设为主线，实施一批标志性、示范性工程，持续拓展对外开放广度和深度，着力提升核心区在服务国家向西开放、保障国家能源资源安全中的战略地位，为推动共建“一带一路”高质量发展做出新的更大贡献。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（新华社乌鲁木齐10月3日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;记者李自良、刘兵、潘莹、孙少雄）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 05:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 三产融合激发乡村新活力（高质量发展调研行）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/04/nw.D110000renmrb_20231004_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月04日星期三&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;行进在稻田边的小火车、可供游玩吃住的汽车度假小镇、温馨整洁的特色民宿……眼下的黑龙江省牡丹江市西安区中兴村，景色美不胜收，游客流连忘返。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“我打算扩大规模，院子里搭上彩钢顶棚，再摆放些桌椅，让更多游客吃上可口的特色美食。”两年前，村民金明洙返乡经营起汤饭馆，现在一年纯收入有30多万元。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;从“空壳村”到农旅融合发展的“旅游村”，中兴村集体收入由2020年的10余万元，增长到去年的360万元。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;近年来，牡丹江市聚焦农业提质增效，坚持三产融合，激发乡村新活力，让广大乡村走上产业振兴新路。去年，全市农民人均收入近2.5万元。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;在宁安市上官地村的响水·国际稻米公园，温暖的阳光洒在玄武湖上，湖面泛起粼粼波光。微风拂过，湖畔的稻田里稻浪翻滚。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“上官地村的黑土地富含各种矿物质、有机质和微量元素，造就了&#39;石板大米&#39;的优秀品质和口感。”宁安市玄武湖大米专业合作社销售经理陈雨佳的脸上洋溢着灿烂笑容。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;2016年，陈雨佳返乡领办宁安市玄武湖大米专业合作社，坚持绿色生态有机种植，带动本村及周边农民就业500余人。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;如今，合作社有机水稻种植规模从最初的50亩扩大到1800亩，还辐射附近村屯6000多亩，每亩收入从5000元左右提高到近1万元。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;截至目前，牡丹江市绿色有机农产品认证面积接近全市播种面积的50%，培育26个国家农产品地理标志登记产品，绿色有机食品认证数量达到220个。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;在农产品种植环节提质增效的同时，牡丹江市不断推进一二三产融合发展，全市规上农产品加工企业已发展到209户，去年农产品加工转化率达到65%。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;在以种植黑木耳闻名的东宁市，菌种菌袋制作、食用菌机械制造、木耳精深加工等一批产业链上下游企业正加速集聚。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;木耳酱、冻干木耳、即食木耳……东宁山友食用菌科技研发有限公司的展厅内，各色木耳深加工产品琳琅满目。“我们多年来持续深耕黑木耳精深加工领域，着力提高产业附加值，产品进入大型商超、铁路餐饮等。”公司相关负责人介绍。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;目前，牡丹江市已创建5个国家级农业产业强镇、1个国家级和5个省级现代农业产业园，多个产业被纳入国家优势特色产业集群建设名单。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 05:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 前三季度西部陆海新通道班列运输货物同比增长14%]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/04/nw.D110000renmrb_20231004_5-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月04日星期三&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231004/1696361085964_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;图为10月2日，满载货物的列车从钦州港东站驶出。&lt;BR/>;新华社记者张爱林摄&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报南宁10月3日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（庞革平、罗婕）据中国铁路南宁局集团有限公司数据：今年前三季度，西部陆海新通道铁海联运班列运输货物63.3万标箱，同比增长14%。中秋国庆假期，西部陆海新通道重要枢纽车站钦州港东站节日物资及粮食、化肥等重点物资运输需求旺盛。广西沿海铁路公司与港口、海关保持沟通联系，对重点物资实行精准保供、优先运输，优化钦州港东站车辆取送作业，车辆取送时间压缩至60分钟，效率提高33%。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 04 Oct 2023 05:26:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>