<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平会见全国“枫桥式工作法”入选单位代表]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/07/nw.D110000renmrb_20231107_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, November 07, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/07/01/rmrb2023110701p25_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On November 6, the party Together with national leaders Xi Jinping, Cai Qi, Li Xi and others, they met at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing with representatives of units selected for the national &quot;Maple Bridge Style Work Method&quot;. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Li Xueren&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, November 6th&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;On the morning of the 6th, Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, President of the State, and Chairman of the Central Military Commission, cordially met with representatives of units selected for the “Maple Bridge Style Work Method” across the country at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing. He expressed sincere greetings and warm congratulations to them, and encouraged them to continue their efforts and persevere. and develop the &quot;Maple Bridge Experience&quot; in the new era, and make new and greater contributions to promoting the construction of a higher level of Safe China. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cai Qi, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Director of the General Office of the CPC Central Committee, and Li Xi, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Secretary of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection, attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;At 10:30 a.m., Xi Jinping arrived at the East Hall of the Great Hall of the People, and the audience burst into warm applause. Xi Jinping waved to the representatives, communicated cordially with them and took photos with them. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Chen Wenqing, Wang Xiaohong, Wu Zhenglong, Zhang Jun and Ying Yong attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping has made a series of important instructions on adhering to and developing the &quot;Maple Bridge Experience&quot; in the new era. All localities have conscientiously implemented the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s important instructions and closely relied on the masses to explore Innovate and strive to create a safe and stable social environment for Chinese-style modernization. The Central Political and Legal Affairs Commission selected 104 units with the &quot;Maple Bridge Style Work Method&quot; nationwide. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平会见古巴总理马雷罗]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/07/nw.D110000renmrb_20231107_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, November 07, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/07/01/rmrb2023110701p16_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of November 6, President Xi Jinping met with Cuban Prime Minister Marrero at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Ding Haitao&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 6th&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;(Reporter Zheng Mingda) On the afternoon of November 6, President Xi Jinping met with Cuban Prime Minister Marrero at the Great Hall of the People. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that China and Cuba are good friends, good comrades and good brothers. Under the guidance and cultivation of successive leaders of China and Cuba, the two countries have gone hand in hand on the road of building socialism with national characteristics, supported each other on issues involving each other&#39;s core interests, and cooperated closely on international and regional issues, forming an unbreakable bond of trust. . China views and develops the special friendly relationship between the two parties and the two countries from a strategic and overall perspective, adheres to the long-term friendship policy between China and Cuba, and is willing to continue to deepen political mutual trust and strategic cooperation with Cuba, and carry out theoretical discussions and experience exchanges on party and state governance. China will continue to firmly support the Cuban people in opposing foreign interference and blockade and safeguarding national sovereignty and national dignity. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that at the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum, I announced eight actions to support high-quality joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and welcomed Cuba&#39;s active docking, especially in agriculture, The cooperation potential between the two countries should be deeply explored in the fields of tourism, health, science and technology, information and communications, etc., and the cooperation between the two countries should be deepened and solidified. It is hoped that Cuba will continue to make good use of important platforms such as the China International Import Expo to promote more specialty products to enter the Chinese market. In September this year, Cuba successfully hosted the &quot;G77 and China&quot; summit, making important contributions to promoting unity and cooperation among developing countries. China is willing to work with Cuba to continue to safeguard the sovereignty, security and development interests of developing countries. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Marrero conveyed the cordial greetings from Comrade Raul and President Díaz-Canel to President Xi Jinping, and said that he was very happy to come to China to attend the Sixth China International Import Expo. Through this visit, I have a deeper understanding of China&#39;s great achievements in development and the core leadership role played by the Communist Party of China in China&#39;s revolution and development process. President Xi Jinping&#39;s important thoughts on state governance have important inspiration and reference for Cuba and the world. For a long time, China has given Cuba a lot of sincere help, which is of great significance to Cuba in overcoming difficulties and developing its socialist cause. Cuba hopes to further strengthen unity and cooperation with China, firmly support each other, advance with the times to develop their respective socialist undertakings, and better benefit the two peoples. Cuba is willing to work with China to jointly build the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; with high quality, deepen practical cooperation in various fields, intensify communication and coordination in international and regional affairs, oppose hegemony and bullying, and safeguard international fairness and justice. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Wang Yi attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平会见塞尔维亚总理布尔纳比奇]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/07/nw.D110000renmrb_20231107_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, November 07, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/07/01/rmrb2023110701p15_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of November 6, President Xi Jinping met with Serbian Prime Minister Brnabic at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Ding Haitao&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 6th&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;(Reporter Zheng Mingda) On the afternoon of November 6, President Xi Jinping met with Serbian Prime Minister Brnabic at the Great Hall of the People. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that President Vučić came to China not long ago to attend the 3rd “One Belt, One Road” International Cooperation Summit Forum, and this time Ms. Prime Minister came to China to attend the 6th China International Import Expo, which reflected the Serbian side’s Sincere friendship with the Chinese people and a firm belief in developing relations with China. China and Serbia are &quot;iron friends&quot; who have gone through ups and downs and shared weal and woe. The relations between the two countries have a profound history, a solid foundation of public opinion, extensive common interests, and strong motivation for cooperation. In recent years, bilateral relations have continued to operate at a high level, the comprehensive strategic partnership has become increasingly rich in connotation, and practical cooperation has yielded fruitful results. Under the new situation, China is willing to work with Serbia to promote the high-quality development of bilateral relations and better benefit the two peoples. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that both sides should work together to build and operate major cooperation projects between the two countries, promote the China-Serbia Free Trade Agreement to take effect as soon as possible, strengthen cooperation in scientific and technological innovation, deepen cooperation in education, sports, tourism and other fields, and expand Personnel exchanges, inheritance and promotion of China-Serbia friendship. China supports Serbia in pursuing an independent development path and is willing to strengthen multilateral coordination and cooperation with Serbia to jointly safeguard international fairness and justice. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Brnabic said that I came to China to attend the Shanghai International Import Expo in 2019 and visited China again after a few years. I am deeply impressed by China’s rapid development and revitalization as well as President Xi Jinping’s strategic vision and outstanding leadership. admire. Serbia-China relations are solid and sound. China has become Serbia’s largest investment partner. Cooperation projects such as the HBIS Smederevo Steel Plant have changed the development landscape of Serbia. The two countries reached a free trade agreement within half a year, fully demonstrating the firm determination of both sides to further deepen their relations. China has always supported Serbia in safeguarding national sovereignty and dignity, and the Serbian people are deeply grateful for this. Serbia firmly adheres to the one-China policy and looks forward to continuing to support each other with China, continue to promote the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, and deepen cooperation in various fields such as scientific and technological innovation, people-to-people and cultural exchanges. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Wang Yi attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平会见澳大利亚总理阿尔巴尼斯]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/07/nw.D110000renmrb_20231107_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, November 07, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/07/01/rmrb2023110701p14_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of November 6, President Xi Jinping met with Australian Prime Minister Albanese, who was in China for an official visit, at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Ding Haitao&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 6th&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;(Reporter Zheng Mingda) On the afternoon of November 6, President Xi Jinping met with Australian Prime Minister Albanese, who was in China for an official visit, at the Great Hall of the People. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that this year marks the 50th anniversary of Prime Minister Whitlam’s visit to China. Your visit can be said to build on the past and open up the future. With the joint efforts of both sides, China and Australia have resumed exchanges in various fields and embarked on the right path to improve and develop relations. China and Australia are both countries in the Asia-Pacific region and important members of the G20. The two countries have no historical grievances or fundamental conflicts of interest and can fully become partners of mutual trust and mutual success. Both sides should grasp the correct development direction of China-Australia relations amid profound changes in world trends. From the perspective of putting one&#39;s own country first, the world is small and crowded, full of risks and competition. From the perspective of a shared destiny, the world is broad and broad, with opportunities and cooperation everywhere. In the stormy waters of the global crisis, countries are not riding on more than 190 small boats, but on one big ship with a shared destiny. China and Australia should follow the trend of the times, proceed from the common interests of both countries, jointly build a China-Australia relationship that treats each other equally, seeks common ground while reserving differences, and mutually beneficial cooperation, and promote the continuous development of the China-Australia comprehensive strategic partnership. This is in line with the common interests of the two countries and their peoples, in line with the common expectations of regional countries, and will also help the international community better respond to various risks and challenges brought about by the century-old changes in the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping emphasized that at present, the world economy is experiencing increasing instability, uncertainty, and unpredictable factors, and the economies of all countries are facing considerable challenges. Facing the complex external environment, China&#39;s economy has withstood the pressure, stabilized its scale, and improved its quality. China&#39;s development still has a good supporting foundation and many favorable conditions. China will bring valuable benefits to the uncertain world economy with its stable development. Certainty. China&#39;s development cannot be separated from the world, and the world&#39;s development also needs China. &quot;High walls in small courtyards&quot;, &quot;decoupling and disconnection&quot;, or &quot;removing risks&quot; are essentially protectionism, which goes against the laws of the market, the laws of technological development, and the development trend of human society. China pursues a mutually beneficial and win-win opening-up strategy, promotes the construction of a new development pattern, and comprehensively promotes the construction of a strong country and national rejuvenation with Chinese-style modernization. This will bring unprecedented opportunities to countries around the world, including Australia. China and Australia should enhance mutual understanding and trust in peaceful coexistence and achieve common development in mutually beneficial cooperation. Give full play to the potential of the China-Australia Free Trade Agreement, expand cooperation in emerging areas such as climate change and green economy, maintain the global and regional free trade system, and provide a good business environment for the investment and operation of enterprises in both countries. The two governments should support exchanges between legislative bodies, political parties, think tanks, youth, and local governments, create more convenient conditions for personnel exchanges, enhance mutual understanding and mutual understanding between the two peoples, and build a solid public opinion foundation for the friendship between the two countries. China does not engage in exclusive cliques, group politics, or camp confrontation in the Asia-Pacific region. Small circles cannot solve the big challenges facing the world, and small groups cannot adapt to the great changes in today&#39;s world. We must first be vigilant and secondly oppose those attempts to mess up the Asia-Pacific region. China is willing to carry out more trilateral and multi-party cooperation with Australia to support South Pacific countries in enhancing development resilience, coping with climate change and other challenges, and maintaining peace and stability in the Asia-Pacific region in an open and inclusive manner. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Albanese said that he was honored to pay an official visit to China at this historic moment marking the 50th anniversary of Mr. Whitlam’s visit to China. In recent years, China has made amazing achievements in poverty alleviation and development. China&#39;s long-term, stable and sustainable development has benefited Australia and the world a lot. Both sides should respect each other, treat each other as equals and benefit from each other, maintain communication and exchanges, enhance understanding and cooperation, and achieve mutual benefit and win-win results. The Chinese people also have the right to development. I have always been positive and optimistic about the prospects of China&#39;s economy. Australia and China have different political systems, and it is normal to have differences, but differences should not be allowed to define the relationship between the two countries. Australia and China share extensive common interests, and dialogue and cooperation are the right choices. Australia adheres to the one-China policy and is willing to work with China to actively promote the stable development of bilateral relations, intensify economic and trade exchanges, strengthen cooperation in clean energy, climate change and other fields, so as to bring more benefits to the two peoples. Australia is willing to strengthen communication with China on regional affairs such as the Pacific Islands Forum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Yi attended the meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平会见南非副总统马沙蒂莱]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/07/nw.D110000renmrb_20231107_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, November 07, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/07/01/rmrb2023110701p13_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of November 6, President Xi Jinping met with Vice President Mashatile of South Africa at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Ding Haitao&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 6th&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;(Reporter Zheng Mingda) On the afternoon of November 6, President Xi Jinping met with Vice President Mashatile of South Africa at the Great Hall of the People. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that this year marks the 25th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and South Africa, and relations between the two countries have entered a &quot;golden era.&quot; In August this year, I paid my fourth state visit to South Africa, and we unanimously decided with President Ramaphosa that China and South Africa should be strategic partners with a high degree of mutual trust, development partners with common progress, friendly partners with mutual understanding, and partners who uphold justice. Global partners. China is willing to work with South Africa to continuously enrich the connotation of China-South Africa comprehensive strategic partnership and push bilateral relations to a new level. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that China supports South Africa in exploring a modernization path that suits its national conditions and is willing to work with South Africa to further consolidate the foundation of political mutual trust and enhance the level of mutually beneficial cooperation. China is willing to work with South Africa and other African countries to implement China&#39;s three measures to support Africa&#39;s industrialization, agricultural modernization, and talent training, as well as eight actions to jointly build the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; with high quality, and create a number of high-standard, people-friendly, and sustainable Cooperation projects will enhance the strategic nature and sustainability of China-Africa cooperation and promote the building of a high-level China-Africa community with a shared future. Both sides should continue to cooperate closely within the BRICS mechanism, strengthen solidarity and cooperation among developing countries, and promote the development of the global governance system in a direction that is beneficial to developing countries. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Mashatile said that President Xi Jinping’s successful state visit to South Africa in August this year further consolidated the traditional friendship between South Africa and China and injected strong impetus into the future development of relations. President Ramaphosa awarded President Xi Jinping the highest medal of honor, which demonstrates the South African people&#39;s high recognition and gratitude to President Xi Jinping for his significant contributions to promoting South Africa-China friendship. The South hopes to strengthen the alignment of its development strategy with China&#39;s &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative and continue to deepen practical cooperation in various fields. The South highly appreciates China&#39;s contribution to safeguarding the interests of developing countries and promoting world peace, and hopes to continue to strengthen collaboration with China within multilateral mechanisms such as BRICS. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Wang Yi attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平向首届“一带一路”科技交流大会致贺信]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/07/nw.D110000renmrb_20231107_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, November 7, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 6&amp;nbsp; &quot;Congratulatory letter from the Science and Technology Exchange Conference. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum was successfully held, and the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; has entered a new stage of high-quality development. Scientific and technological cooperation is an important part of cooperation in jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. China will carry forward the Silk Road spirit with peace and cooperation, openness and inclusiveness, mutual learning, and mutual benefit as its core, deeply implement the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; science and technology innovation action plan, promote international science and technology innovation exchanges, and jointly tap the potential of innovation growth with other countries. Stimulate the potential of innovation cooperation, strengthen innovation partnerships, promote innovation results to benefit people of all countries, help build high-quality development of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, and promote the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The theme of the first &quot;Belt and Road&quot; Science and Technology Exchange Conference is &quot;Co-building a road to innovation and jointly promoting cooperative development&quot;. It is organized by the Ministry of Science and Technology, Chinese Academy of Sciences, Chinese Academy of Engineering, China Association for Science and Technology, Chongqing Municipal People&#39;s Government and Sichuan Co-sponsored by the Provincial People&#39;s Government and supported by the National Development and Reform Commission, it opened in Chongqing on the same day. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 促进创新成果更多惠及各国人民]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/07/nw.D110000renmrb_20231107_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, November 7, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;The first “Belt and Road” Science and Technology Exchange Conference opened in Chongqing on November 6. President Xi Jinping sent a congratulatory letter to the conference. President Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter aroused enthusiastic responses from the Chinese and foreign guests and people from all walks of life at the meeting. Everyone expressed that they should vigorously promote the Silk Road spirit, thoroughly implement the “Belt and Road” science and technology innovation action plan, strengthen innovation partnerships, and promote innovation results to benefit more countries. People, help jointly build high-quality development of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and promote the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Scientific and technological cooperation is an important part of the cooperation in jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. President Xi Jinping attaches great importance to the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; scientific and technological exchanges and cooperation, and pointed out at the opening ceremony of the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum , &quot;China will continue to implement the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; scientific and technological innovation action plan and hold the first &#39;Belt and Road&#39; scientific and technological exchange conference.&quot; Less than a month later, the first &quot;Belt and Road&quot; Science and Technology Exchange Conference was held, further pointing out the direction for jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and gathering strong impetus to promote science and technology exchanges and cooperation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Dai Gang, Director of the Department of International Cooperation of the Ministry of Science and Technology, said that holding the first &quot;Belt and Road&quot; Science and Technology Exchange Conference is a concrete measure to implement the eight actions proposed by President Xi Jinping to support high-quality joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. &quot;In accordance with the spirit of the congratulatory letter, we will thoroughly implement the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; scientific and technological innovation action plan, regard the construction of innovation platforms as an important carrier, service interconnection and common development as an important direction, regard the construction of an open innovation ecosystem as an important content, and promote various cooperation The measures have been implemented in a solid manner,&quot; Dai Gang said. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Listening to President Xi Jinping’s congratulatory message at the scene, Jakob István, Vice Chairman of the Hungarian Parliament, who came to China to attend the first “Belt and Road” Science and Technology Exchange Conference, said that China has become an important force in world development and has contributed to the world. Peace and stability have injected impetus. China regards scientific and technological development cooperation as one of the solutions to global challenges, and has strengthened scientific and technological cooperation under the framework of jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. We look forward to closer and more pragmatic cooperation between the two sides under the &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; initiative in the future. The Hungarian government and scientists are very happy to participate in it. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;President Xi Jinping’s congratulatory message inspired Li Mingzhang, a second-level researcher at the China-New Zealand Kiwi “Belt and Road” Joint Laboratory who has been engaged in “Belt and Road” scientific and technological exchanges and cooperation for a long time. &quot;Using the joint laboratory as a platform, we will further strengthen the Belt and Road scientific and technological exchanges and cooperation in accordance with the guidance of the congratulatory letter, integrate innovative kiwi fruit variety improvement, major pest and disease prevention and control, safe production and other key industrialization technologies to promote the joint construction of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; The high-quality development of the national kiwifruit industry has brought tangible benefits to the people.&quot; Li Mingzhang said. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;&quot;President Xi Jinping sent a congratulatory letter to the first &#39;Belt and Road&#39; Science and Technology Exchange Conference, which released a very positive signal, indicating that China is paying more and more attention to the scientific and technological cooperation of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; initiative.&quot; Uzbekistan In an interview with Xinhua News Agency, independent analyst Ulazhalieva said that with the advancement of the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, cooperation in the political, economic and humanistic fields continues to deepen, and the scientific and technological field is becoming the focus of attention of all parties. Only deepening Through communication and exchange in the field of science and technology, all parties can form connections at a practical level, unleash creativity, and jointly tap into scientific and technological innovation capabilities. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;&quot;President Xi Jinping sent a special congratulatory letter to the conference, which made everyone feel very excited.&quot; Jia Ziwen, deputy director of the Management Committee of Chongqing High-tech Zone in the Western Science City, said that we will fully integrate into the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative and adhere to the &quot; Pay equal attention to &quot;bringing in&quot; and &quot;going out&quot;, gather high-end elements, strengthen the empowerment of scientific and technological innovation, anchor the goal of building a core carrying area of ​​a nationally influential science and technology innovation center, and effectively promote the construction of the Chengdu-Chongqing twin-city economic circle to be in-depth and practical. . &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cuban scientist Pedele has long been committed to enhancing the special friendly relations between Cuba and China, actively promoting Sino-foreign research cooperation and achieving many breakthroughs. Recently, he wrote to President Xi Jinping to introduce the results achieved by his team, expressing his willingness to continue to promote Cuba-China friendship and contribute to the implementation of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative on a larger scale around the world. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Not long ago, Pedel received a reply letter from President Xi Jinping. In his letter, President Xi Jinping emphasized that “international scientific and technological cooperation is a major trend” and “all countries need to jointly promote the cause of human peace and development through scientific and technological innovation.” With the joy of receiving the reply letter, Pei Dele participated in the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; Science and Technology Exchange Conference. On the morning of the 6th, he heard President Xi Jinping’s letter again at the conference. He was very happy and felt that he had an additional responsibility on his shoulders. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>; &quot;The fundamental starting point and goal of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; initiative is to explore new ways of common development among distant and close neighbors and to open up a &#39;happy road&#39; that benefits all countries and the world. As President Xi Jinping said, we hope that in the new era During this period, cooperation between Cuba and China in various fields, including science and technology, has been continuously deepened to better benefit the people of the two countries,&quot; said Pedele. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;(Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 6)&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 助力共建“一带一路”高质量发展]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/07/nw.D110000renmrb_20231107_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, November 7, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>; &quot;The joint construction of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; has entered a new stage of high-quality development.&quot; On November 6, President Xi Jinping addressed the first The &quot;Belt and Road&quot; Science and Technology Exchange Conference sent a congratulatory letter, solemnly declaring China&#39;s actions and determination to promote international science and technology innovation exchanges and promote innovation results to benefit people of all countries, and to inject new energy into helping the high-quality development of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and promoting the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind. Strong positive energy. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;This year marks the 10th anniversary of the joint construction of the “Belt and Road” initiative. Over the past 10 years, the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; has spanned differences in civilizations, cultures, social systems and development stages, opened up new paths for exchanges between countries, established a new framework for international cooperation, and brought together the greatest common denominator for the common development of mankind. Scientific and technological cooperation is an important part of cooperation in jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. China and relevant co-building countries insist on taking scientific, technological and humanistic exchanges as an important foundation, taking the construction of innovation platforms as an important carrier, taking serving interconnection and common development as an important direction, and taking the construction of an open innovation ecosystem as an important content. From supporting more than 10,000 young scientists from jointly building countries to come to China for short-term work and exchanges, to jointly building more than 50 &quot;Belt and Road&quot; joint laboratories, from implementing a number of &quot;small but beautiful&quot; cooperation projects, to building 9 multinational Technology transfer platform...With the joint participation and promotion of all parties, the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; science and technology cooperation mechanism continues to deepen, the exchanges of scientific researchers become closer, and the results of scientific and technological cooperation become increasingly fruitful. Up to now, China has signed intergovernmental science and technology cooperation agreements with more than 80 co-building countries, jointly building an all-round, multi-level, and wide-ranging &quot;Belt and Road&quot; science and technology cooperation pattern, and yielding solid and heavy &quot;fruits&quot; of cooperation. . &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Currently, the world is undergoing major changes unprecedented in a century, and a new round of scientific and technological revolution and industrial transformation are developing in depth. Scientific and technological innovation is an important engine for the development of human society. To solve the problem of common development, mankind needs international cooperation and open sharing more than ever. Only by strengthening global scientific and technological innovation cooperation, accelerating technology transfer and knowledge sharing, bridging the digital divide, and jointly cultivating new drivers of global development can we create a better future for mankind. As a key force in promoting economic development, improving people&#39;s livelihood and responding to global challenges, scientific and technological innovation is a key area in the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and a key direction of common concern for all countries. We should always be guided by the concept of building a community with a shared future for mankind, aim at high standards, benefit people&#39;s livelihood, and be sustainable, adhere to the principle of extensive consultation, joint contribution, and shared benefits, and promote the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; scientific and technological innovation cooperation to be deeper and more practical, so as to promote more innovation results. Benefit people of all countries and contribute scientific and technological strength to promote the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; has entered a new stage of high-quality development, which is of great significance to leading international cooperation and global development under the new situation. Not long ago, in his keynote speech at the opening ceremony of the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum, President Xi Jinping solemnly announced China&#39;s eight actions to support high-quality joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and proposed a plan centered on &quot;promoting scientific and technological innovation.&quot; The series of practical measures fully demonstrate China&#39;s responsibility as a major country to promote high-quality development of the Belt and Road Initiative with practical actions and work with other countries to make greater contributions to solving problems for all mankind. Facing the future, China will carry forward the Silk Road spirit with peace and cooperation, openness and inclusiveness, mutual learning, and mutual benefit as its core, deeply implement the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; science and technology innovation action plan, promote international science and technology innovation exchanges, and jointly explore innovation with other countries. growth potential, stimulate the potential for innovation cooperation, strengthen innovation partnerships, and promote innovation results to benefit people of all countries. If all parties work together to deepen international cooperation on the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and achieve new development of higher quality and higher levels in the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, they will surely inject new energy into promoting the modernization of all countries in the world and jointly promoting the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind. Strong momentum. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; pursues development, advocates win-win results, and delivers hope. Only through continuous self-improvement and unremitting struggle can we reap abundant fruits and establish long-term achievements that will benefit the future and benefit all people. Let us take the first “Belt and Road” Science and Technology Exchange Conference as an opportunity to adhere to goal orientation and action orientation, stick to the green hills and draw a blueprint to the end, thoroughly implement the “Belt and Road” science and technology innovation action plan, jointly build a road to innovation, and Promote cooperation and development, promote high-quality joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; to shine with the glory of the times, and jointly build a better world. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 持续拓展对外开放深度广度]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/07/nw.D110000renmrb_20231107_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, November 7, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;The Shanghai International Reinsurance Trading Center officially launched operations on October 26 in the Lingang New Area of ​​the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone. The international reinsurance business platform was unveiled, 4 supporting rules were released, and 15 settled institutions signed contracts, marking a breakthrough in the construction of the institutional system of the international reinsurance functional area. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The trading center focuses on cross-border reinsurance business, covering registration management, reinsurance transactions, international transfer premium statistics, differentiated solvency factors, etc., helping to create a platform with lower transaction risks, higher information transparency, and An open window with more concentrated transaction elements. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;On November 5, 2018, President Xi Jinping announced in his keynote speech at the opening ceremony of the first China International Import Expo that &quot;a new area will be added to the China Shanghai Free Trade Pilot Zone.&quot; &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Since its listing on August 20, 2019, the Lingang New Area has promoted a series of opening-up measures: the implementation of the &quot;main zoning&quot; system represented by the integrated supervision of &quot;one company and two places&quot; for Shanghai Aircraft Manufacturing , the country&#39;s first wholly foreign-owned vehicle manufacturing project - Tesla Shanghai Gigafactory was put into operation, the country&#39;s first foreign-controlled joint venture financial management company - Huihua Financial Management was established, and the first financial technology company wholly owned by a multinational financial group - HSBC Jinke; the first in the country to allow well-known overseas arbitration institutions to set up business offices and carry out foreign-related arbitration business in the Lingang New Area... In 2020, Lingang received US$520 million in foreign investment, which will increase to US$2.04 billion in 2022. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In order to enhance the ability to allocate global factor resources, the Lingang New Area has launched a pilot reform of high-level open foreign exchange management for cross-border trade and investment. Since its listing, the cumulative cross-border RMB settlement volume has exceeded 2 trillion yuan, and the cross-border foreign currency settlement volume has exceeded 40 billion US dollars. The first cross-border RMB settlement transaction of LNG (liquefied natural gas) between China and a member state of the Gulf Arab States Cooperation Council was implemented, and a new international trade public service platform - Cross-Border Connect was built. Build the &quot;China Yangshan Port&quot; international shipping port, ranking first in the country in terms of the number of registered ships on international routes. In 2022, Yangshan Port will complete container throughput of 23.92 million TEUs, accounting for 50.6% of Shanghai Port. Completed the country&#39;s first cross-border data flow security assessment in the field of intelligent connected vehicles. Build a new data infrastructure system with an internationally advanced level, open a dedicated channel for international data transmission, and build a high-level computing power center. Five international maritime optical cables and two maritime optical cable landing stations have been built. We are preparing to build a direct international maritime optical cable from Shanghai to Singapore to attract more data elements to flow to China. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Lingang New Area continues to enhance its innovation sources and international innovation synergy capabilities. From November 6th to 8th, the 6th World Top Scientists Forum was held at the permanent site of the World Top Scientists Forum in Lingang New Area, Shanghai. More than 300 scientists from 25 countries and regions participated. In order to retain more talents, Lingang implements a work-type residence permit of up to 5 years for foreign talents, and grants a work permit of more than 2 years at a time to urgently needed talents. Relax the restrictions on the employment of high-end overseas talents in the modern service industry and form a positive list of registered practitioners and qualification examinations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In order to create a cutting-edge industrial cluster with international market competitiveness, the Lingang New Area gathers chain-main enterprises and attracts more than 200 supporting enterprises to settle there. In 2022, the output value of intelligent new energy vehicles will exceed 260 billion yuan. At the same time, the Lingang New Area has built the Dishui Lake AI Innovation Port, housing 150 artificial intelligence companies and more than 5,000 AI R&amp;D personnel. Build a biomedical characteristic industrial park in Lingang and build a high-energy research hospital. To build an independent, controllable, safe and reliable domestic large aircraft industry cluster, the first independently developed domestic commercial large aircraft engine demonstrator was successfully ignited for the first time, and the domestic large aircraft C919 has started commercial passenger flights. On October 27, Lingang International Data Economy Industrial Park was officially unveiled. According to the plan, the International Data Economy Industrial Park will be built into a high-level international data cooperation bridgehead, a high-standard data cross-border system innovation pioneer area, a high-quality international data industry cluster and a new hub for high-level data circulation infrastructure. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;At present, the Lingang New Area has initially established a relatively mature institutional system for liberalization and facilitation of investment and trade, created a number of functional platforms with a higher degree of openness, and initially built an open and competitive area with international market competitiveness. type industrial system. Lingang optimizes the level of government services and centralizes the execution of 1,215 urban and municipal administrative matters. Establish a registration confirmation system, shortening the time for enterprise registration and registration by 75%; carry out &quot;joint processing of certificates and licenses&quot; to achieve one-time processing of enterprise admission and operation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Since its listing, the economic strength and total economic volume of the Lingang New Area have increased significantly, and 102 breakthrough innovation cases have been formed; a total of nearly 500 cutting-edge technology industry projects have been signed, involving a total investment of more than 600 billion yuan. From January to June 2023, the total output value of Lingang&#39;s industrial enterprises above designated size increased by 52.6% year-on-year, fixed asset investment in the whole society increased by 57.2% year-on-year, and tax revenue increased by 47.5% year-on-year. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 2023年世界互联网大会乌镇峰会即将举行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/07/nw.D110000renmrb_20231107_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, November 7, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;With the theme of “Building an inclusive, universally beneficial, and resilient digital world—Working together to build a community with a shared future in cyberspace” The 2023 World Internet Conference Wuzhen Summit will be held in Wuzhen, Zhejiang from November 8th to 10th. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tongxiang City, Jiaxing, Zhejiang Province, where Wuzhen is located, has optimized various service guarantees and gone all out to ensure that the summit is a complete success. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Welcoming guests with a better urban environment&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On October 20, the press conference of the 2023 World Internet Conference Wuzhen Summit was held in Beijing. Wuzhen sends an invitation to the world to &quot;meet in Wuzhen and have a ten-year appointment together.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This year’s summit has expanded in scale and conference activities have increased, and Tongxiang City has accurately arranged various venues. A total of 3,640 5G base stations have been built in the city, and key areas such as Xizha Scenic Area, Wuzhen Internet International Convention and Exhibition Center, Light of the Internet Expo Center, and Wuzhen World Internet Science and Technology Museum have achieved high-quality 5G signal coverage. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In accordance with the requirements of world-class conference venues, Tongxiang City continues to optimize the conference site environment, carefully build a number of landscapes and signs that highlight Tongxiang&#39;s local characteristics at important passages and important nodes, and build a veritable &quot;urban garden&quot; ” to welcome visitors from all over the world with a better urban environment. Paying close attention to environmental improvement, Tongxiang has made every effort to promote blue skies, clear water, waste removal, and pure land defense. From January to October this year, Tongxiang’s air quality rate was 88.1%, and the proportion of water quality in Class III and above in 13 monitoring sections above municipal control was 92.3%. %. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tongxiang City innovates digital methods for organizing conferences, integrating digital elements into the entire process and all aspects of conference preparation, especially constructing smart scenarios to promote the comprehensive integration of three systems including smart conference affairs, guest registration, and guest reception. , to achieve information co-construction and sharing and comprehensive coverage of links. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the morning of the 5th, after the 807 volunteers for the conference completed their assembly in Wuzhen, they rushed to their posts and began intense etiquette training and on-the-spot work. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From the high-speed rail Tongxiang Station to Wuzhen, many landscape sketches and signs are arranged along the line. The creativity in every corner and the ingenuity inside and outside create a strong conference atmosphere. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The “Ten-Year Covenant” has added a number of highlight activities&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to reports, the theme of this year’s summit is “Building an Inclusive, Universally Beneficial and Resilient Building” &quot;Digital World - Work Together to Build a Community of Shared Future in Cyberspace&quot;, from multiple dimensions such as cooperation and development, technology and industry, governance and security, humanities and society, it advocates digital cooperation, digital green collaborative transformation, youth and digitalization around global development. 20 sub-forums will be held on topics such as the future.今年峰会将关注数字技术同经济社会各领域深度融合的发展趋势，反映国际社会以数字合作推动全球发展、促进人类福祉的共同愿景。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年是世界互联网大会乌镇峰会举办的第十年。本次乌镇峰会将在往年特色基础上，新增多项亮点活动。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界互联网大会秘书长任贤良用“三个第一”概括本次峰会的亮点：第一次颁发“十年纪念荣誉”，向积极参与峰会活动、为峰会筹办及大会国际组织建设作出过突出贡献的友好人士和机构颁发“十年纪念荣誉”；第一个互联网科技馆正式开馆，全球首个以互联网为主题的大型科技馆将通过展示互联网关键技术、标志事件等，勾勒互联网发展进程，生动展现互联网在经济社会发展中发挥的积极作用；第一次设立“全球青年领军者计划”，搭建互联网领域优秀青年互学互鉴的国际交流合作平台，为互联网领域的新生力量创造更多机遇。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据了解，乌镇峰会系列品牌活动也将在变中求新。世界互联网领先科技成果发布活动将全面升级，成果首次区分基础研究、关键技术和工程研发3种类型。 “携手构建网络空间命运共同体精品案例”将以裸眼3D立体屏与大屏幕相结合的方式在峰会现场呈现。 “直通乌镇”全球互联网大赛今年重启海外赛区，吸引了来自全球70个城市的1005个项目报名参赛，峰会期间将举办决赛及颁奖典礼。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“互联网之光”展现数字化风采&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5日上午，在互联网之光博览中心各大展区，施工人员、参展商正紧张有序地布展。 “互联网之光”博览会今年将首次推出未来生活数字体验馆，组织“拾光”纪念系列活动。阿里巴巴、腾讯等500余家知名企业和机构线上线下联动参展，着力展现参展企业的数字化风采。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023年是卡巴斯基与“互联网之光”博览会携手的第六年。今年的“互联网之光”博览会上，卡巴斯基将展示容器安全、扩展检测与响应、卡巴斯基操作系统等内容。据卡巴斯基相关负责人郑启良介绍，公司将推动和加强国际合作，构建一个更为安全的世界。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;360集团既是网络安全企业、数字安全企业，也是网络平台企业。 360集团创始人周鸿祎表示，在今年博览会上，360集团将展示数字安全服务和360人工智能大模型，助力产业数字化、数字经济发展，为产业数字化向智能化升级提供技术支持。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此外，在今年峰会上，由国家文物局指导、敦煌研究院与腾讯联合打造的“数字藏经洞（国际版）”将正式对外发布。产品将推出英语、法语版本，海外用户可以通过“数字敦煌”网站一键“穿越”千里，随时随地体验莫高窟藏经洞的千年数字之旅。这将为中华文化的数字化、世界文化遗产数字化做出有益的探索。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“共赴十年之约”，2023年世界互联网大会乌镇峰会，乌镇准备好了！ &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 图片报道]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/07/nw.D110000renmrb_20231107_5-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月07日星期二&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231107/1699302825335_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;受强冷空气影响，东北地区近日出现降雪、雨夹雪天气，部分地区冻雨与降雪叠加，给交通带来一定影响。中国铁路哈尔滨局集团有限公司对受降雪影响主要铁路区段启动预警，组织5000余名铁路职工，调集大功率风力除雪机、除雪车辆等设备，对站场道岔、股道及线路、桥梁、隧道端口处的积雪进行清除，减少对运输秩序的影响。图为11月6日，轨道除雪车对积雪区段线路进行持续检查巡视和除雪。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;李心萍&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;芦&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;男摄影报道&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 07 Nov 2023 05:56:07 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>