<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 再接再厉抓好灾后恢复重建 确保广大人民群众安居乐业温暖过冬]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/11/nw.D110000renmrb_20231111_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, November 11, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/11/01/rmrb2023111101p20_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;November 10, CCP Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, President of the State, and Chairman of the Central Military Commission, inspected post-disaster recovery and reconstruction work in Beijing and Hebei. On the morning of the 10th, Xi Jinping visited the Miaofengshan National School in Mentougou, Beijing, to express cordial condolences to the families of martyrs who died in the line of duty, as well as grassroots party members and cadres participating in flood prevention and disaster relief, fire and emergency rescue personnel, state-owned enterprise employees, volunteer representatives, etc. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Ju Peng&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot; center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231111/1699648225552_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>; &lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On November 10, Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, President of the State, and Chairman of the Central Military Commission, inspected post-disaster recovery and reconstruction work in Beijing and Hebei. On the morning of the 10th, Xi Jinping had a cordial exchange with the local people during an inspection in Shuiyuzui Village, Miaofengshan Town, Mentougou, Beijing. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Yue Yuewei&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center &quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231111/1699648232400_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt; TD>;&lt;p>;On November 10, Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, President of the State, and Chairman of the Central Military Commission, inspected post-disaster recovery and reconstruction work in Beijing and Hebei. On the afternoon of the 10th, Xi Jinping inspected the house reconstruction construction site in Wanquanzhuang Village, Diaowo Town, Zhuozhou City, Baoding, Hebei Province. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Ju Peng&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot; center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/11/01/rmrb2023111101p18_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR >; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On November 10, Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, President of the State, and Chairman of the Central Military Commission, inspected post-disaster recovery and reconstruction work in Beijing and Hebei. This is the afternoon of the 10th. When Xi Jinping inspected the Baigou River Management Project (Zhuozhou Section) in Zhuozhou City, Baoding, Hebei, he met with water conservancy project construction personnel and officers and soldiers of the People&#39;s Liberation Army and Armed Police Force, militia reservists, fire rescue teams, etc. who had participated in Zhuozhou flood relief. Representatives from all aspects had cordial exchanges. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Yue Yuewei&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;■Party committees and governments at all levels, and all relevant parties It is necessary to conscientiously implement the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, and continue to work hard at post-disaster recovery and reconstruction to ensure that the broad masses of the people live and work in peace and contentment and have a warm winter. We must always adhere to the people-centered approach, adhere to the system concept, persist in seeking truth and pragmatism, scientific planning, and rational layout, seize the opportunity to make up for shortcomings and strengths and weaknesses, accelerate the improvement of the flood control engineering system and emergency management system, and continuously improve the disaster prevention, reduction, and relief capabilities&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;■I have always been thinking about the people in the disaster area. The Communist Party is a party that serves the people. It always puts the people at the top of its heart and will go all out whether it is emergency rescue or disaster relief or post-disaster recovery and reconstruction. I hope that the villagers will strengthen their confidence and work hard to build a better homeland&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■The second batch of thematic education is being carried out in depth. Party organizations at all levels in the disaster area should closely combine thematic education with post-disaster recovery and reconstruction, and vigorously promote flood prevention In the spirit of disaster relief, give full play to the fighting fortress role of grassroots party organizations and the vanguard and exemplary role of party members and cadres, and use the results of recovery and reconstruction and the satisfaction of the people to test the effectiveness of thematic education&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■Under the correct decision-making and deployment of the Party Central Committee, Powerful and effective measures were taken at all levels and in all aspects to minimize the losses from the once-in-a-century flood disaster. Post-disaster recovery and reconstruction involves a wide range of projects, involving large amounts of capital investment. Recently, the central government decided to issue an additional 1 trillion yuan of treasury bonds to support post-disaster recovery and reconstruction and project construction to enhance disaster prevention, reduction and relief capabilities. Party committees and governments at all levels and relevant departments must adhere to truth-seeking and pragmatism, scientific planning, and rational layout, use funds wisely, promote project construction with high quality, and build various projects into popular projects, high-quality projects, and clean projects&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This newspaper, Beijing/Baoding, Hebei, November 10th&amp;nbsp; During the reconstruction work, it was emphasized that party committees and governments at all levels and all relevant parties must conscientiously implement the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, make persistent efforts to restore and rebuild after the disaster, and ensure that the people live and work in peace and contentment and have a warm winter. We must always adhere to the people-centered approach, adhere to the system concept, adhere to truth-seeking and pragmatism, scientific planning, and rational layout, seize the opportunity to make up for shortcomings and strengths and weaknesses, accelerate the improvement of flood control engineering systems and emergency management systems, and continuously improve disaster prevention, reduction, and relief capabilities. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the end of July and early August this year, extreme rainfall occurred in North China, Huanghuai and other places, causing floods and geological disasters, causing heavy casualties in Beijing, Hebei and other places. Xi Jinping has always been concerned about the people affected by the disaster, attaching great importance to flood prevention, flood relief, and post-disaster recovery and reconstruction. He has issued important instructions on many occasions, requiring relevant localities and departments to make every effort to ensure the safety of people&#39;s lives and property and restore normal production and living order in the disaster areas as soon as possible. In early September, Xi Jinping went to Shangzhi City, Heilongjiang Province to visit and express condolences to the victims. As winter begins in the north, Xi Jinping went to Beijing and Hebei, the severely affected areas, to visit and express condolences to the affected people, and to inspect and guide post-disaster recovery and reconstruction work. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On November 10, Xi Jinping, accompanied by Yin Li, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee, Secretary of the Beijing Municipal Party Committee and Yin Yong, Mayor of Beijing, Ni Yuefeng, Secretary of the Hebei Provincial Party Committee, and Wang Zhengpu, Governor of Hebei Province, arrived successively. Mentougou, Baoding and other places to understand the post-disaster recovery and reconstruction situation on the spot. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Yongding River Sanjiadian Water Diversion Hub is a control project in the Guantingshan Gorge section of the Yongding River. On the morning of the 10th, Xi Jinping came here to listen to reports on the Beijing water system, Yongding River restoration and management, and barrage operation, and learn about the progress of post-disaster recovery and reconstruction. Xi Jinping pointed out that mountainous areas such as Mentougou and Fangshan have high mountains and deep valleys, and continuous heavy rainfall can easily cause severe flash floods. They are key areas for flood prevention and relief in Beijing. It is necessary to build and utilize control projects such as reservoirs, and to improve flood control standards for roads, houses and other buildings in mountainous areas to effectively improve flood control and flood resistance capabilities. Based on the characteristics of Beijing&#39;s water system, summing up historical experience, targeting prominent problems and weak links, and in accordance with the principles of &quot;upper storage, middle dredging, lower drainage, and effective flood control&quot;, we must repair water-damaged facilities and strengthen the construction of key water conservancy projects to ensure the safety of the capital. Provide strong support for flood control safety. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Later, Xi Jinping drove to Miaofengshan National School. During this year&#39;s flood season, it serves as a temporary disaster shelter and a location for flood prevention and relief personnel. Xi Jinping walked into a classroom where the children were having a themed class meeting under the leadership of the teacher. Everyone rushed to show Grandpa Xi their handicrafts with the theme of flood relief, and reported their experiences and feelings in the face of floods. Xi Jinping was very happy after hearing this. He said that ensuring that disaster-stricken students can return to school on time is a clear requirement of the Party Central Committee for post-disaster recovery and reconstruction. Through the joint efforts of all parties, all schools in the disaster area have opened on time. Seeing the happy smiles of the children is very practical and gratifying. Your school successfully avoided danger during this flood prevention and fighting, and played a good role as a &quot;safety island&quot;. We must make good use of this vivid teaching material to carry out safety education and improve children&#39;s safety awareness and risk avoidance abilities. This flood fighting and disaster relief work will be unforgettable for the children, and they must learn to be grateful, set their ambitions, and become builders and successors of the socialist cause. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the school playground, Xi Jinping cordially expressed condolences to the families of martyrs who sacrificed their lives in the line of duty, as well as grassroots party members and cadres who participated in flood prevention and disaster relief, fire and emergency rescue personnel, state-owned enterprise employees, volunteer representatives, etc. Xi Jinping said that in this fight against floods and disaster relief, grassroots party members and cadres are at the forefront and have the courage to take on their responsibilities. Officers and soldiers of the People&#39;s Liberation Army, the Armed Police Force, and fire and rescue team officers and soldiers stand up and move forward towards danger. Employees of state-owned enterprises have heard of the &quot;flood&quot; and have In response to the mobilization and emergency rescue, all walks of life and volunteers actively participated and dedicated their love, which wrote the great love of the world that no one has mercy on the flood, and demonstrated the remarkable advantages of the socialist system that one side is in trouble and all parties support it, and the people of the country are united and work together in the same boat. , many touching stories emerged. Many party members and cadres died in flood fighting and rescue operations. We must always remember them and vigorously publicize their heroic deeds. Relevant parties must take care of their families. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Around noon, Xi Jinping came to Shuiyuzui Village, Miaofengshan Town for inspection. At the riverside platform at the entrance of the village, Xi Jinping listened to a briefing on the village, and then walked to inspect the appearance of the village and learn about the restoration, construction and improvement of infrastructure. Xi Jinping pointed out that after major floods, it is necessary to carry out extensive construction and improvement, and greatly improve the level of water conservancy facilities and flood control facilities. We must adhere to the people-centered approach, focus on the long term, and plan scientifically, closely integrate restoration and reconstruction with the promotion of high-quality development, the construction of resilient cities, the revitalization of rural areas, and the construction of ecological civilization, and take targeted measures to comprehensively improve prevention and control measures. Disaster reduction and relief capabilities. In particular, it is necessary to improve the urban and rural grassroots emergency management organization system and enhance the grassroots disaster prevention and avoidance, self-rescue and mutual rescue capabilities. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the home of villager Li Meng, Xi Jinping asked in detail about the damage to the house, repair expenses, heating, etc. Xi Jinping said that ensuring that the affected people survive the winter safely and warmly is a hard task. Winters are long in the north, and winters in the mountains are especially cold. Heating work must be carried out in detail and implemented in every household. For disaster-stricken households that have completed house repairs, reinforcements or reconstruction and are eligible for occupancy, we should provide guidance and help them implement winter heating. For the disaster-stricken households whose houses have not yet been rebuilt, measures such as staying with relatives and friends, renting houses, and government resettlement should be used to ensure that they have a warm winter. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When leaving the village, the local people warmly bid farewell to the General Secretary. Xi Jinping told everyone that I have always been thinking about the people in the disaster area. The Communist Party is a party that serves the people. It always puts the people at the top of its heart and will go all out whether it is emergency rescue or disaster relief or post-disaster recovery and reconstruction. I hope that the villagers will strengthen their confidence and work hard to build a better home. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During this year’s flood season, Zhuozhou City, Baoding suffered severe flooding, but normal production and living order has basically been restored. On the afternoon of the 10th, Xi Jinping came to Yongji Xiuyuan Community in Shuangta Street. He first walked into the drug store and supermarket at the entrance of the community and asked the merchants in detail about the business recovery situation. Then he went to the community heating station to learn about the operation of the heating facilities. Xi Jinping said that after this disaster, residents and some production and operation units suffered a lot of losses. Party committees and governments at all levels must take multiple measures to help the affected people, enterprises, and merchants tide over the difficulties. Urban restoration and reconstruction must make disaster prevention and reduction demonstration plans, fully consider risk avoidance and disaster avoidance, set aside flood channels, flood discharge areas, and flood detention areas, update drainage pipe networks and other infrastructure, and improve urban operation support capabilities. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping visited resident Dong Caiying’s home to visit and express condolences, and inquired in detail about flood levels, emergency housing, furniture and appliance updates, heating, and related subsidies. Dong Caiying told the General Secretary that with the help of party members and cadres, the house has been cleaned and repaired and moved in. There is no problem in staying warm in the winter. Xi Jinping emphasized that the first priority for urban post-disaster recovery and reconstruction is to restore the lives of every household and the living environment of the community. It is necessary to check for leaks and fill them, and to make the work more detailed and practical. Grassroots organizations, party members and cadres, neighbors, professional forces and volunteers from all fields must work together. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When leaving the community, Xi Jinping had a cordial exchange with the residents. Xi Jinping told everyone that the disaster in Zhuozhou was very serious. At that time, I paid attention to the situation here every day and missed you very much. Today I see that municipal public service facilities have returned to normal operation and everyone&#39;s life has basically returned to normal, which makes me feel much more at ease. After the storm comes the rainbow. Under the strong leadership of the Party Central Committee, as long as everyone works together, we will be able to live a better life. The second batch of thematic education is being carried out in depth. Party organizations at all levels in the disaster area must closely integrate thematic education with post-disaster recovery and reconstruction, vigorously promote the spirit of flood fighting and disaster relief, give full play to the role of grassroots party organizations as fighting fortresses and the vanguard and exemplary role of party members and cadres, and use recovery and reconstruction to Results and people’s satisfaction are used to test the effectiveness of thematic education. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wanquanzhuang Village in Diaowo Town is located in the Langouwa flood storage and detention area. During this year’s flood season, all 311 households in the village were affected. Xi Jinping carefully inspected the restoration and reconstruction of village roads, houses, etc. He walked into the house reconstruction construction site, asked about the disaster losses, construction progress, rental transition, etc., and encouraged them to unite as one, overcome the difficulties together, and rebuild the harmonious and beautiful countryside. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The house of villager Yang Peiran’s house was slightly damaged and has been reinforced and repaired and moved in. Xi Jinping walked into Yang Peiran&#39;s home and learned about their family income, repair expenses, production recovery and other conditions. Xi Jinping pointed out that house repair, reinforcement and reconstruction are the top priority for post-disaster recovery and reconstruction. Now it seems that the tasks of repair and reinforcement have been basically completed, but the heaviest and most difficult task is reconstruction. Party committees and governments at all levels must pay special attention to the reconstruction households, and provide appropriate resettlement to those who have special difficulties during the transition period and are unable to solve their housing problems on their own. Practical and effective measures must be taken to prevent people from falling back into poverty due to disasters. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When leaving, the villagers greeted the General Secretary loudly. Xi Jinping told everyone that in the face of floods that are rare in history, the villagers have suffered great losses, and I would like to express my condolences to everyone! Party committees and governments at all levels are taking various measures to solidly promote post-disaster recovery and reconstruction. It is hoped that the villagers will be self-reliant, work hard, and use their hard-working hands to speed up recovery and reconstruction and promote rural revitalization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping also walked into the farmland near the village to observe the growth of winter wheat and Chinese cabbage. He pointed out that agricultural production is an important aspect of post-disaster recovery and reconstruction, which is not only directly related to the income of every household, but also related to national food security. We must continue to repair disaster-damaged farmland and agricultural facilities, increase the supply of agricultural materials, strengthen agricultural technology guidance, organize and arrange agricultural production this winter and next spring, and strive for a good harvest next year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Baigou River is a backbone flood channel in the Daqing River Basin. Xi Jinping came to the Baigou River Management Project (Zhuozhou Section), inspected the progress of the project, and listened to a report on the status of major water conservancy projects in post-disaster reconstruction in Hebei Province. Xi Jinping pointed out that the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei water system is connected, and flood prevention and fighting are a game of chess. It is necessary to conduct in-depth research and promote the construction of a flood control engineering system in the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region. Adhere to the system concept, coordinate river basins and regions, properly handle the relationship between upstream and downstream, left and right banks, main branches and tributaries, scientifically layout the functional construction of reservoirs, rivers, embankments, flood storage and detention areas, etc., and improve the flood control capacity of the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region as a whole. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the embankment, Xi Jinping cordially visited and expressed condolences to the water conservancy project construction personnel and representatives of the People&#39;s Liberation Army and Armed Police Force officers and soldiers, militia reservists, fire rescue teams and other personnel who had participated in Zhuozhou flood fighting and rescue. He said that during this time of flood relief and disaster relief, forces from all walks of life and the broad masses of the people worked together to build a solid line of defense for flood prevention and disaster relief and to protect their homes, which fully demonstrated the strong political advantages of our party and country. The people thank you, the party and the government thank you! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before returning to Beijing, Xi Jinping told the accompanying personnel and local cadres that under the correct decision-making and deployment of the Party Central Committee, powerful and effective measures were taken at all levels and in all aspects to minimize the losses from the once-in-a-century flood disaster. Post-disaster recovery and reconstruction involves a wide range of projects, involving large amounts of capital investment. Recently, the central government decided to issue an additional 1 trillion yuan of treasury bonds to support post-disaster recovery and reconstruction and project construction to enhance disaster prevention, reduction and relief capabilities. Party committees and governments at all levels and relevant departments must adhere to truth-seeking and pragmatism, scientific planning, and rational layout, use funds wisely, promote project construction with high quality, and build various projects into popular projects, high-quality projects, and clean projects. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cai Qi, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and director of the General Office of the CPC Central Committee, accompanied the inspection. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He Weidong participated in relevant activities, and was accompanied by responsible comrades from relevant departments of the central and state agencies for inspection. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平将赴美国举行中美元首会晤 同时出席亚太经合组织第三十次领导人非正式会议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/11/nw.D110000renmrb_20231111_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, November 11, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 10th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Foreign Ministry Spokesperson Hua Chunying announced on the 10th: In response to the U.S. At the invitation of President Biden, President Xi Jinping will go to San Francisco, the United States, to hold the China-US Presidential Meeting from November 14th to 17th. He will also be invited to attend the 30th APEC Leaders&#39; Informal Meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平复信费城交响乐团总裁兼首席执行官马思艺]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/11/nw.D110000renmrb_20231111_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, November 11, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 10th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Recently, President Xi Jinping responded to a letter to the President and Chief Executive Officer of the Philadelphia Orchestra Official Ma Siyi. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that he learned that the Philadelphia Orchestra came to China for the 13th time in November and cooperated with China to hold a series of performance exchange activities to commemorate its first visit to China in 1973 and continue to write a half-century-long relationship with the Chinese people. I am truly happy about our musical friendship. 50 years ago, the orchestra came to China to embark on an &quot;ice-breaking tour&quot; of Sino-US cultural exchanges, which was of great significance in the normalization of Sino-US relations. Over the past 50 years, the orchestra, as an active &quot;cultural envoy&quot; between China and the United States, has visited China 12 times and played a positive role in promoting the development of Sino-US relations. Today, 50 years later, the Philadelphia Orchestra, the China Symphony Orchestra and singers from many countries performed in China, which will surely go down in history as a precious story. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping emphasized that music crosses national boundaries and culture builds bridges. It is hoped that the Philadelphia Orchestra will work with artists from all over the world, including China and the United States, to adhere to civilized equality, mutual learning, dialogue, and tolerance, to intensify exchanges and cooperation, promote artistic prosperity, and open a new chapter for China-U.S. cultural exchanges and friendship between peoples of all countries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In September 1973, the Philadelphia Orchestra visited China for the first time, becoming the first American orchestra to visit China after the founding of New China. Recently, Ma Siyi, president and CEO of the Philadelphia Orchestra, sent a letter to President Xi Jinping, reviewing the history of the orchestra&#39;s exchanges with China, introducing the performance and exchange activities held in China in November this year to commemorate the 50th anniversary of the orchestra&#39;s first visit to China, and hoping that through music, it will continue to Build a bridge of communication between the two peoples and the two cultures. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 努力把家园建设得更加美好]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/11/nw.D110000renmrb_20231111_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, November 11, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;On the 10th, when inspecting post-disaster recovery and reconstruction work in Beijing and Hebei, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized that we should continue to work hard at post-disaster recovery and reconstruction, Ensure that the broad masses of the people live and work in peace and contentment and have a warm winter. General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s deep concern and earnest entrustment have made the cadres and the masses in the disaster-stricken areas feel warm and inspired. Everyone expressed that they would strengthen their confidence and go all out to make their homeland a better place. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Feeling warm, the General Secretary always keeps the safety of the people at heart&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Zhuozhou, Hebei Province, after the beginning of winter, the lowest outdoor temperature dropped below zero degrees Celsius. The 29 residential buildings in Yongji Xiuyuan Community on Shuangta Street have been heated, and the rooms are warm and cozy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;After General Secretary Xi Jinping entered the house, he was very concerned about our disaster situation and current life. The whole family felt warm in their hearts, and felt that the General Secretary was very kind and always kept us people in his heart.&quot; Residents of the community Dong Caiying said that under the strong leadership of the Party Central Committee and everyone working together, we will be able to live a better life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This summer, after floods occurred in Beijing, Tianjin, Hebei and Northeast China, General Secretary Xi Jinping has been paying close attention to the flood situation across the country. He has always been concerned about the people affected by the disaster and visited many severely affected areas to inspect and express condolences. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I really didn’t expect Grandpa Xi to come to our class. He listened very carefully and interacted with everyone.” said Duan Jinxi, a fifth-grade student in Class 1 of Miaofengshan National School in Mentougou District, Beijing. Because the terrain is relatively high, during this year&#39;s flood season, her school served as a temporary shelter and a location for flood prevention and relief personnel. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the period of placement with his parents in school, Duan Jinxi was deeply impressed by the sight of helicopters airdropping relief supplies to the playground: &quot;I made a helicopter model out of clay to share this experience. I want to follow Xi&#39;s instructions Grandpa’s teachings, establish great ambitions, and be the builders and successors of the socialist cause.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the flood fighting and rescue operations, a group of party members and cadres charged forward, and many touching stories emerged. Liu Jie, deputy mayor of Longquan Town in Mentougou District, died heroically when he encountered a flash flood while persuading people to move to avoid danger. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;General Secretary Xi Jinping carefully asked whether our lives are guaranteed, which made me fully feel the care and concern of the Party Central Committee.&quot; Tears rolled in the eyes of Liu Jie&#39;s lover Liu Xuan, &quot;I will work hard in the future and supervise my son Study hard and work together to pass on his father’s spirit of self-sacrifice for others.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhao Yang, a technician of the Qingdao fleet of the Baotou Passenger Transport Section of China Railway Hohhot Bureau Group Co., Ltd., saw the news of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s inspection on his mobile phone, and was heartbroken. very touched. More than three months ago, on the K396 train that was stranded due to floods, Zhao Yang, a flight attendant, choked up and shouted to comfort passengers, which moved countless people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“General Secretary Xi Jinping said that the Communist Party is a party that serves the people and always puts the people at the highest position in its heart. As a grassroots party member, I will transform the General Secretary’s high hopes and trust into greater work motivation . Whether it is emergency rescue or disaster relief or daily work, we will go all out.&quot; Zhao Yang said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;I am deeply encouraged to go all out to carry out post-disaster recovery and reconstruction&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the farmland near Wanquanzhuang Village, Diaowo Town, Zhuozhou, winter wheat and crops are replanted. The cabbage is growing beautifully. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;General Secretary Xi Jinping came to our village and was concerned about post-disaster production, life and housing reconstruction, especially how we spend the winter. I thank the General Secretary and the Communist Party from the bottom of my heart.&quot; Recalling that the General Secretary walked into Villager Yang Peiran was very excited about the scene in his own home. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thousands of miles away in Shangzhi City, Heilongjiang Province, Yang Chungui, a villager in Longwangmiao Village, feels at ease with his current life: &quot;When the General Secretary came to visit us in early September, the floor tiles had just been installed in the house and were still being scraped. Now the house has been repaired, and the fire bed, wardrobe, and cabinets are all brand new.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gao Feng, deputy director of the Shangzhi Municipal Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau, said: &quot;House repair, reinforcement, and reconstruction are the top priority for post-disaster recovery and reconstruction. It is also a matter of concern to General Secretary Xi Jinping. On the basis of completing the reconstruction of houses, we will continue to pay attention to the housing and living conditions of the disaster-stricken people and speed up the reconstruction of harmonious rural areas.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past few days, Jinma, Shulan City, Jilin Province The town&#39;s construction of mechanical plowing roads and new irrigation canals are being accelerated. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Seeing on the news that the General Secretary once again walked into the farmland to inspect the post-disaster recovery of production, Zhai Cheng, the mayor of Jinma Town, felt that he had a heavy responsibility on his shoulders: &quot;Agricultural production is not only related to the income of every household, but also to the country. Food security. We will continue to repair the farmland and agricultural facilities destroyed by the disaster, organize and arrange agricultural production this winter and next spring, and strive for a good harvest next year.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Baigou River flowing through Zhuozhou, Hebei is A backbone flood channel in the Daqing River Basin. On the afternoon of the 10th, at the construction site of the Baigou River Management Project (Zhuozhou Section), hundreds of workers were carrying out dam reinforcement and other work. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Despite the cold weather, the general secretary&#39;s words made everyone more motivated.&quot; Zhao Manjiang, general manager of the First Branch of Hebei Provincial Water Conservancy Engineering Bureau Group Co., Ltd. said, &quot;Next, we will follow the general secretary&#39;s requirements, We should not only ensure the progress of the project, but also carry out the construction of water conservancy projects with high quality and high standards, and put in great efforts to make these facilities better play a role in flood prevention and fight against floods and protect the safety of the people.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Clear the direction and continue to Improving disaster prevention, reduction and relief capabilities&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping came to inspect and investigate the restoration and construction of infrastructure, which made Wang Yao, Secretary of the Party Committee of Miaofengshan Town, Mentougou District, Beijing very excited: &quot;We are here in Beijing One of the key areas for flood prevention and relief. The General Secretary emphasized that after major floods, large-scale construction and restoration must be carried out. We will speed up the implementation of this requirement, take effective measures according to local conditions, and comprehensively improve disaster prevention, reduction and relief capabilities.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;Adhere to the system concept&quot; and &quot;work hard to make up for the shortcomings and strengths and weaknesses&quot;, General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s earnest instructions made Wang Yawei, deputy director of the Department of Emergency Disaster Reduction and Public Services of the China Meteorological Administration, clarify the direction of work, &quot;Next, we will adopt The linkage system of vertical level-by-level reminders and horizontal department coordination further improves the efficiency from &#39;early warning&#39; to &#39;action&#39; at the grassroots level.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huang Zhenyu, Director of the Flood Control Office of Nan&#39;an City, Fujian Province, said in his speech to General Secretary Xi Jinping, &quot;Improving urban and rural areas &quot;Grassroots emergency management organization system&quot; is very touching. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Recently, we have introduced a plan to improve the emergency mechanism to comprehensively improve disaster prevention, reduction and relief capabilities from the command system, monitoring and forecasting, flood prevention and drainage.&quot; Huang Zhenyu said that a comprehensive information command system for emergency rescue will be built. , using digitalization to improve overall emergency and disaster response speed and processing capabilities. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Post-disaster recovery and reconstruction involves a wide range of projects, with large capital investment. Recently, the central government decided to issue an additional 1 trillion yuan of treasury bonds to focus on supporting post-disaster recovery and reconstruction and improving disaster prevention, reduction and relief capabilities, so as to make up for the country&#39;s shortcomings in resisting natural disasters. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The General Secretary emphasized that we must adhere to truth-seeking and pragmatism, scientific planning, rational layout, and use funds wisely. We deeply feel the great responsibility.” Luo Guosan, Director of the Fixed Asset Investment Department of the National Development and Reform Commission, said, At present, the implementation working mechanism for the additional treasury bond issuance project has been launched, and various localities are being organized to sort out and apply for a batch of projects. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Luo Guosan said that he will strictly follow the principle of &quot;funds and factors follow the project, and the project follows the plan&quot;, select projects as soon as possible and issue a project list and arrangement amount, and strive to transfer most of the national debt before the end of November Allocate funds to specific projects, consolidate the responsibilities of local and relevant departments, and build various projects into popular projects, high-quality projects, and clean projects. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 10)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href =&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 为实体经济稳定增长营造良好的货币金融环境（权威访谈）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/11/nw.D110000renmrb_20231111_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, November 11, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Since the beginning of this year, the prudent monetary policy has been precise and powerful, increased countercyclical adjustments, effectively served the real economy, and effectively prevented and controlled Financial risks have promoted the overall recovery of our country&#39;s economy. Next, how to implement the decisions and arrangements of the Central Financial Work Conference and provide high-quality financial services for economic and social development? How to better prevent and resolve financial risks? Our reporter interviewed Pan Gongsheng, Secretary of the Party Committee and President of the People&#39;s Bank of China, and Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Director of the State Administration of Foreign Exchange. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Monetary policy has strongly supported the development of the real economy&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Reporter: The central financial work conference held recently made arrangements for financial work in the current and future periods. , how will the People&#39;s Bank of China and the State Administration of Foreign Exchange implement it? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pan Gongsheng: The People&#39;s Bank of China and the State Administration of Foreign Exchange will thoroughly study and implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s important speech at the Central Financial Work Conference and the Party Central Committee&#39;s decision-making and deployment, formulate implementation plans, and systematically plan key points in the future. Work tasks and ideas and initiatives. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;First, adhere to the centralized and unified leadership of the Party Central Committee over financial work. Insert the Party&#39;s leadership into all aspects and the entire process of the work of the People&#39;s Bank of China and the State Administration of Foreign Exchange, improve the system and mechanism of the Party&#39;s management of finance, and transform the political and institutional advantages of the Party&#39;s leadership into financial governance effectiveness. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The second is to adhere to the fundamental purpose of financial services for the real economy. Improve the modern monetary policy framework with Chinese characteristics, always maintain the stability of monetary policy, pay more attention to cross-cyclical and counter-cyclical adjustments, enrich the monetary policy toolbox, and create a solid foundation for stabilizing prices, promoting economic growth, expanding employment, and maintaining the balance of international payments. Good monetary and financial environment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The third is to insist on coordinating development and security, preventing and defusing major financial risks, and maintaining the smooth operation of the financial market. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fourth is to persist in deepening financial reform. Accelerate the construction of a modern central bank system, improve the dual-pillar regulatory framework of monetary policy and macro-prudential policy, deepen the market-oriented reform of interest rates and exchange rates, and deepen the structural reform of the financial supply side. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fifth is to expand high-level two-way opening up of finance. We will steadily and steadily advance the internationalization of the RMB, deepen reform and opening up in the foreign exchange field, promote trade, investment and financing facilitation, steadily expand the institutional opening of the financial market, and actively participate in international financial governance. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Reporter: Since the beginning of this year, what measures has the People&#39;s Bank of China taken to increase efforts to support the real economy? How effective are these measures? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pan Gongsheng: Since the beginning of this year, monetary policy has increased counter-cyclical adjustments, coordinated the use of aggregate and structural, quantitative and price tools, and more effectively supported the development of the real economy. At present, the total amount of money and credit maintains rapid growth, the credit structure continues to be optimized, and corporate loan interest rates are at a low level, providing strong and effective support for economic recovery and development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The total amount is reasonable and sufficient. At the end of September, the stock of broad money (M2) and social financing maintained a rapid growth of about 10% year-on-year. The structure is more optimized. The year-on-year growth rate of the inclusive small and micro loan balance has exceeded 20% for four consecutive years. The number of credit users has exceeded 60 million, which is doubled from the end of 2019. The loan balance of technology-based small and medium-sized enterprises has increased by 23% year-on-year. The green loan balance A year-on-year increase of 37%, and the balance of medium and long-term loans in the manufacturing industry increased by 38% year-on-year. Prices have stabilized with some decline. The weighted average interest rate of newly issued corporate loans in September was 3.82%, which is at a historically low level. The reduction in the existing first-home loan interest rate has benefited approximately 50 million households and 150 million people, saving household interest expenses of approximately 170 billion yuan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the next step, monetary policy will pay more attention to inter-cyclical and counter-cyclical adjustments, balance the short-term and long-term, stabilize growth and prevent risks, internal balance and external balance, and maintain the relationship between currency, credit and social financing. The scale will grow at a reasonable scale, continue to increase support for major strategies, key areas and weak links, promote the stabilization and decline of financing costs for the real economy, and strive to create a good monetary and financial environment for the stable growth of the real economy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;my country’s financial system is overall stable and the financial market is operating smoothly&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Reporter: How is the overall operation of my country’s financial system currently? What are the key tasks of the People&#39;s Bank of China in preventing and defusing financial risks? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pan Gongsheng: At present, my country&#39;s financial system is overall stable, the operating and regulatory indicators of financial institutions are within reasonable ranges, and the financial market is operating smoothly. As of the end of June, the capital adequacy ratio, non-performing loan ratio and provision coverage ratio of China&#39;s commercial banks were 14.7%, 1.62% and 206% respectively. According to the financial institution rating results of the People&#39;s Bank of China, the vast majority of banking financial institutions are operating stably. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the same time, we pay close attention to financial risks in some areas. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In terms of the real estate market, my country&#39;s real estate market is currently undergoing structural changes. The central level of housing demand, the transaction structure of the housing market, and the industry model are all facing some profound changes. The real estate market is changing from an incremental market to a growth-oriented one. Pay equal attention to the transition between quantity and stock. Overall, this process has limited spillovers to the financial system and real estate financial risks are controllable. Since the beginning of this year, the financial sector has taken comprehensive measures from both the supply and demand sides and introduced a number of financial policies to better meet rigid and improved housing needs and promote the acceleration of the construction of a new development model for the real estate industry. In the long term, my country&#39;s urbanization is still in the development stage, and households have a large demand for improved housing, which can provide support for the long-term stable development of the real estate market and industry. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In terms of local government debt, generally speaking, my country&#39;s government debt level is at the lower middle level internationally. From a structural point of view, the central government&#39;s debt burden is relatively light, and most local government debt levels are also low. It is high and has more resources and means to resolve debts. The Party Central Committee and the State Council attach great importance to preventing and resolving local debt risks. In accordance with the deployment requirements of the central government, relevant localities have recently adopted methods such as revitalizing or selling assets to actively raise resources to resolve debts, and have achieved good results. The financial management department has also taken active actions to guide financial institutions to steadily support the resolution of debt risks of financing platforms through market-oriented methods such as extensions, loan repayments, and replacements, and safeguard the legitimate rights and interests of financial institutions in accordance with the law; at the same time, through the establishment of normalized financing platform finance Debt monitoring mechanism, promote the market-oriented transformation of financing platforms, etc., and improve long-term mechanisms to prevent and resolve local debt risks. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition, the risks of small and medium-sized financial institutions and the risks of illegal financial activities still require continued attention. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the next step, we will insist on coordinating development and security, improve financial risk prevention, early warning and disposal mechanisms in accordance with the deployment of the Central Financial Work Conference, and steadily and orderly promote key areas and We will deal with key financial risks, bring all financial activities under supervision in accordance with the law, severely crack down on illegal financial activities, promote financial stability legislation, accelerate the construction of financial stability guarantee funds, and resolutely maintain the bottom line of no systemic financial risks. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Reporter: How do you view the current exchange rate situation? How to deal with exchange rate fluctuations? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pan Gongsheng: There are many factors that affect the exchange rate. The first is economic fundamentals. This is the most fundamental factor. my country&#39;s economy continues to pick up and improve, and the RMB exchange rate is basically stable, which has a solid foundation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第二是国际金融环境。国际市场普遍认为美联储此轮加息接近尾声，未来中美利差会逐步收敛至正常区间。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第三是人民币资产的投资价值和吸引力。中长期看，随着中国经济增长动能不断激活和金融市场进一步开放，人民币资产投资属性和避险属性凸显，人民币资产展现出良好的投资价值。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们有信心、有能力维护外汇市场的稳定运行，保持人民币汇率在合理均衡水平上的基本稳定。下一阶段，中国人民银行、国家外汇局将综合施策、稳定预期，坚决防止单边预期自我实现，坚决对市场顺周期行为进行纠偏，坚决对扰乱市场秩序行为进行处置，坚决防范汇率超调风险。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;继续稳步扩大金融领域制度型开放&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：近年来，金融对外开放取得了哪些进展？下一步有何考虑？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;潘功胜：近年来，中国人民银行主动有序扩大金融业高水平开放。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一是大幅放宽金融服务业市场准入。 2018年以来，金融管理部门推出了50多条金融业开放措施，吸引外资来华设立了超过110家金融机构。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;二是积极推进债券市场高水平对外开放。 “债券通”“互换通”平稳高效运行，债券市场投资环境持续优化，境外投资者入市投资便利性不断提升。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三是稳步推进人民币国际化。人民币作为支付货币、投融资货币、储备货币的功能不断增强，已初步具备了国际使用的网络效应，为境内外主体提供了更加多元化的货币选择。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在扩大对外开放的同时，我们还积极参与国际金融治理。今年，中美、中欧成立了金融工作组，就经济和金融领域相关问题与美、欧加强沟通和合作。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;下一步，中国人民银行将按照党中央、国务院统一部署，继续稳步扩大金融领域制度型开放，着力营造市场化、法治化、国际化一流营商环境。同时，坚持多边主义原则，以建设者、贡献者的角色参与全球经济金融治理。 &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 再接再厉抓好灾后恢复重建 确保广大人民群众安居乐业温暖过冬]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/11/nw.D110000renmrb_20231111_6-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月11日星期六&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/11/01/rmrb2023111101p20_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;11月10日，中共中央总书记、国家主席、中央军委主席习近平在北京、河北考察灾后恢复重建工作。这是10日上午，习近平在北京门头沟妙峰山民族学校，亲切慰问因公牺牲烈士家属和参与防汛抗洪救灾的基层党员干部群众、消防及应急救援人员、国企职工、志愿者代表等。&lt;BR/>;新华社记者鞠鹏摄&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231111/1699648225552_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;11月10日，中共中央总书记、国家主席、中央军委主席习近平在北京、河北考察灾后恢复重建工作。这是10日上午，习近平在北京门头沟妙峰山镇水峪嘴村考察时，同当地群众亲切交流。&lt;BR/>;新华社记者岳月伟摄&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231111/1699648232400_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;11月10日，中共中央总书记、国家主席、中央军委主席习近平在北京、河北考察灾后恢复重建工作。这是10日下午，习近平在河北保定涿州市刁窝镇万全庄村房屋重建施工现场考察。&lt;BR/>;新华社记者鞠鹏摄&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/11/01/rmrb2023111101p18_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;11月10日，中共中央总书记、国家主席、中央军委主席习近平在北京、河北考察灾后恢复重建工作。这是10日下午，习近平在河北保定涿州市白沟河治理工程（涿州段）考察时，同水利工程建设人员和曾经参加涿州抗洪救援的解放军和武警部队官兵、民兵预备役人员、消防救援队伍等方面的代表亲切交流。&lt;BR/>;新华社记者岳月伟摄&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;■各级党委和政府、各有关方面要认真贯彻落实党中央决策部署，再接再厉抓好灾后恢复重建，确保广大人民群众安居乐业、温暖过冬。要始终坚持以人民为中心，坚持系统观念，坚持求真务实、科学规划、合理布局，抓紧补短板、强弱项，加快完善防洪工程体系、应急管理体系，不断提升防灾减灾救灾能力&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■我心里一直惦念着灾区的人民群众。共产党是为人民服务的党，永远把老百姓放在心中最高位置，无论是抢险救灾还是灾后恢复重建，都会全力以赴。希望乡亲们坚定信心，努力把家园建设得更加美好&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■第二批主题教育正在深入开展，灾区各级党组织要把主题教育与灾后恢复重建紧密结合起来，大力弘扬抗洪救灾精神，充分发挥基层党组织战斗堡垒作用和党员干部先锋模范作用，用恢复重建成果和人民群众满意度来检验主题教育的成效&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■在党中央的正确决策部署下，各级各方面采取有力有效措施，把百年一遇的洪涝灾害损失降到了最低。灾后恢复重建涉及范围广，工程项目多，资金投入大。最近中央决定增发1万亿元国债，用于支持灾后恢复重建和提升防灾减灾救灾能力的项目建设。各级党委和政府、各有关部门要坚持求真务实、科学规划、合理布局，把资金用到刀刃上，高质量推进项目建设，把各项工程建设成为民心工程、优质工程、廉洁工程&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本报北京/河北保定11月10日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;中共中央总书记、国家主席、中央军委主席习近平10日在北京、河北考察灾后恢复重建工作时强调，各级党委和政府、各有关方面要认真贯彻落实党中央决策部署，再接再厉抓好灾后恢复重建，确保广大人民群众安居乐业、温暖过冬。要始终坚持以人民为中心，坚持系统观念，坚持求真务实、科学规划、合理布局，抓紧补短板、强弱项，加快完善防洪工程体系、应急管理体系，不断提升防灾减灾救灾能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年7月底8月初，华北、黄淮等地出现极端降雨，引发洪涝和地质灾害，造成北京、河北等地重大人员伤亡。习近平一直牵挂着受灾群众，高度重视防汛抗洪救灾和灾后恢复重建工作，多次作出重要指示批示，要求有关地方和部门全力保障人民群众生命财产安全，尽快恢复灾区正常生产生活秩序。9月上旬，习近平前往黑龙江尚志市看望慰问受灾群众。北方入冬之际，习近平又来到北京、河北受灾较重的相关地区，看望慰问受灾群众，检查指导灾后恢复重建工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;11月10日，习近平在中共中央政治局委员、北京市委书记尹力和市长殷勇，河北省委书记倪岳峰和省长王正谱分别陪同下，先后来到门头沟、保定等地，实地了解灾后恢复重建情况。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;永定河三家店引水枢纽是永定河官厅山峡段控制性工程。10日上午，习近平来到这里，听取北京市水系、永定河修复治理、拦河闸运行等情况汇报，了解灾后恢复重建进展。习近平指出，门头沟、房山等山区地带山高谷深，连续强降雨容易造成特大山洪，是北京防汛抗洪的重点区域。既要建好用好水库等控制性工程，也要完善山区道路、房屋等建筑物的防洪标准，切实提高防汛抗洪能力。要立足北京水系特点、总结历史经验，针对突出问题和薄弱环节，按照“上蓄、中疏、下排、有效治洪”的原则，抓紧修复水毁设施，加强重点水利工程建设，为保障首都防洪安全提供有力支撑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随后，习近平乘车来到妙峰山民族学校。今年汛期，这里作为临时避灾场所和防汛抗洪救灾人员驻地。习近平走进一间教室，孩子们正在老师的带领下开主题班会。大家争着向习爷爷展示自己以抗洪救灾为主题的手工制品，并汇报自己在洪灾面前的经历和感受，习近平听后很高兴。他说，保证受灾学生都能按时开学返校，是党中央对灾后恢复重建提出的明确要求。经过各方面共同努力，所有灾区学校都按时开学了，看到孩子们幸福的笑容，很踏实很欣慰。你们学校在这次防汛抗洪中成功避险，而且很好发挥了“安全岛”作用，要用好这一生动教材，开展安全教育，提升孩子们的安全意识和避险能力。这次抗洪救灾孩子们会终生难忘，要让他们学会感恩、立下志向，做社会主义事业的建设者和接班人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;学校操场上，习近平亲切慰问了因公牺牲烈士家属和参与防汛抗洪救灾的基层党员干部群众、消防及应急救援人员、国企职工、志愿者代表等。习近平说，在这场抗洪抢险救灾斗争中，基层党员干部冲锋在前、勇于担当，人民解放军、武警部队官兵、消防救援队伍指战员挺身而出、向险前行，国有企业职工闻“汛”而动、紧急驰援，社会各界和志愿者积极参与、奉献爱心，书写了洪水无情人有情的人间大爱，展现了社会主义制度一方有难、八方支援的显著优势和全国人民万众一心、同舟共济的奋斗精神，涌现出许多感人故事。多名党员干部在抗洪抢险中牺牲，我们要永远怀念他们，大力宣扬他们的英勇事迹，有关方面要关心照顾好他们的家人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;临近中午，习近平来到妙峰山镇水峪嘴村考察。在村口河边平台，习近平听取该村情况介绍，随后步行察看村容村貌，了解基础设施恢复建设提升等情况。习近平指出，大涝大灾之后，务必大建大治，大幅度提高水利设施、防汛设施水平。要坚持以人民为中心，着眼长远、科学规划，把恢复重建与推动高质量发展、推进韧性城市建设、推进乡村振兴、推进生态文明建设等紧密结合起来，有针对性地采取措施，全面提升防灾减灾救灾能力。特别要完善城乡基层应急管理组织体系，提升基层防灾避险和自救互救能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在村民李盟家，习近平详细询问房屋受损、修缮支出、取暖等情况。习近平表示，确保受灾群众安全温暖过冬是一项硬任务。北方冬季长，山里冬天尤其冷，取暖工作务必落实落细，做到每家每户。对已经完成房屋修缮加固或重建、具备入住条件的受灾户，要指导帮助他们落实冬季取暖。对尚未完成房屋重建的受灾户，要通过投亲靠友、租房、政府安置等方式，确保他们温暖过冬。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;离开村子时，当地群众热情欢送总书记。习近平对大家说，我心里一直惦念着灾区的人民群众。共产党是为人民服务的党，永远把老百姓放在心中最高位置，无论是抢险救灾还是灾后恢复重建，都会全力以赴。希望乡亲们坚定信心，努力把家园建设得更加美好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年汛期，保定涿州市遭遇特大洪涝灾害，目前已基本恢复正常生产生活秩序。10日下午，习近平来到双塔街道永济秀园小区。他首先走进小区门口的药店、超市，向商户详细询问经营恢复情况，接着来到小区热力站，了解供暖设施运行情况。习近平表示，经历这场大灾，居民和一些生产经营单位损失不少，各级党委和政府要多措并举，努力帮助受灾群众和企业、商户渡过难关。城市恢复重建要做好防灾减灾论证规划，充分考虑避险避灾，留出行洪通道和泄洪区、滞洪区，更新排水管网等基础设施，提升城市运行保障能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平走进居民董彩英家看望慰问，详细询问洪水水位、应急居住、家具家电更新、供暖、相关补助等情况。董彩英告诉总书记，在党员干部帮助下，房子已完成清理修缮并入住，温暖过冬没问题。习近平强调，城市灾后恢复重建，首要的是家家户户生活和社区居住环境的恢复。要查漏补缺，把工作进一步做细做实，基层组织、党员干部、街坊邻里、各方面专业力量和志愿者要一起努力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;离开小区时，习近平同小区居民亲切交流。习近平对大家说，涿州的这次灾情很重，那时我每天都关注着你们这里的情况，很是挂念大家。今天看到市政公共服务设施已恢复正常运转，大家的生活也已基本恢复正常，心里踏实了很多。风雨之后见彩虹。在党中央坚强领导下，只要大家齐心协力，就一定能够过上更加美好的生活。第二批主题教育正在深入开展，灾区各级党组织要把主题教育与灾后恢复重建紧密结合起来，大力弘扬抗洪救灾精神，充分发挥基层党组织战斗堡垒作用和党员干部先锋模范作用，用恢复重建成果和人民群众满意度来检验主题教育的成效。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;刁窝镇万全庄村位于兰沟洼蓄滞洪区，今年汛期全村311户全部受灾。习近平仔细察看村道、房屋等恢复重建情况。他走进房屋重建施工现场，询问受灾损失、施工进展、租房过渡等情况，勉励他们团结一心，共渡难关，重建和美乡村。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;村民杨佩然家房屋受损较轻，已加固修缮完成并入住。习近平走进杨佩然家里，了解他们的家庭收入、修缮花销、生产恢复等情况。习近平指出，房屋修缮加固重建，是灾后恢复重建的头等大事。现在看，修缮、加固的任务已基本完成，任务最重、难度最大的还是重建。对重建户，各级党委和政府要格外关心，过渡期有特殊困难、自身无法解决居住问题的，要给予适当安置。要采取切实有效措施，防止因灾返贫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;临别时，村民们高声向总书记问好。习近平对大家说，面对历史罕见的洪灾，乡亲们遭受了很大的损失，我向大家表示慰问！各级党委和政府正在多方采取措施，扎实推进灾后恢复重建。希望乡亲们自力更生、艰苦奋斗，用自己的勤劳双手，加快恢复重建、推进乡村振兴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平还走进村边农田，察看冬小麦和大白菜长势。他指出，农业生产是灾后恢复重建的重要方面，不仅直接关系家家户户的收入，也关系国家粮食安全。要继续抓紧修复灾毁农田和农业设施，加大农资供应保障力度，加强农技指导，组织安排好今冬明春的农业生产，争取明年有个好收成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白沟河是大清河流域一条骨干行洪河道。习近平来到白沟河治理工程（涿州段），察看工程进展，听取河北省灾后重建重大水利工程情况汇报。习近平指出，京津冀水系相连，防汛抗洪是一盘棋，要深入研究推进京津冀地区防洪工程体系建设。坚持系统观念，统筹流域和区域，处理好上下游、左右岸、干支流关系，科学布局水库、河道、堤防、蓄滞洪区等的功能建设，整体提高京津冀地区的防洪能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;堤坝上，习近平亲切看望慰问水利工程建设人员和曾经参加涿州抗洪救援的解放军和武警部队官兵、民兵预备役人员、消防救援队伍等方面的代表。他说，这次抗洪救灾，各方面力量与广大人民群众风雨同舟，共同构筑起防汛救灾、守护家园的坚固防线，充分展现了我们党和国家的强大政治优势。人民群众感谢你们，党和政府感谢你们！&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;返回北京前，习近平对陪同人员和当地干部说，在党中央的正确决策部署下，各级各方面采取有力有效措施，把百年一遇的洪涝灾害损失降到了最低。灾后恢复重建涉及范围广，工程项目多，资金投入大。最近中央决定增发1万亿元国债，用于支持灾后恢复重建和提升防灾减灾救灾能力的项目建设。各级党委和政府、各有关部门要坚持求真务实、科学规划、合理布局，把资金用到刀刃上，高质量推进项目建设，把各项工程建设成为民心工程、优质工程、廉洁工程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中共中央政治局常委、中央办公厅主任蔡奇陪同考察。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;何卫东参加有关活动，中央和国家机关有关部门负责同志陪同考察。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 习近平复信费城交响乐团总裁兼首席执行官马思艺]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/11/nw.D110000renmrb_20231111_7-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月11日星期六&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;新华社北京11月10日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;近日，国家主席习近平复信费城交响乐团总裁兼首席执行官马思艺。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平指出，得知费城交响乐团11月第13次来华并与中方合作举办系列演出交流活动，纪念1973年首次访华，续写与中国人民之间跨越半个世纪的音乐友谊，我感到由衷的高兴。 50年前，乐团来华开启中美文化交流“破冰之旅”，在中美关系正常化中具有非常重要的意义。 50年来，乐团作为活跃在中美两国间的“文化使者”先后12次访华，为促进中美关系发展发挥了积极作用。 50年后的今天，费城交响乐团和中国交响乐团及多国歌唱家一起在华演出，必将作为一段珍贵佳话载入史册。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平强调，音乐跨越国界，文化架起桥梁。希望费城交响乐团和包括中美在内的世界各国艺术家一道，坚持文明平等、互鉴、对话、包容，密切交流合作，促进艺术繁荣，为中美人文交流和各国人民友好再续新篇。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1973年9月，费城交响乐团首次访华，成为新中国成立后第一个访华的美国乐团。近日，费城交响乐团总裁兼首席执行官马思艺致信习近平主席，回顾该团与中国的交往历史，介绍今年11月来华举办纪念乐团首次访华50周年演出交流活动的情况，希望通过音乐继续在两国人民和两国文化间架起沟通桥梁。 &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 2023年世界互联网大会乌镇峰会闭幕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/11/nw.D110000renmrb_20231111_8-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月11日星期六&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报嘉兴11月10日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者金歆）为期3天的2023年世界互联网大会乌镇峰会10日在浙江乌镇闭幕。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;据介绍，今年是乌镇峰会连续成功举办的第十年。此次峰会以“建设包容、普惠、有韧性的数字世界——携手构建网络空间命运共同体”为主题，采用线上线下相结合的方式举办，受到国际社会广泛关注。峰会围绕全球发展倡议数字合作、人工智能等议题举办20场分论坛。共有来自126个国家和地区的1800多位嘉宾参会，国别数创历届新高。 &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 2023“直通乌镇”全球互联网大赛结果揭晓]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/11/nw.D110000renmrb_20231111_9-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月11日星期六&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报嘉兴11月10日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者金歆）2023“直通乌镇”全球互联网大赛颁奖典礼10日在浙江乌镇举办。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;作为世界互联网大会乌镇峰会重要活动之一，大赛旨在推动全球互联网合作创新，激发互联网创业活力，集聚互联网青年人才，在全球范围内高质量推动互联网产业精准对接。今年大赛共吸引来自23个国家的1005个项目报名。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;最终，杭州汇健科技有限公司的基于纳米耗材及AI的高通量临床质谱诊断平台项目、魔视智能科技（上海）有限公司的车规级自动驾驶域控制器研发与产业化项目、北京云圣智能科技有限责任公司的全自动空天一体化巡检全息感知管控系统项目等7个项目分别获得数字医疗、网联汽车、数字海洋空天等7个专题赛的特等奖。此外，还有7个项目获一等奖，21个项目获二等奖，35个项目获三等奖。 &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[03版要闻 - 外交部发言人就习近平主席将应邀赴美国举行中美元首会晤 同时出席亚太经合组织第三十次领导人非正式会议答记者问]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/11/nw.D110000renmrb_20231111_1-03.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月11日星期六&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;新华社北京11月10日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;外交部发言人10日就习近平主席将应邀赴美国举行中美元首会晤、同时出席亚太经合组织第三十次领导人非正式会议答记者问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;问：中方发布了习近平主席将赴美国旧金山与拜登总统举行中美元首会晤的消息。这是两国元首继去年巴厘岛会晤后举行的首次面对面会晤，国际社会高度关注。中方对此次会晤有何期待？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;答：应美国总统拜登邀请，中国国家主席习近平将赴美举行中美元首会晤，同时应邀出席亚太经合组织第三十次领导人非正式会议。两国元首将就事关中美关系的战略性、全局性、方向性问题，以及事关世界和平与发展的重大问题深入沟通。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;问：习近平主席下周将出席亚太经合组织第三十次领导人非正式会议。中方对此次会议有何期待？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;答：在亚太经合组织首次领导人会议召开三十周年之际，习近平主席应邀出席会议，充分体现了中方对亚太经济合作的高度重视。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当前，世界经济面临诸多不稳定不确定因素，各方期待亚太继续发挥引擎作用，引领世界经济增长。亚太经合组织是亚太地区重要经济合作平台。习近平主席将在会上发表重要讲话，全面阐述中国对深化亚太合作、促进地区和世界经济增长的重要主张。我们期待各方坚守亚太合作初心，聚焦地区迫切需求，深化团结合作，全面平衡落实亚太经合组织2040年布特拉加亚愿景，推动会议取得积极成果，为亚太和世界增长注入新动力，携手构建亚太命运共同体。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[03版要闻 - 纪念费城交响乐团访华50周年音乐会在京举行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/11/nw.D110000renmrb_20231111_2-03.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月11日星期六&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;新华社北京11月10日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者王宾）11月10日，“跨越半个世纪的友谊”——纪念费城交响乐团访华50周年音乐会在北京举行。中共中央政治局委员、中宣部部长李书磊出席音乐会，宣读习近平主席致费城交响乐团总裁兼首席执行官马思艺的复信并致辞。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;李书磊指出，习近平主席的复信充分体现了对深化中美两国人文交流的高度重视，对拓展中美全方位文化交流合作的殷切期许。李书磊表示，一直以来，文化交流互鉴在促进中美民心相通、筑牢两国关系民意基础中发挥着持久而独特的作用。中方愿与包括美国在内的世界各国文化机构和艺术家一道，共同践行全球文明倡议，基于对艺术的共同热爱加强交流。希望中美文化艺术界的朋友们携手同行，为促进中美两国人民相知相亲贡献文化力量。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;本次音乐会由文化和旅游部主办，中国对外文化交流协会、中国人民对外友好协会、美国国务院支持，费城交响乐团、中国交响乐团、美国亚裔表演艺术中心共同演出。 &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 11 Nov 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>