<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 内蒙古大力发展生态农牧业]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/30/nw.D110000renmrb_20231130_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 30, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;In June this year, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized during his inspection in Inner Mongolia that we should give full play to the advantages of agriculture and animal husbandry, from land, technology Starting from aspects such as , seed sources, water and grass, we will steadily optimize the regional layout and production structure of agriculture and animal husbandry, promote the transformation and development of agriculture and animal husbandry, vigorously develop ecological agriculture and animal husbandry, do a good job in intensive processing of agricultural and animal products and building green and organic brands, and promote The integrated development of primary, secondary and tertiary industries promotes the high-quality development of agriculture and animal husbandry. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region thoroughly implements the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions, from promoting water-saving agriculture, implementing grassland grazing bans and rest grazing and grass-livestock balance systems, developing intensive processing of agricultural and livestock products, and building green organic brands. Start by vigorously developing ecological agriculture and animal husbandry. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The Modern Agriculture and Animal Husbandry Science and Technology Demonstration Park in Wulateqian Banner, Bayannur City, is located on the south bank of Wuliangsuhai Sea. &quot;The demonstration garden has carried out pilot demonstrations of high-efficiency water-saving and fertilizer-saving. Through the application of technologies such as integrated water-fertilizer precision irrigation, it can save 20% of water per mu, reduce the use of pesticides by 20% and chemical fertilizers by 10%, and the ecological benefits are obvious.&quot; Ulat said before Liu Jun, director of the Banner Agriculture and Animal Husbandry Technology Extension Center, said. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“Inner Mongolia vigorously promotes water-saving agriculture and accelerates the transformation of water use methods from extensive and inefficient to conservation and intensive. This year, 373 million cubic meters of water can be saved.” Guo Zhanjiang, director of the Autonomous Region’s Department of Agriculture and Animal Husbandry, said in 2016 By 2022, the average water consumption per mu in Inner Mongolia will drop from 305 cubic meters to 214 cubic meters, and the effective utilization coefficient of farmland irrigation water will increase from 0.532 to 0.574. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;To solve the problem of overloading and overgrazing of grasslands, Inner Mongolia is focusing on implementing the animal husbandry transformation and improvement project. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In Haibuzi Village, Siziwang Banner, Ulanqab City, there is a &quot;sheep community&quot;: 24 high-standard sheep houses come into view, with facilities such as straw storage sheds and lambing nursery rooms. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In October 2022, Haibuzi Village coordinated and integrated agriculture-related and animal husbandry-related funds, and introduced leading enterprises to build the Dumeng mutton sheep breeding complex standardized breeding community, which can accommodate 1,500 basic ewes. &quot;Our village has more than 3,000 acres of grassland. In the past, the grassland was degraded due to overloading and overgrazing.&quot; Liu Jianzhong, secretary of the Party branch of Haibuzi Village, said that not only has the grassland been rested for grazing, but the average income of farmers this year is expected to increase by about 20,000 yuan. . &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;&quot;Inner Mongolia has reduced the number of livestock carried on natural grasslands and solved the problem of &#39;livestock&#39; by developing pen breeding; by developing artificial forage planting, it has improved the utilization rate of caragana and straw resources and rationally utilized natural grasslands. Solve the &#39;grass&#39; problem.&quot; Zhao Yusheng, deputy director of the Autonomous Region&#39;s Agriculture and Animal Husbandry Department, said that so far, Inner Mongolia has built 156 million square meters of livestock greenhouses, with a feed grass supply capacity of about 80 million tons per year. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Focusing on improving the comprehensive benefits of agriculture and animal husbandry, Inner Mongolia has accelerated the creation of a green and organic brand of agricultural and livestock products. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In the fully intelligent unmanned cow barn of Youran Animal Husbandry’s Chilechuan Ecological Smart Ranch in Tumutzuo Banner, Hohhot City, intelligent equipment such as feeding robots and milking robots perform their respective duties. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“Through breed improvement and intelligent and refined management, the average daily yield of dairy cows has been effectively increased this year.” Zhao Guoliang, the person in charge of the livestock business of Youran Animal Husbandry, said. Not far away, in the Yili Modern Smart Health Valley production base, the green high-quality raw milk produced by the Chilechuan Ecological Smart Ranch is being made into various dairy products. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“Through cultivating enterprises to extend the chain, the intensive processing industry of agricultural and livestock products has accelerated development.” Guo Zhanjiang said that Inner Mongolia is focusing on building green organic brands, so that organic milk, Horqin beef, Chifeng millet, Kulun buckwheat and other high-quality Agricultural and livestock products are sold all over the country. Since the beginning of this year, Inner Mongolia has launched green agricultural and livestock product promotion activities in Beijing, Shandong, Guangdong, Sichuan and other places, with a total contract value of 19.248 billion yuan. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In order to promote the high-quality development of the green agricultural and livestock products processing industry, Inner Mongolia has issued an implementation plan for the development of the green agricultural and livestock products processing industry, vigorously promoting the improvement of innovation capabilities, the cultivation of advantageous brands, and the green transformation of the industry. It is planned that by 2025, the output value of Inner Mongolia&#39;s agricultural and livestock products processing industry will reach 400 billion yuan, an increase of 47% from 2020; the processing conversion rate of major agricultural and livestock products will reach 80%, an increase of 20 percentage points from 2020. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 06:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 风电装机容量已超4亿千瓦（新数据 新看点）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/30/nw.D110000renmrb_20231130_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 30, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/30/01/rmrb2023113001p21_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;Data source: National Energy Administration &lt;BR/>;Drawing: Zhang Danfeng&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Qinghai-Tibet Plateau, the world’s highest photovoltaic project - Huadian The Caipeng photovoltaic project in Tibet is sprinting towards its production target and is expected to generate 90 million kilowatt-hours of clean electricity every year, further alleviating the local electricity shortage during the dry season in winter and spring; on the southeast coast, the world&#39;s first floating wind-fishing integration project &quot;National Energy Sharing&quot; &quot;The platform has completed all engineering installations, and the floating wind turbines and breeding cages are combined to achieve both power generation and fish farming...&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The National Energy Administration recently released data showing that as of the end of October, the country&#39;s cumulative installed power generation capacity was approximately 2.81 billion kilowatts, a year-on-year increase of 12.6%. Among them, the installed capacity of solar power generation is approximately 540 million kilowatts, a year-on-year increase of 47%; the installed wind power capacity is approximately 404 million kilowatts, a year-on-year increase of 15.6%. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;From January to October, the country&#39;s major power generation companies completed an investment of 662.1 billion yuan in power supply projects, including 269.4 billion yuan in solar power, a year-on-year increase of 71.2%; and 171.7 billion yuan in wind power, a year-on-year increase of 42.5%. &quot;New energy sources such as wind power and photovoltaics are showing a good trend of rapid development, good operation quality, high utilization level, and strong industrial competitiveness.&quot; said Li Chuangjun, director of the New and Renewable Energy Department of the National Energy Administration. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;——Centralized and distributed development should be carried out simultaneously to help the “supply” of new energy. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In the Ningxia Tengger Desert New Energy Base, the second phase of the 2 million kilowatt photovoltaic project has stepped up construction. &quot;After completion and grid connection, it is expected to provide more than 3.9 billion kilowatt hours of clean electricity every year.&quot; National Energy Group Longyuan Electric Power Chang Zhanding, director of the Engineering Construction Department of Ningxia Company, introduced. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Centralized development is &quot;big and powerful&quot;, while distributed development is &quot;small but beautiful&quot;. On the roof of Cai Jiagui, a villager in Xidong Village, Taishun County, Wenzhou, Zhejiang, 45 photovoltaic panels are arranged neatly. &quot;In addition to personal use at home, excess electricity can also be sold to the power grid company.&quot; Cai Jiagui said. Five counties in Wenzhou have been included in the county-wide rooftop distributed photovoltaic development pilot program. This year, the installed capacity of household photovoltaic applications for new installations has increased by more than 300% year-on-year. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;As of the end of September, the cumulative installed capacity of household distributed photovoltaics nationwide exceeded 100 million kilowatts. At present, the cumulative number of household distributed photovoltaic installations in rural areas exceeds 5 million, driving effective investment of more than 500 billion yuan. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;——The supporting construction of power grid projects is advanced in an orderly manner to ensure that new energy can be “delivered”. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In November, the foundation construction of the first line section of the upper reaches of the Jinsha River-Hubei UHV project was completed in Ganzi, Sichuan. This first UHV DC project to enter the hinterland of the Sichuan-Tibet Plateau is expected to deliver nearly 40 billion kilowatt-hours of clean electricity to central China every year after completion. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Since this year, newly started UHV AC/DC projects such as Zhangbei-Shengli, Ningxia-Hunan, Hami-Chongqing, etc. have accelerated the formation of effective investment. From January to October, investment in power grid projects nationwide reached 373.1 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 6.3%. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;——Accelerate the improvement of energy storage and peak shaving capabilities to promote the &quot;good use&quot; of new energy. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In Guangdong, the second phase of the Meizhou pumped storage power station project has entered the mechanical and electrical equipment installation stage. &quot;Technologies such as pumped hydro storage and new energy storage can help convert fluctuating new energy into stable power supply.&quot; said Zhan Caifeng, deputy general manager of the Meishu Storage Phase II Project Department of China Southern Power Grid. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;As of the end of September, the national installed capacity of pumped hydro energy storage reached 50 million kilowatts. In addition, since this year, the scale of new energy storage installations has continued to expand, and various technical projects such as lithium batteries, compressed air, and flow batteries have grown rapidly. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 06:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 丁薛祥访问土库曼斯坦并主持中土合作委员会第六次会议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/30/nw.D110000renmrb_20231130_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 30, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231130/1701293177013_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;November 28th to 29th, Central Committee of the Communist Party of China Ding Xuexiang, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau and Vice Premier of the State Council, visited Turkmenistan, met with President Serdar Berdimukhamedov of Turkmenistan, held talks with Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Meredov of Turkmenistan and co-chaired China-Turkmenistan cooperation Sixth meeting of the Committee. This is November 29. Ding Xuexiang met with Turkmenistan President Serdar Berdimukhamedov. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Li Tao&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Xinhua News Agency, Ashgabat, November 29 (Reporters Liu Kai and Zheng Mingda) From November 28 to 29, Ding Xuexiang, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Vice Premier of the State Council, visited Turkmenistan and met with Turkmen President Serdar Berdymuha. Medov held talks with Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Meredov of Turkmenistan and co-chaired the sixth meeting of the China-Turkmen Cooperation Committee. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ding Xuexiang said that China-Turkish relations have achieved a &quot;big leap&quot; this year. President Xi Jinping and President Gurbanguly Berdimuhamedov jointly announced that they would upgrade the relationship between the two countries to a comprehensive strategic partnership and implement a community of shared future at the bilateral level. China is willing to work with Turkey to implement the important consensus reached by the two heads of state, continuously enrich the new connotation of China-Turkey comprehensive strategic partnership, and continue to inject new impetus into the construction of a community with a shared future between China and Turkey. China is a trustworthy friend and partner of Turkmenistan and firmly supports Turkmenistan in safeguarding its sovereignty, independence and territorial integrity and pursuing a development path that suits its national conditions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ding Xuexiang pointed out that China-Turkmenistan cooperation is highly complementary, has huge potential and broad prospects. The two sides should give full play to their complementary advantages, tap into the potential for cooperation, continue to deepen and expand cooperation in key areas, and turn the grand blueprint planned by the leaders of the two countries into practical results to better benefit the two countries and their peoples. China is willing to work with Central Asian countries, including Turkey, to steadily advance the construction of China-Central Asia cooperation mechanisms. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Germany Berdimukhamedov asked Ding Xuexiang to convey his sincere greetings to President Xi Jinping, saying that Turkey and China have profound traditional friendship and that the all-round cooperation between the two countries is strategic, long-term and special. Turkey is willing to strengthen strategic communication with China, deepen practical cooperation in various fields, and push Turkey-China comprehensive strategic partnership to a new level. The outcomes of the first China-Central Asia Summit are being effectively implemented. Turkey firmly supports the China-Central Asia cooperation mechanism and is willing to work with China to promote regional security, stability, development and prosperity. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the 29th, Ding Xuexiang and Meredov co-chaired the sixth meeting of the China-Turkmen Cooperation Committee. The meeting fully affirmed the progress made in practical cooperation between the two sides, focusing on cooperation issues such as economy and trade, investment, natural gas, connectivity, cultural exchanges, and security, and exchanged in-depth views and planned the focus of cooperation in the next stage. The two sides agreed to further strengthen the alignment of development strategies and lead all-round cooperation between China and Turkey through high-quality joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. Efforts should be made to increase the scale of economic, trade and investment cooperation, continue to deepen natural gas cooperation, accelerate consultations on the docking of priority economic projects, and carry out more project cooperation in non-resource fields. Actively create a new pattern of connectivity and further deepen China-Turkmenistan transportation and logistics cooperation. Expand new channels for people-to-people and cultural exchanges, organize cultural year-related activities, and promote the early implementation of projects such as mutual establishment of cultural centers, the establishment of Luban workshops, and traditional medicine centers in the country. Continue to expand security cooperation, further deepen anti-terrorism cooperation, and jointly combat the &quot;three evil forces&quot;. The China-Turkmenistan Cooperation Committee should fully implement the important consensus reached by the two heads of state, give full play to the role of overall planning, coordination and guidance, and push the practical cooperation between the two countries to a new level. After the meeting, Ding Xuexiang and Meredov signed the &quot;Minutes of the Sixth Meeting of the China-Turkmen Cooperation Committee&quot; and witnessed the signing of a memorandum of understanding on deepening scientific and technological cooperation, an international road transport agreement and other cooperation documents. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 06:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 韩正会见中俄友好、和平与发展委员会第十四次全体会议与会代表]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/30/nw.D110000renmrb_20231130_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 30, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 29th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Vice Chairman Han Zheng met with China-Russia Friendship Group in Beijing on the 29th , representatives from both sides attending the 14th plenary session of the Peace and Development Commission. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Han Zheng said that under the strategic guidance of President Xi Jinping and President Putin, the China-Russia comprehensive strategic partnership of coordination for a new era has continued to develop healthily and steadily. Political mutual trust between the two sides has continued to deepen, pragmatic cooperation has steadily advanced, and the foundation of public opinion has become increasingly solid. This year, the two heads of state met twice face-to-face, making comprehensive arrangements for the development of bilateral relations and charting the course for promoting Sino-Russian people-to-people friendship. It is hoped that the committee will implement the important consensus reached by the two heads of state, take the opportunity of celebrating the 75th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and Russia next year and hosting the Cultural Year, give full play to the strong cohesion, inspiration and driving force of people-to-people diplomacy, and make new and greater contributions to the development of bilateral relations. . &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Titov, the Russian chairman of the committee, said that Russia-China relations are at a historical high, with outstanding results in people-to-people and cultural exchanges and practical cooperation. The committee will seize the important time points next year to continue to promote people-to-people exchanges between the two countries and help Russia-China relations continue to reach new levels. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 06:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 合肥打造空天信息产业新高地（加快形成新质生产力）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/30/nw.D110000renmrb_20231130_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 30, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;“Chasing the Starry Sky” is shining into the industrial reality of Hefei, Anhui. On September 5 this year, the &quot;Hefei High-tech No. 1&quot; satellite was launched on a rocket from the Oriental Space Port, ushering in a glorious moment for Hefei&#39;s aerospace information industry. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the exhibition hall of the Deep Space Exploration Laboratory in the western suburbs of Hefei, the Tiandu-1 and Tiandu-2 test satellite models are eye-catching. &quot;The names of the two satellites come from the main peak of Huangshan Mountain. They were developed by our laboratory and are planned to be launched next year.&quot; Yu Jike, business director of the laboratory, said that the two satellites will jointly carry out technical verification with the Queqiao-2 relay satellite, and will be followed by the Queqiao-2 relay satellite. Provide design reference for the demonstration and implementation of Tongnao remote constellation system. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This laboratory will be built into a comprehensive support platform for major scientific and technological projects in the field of deep space exploration in my country. Around it, the Space and Space Information Industrial Park &quot;aiming at&quot; deep space Internet, deep space remote sensing, and deep space resource utilization has begun to take shape. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Integrating scientific and technological innovation resources, Hefei insists on taking innovation as its biggest policy and bravely serves as a pioneer in scientific and technological innovation and industrial innovation. It not only has the Deep Space Exploration Laboratory, the National Laboratory of Quantum Information Science, and the Beidou Navigation Technology Anhui Provincial laboratories and other innovative platforms and large scientific facilities have also cultivated multiple industries with a scale of over 100 billion yuan, such as automobiles, integrated circuits, and flat panel displays. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Hefei’s technological innovation platform and industrial ecology, as well as the local government’s support for the aerospace industry, are important reasons for us to choose here.” said Sun Yaohui, Vice President of Zhongke Star Map Digital Earth Hefei Co., Ltd. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In November 2021, the Aerospace Information Innovation Institute of the Chinese Academy of Sciences launched a strategic cooperation with Hefei City, and Zhongke Star Map launched the GEOVIS Digital Earth Global Headquarters project in Hefei. Since then, Hefei has begun planning the aerospace information industry and competing for new tracks. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Introduced &quot;Several Policies to Accelerate the High-Quality Development of the Aerospace Information Industry&quot;; launched the 5 billion yuan Anhui Aerospace Information Industry Fund and the first commercial aerospace information special fund - Heshengxingtu Fund; Hefei High-tech Zone establishes an industrial park, integrates the aerospace information industry into the &quot;Future Science City&quot; spatial planning, and provides policy support in terms of headquarters landing, R&amp;D innovation, financing support, frequency rail resources, etc... A large number of scientific research institutions, R&amp;D teams and Innovative enterprises are committed to the development of the aerospace information industry. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing Guodian Hi-Tech Co., Ltd. is here with the &quot;Apocalypse Constellation&quot;. &quot;Hefei High-tech No. 1&quot; is the 21st low-orbit communication service satellite among the 38 stars planned in the Apocalypse constellation. He Yiming, general manager of Apocalypse Satellite Internet of Things Technology Co., Ltd., said that the launch and operation of the Apocalypse Constellation is like &quot;laying a foundation&quot; in space, providing powerful aerospace infrastructure for the development of the aerospace information industry, and will drive the development of sensors, the Internet of Things, and large-scale Upgrading and transformation of data and other industries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China Satellite Technology Group Co., Ltd. is here. This company, which was born out of the Aerospace Information Innovation Institute of the Chinese Academy of Sciences, has built a base in Hefei High-tech Zone in less than a year. &quot;Hefei&#39;s industrial soil has accelerated the industrialization of our original innovation results.&quot; said Zhou Jian, the company&#39;s general manager. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The zero-gravity aircraft &quot;flyed&quot;. Zero Gravity Aircraft Industry (Hefei) Co., Ltd. is an innovative enterprise led by academicians, which mainly develops manned electric vertical take-off and landing aircraft. In October, the first-generation multi-rotor manned electric vertical take-off and landing aircraft ZG-ONE No. 1 was assembled and successfully tested. Li Yiheng, general manager of the company, said: &quot;From deep space to low altitude, from information services to hardware equipment, a local industrial ecology is rich, giving enterprises a greater space for development.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Today&#39;s technology, the future industry. Through application traction, capital assistance, and ecological creation, Hefei&#39;s aerospace information industry has developed rapidly. Since the end of 2021, Hefei has signed 54 aerospace information industry projects with an agreed investment amount of 33.5 billion yuan, bringing together nearly 100 aerospace information industry-related companies and innovation platforms. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The aerospace information industry is a typical new productive force. With the establishment and operation of a number of leading enterprises such as Aerospace Hongtu, Galaxy Aerospace, and Beihang Aerospace, Hefei has initially formed a space for aerospace product design, manufacturing, integration, A whole industry chain framework for testing, experimentation and information services.&quot; The person in charge of Hefei&#39;s aerospace information industry team said that there are currently more than 60 reserve projects under discussion, with an intended investment of over 20 billion yuan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the &quot;Hefei City&#39;s &quot;14th Five-Year Plan&quot; Aerospace Information Industry Development Plan&quot;, Hefei strives to form a satellite manufacturing industry with a scale of about 10 billion yuan and a satellite manufacturing industry with a scale of about 30 billion yuan by the end of the &quot;14th Five-Year Plan&quot; Application terminals and operation service industries, &quot;Tongdaoyao&quot; data comprehensive application and supporting industries with a scale of about 50 billion yuan, and cultivating a &quot;space and space&quot; industrial ecology with a scale of 100 billion yuan. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 06:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 海口新海滚装码头客运综合枢纽站项目试运营]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/30/nw.D110000renmrb_20231130_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 30, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231130/1701293183546_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/ TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;On November 29, the Haikou Xinhai Ro-Ro Terminal Passenger Transport Comprehensive Hub Project was put into trial operation. The project and the new seaport comprehensive transportation hub and supporting facilities construction project have a total construction area of ​​216,000 square meters, with an annual designed throughput capacity of 35 million passengers and 5.6 million vehicles. After being put into operation, the Xinhai Passenger Transport Comprehensive Hub Station will integrate port waiting, port inspection, hub commerce and other functions, and will play an important role in promoting the integrated development of Haikou Port, Industry and City, and promoting the construction of the Qiongzhou Strait Economic Zone and Hainan Free Trade Port. The picture shows the Xinhai Passenger Transport Comprehensive Hub Station project site. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Our reporter&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Cao Wenxuanwen&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency reporter&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Photo by Guo&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Cheng&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/ enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 06:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 凝聚开放共识 汇聚发展合力（今日谈）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/30/nw.D110000renmrb_20231130_7-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 30, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;&quot;Link the world and create the future together.&quot; On November 28, the first China International Supply Chain Promotion Expo opened in Beijing. More than 500 Chinese and foreign companies and institutions gathered together to showcase new technologies, new products, and new services in key links in the upstream, midstream, and downstream of each chain, and to promote the global industrial division of labor. , resource allocation, innovative cooperation and achievement sharing. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: &quot;Maintaining the resilience and stability of global industrial and supply chains is an important guarantee for promoting world economic development and serves the common interests of people of all countries in the world.&quot; Division of labor and cooperation in global industrial and supply chains are the key to economic globalization. inevitable choice. In the &quot;Smart Auto Chain&quot; exhibition area, a company brought ceramic aluminum seed crystal raw materials to meet the demand for lightweight vehicles; an exhibitor focused on intelligent driving solutions to provide drivers with a better experience; and a complete vehicle dedicated to aviation food was on display. , realizing unmanned operations... This world&#39;s first national-level exhibition with the theme of supply chain not only displays products, but also displays chains and ecology; it not only focuses on transactions, but also focuses on long-term cooperation and common development. Promoting the connection between upstream, mid-stream and downstream, the integration of large and medium-sized enterprises, the collaboration of industry, academia and research, and the interaction between Chinese and foreign enterprises will help enhance new development momentum, open up new development space, and inject confidence into the stability of global industrial and supply chains. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;At present, the global industrial system and industrial chain supply chain are showing a trend of diversified layout, regional cooperation, green transformation, and digital acceleration. Using the first Chain Expo as a window to build open consensus and gather development synergies, it will surely help build a safe, stable, smooth and efficient, open and inclusive, mutually beneficial and win-win global industrial chain and supply chain system, in order to promote the global economic cycle and boost world economic growth. , and contribute to improving the well-being of people in all countries. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 06:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 严厉打非治违  深查彻改隐患 全力做好岁末年初安全生产工作]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/30/nw.D110000renmrb_20231130_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 30, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 29th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The National Video and Telephone Conference on Production Safety was held in Beijing on the 29th. Zhang Guoqing, Prime Minister and Director of the Security Committee of the State Council, attended the meeting and delivered a speech. Wang Xiaohong, State Councilor and Deputy Director of the Security Committee of the State Council, presided over the meeting. The meeting emphasized the need to thoroughly implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions, implement the requirements of Prime Minister Li Qiang, learn lessons from recent accidents, draw inferences from one example to strictly control safety risks in key industries, make great efforts to improve the quality and efficiency of hidden danger investigation and rectification, and take strong measures to do a good job in the year-end Work on safety in production at the end of the year and the beginning of the year, and resolutely prevent and contain major accidents. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The meeting required that we should accurately grasp the true safety situation of mines, vigorously promote mine safety improvements, comprehensively inspect and &quot;screen&quot; underground and above-ground areas, eliminate potential safety hazards such as bathroom baskets as soon as possible, and deepen the management of major mine disasters. Strictly crack down on over-excavation and over-exploitation, private excavation, and evasion of supervision. It is necessary to highlight large commercial complexes, high-rise buildings, &quot;nine small places&quot;, &quot;factories within factories&quot;, commercial self-built houses, and key places such as hospitals, schools, and nursing homes, and comprehensively promote the investigation and rectification of fire hazards, supervision and law enforcement, and fire prevention publicity. Resolutely curb the tendency of frequent fires. It is necessary to strengthen safety management and control in key areas such as hazardous chemicals, transportation, and construction based on winter climate characteristics. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The meeting emphasized that we must keep our eyes downward, conduct professional inspections directly on-site, conduct in-depth investigations into specific problems, take heavy measures to promote rectification, and pay close attention to the safety management of front-line positions. It is necessary to further consolidate regulatory responsibilities, strictly manage the regulatory team, deepen the root cause of the problem, and accelerate the consolidation of the grassroots foundation for safe production. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 06:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 解决关键小事  办好民生大事（政策解读）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/30/nw.D110000renmrb_20231130_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 30, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Community is the basic unit of urban public services and urban governance. In order to better promote high-quality inclusive public services at the grassroots level and into communities, the National Development and Reform Commission and relevant departments have studied and formulated the &quot;Implementation Plan for the Construction of Embedded Service Facilities in Urban Communities&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Plan&quot;), which was recently approved by the General Office of the State Council. Forward to all regions and departments for implementation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What changes will the &quot;Plan&quot; bring to people&#39;s lives? Relevant persons in charge from the National Development and Reform Commission and other departments provided interpretations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;In accordance with the principles of precision, scale and marketization, we will prioritize and focus on providing urgently needed services&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Although the community is small, it is connected to thousands of households. . At present, more than 65% of my country&#39;s population lives in cities, and residents mainly live in communities. Whether you can enjoy high-quality and inclusive public services at your doorstep is not only a &#39;key matter&#39; but also a &#39;big matter for people&#39;s livelihood.&#39;&quot; National Development and Reform Commission Social Liu Ming, Director of the Development Department, said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What and how to build embedded service facilities in urban communities? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liu Ming introduced that in accordance with precise service requirements, all localities should prioritize and focus on providing services that are urgently needed by the public, such as community meal assistance, child care, etc., and gradually supplement other services to ensure convenience, accessibility, and Affordable prices and guaranteed quality. Focus on promoting and giving priority to the construction (renovation) of community-embedded service complexes (community service centers) with complex and integrated functions to provide one-stop services to residents. Communities that do not meet the conditions for the time being can build embedded service facilities with relatively single functions in a &quot;flower arrangement&quot; style. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The &quot;Plan&quot; clarifies that the scope of project implementation covers all types of cities, with priority given to promoting construction in large cities with a permanent population of more than 1 million. &quot;We will follow the idea of ​​&#39;piloting first and gradually rolling out&#39; and select some cities and communities to pilot. On the basis of summarizing the experience and effective construction models formed by the pilot, we will steadily and orderly expand to other cities and more communities. Push it away.&quot; Liu Ming said that the positioning of building community embedded service facilities can be grasped from three aspects -&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is a project to benefit the people&#39;s livelihood by promoting public services to better cover the residents. Organically embed public service resources into thousands of communities, deliver high-quality and convenient public services to thousands of households, make high-quality services within walking distance, and allow the masses to enjoy high-quality services at their doorsteps and downstairs, which can effectively solve the problem of picking up and running errands for the masses. It is difficult to effectively reduce public service and social operating costs. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is a heart-warming project to build the community into a happy home for the people. Bringing urgently needed services into the community and continuously improving community functions will make the community a happy home that carries the people&#39;s good life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is a people-benefit project that effectively enhances people’s sense of gain, happiness, and security. We insist that people go to the grassroots, money is invested in the grassroots, and policies are tilted towards the grassroots. We allocate resources scientifically, accurately meet needs, and integrate community services into the lights of thousands of homes and deliver them to thousands of households. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Ministry of Natural Resources is promoting in-depth special research on public service facilities and other aspects in various regions, and determines floor area ratio with the guidance of strengthening the protection of people&#39;s livelihood and stimulating public welfare contributions. “Municipal infrastructure, public service facilities, and public safety facilities projects implemented to ensure the basic living needs of residents and make up for urban shortcomings, on the premise that they do not have a negative impact on the surrounding areas, the scale of their new buildings may not be affected by the planned volume. &quot;Constraints of rate indicators.&quot; Yang Jun, deputy director of the Bureau of Land and Spatial Planning of the Ministry of Natural Resources, said that on the basis of these guidelines, various localities can explore and innovate planning and land policies to support the construction of embedded service facilities in urban communities according to local conditions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Carry out urban physical examinations, find out the shortcomings of community facilities, and focus on community service facilities in the construction of complete communities&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, urban and rural housing construction The ministry has taken a series of measures to strive to build &quot;good communities&quot; that satisfy the masses: Since 2019, it has guided various localities to add 56,000 community service facilities such as elderly care and childcare in the renovation of old urban communities, benefiting more than 3,800 residents. 10,000 households; since 2020, we have actively promoted the construction of complete communities, equipped with &quot;one elderly and one small&quot; service facilities that are urgently needed by the people. The proportion of newly built residential areas with up-to-standard elderly care service facilities has increased from 46.1% in 2020 to 83.2% in 2022. %. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The goal of building a complete community is consistent with the implementation of the community embedded service facility construction project. In order to connect the two tasks, we have adopted the strategy of focusing the construction of a complete community on community service facilities and overall coordination of the community. Measures such as service facility construction standards and the establishment of efficient connection working mechanisms.&quot; Zhang Yan, deputy director of the Department of Building Energy Conservation and Science and Technology of the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development, said that in the next step, multiple measures will be taken to cooperate with the National Development and Reform Commission to do relevant work. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Carry out comprehensive urban physical examinations to find out the shortcomings of community facilities. Starting from 2024, urban physical examinations will be comprehensively carried out in cities at the prefecture level and above. Residential areas, communities, and blocks will be listed as the basic units of urban physical examinations, and community elderly care service facilities, infant care service facilities, public activity venues, and cultural activities will be identified. We will list the problems and shortcomings of centers and other facilities that are not up to standard, have imperfect functions, and have insufficient services. We will list the problems, enter them into the information platform, and implement dynamic updates to provide strong support for the scientific planning, rational layout, and accurate embedding of community service facilities. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Implement urban renewal actions and build community facilities according to local conditions. In the renovation of old urban communities, we carry out &quot;corridor revolution&quot;, &quot;environmental revolution&quot; and &quot;management revolution&quot;, and improve supporting facilities through additional construction, purchase, replacement, leasing, renovation and other methods. In the construction of a complete community, we will focus on the shortcomings of service facilities for &quot;one old and one young&quot;, implement a number of construction projects such as elderly service stations, nurseries, and kindergartens to connect the 15-minute living circle, and promote the coordinated construction and joint transformation of adjacent communities and surrounding areas , Strengthen the co-construction and sharing of facilities. In the process of creating vibrant neighborhoods, we will implement the renovation of old commercial areas, pedestrian streets, old factory areas, etc., and prioritize the vacated space resources for the construction of public service facilities. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Strengthen and improve residential property management to help improve community service levels. Give full play to the advantages of property service companies being close to residents, develop community elderly care, child care, housekeeping, meal assistance and other life service businesses, and explore the &quot;property service + life service&quot; model. Promote property service companies to accelerate the development of online and offline life services, improve smart property management service levels, fill in community service shortcomings, and better meet the diverse and multi-level living needs of residents. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Bring elderly care services to the elderly and provide various forms of care services for infants and young children under 3 years old&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The &quot;Plan&quot; proposes that community-embedded Service facilities provide community residents with one or more services such as elderly care, community meal assistance, housekeeping convenience, health services, sports and fitness, culture and leisure, and children&#39;s recreation. Among them, elderly care services are an important part. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vigorously developing home and community elderly care services is an important and urgent task to comply with the desire of most elderly people to rely on community home care and to solve the urgent, difficult and anxious problems of the elderly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The introduction of the &quot;Plan&quot; is of great significance for accelerating the construction of home and community elderly care service networks and quickly delivering elderly care services to the bedside of the elderly.&quot; said Li Yongxin, deputy director of the Department of Elderly Care Services of the Ministry of Civil Affairs. , relying on community-embedded service facilities, can provide support for home-based elderly care from four aspects: First, it helps to improve the home-community elderly care service network and open up the &quot;last mile&quot; of providing elderly care services to the elderly; second, it increases the number of people with short-term care. Nursing-type elderly care beds with nursing functions will effectively meet the needs of the elderly to receive professional care services at their doorstep; third, it will help promote the multi-point layout of elderly meal assistance services, make services more accessible, and make them more convenient and accessible to more people. The elderly can eat hot meals at their doorstep; fourth, it helps operating entities such as elderly care service agencies to provide daily care, daily visits, meal assistance, cleaning assistance, bathing assistance, medical assistance, walking assistance, and emergency assistance for the elderly at home. Door-to-door service to meet diverse elderly care service needs. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Community embedded childcare services can provide full-day care, half-day care, hourly care, temporary care and other forms of care services for infants and young children under 3 years old. It is one of the forms of childcare services recognized by families. one. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xu Yongjun, deputy director of the Population and Family Department of the National Health Commission, said that relying on communities to develop inclusive childcare services has unique advantages: First, it can achieve the goal of providing care nearby and conveniently, especially in residential areas. The living environment of the community and the family are homogeneous, which is convenient for the development and growth of infants and young children; secondly, the community&#39;s supporting buildings and public activity venues can be used to revitalize idle resources and provide them for use by childcare service institutions, reducing operating costs and service prices; thirdly, It can give full play to the advantages of social organizations, real estate properties, community-based enterprises and institutions and other social forces to enrich service content. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The key to carrying out pilot city construction lies in the local area.” Liu Ming said that all localities must conscientiously implement the requirements of the “Plan”, effectively strengthen organizational leadership, prepare high-quality implementation plans, and improve construction and operation systems. Study and formulate a list of support policies and actively prepare project reserves. &quot;We will work with relevant departments to guide and urge all localities to conscientiously complete the pilot application and construction work.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr >;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt; br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 06:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 2024届高校毕业生“秋季校园招聘月”启动]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/30/nw.D110000renmrb_20231130_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 30, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, November 29th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Wu Dan) The Ministry of Education has recently launched the 2024 college graduation program The &quot;Autumn Campus Recruitment Month&quot; series of activities for students has been launched nationwide, including special recruitment activities, special actions to promote employment by visiting companies, &quot;employment education&quot; theme education, the first national college student career planning competition and other series of activities to further integrate the society resources, provide centralized employment positions, and strengthen employment guidance services in colleges and universities. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;It is reported that the Ministry of Education will hold more than 40 special recruitment activities with relevant parties. Among them, together with 12 social recruitment agencies, we jointly launched the &quot;24365 Campus Recruitment Service&quot; online recruitment month activity, organizing more than 20 series of special recruitment activities for key areas, key industries, key groups, etc.; organizing employment and entrepreneurship guidance for general universities across the country The committee&#39;s 19 sub-industries have held more than 20 &quot;special job fairs for college graduates in industry fields&quot; to provide job information for graduates of relevant majors. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;At the same time, various localities will hold regional, industry and alliance online and offline special job fairs based on local realities to provide sufficient high-quality job resources for college graduates in the region. Various colleges and universities will hold various forms of online and offline campus recruitment activities to help graduates find employment. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The Ministry of Education has made it clear that universities and employers are encouraged to carry out docking cooperation in targeted talent training and training, employment internship bases, human resources improvement, research in key areas, and assistance to needy groups; focusing on the employment situation, career In terms of planning, job search skills, etc., we will create a batch of high-quality public welfare live broadcast courses on &quot;Internet + Employment Guidance&quot;; coordinate and promote career planning competitions, coordinate and promote the competitions with various employment guidance, online and offline recruitment and other concurrent activities, and promote competitions to promote learning , Use competition to promote teaching, use competition to promote achievement. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 06:56:07 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 经营主体信用监管4项重点国家标准通过立项评审]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/30/nw.D110000renmrb_20231130_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 30, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, November 29th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Lin Lili) The National Standards and Technology Review Center recently Organized a national credit supervision standard project review meeting in Beijing. Based on the review results of the National Standards and Technical Review Center, three national standards for credit supervision were issued: &quot;Implementation Guidelines for Credit Commitments of Business Entities&quot;, &quot;Credit Evaluation Indicators for Individual Industrial and Commercial Households&quot; and &quot;Enterprise Credit File Information Requirements&quot; Passed the project review. Together with the national standard &quot;Guidelines for the Classification of Untrustworthy Information of Business Entities&quot; that was reviewed and approved in July this year, four key national standards for credit supervision have passed the project review. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Among them, the national standard &quot;Guidelines for the Implementation of Credit Commitments of Business Entities&quot; proposes the types of credit commitments of business entities, commitment content, commitment procedures, commitment management and commitment application; the national standard &quot;Credit Evaluation Indicators for Individual Industrial and Commercial Households&quot; It puts forward the basic principles, index content, index setting and grade classification for the construction of credit evaluation indicators for individual industrial and commercial households; the national standard &quot;Enterprise Credit File Information Requirements&quot; puts forward the basic principles for establishing enterprise credit files, file information types, information sources and file inclusions. Information items; the national standards of the &quot;Classification of Business Main Anthology Information Category&quot; propose the basic principles, classification system architecture, category of credit information, and classification expansion principles for the classification of information classification. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; The State Administration of Market Supervision and Administration will implement the standard drafting work, and in accordance with the &quot;Opinions of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; the State Council&#39;s Opinions on Accelerating the Construction of the National Unified Unified Market&quot; &quot; Opinions of the new development pattern &quot;&quot; Regulations on Promoting the Development of Individual Industry and Commerce &quot;and other policy requirements, build a credit supervision standard system with sound legal systems, complete mechanisms, smooth operations, and efficient supervision, and promote the construction of a high -quality of the credit system for business entities with credit supervision standardization. Development to help build a national unified market. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 30 Nov 2023 06:56:07 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>