<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平出席第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛开幕式并发表主旨演讲]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20231019_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 19, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-10/19/01/rmrb2023101901p30_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the morning of October 18, President Xi Jinping attended the opening ceremony of the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing and delivered a keynote speech titled &quot;Building an Open, Inclusive, Connected, and Common Development World.&quot; &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Wang Ye&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot; center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-10/19/01/rmrb2023101901p31_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR >; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the morning of October 18, President Xi Jinping attended the opening ceremony of the 3rd “Belt and Road” International Cooperation Summit Forum at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing and delivered a speech titled “Building Openness, Inclusion, Interconnection, A keynote speech for a world of common development. This is a group photo taken before the meeting of Xi Jinping with international dignitaries such as foreign heads of state, heads of government and heads of international organizations attending the summit forum. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Huang Jingwen&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;The achievements made in the past 10 years are extremely precious , the experience is worth summarizing. We deeply realize that mankind is an interdependent community with a shared future. When the world is good, China will be good; when China is good, the world will be better. Through the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, China&#39;s door to the outside world is opening wider and wider, and the Chinese market is more closely connected with the world market. We deeply realize that only win-win cooperation can accomplish things, do good things, and do great things. As long as all countries have the desire to cooperate and coordinate actions, natural chasms can be opened up, &quot;land-locked countries&quot; can become &quot;land-linked countries&quot;, and lowlands of development can become highlands of prosperity. We deeply realize that the Silk Road spirit of peace and cooperation, openness and inclusiveness, mutual learning, and mutual benefit is the most important source of strength for jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. The joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; emphasizes that when everyone adds fuel and helps each other, we can go a long way. What we advocate is that we can live well and let others live well. What we practice is interconnection, mutual benefit and reciprocity. What we pursue is Common development and win-win cooperation. We do not engage in ideological confrontation, geopolitical games, or group political confrontations. We oppose unilateral sanctions, economic coercion, and &quot;decoupling and breaking links.&quot; The 10-year history has proved that the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; stands on the right side of history, conforms to the logic of the progress of the times, and follows the right path in the world. We must have the determination to remain calm even when flying through chaotic clouds, and with a responsible attitude toward history, the people, and the world, we must work together to respond to various global risks and challenges and create a world of peace, development, cooperation, and win-win for future generations. bright future. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■This year marks the 10th anniversary of my proposing the Belt and Road Initiative. The original intention of proposing this initiative is to learn from the ancient Silk Road, take interconnection as the main line, and strengthen policy communication, facility connectivity, unimpeded trade, financial integration, and people-to-people bonds with other countries, so as to inject new momentum into world economic growth and open up new avenues for global development. New space, creating a new platform for international economic cooperation&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■China is comprehensively promoting the construction of a strong country and the great cause of national rejuvenation with Chinese-style modernization. What we pursue is not China&#39;s modernization alone, but we look forward to working with other countries, including developing countries, to realize modernization together. World modernization should be modernization of peaceful development, modernization of mutually beneficial cooperation, and modernization of common prosperity. China is willing to deepen the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; cooperative partnership with all parties, promote the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; into a new stage of high-quality development, and make unremitting efforts to realize the modernization of all countries in the world&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■ Announced China&#39;s support for high-quality development Eight actions to jointly build the “Belt and Road” with quality: 1. Build a three-dimensional interconnection network for the “Belt and Road”. 2. Support the building of an open world economy. 3. Carry out practical cooperation. 4. Promote green development. 5. Promote scientific and technological innovation. 6. Support people-to-people exchanges. 7. Build a path of integrity. 8. Improve the “Belt and Road” international cooperation mechanism&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■ The joint construction of the “Belt and Road” originates from China, and the results and opportunities belong to the world. Let us keep in mind the expectations of the people, bravely shoulder the historical burden, keep abreast of the pulse of the times, build on the past and forge ahead with courage, deepen the international cooperation on the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, and welcome new developments of higher quality and higher levels in the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. Promote the modernization of all countries in the world, build an open, inclusive, interconnected, and common development world, and jointly promote the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This newspaper, Beijing, October 18 &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Wang Hailin, Zhang Wujun, Zhu Yingqi) On the morning of October 18, President Xi Jinping attended the opening ceremony of the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum at the Great Hall of the People and delivered a speech entitled &quot;Building Openness, Inclusion, and Connectivity&quot; , a world of common development&quot; keynote speech. Xi Jinping announced China&#39;s eight actions to support high-quality joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and emphasized that China is willing to deepen the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; cooperative partnership with all parties, promote the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; into a new stage of high-quality development, and contribute to the realization of world All countries have made unremitting efforts to modernize. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the golden autumn, the sky is high and the air is crisp, the wind is clear and the sun is bright. In Tiananmen Square, the national flags of the countries co-building the “Belt and Road” fluttered in the wind, complementing each other. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;International dignitaries such as foreign heads of state, heads of government and heads of international organizations attending the summit forum arrived one after another. The &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; project has achieved fruitful results over the past ten years on the large screens on both sides of the east entrance hall of the Great Hall of the People. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping took a group photo with foreign leaders attending the opening ceremony. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To the music of &quot;Peace-A Community with a Shared Future&quot;, Xi Jinping entered the venue together with foreign leaders. The whole audience stood up to give a warm welcome. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping delivered a keynote speech entitled &quot;Building an Open, Inclusive, Interconnected, and Common Development World.&quot; (See the second page for the full text of the speech)&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that this year marks the 10th anniversary of my proposing the joint construction of the “Belt and Road” initiative. The original intention of proposing this initiative is to learn from the ancient Silk Road, take interconnection as the main line, and strengthen policy communication, facility connectivity, unimpeded trade, financial integration, and people-to-people bonds with other countries, so as to inject new momentum into world economic growth and open up new avenues for global development. New space to create a new platform for international economic cooperation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the past 10 years, we have adhered to our original aspirations and worked hand in hand to promote the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; international cooperation from scratch, flourish and achieve fruitful results. The “Belt and Road” cooperation extends from the Eurasian continent to Africa and Latin America. More than 150 countries and more than 30 international organizations have signed cooperation documents on the joint construction of the “Belt and Road” and established more than 20 multilateral cooperation platforms in professional fields; a large number of iconic &quot;Small but beautiful&quot; projects and projects that benefit people&#39;s livelihood have taken root; consultation, joint contribution and sharing, openness, greenness and cleanliness, high standards and sustainability to benefit people&#39;s livelihood have become important guiding principles for high-quality joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. Over the past 10 years, we have been committed to building a global interconnection network led by economic corridors, with major channels and information highways as the skeleton, and relying on railways, highways, airports, ports, and pipeline networks, covering land, sea, space, and the Internet. , effectively promoted the circulation of goods, capital, technology, and personnel from various countries, and promoted the ancient Silk Road that has lasted for thousands of years to rejuvenate in the new era. The joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; adheres to the principle of extensive consultation, joint contribution and shared benefits, spanning different civilizations, cultures, social systems and differences in development stages, opening up new paths for exchanges between countries, building a new framework for international cooperation, and bringing together the greatest convention for the common development of mankind. number. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping emphasized that the achievements made in the past 10 years are extremely valuable and the experience is worth summarizing. We deeply realize that mankind is an interdependent community with a shared future. When the world is good, China will be good; when China is good, the world will be better. Through the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, China&#39;s door to the outside world is opening wider and wider, and the Chinese market is more closely connected with the world market. We deeply realize that only win-win cooperation can accomplish things, do good things, and do great things. As long as all countries have the desire to cooperate and coordinate actions, natural chasms can be opened up, &quot;land-locked countries&quot; can become &quot;land-linked countries&quot;, and lowlands of development can become highlands of prosperity. We deeply realize that the Silk Road spirit of peace and cooperation, openness and inclusiveness, mutual learning, and mutual benefit is the most important source of strength for jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. The joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; emphasizes that when everyone adds fuel and helps each other, we can go a long way. What we advocate is that we can live well and let others live well. What we practice is interconnection, mutual benefit and reciprocity. What we pursue is Common development and win-win cooperation. We do not engage in ideological confrontation, geopolitical games, or group political confrontations. We oppose unilateral sanctions, economic coercion, and &quot;decoupling and breaking links.&quot; The 10-year history has proved that the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; stands on the right side of history, conforms to the logic of the progress of the times, and follows the right path in the world. We must have the determination to remain calm even when flying through chaotic clouds, and with a responsible attitude toward history, the people, and the world, we must work together to respond to various global risks and challenges and create a world of peace, development, cooperation, and win-win for future generations. bright future. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that China is comprehensively advancing the great cause of building a strong country and rejuvenating the nation with Chinese-style modernization. What we pursue is not China&#39;s modernization alone, but we look forward to working with other countries, including developing countries, to realize modernization together. World modernization should be modernization of peaceful development, modernization of mutually beneficial cooperation, and modernization of common prosperity. China is willing to deepen the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; cooperative partnership with all parties, promote the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; into a new stage of high-quality development, and make unremitting efforts to realize the modernization of all countries in the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping announced eight actions for China to support high-quality joint construction of the “Belt and Road”: &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1. Build a three-dimensional interconnection network for the “Belt and Road”. China will accelerate the high-quality development of China-Europe trains, participate in the construction of the Trans-Caspian International Transport Corridor, successfully host the China-Europe International Cooperation Forum, and work with all parties to build a new logistics channel for the Eurasian continent supported by direct railway and highway transportation. Actively promote the integrated development of &quot;Silk Road and Maritime Transport&quot; ports, shipping and trade, and accelerate the construction of the New Land-Sea Corridor and the Air Silk Road. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2. Support the building of an open world economy. China will create a &quot;Silk Road E-commerce&quot; cooperation pilot zone and negotiate free trade agreements and investment protection agreements with more countries. Comprehensively remove restrictions on foreign investment access in the manufacturing sector. Actively follow international high-standard economic and trade rules, further promote high-level opening up of cross-border service trade and investment, expand market access for digital products, and deepen reforms in the fields of state-owned enterprises, digital economy, intellectual property, and government procurement. China will hold the &quot;Global Digital Trade Expo&quot; every year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;3. Carry out pragmatic cooperation. China will coordinate the promotion of landmark projects and &quot;small but beautiful&quot; people&#39;s livelihood projects. The China Development Bank and the Export-Import Bank of China will set up RMB financing windows, and the Silk Road Fund will add new funds to support the joint construction of &quot;Belt and Road&quot; projects in a market-oriented and commercial manner. China will also implement 1,000 small livelihood assistance projects, promote Sino-foreign vocational education cooperation through Luban Workshop, etc., and work with all parties to strengthen the safety of projects and personnel involved in the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4. Promote green development. China will continue to deepen cooperation in green infrastructure, green energy, green transportation and other fields, increase support for the “Belt and Road” Green Development International Alliance, continue to hold the “Belt and Road” Green Innovation Conference, and build a photovoltaic industry dialogue and exchange mechanism and a green and low-carbon Expert network. Implement the “Belt and Road” green investment principles and conduct 100,000 training sessions for partner countries by 2030. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5. Promote technological innovation. China will continue to implement the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; science and technology innovation action plan, hold the first &quot;Belt and Road&quot; science and technology exchange conference, expand the number of joint laboratories built with all parties to 100 in the next five years, and support young scientists from all over the world to come to China for short-term work. China will propose a global artificial intelligence governance initiative at this forum and is willing to strengthen exchanges and dialogue with other countries to jointly promote the healthy, orderly and safe development of global artificial intelligence. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6. Support non-governmental exchanges. China will hold the &quot;Liangzhu Forum&quot; to deepen civilized dialogue with countries co-building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. On the basis of the Silk Road International Theater, Art Festival, Museum, Art Gallery, and Library Alliance, the Silk Road Tourism Cities Alliance was established. Continue to implement the “Silk Road” Chinese Government Scholarship Program. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7. Build a path of integrity. China will work with its partners to release the &quot;Belt and Road Initiative&#39;s Integrity Construction Achievements and Prospects&quot;, launch the &quot;Belt and Road Initiative&#39;s Integrity Construction Advanced Principles&quot;, establish a &quot;Belt and Road Initiative&quot; enterprise integrity and compliance evaluation system, and cooperate with international organizations to carry out the &quot;Belt and Road Initiative&quot; “Integrity Research and Training. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;8. Improve the “Belt and Road” international cooperation mechanism. China will strengthen the construction of multilateral cooperation platforms with countries participating in the Belt and Road Initiative in the fields of energy, taxation, finance, green development, disaster reduction, anti-corruption, think tanks, media, culture and other fields. Continue to hold the “Belt and Road” International Cooperation Summit Forum and establish a secretariat for the summit forum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping finally pointed out that the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; originated from China, and the results and opportunities belong to the world. Let us keep in mind the expectations of the people, bravely shoulder the historical burden, keep abreast of the pulse of the times, build on the past and forge ahead with courage, deepen the international cooperation on the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, and welcome new developments of higher quality and higher levels in the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. Promote the modernization of all countries in the world, build a world that is open, inclusive, interconnected, and common development, and jointly promote the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Argentine President Fernandez, Chilean President Boric, Republic of Congo President Sassou, Indonesian President Joko, Kazakhstan President Tokayev, Kenyan President Ruto, Laos President Thongloun Sisoulith, and Mongolian President Khurelsukh, Russian President Vladimir Putin, Serbian President Vucic, Sri Lankan President Wickremesinghe, Turkmenistan’s national leader and Chairman of the Council of People’s Commissars Gurbanguly Berdimuhamedov, Uzbekistan President Mirziyoyev, Vietnamese President Vo Van Tring, Cambodian Prime Minister Hun Manai, Egyptian Prime Minister Madbouly, Ethiopian Prime Minister Abiy, Hungarian Prime Minister Orban, Mozambique Prime Minister Maleane, Pakistani Prime Minister Kakkar, Papua New Guinea Prime Minister Marape, Prime Minister of Thailand Settar, Vice President of Nigeria Shettima, Special Representative of the President of the United Arab Emirates and Chief of the Emirate of Ras Al Khaimah Qasimi, Special Representative of the President of France and former Prime Minister Raffarin, Senior Representative of the Prime Minister of Greece and Minister of Development Skrekas Heads of state, heads of government, and high-level representatives from more than 20 countries, as well as heads of international organizations such as United Nations Secretary-General Guterres and New Development Bank President Rousseff attended the opening ceremony. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Putin, Tokayev, Jokowi, Fernandez, Abiy, and Guterres also delivered speeches at the opening ceremony. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ding Xuexiang presided over the opening ceremony. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cai Qi, Wang Yi, Yin Li, He Lifeng, Wang Xiaohong and others attended. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 07:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平同俄罗斯总统普京会谈]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20231019_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 19, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-10/19/01/rmrb2023101901p29_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;At noon on October 18, President Xi Jinping held talks at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing with Russian President Vladimir Putin, who was in China to attend the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Zhang Ling&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;This newspaper, Beijing, October 18th&amp;nbsp ;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Du Shangze and Wang Hailin) ​​At noon on October 18, President Xi Jinping held talks at the Great Hall of the People with Russian President Vladimir Putin, who was in China to attend the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that President Putin has attended the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum for three consecutive times, which reflects Russia&#39;s support for the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative. Russia is an important partner for China in international cooperation in building the “Belt and Road” initiative. Major infrastructure projects such as the China-Russia east-route natural gas pipeline have been put into operation, bringing tangible benefits to the people of the two countries. China is willing to work with Russia and the countries of the Eurasian Economic Union to promote the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and the Eurasian Economic Union, and carry out higher-level and deeper regional cooperation. We hope that the China-Mongolia-Russia natural gas pipeline project will make substantial progress as soon as possible. , carry out the &quot;Wanli Tea Road&quot; cross-border tourism cooperation, and build the China-Mongolia-Russia Economic Corridor into a high-quality connectivity development path. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping emphasized that developing Sino-Russian relations featuring permanent good-neighborly friendship, comprehensive strategic coordination, and mutually beneficial cooperation is not a temporary solution, but a long-term solution. Next year marks the 75th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and Russia. China is willing to work with Russia to accurately grasp the historical trend, base on the fundamental interests of the two peoples, and continuously enrich the contemporary connotation of bilateral cooperation. China supports the Russian people in taking the path of national rejuvenation of their own choice and safeguarding national sovereignty, security and development interests. Both sides should promote the high-quality development of China-Russia pragmatic cooperation, actively explore cooperation in strategic emerging industries, and take the 2024-2025 China-Russia Cultural Year as an opportunity to hold more colorful cultural exchange activities. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that not long ago, the BRICS countries achieved historic expansion, demonstrating the confidence of developing countries in promoting world multipolarity and democratization of international relations. China supports Russia in successfully hosting the BRICS Leaders’ Meeting in Kazan next year, and is willing to continue to strengthen communication and coordination with Russia within multilateral frameworks such as the United Nations, the Shanghai Cooperation Organization, and the Group of 20, so as to safeguard food security, energy security, and global peace and stability. The stability of industrial and supply chains will play a greater role in safeguarding the common interests of China and Russia, as well as regional and developing countries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Putin congratulated the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum on its complete success, saying that the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative proposed by President Xi Jinping 10 years ago has achieved great success and has become an important international initiative recognized by the world. public product. I speak highly of President Xi Jinping’s keynote speech at the opening ceremony of the forum, appreciate President Xi Jinping’s foresight, and believe in and wish greater achievements in the great cause of jointly building the “Belt and Road”. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Putin said that President Xi Jinping paid a successful state visit to Russia in March this year. We had in-depth communication on many major issues, and the consensus reached is being seriously implemented. The evolution of the international situation has fully confirmed President Xi Jinping’s strategic judgment of major changes unseen in a century. Russia is willing to work with China to intensify communication and cooperation within multilateral mechanisms such as BRICS, safeguard the international system based on international law, and promote the establishment of a more fair and reasonable global governance system. There is only one China in the world, and Taiwan is an inalienable part of China&#39;s territory. Russia firmly adheres to the one-China policy and firmly supports China in safeguarding national sovereignty and territorial integrity. Russia is willing to work with China to take the opportunity of celebrating the 75th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between the two countries next year to further promote the development of Russia-China comprehensive strategic partnership of coordination. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two heads of state also had an in-depth exchange of views on the situation between Palestine and Israel. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cai Qi and Wang Yi attended the talks. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 07:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平会见阿根廷总统费尔南德斯]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20231019_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 19, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231019/1697667243587_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the evening of October 18, President Xi Jinping The Great Hall of the People in Beijing met with Argentine President Fernandez, who was in China to attend the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Li Xueren&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 18th&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;(Journalist permission, Zhang Xiao) On the evening of October 18, President Xi Jinping met at the Great Hall of the People with Argentine President Fernandez, who was in China to attend the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that over the past 50 years since the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and Afghanistan, the two sides have always respected each other, treated each other as equals, and achieved mutual benefit and win-win results. In recent years, under our joint leadership, China-UAE relations have continued to reach new heights. China and Argentina are both major developing countries, and both shoulder the historical mission of promoting national development and revitalization, realizing the people&#39;s yearning for a better life, and safeguarding international fairness and justice. China is willing to work with Afghanistan to strengthen strategic alignment, promote the stability and long-term development of China-Afghanistan relations, and set an example of unity and cooperation among countries in the global South. China supports Argentina in maintaining economic and financial stability, and is willing to share development opportunities with Argentina, promote high-quality joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, and deepen practical cooperation in agriculture, infrastructure and other fields. China is willing to import more high-quality products from Argentina and encourage more Chinese companies to invest in Argentina. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping congratulated Argentina on being invited to join the BRICS cooperation mechanism, and pointed out that China and Argentina should strengthen strategic coordination within the framework of the United Nations, the G20, the BRICS cooperation mechanism and other frameworks, and promote the implementation of global development initiatives and global security Initiative and global civilization initiative to promote the building of a community with a shared future for mankind. China has always supported the integration process of Latin America and the Caribbean and is willing to work with Argentina and other Latin American and Caribbean countries to promote the construction of the China-Latin America Forum and the development of China-Latin America relations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fernandez said that a friend in need is a friend indeed. In the past few years, whether in the face of the COVID-19 epidemic, severe drought, or financial and economic difficulties, China has extended a precious helping hand to the Argentine people, which has deeply moved the Argentine side and will be remembered in their hearts. China is Argentina&#39;s true friend. President Xi Jinping&#39;s important initiatives such as jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and building a community with a shared future for mankind have pointed the way forward for the world, created important opportunities for developing countries, and played an irreplaceable role in promoting world peace, fairness and sustainable development. The Albanian side fully agrees and actively supports it. Afghanistan firmly adheres to the one-China principle and hopes to deepen cooperation with China in the fields of economy, trade, infrastructure and other fields to promote new development of the comprehensive strategic partnership between Afghanistan and China. Argentina is willing to actively promote the development of Latin America-China relations, work with China to adhere to multilateralism, and strengthen communication and coordination within frameworks such as the G20 and the BRICS cooperation mechanism. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cai Qi and Wang Yi attended the meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 07:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平会见肯尼亚总统鲁托]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20231019_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 19, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231019/1697667251433_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the evening of October 18, President Xi Jinping The Great Hall of the People in Beijing met with Kenyan President Ruto, who was in China to attend the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Li Xueren&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 18th&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;(Reporter permission, Chen Xu) On the evening of October 18, President Xi Jinping met at the Great Hall of the People with President Ruto of Kenya, who was in China to attend the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that China-Kenya friendship has a long history. Since the establishment of diplomatic relations 60 years ago, the two countries have treated each other as equals and supported each other. They are good friends who trust each other and good partners for win-win cooperation. In recent years, China and Kenya have cooperated in the implementation of a large number of projects such as the Mombasa-Nairobi Railway and the Mombasa Oil Terminal. The joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative has blossomed in Kenya, giving the people of the two countries a greater sense of gain. China views China-Kenya relations from a strategic and long-term perspective, and is willing to work with Kenya to promote the continuous development of the comprehensive strategic cooperative partnership between the two countries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping emphasized that China supports Kenya in independently exploring a modernization path that suits its own reality, and is willing to carry out exchanges of experience in state governance and administration with Kenya and firmly support each other. Kenya is welcome to make full use of trade promotion initiatives and platforms such as the &quot;green channel&quot; for African agricultural products to be exported to China, share the dividends of the Chinese market and opening up, and promote the export of more Kenyan characteristic and high-quality products to China. China supports more Chinese companies to invest in Kenya, expand cooperation in digital economy, new energy and other fields, and help Kenya achieve green development. Both sides should make good use of platforms such as the Confucius Institute and Luban Workshop to deepen local cooperation and people-to-people exchanges. Strengthen multilateral communication and collaboration, practice true multilateralism, and safeguard the common interests of developing countries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ruto expressed congratulations to China for successfully hosting the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. Since the establishment of diplomatic relations between Kenya and China 60 years ago, the two sides have always trusted and respected each other. Especially since President Xi Jinping proposed the Belt and Road Initiative, Kenya has benefited a lot from cooperation with China. Important projects such as the Mombasa-Nairobi Railway have greatly enhanced Kenya’s economic development capabilities and enhanced people’s well-being. It is believed that the eight actions proposed by President Xi Jinping to jointly build the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; with high quality can further help Kenya and Africa achieve industrialization, agricultural modernization and economic integration. Kenya firmly adheres to the one-China policy, supports China&#39;s legitimate stance on human rights and other issues, and hopes to learn from China&#39;s successful development experience, deepen practical cooperation and people-to-people and cultural exchanges, and promote the continuous development of the Kenya-China comprehensive strategic cooperative partnership and Africa-China relations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cai Qi and Wang Yi attended the meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 07:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平会见尼日利亚副总统谢蒂马]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20231019_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 19, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-10/19/02/rmrb2023101902p12_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of October 18, President Xi Jinping met at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing with Vice President Shettima of Nigeria, who was in China to attend the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Li Xueren&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 18th&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;(Reporter permission, Lin Miaomiao) On the afternoon of October 18, President Xi Jinping met at the Great Hall of the People with Nigerian Vice President Shettima, who was in China to attend the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that this year marks the 10th anniversary of my proposing the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative, and the 10th anniversary of my proposing the policy concept of sincerity, real results, affinity and good faith towards Africa. Over the past 10 years, China-Africa cooperation in building the Belt and Road Initiative has shown great vitality, and a large number of landmark projects have been completed one after another. There are many highlights in the cooperation between China and Nepal in jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. A large number of cooperation projects such as railways, ports, power stations, and communication backbone networks have been completed one after another, and the construction of free trade zones has made remarkable achievements. China is willing to continue working with Nigeria to promote China-Nigeria and China-Africa cooperation in jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; to achieve more tangible results and help Nigeria and Africa achieve industrialization and agricultural modernization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping emphasized that since China and Nigeria established diplomatic relations more than half a century ago, the two countries have always adhered to mutual respect and mutual benefit. Facing a world intertwined with chaos, China and Nepal need to strengthen unity and cooperation more than ever. China supports Nigeria in taking a modernization path that suits its national conditions, and is willing to strengthen personnel exchanges with Nigeria at all levels and promote high-quality practical cooperation. China supports Nigeria in playing a greater role in international and regional affairs, and is willing to strengthen strategic coordination with Nigeria, promote democratization of international relations, and safeguard the common interests of developing countries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shettima expressed congratulations to China for successfully hosting the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. Nigeria and China are good friends who share weal and woe and help each other. China has always treated Nigeria and other African countries with respect and equality, never dictated to others, and has done its best to support the African people in their pursuit of independence and development. Thanks to China for proposing a series of important global cooperation initiatives for developing countries, providing valuable assistance to Nigeria&#39;s development, and assisting the industrialization process of Nigeria and Africa. Nigeria attaches great importance to developing relations with China, unswervingly pursues the one-China policy, is firmly committed to the high-level development of Nigeria-China relations, and is willing to continue to deepen cooperation with China in jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and elevate Nigeria-China relations to a new level. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cai Qi and Wang Yi attended the meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 07:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平会见联合国秘书长古特雷斯]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20231019_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 19, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231019/1697667267749_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the evening of October 18, President Xi Jinping The Great Hall of the People in Beijing met with United Nations Secretary-General António Guterres, who was in China to attend the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Li Xueren&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 18th&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;(Journalist permission, Ji Ning) On the evening of October 18, President Xi Jinping met at the Great Hall of the People with United Nations Secretary-General Guterres, who was in China to attend the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping emphasized that the world today is facing many global threats and challenges, and the international community must unite and cooperate and pay more attention to development issues. I proposed building a community with a shared future for mankind in order to find the right path to jointly respond to various global challenges; I proposed jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative and the global development initiative in order to gather more positive energy, promote the common development of all countries, and help The United Nations 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development leaves no country behind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that since the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative was proposed 10 years ago, it has achieved many tangible results and demonstrated vigorous vitality. Peaches and plums, the next from Seikei. The joint construction of the Belt and Road Initiative has become a popular global public good and international cooperation platform. The United Nations is an important partner in building the Belt and Road Initiative. China is willing to work with United Nations agencies to solidly promote high-quality joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and contribute to world peace and development. China supports the work of the United Nations and Secretary-General Guterres, and is willing to strengthen cooperation with United Nations agencies to promote multilateralism and world multipolarity, and promote global governance in a more just and reasonable direction. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Guterres said that developing countries are in a fragile and unfair position in terms of infrastructure, investment and financing. The international financial system can no longer reflect the political and economic realities of today&#39;s world and is in urgent need of reform. The Belt and Road Initiative proposed by President Xi Jinping provides a very important and effective way to help developing countries achieve sustainable development and sets a model for South-South cooperation. The eight actions announced by President Xi Jinping at the third Belt and Road Forum for International Cooperation are fully in line with the purposes and goals of the United Nations and will help developing countries accelerate their development. The United Nations highly appreciates China&#39;s firm maintenance of multilateralism, support for the three major global initiatives proposed by President Xi Jinping, and its firm commitment to deepening cooperation with China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cai Qi and Wang Yi attended the meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 07:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 建设开放包容、互联互通、共同发展的世界]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20231019_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 19, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Dear heads of state and government,&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Heads of international organizations,&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;Representatives from various countries,&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Distinguished guests,&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ladies, gentlemen, friends:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Today, we are here to hold the third &quot; The opening ceremony of the Belt and Road International Cooperation Summit Forum. On behalf of the Chinese government and people, and in my own name, I would like to extend a warm welcome to all the guests! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This year marks the 10th anniversary of my proposing the Belt and Road Initiative. The original intention of proposing this initiative is to learn from the ancient Silk Road, take interconnection as the main line, and strengthen policy communication, facility connectivity, unimpeded trade, financial integration, and people-to-people bonds with other countries, so as to inject new momentum into world economic growth and open up new avenues for global development. New space to create a new platform for international economic cooperation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the past 10 years, we have adhered to our original aspirations and worked hand in hand to promote the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; international cooperation from scratch, flourish and achieve fruitful results. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The &quot;Belt and Road&quot; cooperation extends from the Eurasian continent to Africa and Latin America. More than 150 countries and more than 30 international organizations have signed cooperation documents on the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and held 3 &quot;Belt and Road&quot; international conferences. The Cooperation Summit Forum has established more than 20 multilateral cooperation platforms in professional fields. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; cooperation has entered the &quot;meticulous&quot; stage from &quot;general freehand brushwork&quot;, transforming planning diagrams into actual pictures, and a large number of iconic projects and &quot;small but beautiful&quot; projects that benefit people&#39;s livelihood have taken root. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“One Belt, One Road” cooperation has expanded from hard connectivity to soft connectivity. Extensive consultation, joint contribution and shared benefits, openness, greenness and integrity, high standards that benefit people&#39;s livelihood and sustainability have become important guiding principles for high-quality joint construction of the Belt and Road Initiative. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the past 10 years, we have been committed to building an economic corridor as the guide, with large channels and information highways as the skeleton, and relying on railways, highways, airports, ports, and pipeline networks, covering land, sea, and sky. The global interconnection network of the Internet and the Internet has effectively promoted the circulation of goods, funds, technology, and personnel in various countries, and promoted the ancient Silk Road that has lasted for thousands of years to rejuvenate in the new era. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trains running on railways, cars galloping on highways, air flights connecting countries, freighters cutting through waves, and fast and convenient digital e-commerce have become the bells and sails of international trade in the new era. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一座座水电站、风电站、光伏电站，一条条输油、输气管道，越来越智能通达的输电网络，让能源短缺不再是发展的瓶颈，让发展中国家绿色低碳发展的梦想得以点亮，成为新时代可持续发展的绿洲、灯塔。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现代化的机场和码头，通畅的道路，拔地而起的经贸产业合作园区，催生新的经济走廊，激发新的增长动力，成为新时代的商贸大道、驿站。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;精彩纷呈的文化年、艺术节、博览会、展览会，独具特色的鲁班工坊、“丝路一家亲”、“光明行”等人文交流项目，不断深化的民间组织、智库、媒体、青年交流，奏响新时代的丝路乐章。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新冠疫情暴发后，“一带一路”成为生命之路和健康之路。中国向各国提供了上百亿个口罩和23亿剂疫苗，同20多个国家合作生产疫苗，为共建“一带一路”合作伙伴抗击疫情作出独特贡献。中国在疫情最严峻的时候也得到70多个国家的宝贵支持。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共建“一带一路”坚持共商共建共享，跨越不同文明、文化、社会制度、发展阶段差异，开辟了各国交往的新路径，搭建起国际合作的新框架，汇集着人类共同发展的最大公约数。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;女士们、先生们、朋友们！ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去10年取得的成绩弥足珍贵，经验值得总结。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们深刻认识到，人类是相互依存的命运共同体。世界好，中国才会好；中国好，世界会更好。通过共建“一带一路”，中国对外开放的大门越开越大，内陆地区从“后卫”变成“前锋”，沿海地区开放发展更上一层楼，中国市场同世界市场的联系更加紧密。中国已经是140多个国家和地区的主要贸易伙伴，是越来越多国家的主要投资来源国。无论是中国对外投资，还是外国对华投资，都彰显了友谊和合作，体现着信心和希望。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们深刻认识到，只有合作共赢才能办成事、办好事、办大事。只要各国有合作的愿望、协调的行动，天堑可以变通途，“陆锁国”可以变成“陆联国”，发展的洼地可以变成繁荣的高地。经济发展快一些的国家，要拉一把暂时走在后面的伙伴。只要大家把彼此视为朋友和伙伴，相互尊重、相互支持、相互成就，赠人玫瑰则手有余香，成就别人也是帮助自己。把别人的发展视为威胁，把经济相互依存视为风险，不会让自己生活得更好、发展得更快。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们深刻认识到，和平合作、开放包容、互学互鉴、互利共赢的丝路精神，是共建“一带一路”最重要的力量源泉。我曾经讲过，古丝绸之路之所以名垂青史，靠的不是战马和长矛，而是驼队和善意；不是坚船和利炮，而是宝船和友谊。共建“一带一路”注重的是众人拾柴火焰高、互帮互助走得远，崇尚的是自己过得好、也让别人过得好，践行的是互联互通、互利互惠，谋求的是共同发展、合作共赢。不搞意识形态对立，不搞地缘政治博弈，也不搞集团政治对抗，反对单边制裁，反对经济胁迫，也反对“脱钩断链”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10年的历程证明，共建“一带一路”站在了历史正确一边，符合时代进步的逻辑，走的是人间正道。我们要有乱云飞渡仍从容的定力，本着对历史、对人民、对世界负责的态度，携手应对各种全球性风险和挑战，为子孙后代创造和平、发展、合作、共赢的美好未来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;女士们、先生们、朋友们！ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当前，世界之变、时代之变、历史之变正以前所未有的方式展开。中国正在以中国式现代化全面推进强国建设、民族复兴伟业。我们追求的不是中国独善其身的现代化，而是期待同广大发展中国家在内的各国一道，共同实现现代化。世界现代化应该是和平发展的现代化、互利合作的现代化、共同繁荣的现代化。前行道路上，有顺境也会有逆流。我们要坚持目标导向、行动导向，咬定青山不放松，一张蓝图绘到底。中方愿同各方深化“一带一路”合作伙伴关系，推动共建“一带一路”进入高质量发展的新阶段，为实现世界各国的现代化作出不懈努力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在这里，我愿宣布中国支持高质量共建“一带一路”的八项行动：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一、构建“一带一路”立体互联互通网络。中方将加快推进中欧班列高质量发展，参与跨里海国际运输走廊建设，办好中欧班列国际合作论坛，会同各方搭建以铁路、公路直达运输为支撑的亚欧大陆物流新通道。积极推进“丝路海运”港航贸一体化发展，加快陆海新通道、空中丝绸之路建设。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;二、支持建设开放型世界经济。中方将创建“丝路电商”合作先行区，同更多国家商签自由贸易协定、投资保护协定。全面取消制造业领域外资准入限制措施。主动对照国际高标准经贸规则，深入推进跨境服务贸易和投资高水平开放，扩大数字产品等市场准入，深化国有企业、数字经济、知识产权、政府采购等领域改革。中方将每年举办“全球数字贸易博览会”。未来5年（2024—2028年），中国货物贸易、服务贸易进出口额有望累计超过32万亿美元、5万亿美元。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三、开展务实合作。中方将统筹推进标志性工程和“小而美”民生项目。中国国家开发银行、中国进出口银行将各设立3500亿元人民币融资窗口，丝路基金新增资金800亿元人民币，以市场化、商业化方式支持共建“一带一路”项目。本届高峰论坛期间举行的企业家大会达成了972亿美元的项目合作协议。中方还将实施1000个小型民生援助项目，通过鲁班工坊等推进中外职业教育合作，并同各方加强对共建“一带一路”项目和人员安全保障。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;四、促进绿色发展。中方将持续深化绿色基建、绿色能源、绿色交通等领域合作，加大对“一带一路”绿色发展国际联盟的支持，继续举办“一带一路”绿色创新大会，建设光伏产业对话交流机制和绿色低碳专家网络。落实“一带一路”绿色投资原则，到2030年为伙伴国开展10万人次培训。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;五、推动科技创新。中方将继续实施“一带一路”科技创新行动计划，举办首届“一带一路”科技交流大会，未来5年把同各方共建的联合实验室扩大到100家，支持各国青年科学家来华短期工作。中方将在本届论坛上提出全球人工智能治理倡议，愿同各国加强交流和对话，共同促进全球人工智能健康有序安全发展。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;六、支持民间交往。中方将举办“良渚论坛”，深化同共建“一带一路”国家的文明对话。在已经成立丝绸之路国际剧院、艺术节、博物馆、美术馆、图书馆联盟的基础上，成立丝绸之路旅游城市联盟。继续实施“丝绸之路”中国政府奖学金项目。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;七、建设廉洁之路。中方将会同合作伙伴发布《“一带一路”廉洁建设成效与展望》，推出《“一带一路”廉洁建设高级原则》，建立“一带一路”企业廉洁合规评价体系，同国际组织合作开展“一带一路”廉洁研究和培训。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;八、完善“一带一路”国际合作机制。中方将同共建“一带一路”各国加强能源、税收、金融、绿色发展、减灾、反腐败、智库、媒体、文化等领域的多边合作平台建设。继续举办“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛，并成立高峰论坛秘书处。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;女士们、先生们、朋友们！ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十年栉风沐雨，十年春华秋实。共建“一带一路”源自中国，成果和机遇属于世界。让我们谨记人民期盼，勇扛历史重担，把准时代脉搏，继往开来、勇毅前行，深化“一带一路”国际合作，迎接共建“一带一路”更高质量、更高水平的新发展，推动实现世界各国的现代化，建设一个开放包容、互联互通、共同发展的世界，共同推动构建人类命运共同体！ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;祝第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛圆满成功！ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谢谢大家。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（新华社北京10月18日电）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 07:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 习近平会见阿根廷总统费尔南德斯]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20231019_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月19日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231019/1697667243587_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;10月18日晚，国家主席习近平在北京人民大会堂会见来华出席第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛的阿根廷总统费尔南德斯。&lt;BR/>;新华社记者李学仁摄&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;新华社北京10月18日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者许可、张骁）10月18日晚，国家主席习近平在人民大会堂会见来华出席第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛的阿根廷总统费尔南德斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平指出，中阿建交50多年来，双方始终相互尊重、平等相待、互利共赢。近年来，在我们共同引领下，中阿关系不断迈上新台阶。中阿同为发展中大国，都肩负着推动国家发展振兴、实现人民对美好生活向往、维护国际公平正义的历史使命。中方愿同阿方一道，加强战略对接，推动中阿关系行稳致远，树立全球南方国家团结合作的典范。中方支持阿根廷维护经济金融稳定，愿同阿方分享发展机遇，推动高质量共建“一带一路”，深化农业、基础设施等领域务实合作。中方愿进口更多阿根廷优质产品，鼓励更多中国企业赴阿投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平祝贺阿根廷获邀加入金砖国家合作机制，指出中阿要在联合国、二十国集团、金砖合作机制等框架内加强战略协调，推进落实全球发展倡议、全球安全倡议、全球文明倡议，推动构建人类命运共同体。中方一贯支持拉美和加勒比地区一体化进程，愿同阿根廷和其他拉美和加勒比国家一道，推动中拉论坛建设和中拉关系发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;费尔南德斯表示，患难见真情。过去几年里，无论是面对新冠疫情、大旱天灾，还是金融经济困难，中国都向阿根廷人民伸出宝贵援助之手，令阿方深受感动，铭记在心。中国是阿根廷的真正朋友。习近平主席提出的共建“一带一路”、构建人类命运共同体等重要倡议为世界指明了前进方向，为发展中国家创造了重要机遇，为促进世界和平与公平、可持续发展发挥了不可替代的重要作用，阿方完全赞同、积极支持。阿方坚定恪守一个中国原则，希望同中方深化经贸、基础设施等领域合作，推动阿中全面战略伙伴关系实现新发展。阿方愿积极促进拉中关系发展，同中方一道，坚守多边主义，加强在二十国集团和金砖合作机制等框架内沟通协作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蔡奇、王毅参加会见。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 07:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 习近平会见肯尼亚总统鲁托]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20231019_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月19日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231019/1697667251433_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;10月18日晚，国家主席习近平在北京人民大会堂会见来华出席第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛的肯尼亚总统鲁托。&lt;BR/>;新华社记者李学仁摄&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;新华社北京10月18日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者许可、陈旭）10月18日晚，国家主席习近平在人民大会堂会见来华出席第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛的肯尼亚总统鲁托。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平指出，中肯友好源远流长。建交60年来，两国平等相待、相互支持，是彼此信赖的好朋友、合作共赢的好伙伴。近年来，中肯合作实施了蒙内铁路、蒙巴萨油码头等一大批项目，共建“一带一路”倡议在肯尼亚开花结果，让两国人民增强了获得感。中方从战略高度和长远角度看待中肯关系，愿同肯方一道，推动两国全面战略合作伙伴关系不断发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平强调，中方支持肯尼亚自主探索符合本国实际的现代化道路，愿同肯方开展治国理政经验交流，坚定相互支持。欢迎肯方充分利用非洲农产品输华“绿色通道”等贸易促进举措和平台，分享中国市场和开放红利，推动更多肯尼亚特色优质产品对华出口。中方支持更多中国企业赴肯尼亚投资，拓展数字经济、新能源等领域合作，助力肯尼亚实现绿色发展。双方要用好孔子学院、鲁班工坊等平台，深化地方合作和人文交流。加强多边沟通协作，践行真正的多边主义，维护发展中国家共同利益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鲁托表示，祝贺中方成功举办第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛。肯中建交60年来，双方始终相互信任、相互尊重。特别是习近平主席提出共建“一带一路”倡议以来，肯尼亚从同中国合作中获益良多。蒙内铁路等重要项目极大提升了肯经济发展能力，增进了人民福祉。相信习近平主席提出的高质量共建“一带一路”八项行动，能够进一步助力肯尼亚和非洲实现工业化、农业现代化和经济一体化。肯方坚定奉行一个中国政策，支持中方在人权等问题上的正当立场，希望学习借鉴中国成功发展经验，深化务实合作和人文交流，推动肯中全面战略合作伙伴关系和非中关系不断发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蔡奇、王毅参加会见。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 07:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 习近平会见尼日利亚副总统谢蒂马]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20231019_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月19日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-10/19/02/rmrb2023101902p12_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;10月18日下午，国家主席习近平在北京人民大会堂会见来华出席第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛的尼日利亚副总统谢蒂马。&lt;BR/>;新华社记者李学仁摄&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;新华社北京10月18日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者许可、林苗苗）10月18日下午，国家主席习近平在人民大会堂会见来华出席第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛的尼日利亚副总统谢蒂马。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平指出，今年是我提出共建“一带一路”倡议10周年，也是我提出真实亲诚对非政策理念10周年。10年来，中非共建“一带一路”展现出蓬勃生机，一大批标志性项目相继建成。中尼共建“一带一路”合作亮点纷呈，铁路、港口、电站、通信骨干网等大批合作项目陆续竣工，自由贸易区建设成绩斐然。中方愿同尼方继续努力，推动中尼、中非共建“一带一路”合作取得更多实实在在的成果，助力尼日利亚和非洲实现工业化和农业现代化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平强调，中尼建交半个多世纪以来，两国始终坚持相互尊重、互利互惠。面对变乱交织的世界，中尼比以往任何时候都更需要加强团结合作。中方支持尼日利亚走符合本国国情的现代化道路，愿同尼方加强各层级人员往来，高质量推进务实合作。中方支持尼日利亚在国际和地区事务中发挥更大作用，愿同尼方加强战略协调，推动国际关系民主化，维护发展中国家共同利益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谢蒂马表示，祝贺中方成功举办第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛。尼日利亚同中国是患难与共、守望相助的好朋友，中国对尼日利亚等非洲国家始终予以尊重和平等，从不颐指气使，尽力支持非洲人民寻求独立和发展。感谢中方为发展中国家提出系列重要全球合作倡议，并为尼发展提供宝贵帮助，助力尼日利亚和非洲工业化进程。尼方高度重视发展对华关系，坚定不移奉行一个中国政策，坚定致力于尼中关系高水平发展，愿同中方持续深化共建“一带一路”合作，将尼中关系提升到新水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蔡奇、王毅参加会见。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 07:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 习近平会见联合国秘书长古特雷斯]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20231019_5-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月19日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231019/1697667267749_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;10月18日晚，国家主席习近平在北京人民大会堂会见来华出席第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛的联合国秘书长古特雷斯。&lt;BR/>;新华社记者李学仁摄&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;新华社北京10月18日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者许可、吉宁）10月18日晚，国家主席习近平在人民大会堂会见来华出席第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛的联合国秘书长古特雷斯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平强调，当今世界面临许多全球性威胁和挑战，国际社会必须团结合作，更加重视发展问题。我提出构建人类命运共同体，就是为了找到携手应对各种全球性挑战的正确路径；提出共建“一带一路”倡议和全球发展倡议，就是为了汇聚积累更多正能量，促进各国的共同发展，助力联合国2030年可持续发展议程，不让任何国家掉队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平指出，共建“一带一路”倡议提出10年来，取得许多实实在在的成果，展现出蓬勃向上的生机活力。桃李不言，下自成蹊。共建“一带一路”已经成为广受欢迎的全球公共产品和国际合作平台。联合国是共建“一带一路”的重要伙伴。中方愿同联合国机构一道，扎实推进高质量共建“一带一路”，为世界的和平与发展作出贡献。中方支持联合国以及古特雷斯秘书长的工作，愿同联合国机构加强合作，促进多边主义和世界多极化，推动全球治理朝着更加公正合理的方向发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;古特雷斯表示，发展中国家在基础设施和投融资方面都处于脆弱和不公平地位，国际金融体系已不能反映当今世界政治经济现实，亟需进行改革。习近平主席提出的共建“一带一路”倡议为帮助发展中国家实现可持续发展提供了非常重要和有效的途径，树立了南南合作的典范。习近平主席在第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛宣布的八项行动完全契合联合国的宗旨和目标，有利于帮助发展中国家加快实现发展。联合国高度赞赏中国坚定维护多边主义，支持习近平主席提出的三大全球倡议，坚定致力于深化同中国的合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蔡奇、王毅参加会见。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 19 Oct 2023 07:56:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>