<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平向全国广大农民和工作在“三农”战线上的同志们致以节日祝贺和诚挚问候]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/23/nw.D110000renmrb_20230923_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, September 23, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, September 22&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;On the occasion of the sixth &quot;Chinese Farmers&#39; Harvest Festival&quot; On behalf of the Party Central Committee, Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, President of the State, and Chairman of the Central Military Commission, extended holiday congratulations and sincere greetings to farmers across the country and comrades working on the &quot;agriculture, rural areas and farmers&quot; front. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that this year, we have overcome the impact of disasters such as the rare &quot;bad rain&quot; in the Huanghuai River, severe local floods in North and Northeast China, and local drought in the Northwest. Grain production throughout the year is expected to have another bumper harvest, in order to promote economic sustainability. It has provided strong support for the rebound, accelerating the construction of a new development pattern, and promoting high-quality development. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that party committees and governments at all levels must thoroughly implement the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, anchor the goal of building an agricultural power, stabilize the basic agricultural market, do a solid job in &quot;agriculture, rural areas and farmers&quot; in the new era and new journey, and comprehensively Promote rural revitalization, accelerate the pace of agricultural and rural modernization, insist on increasing farmers&#39; income as the central task of &quot;agriculture, rural areas and farmers&quot;, and do everything possible to broaden the channels for farmers to increase income and get rich, so that farmers&#39; pockets will become bigger and bigger, their lives will become better and better, and the world will be livable. A new picture of Yiye and beautiful countryside! &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平会见叙利亚总统巴沙尔]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/23/nw.D110000renmrb_20230923_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, September 23, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-09/23/01/rmrb2023092301p32_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of September 22, President Xi Jinping met at the West Lake State Guesthouse in Hangzhou with Syrian President Bashar al-Assad, who was in China to attend the opening ceremony of the 19th Asian Games. &lt;BR/>;Photographed by Xinhua News Agency reporter Yao Dawei&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Hangzhou, September 22nd&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;(Reporters Li Zhongwen, Wang Hailin) ​​On the afternoon of September 22, President Xi Jinping met at the West Lake State Guesthouse in Hangzhou with Syrian President Bashar al-Assad, who was in China to attend the opening ceremony of the 19th Asian Games. The two heads of state jointly announced the establishment of a China-Syria strategic partnership. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that Syria was one of the first Arab countries to establish diplomatic relations with New China, and was also one of the sponsors of the restoration of New China&#39;s lawful seat in the United Nations that year. Since the establishment of diplomatic relations 67 years ago, China-Syria relations have withstood the test of changing international situations, and the friendship between the two countries has grown stronger over time. The establishment of a strategic partnership between China and Syria will become an important milestone in the history of bilateral relations. China is willing to work with Syria to continuously enrich the connotation of bilateral relations and promote the continuous development of China-Syria strategic partnership. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that China is willing to continue to firmly support each other with Syria on issues involving each other&#39;s core interests and major concerns, safeguard the common interests of the two countries and the vast number of developing countries, and safeguard international fairness and justice. China supports Syria in opposing external interference and unilateral bullying, safeguarding national independence, sovereignty, and territorial integrity, supporting Syria in its reconstruction, strengthening anti-terrorism capacity building, and promoting the political settlement of the Syrian issue based on the principle of &quot;Syrian-led and Syrian-owned&quot; to improve the relations with other Arab countries and play a greater role in international and regional affairs. China is willing to strengthen cooperation with Syria in jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, increase imports of high-quality agricultural products from Syria, work together to implement the global development initiative, global security initiative, and global civilization initiative, and make positive contributions to regional and world peace and development. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Assad said that through its own efforts, China has embarked on a successful path of socialism with Chinese characteristics. China has always stood on the side of international fairness and justice, international law and international humanitarianism in international affairs, and has played an important and constructive role. The Belt and Road Initiative, Global Development Initiative, Global Security Initiative, and Global Civilization Initiative proposed by President Xi Jinping all aim to help all people achieve security and development through cooperation and share a peaceful and prosperous future. Syria highly appreciates and firmly supports and will actively participate. Syria sincerely congratulates China on its great achievements, thanks the Chinese government for its valuable support to the Syrian people, resolutely opposes any interference in China&#39;s internal affairs, and is willing to be China&#39;s long-term and staunch friend and partner. Syria is willing to take the establishment of the Syria-China strategic partnership as an opportunity to strengthen bilateral friendly cooperation and intensify communication and coordination in international and regional affairs. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;After the meeting, the two heads of state jointly witnessed the signing of a number of bilateral cooperation documents such as the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, economic development exchanges, and economic and technological cooperation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The two sides issued the &quot;Joint Statement between the People&#39;s Republic of China and the Syrian Arab Republic on the Establishment of Strategic Partnership.&quot; &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cai Qi, Ding Xuexiang, Wang Yi, Chen Yiqin and others participated in the above activities. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平会见科威特王储米沙勒]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/23/nw.D110000renmrb_20230923_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, September 23, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-09/23/01/rmrb2023092301p20_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of September 22, President Xi Jinping met at the West Lake State Guesthouse in Hangzhou with Crown Prince of Kuwait Al-Mishaal, who was in China to attend the opening ceremony of the 19th Asian Games. &lt;BR/>;Photographed by Xinhua News Agency reporter Liu Bin&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Hangzhou, September 22&amp;nbsp ;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Jiang Nan, Wang Hailin) ​​On the afternoon of September 22, President Xi Jinping met at the West Lake State Guesthouse in Hangzhou with Kuwait Crown Prince Mishal, who was in China to attend the opening ceremony of the 19th Asian Games. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that China and Kuwait have profound traditional friendship. Kuwait was the first Gulf Arab country to establish diplomatic relations with the People&#39;s Republic of China and the first Middle Eastern country to sign a cooperation document on the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; with China. Over the past 52 years since the establishment of diplomatic relations, especially the five years since the establishment of the strategic partnership between the two countries, China-Kuwait relations have made great progress, with fruitful cooperation in various fields. China is willing to work with Kuwait to promote greater development of China-Kuwait relations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that China supports Kuwait in safeguarding national sovereignty and territorial integrity, and is willing to work with Kuwait to safeguard non-interference in internal affairs, the &quot;golden rule&quot; for developing countries to settle down and live in peace. China appreciates Kuwait&#39;s active participation in the cooperation in jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, supports Kuwait in implementing the &quot;2035 National Vision&quot;, and is willing to deepen the docking of development strategies with Kuwait and strengthen cooperation in investment, energy, infrastructure, environmental governance, digital economy and other fields, Deepen law enforcement, security and counter-terrorism cooperation, and intensify people-to-people and cultural exchanges. It is hoped that Kuwait will continue to support China&#39;s rural revitalization strategy and continue to provide a fair, transparent and non-discriminatory market environment for Chinese companies to invest in Kuwait. China is willing to work with Kuwait to implement the outcomes of the first China-Arab States Summit and the China-Gulf Arab States Cooperation Council Summit, continuously improve the level of collective cooperation between China, Arab States and China, enhance communication and cooperation at the United Nations and other multilateral platforms, and safeguard the common interests of developing countries. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Mishaal expressed congratulations to the friendly Chinese people on the upcoming 74th anniversary of the founding of the People&#39;s Republic of China. The Kuwaiti government and people are deeply proud of Kuwait-China relations and are deeply satisfied with the fruitful results achieved by the cooperation between the two countries. The Belt and Road Initiative, the global development initiative, the global security initiative, and the global civilization initiative proposed by President Xi Jinping are based on the lofty goals and purposes of promoting peace and progress of mankind and are of great significance. Kuwait firmly supports and actively participates in them. Kuwait highly appreciates China&#39;s support for Kuwait in safeguarding its sovereignty and territorial integrity, and will continue to firmly adhere to the one-China policy, firmly support China&#39;s position on issues of core interests, and work with China to support the people of all countries in independently choosing development that is in line with their own national conditions and with their own characteristics. the way. Kuwait is willing to deepen practical cooperation with China in various fields and intensify communication and cooperation in the Middle East and Gulf regions. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;After the meeting, the leaders of the two countries jointly witnessed the signing of the &quot;Joint Statement on the Five-Year Plan for Bilateral Cooperation between the People&#39;s Republic of China and the State of Kuwait (2024-2028)&quot; as well as renewable energy, infrastructure construction, environmental governance, etc. A number of bilateral cooperation documents in various fields. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cai Qi, Ding Xuexiang, Wang Yi, Chen Yiqin and others participated in the above activities. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平会见亚洲奥林匹克理事会代理主席辛格]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/23/nw.D110000renmrb_20230923_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, September 23, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-09/23/01/rmrb2023092301p15_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of September 22, President Xi Jinping met at the West Lake State Guesthouse in Hangzhou with Acting Chairman of the Asian Olympic Council Singh, who was in China to attend the opening ceremony of the 19th Asian Games. &lt;BR/>;Photographed by Xinhua News Agency reporter Zhai Jianlan&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;This newspaper, Hangzhou, September 22nd&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;(Reporters Wang Hailin, Liu Junguo) On the afternoon of September 22, President Xi Jinping met at the West Lake State Guesthouse in Hangzhou with Acting Chairman of the Asian Olympic Council Singh, who was in China to attend the opening ceremony of the 19th Asian Games. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping expressed his gratitude to Singh and the Olympic Council of Asia for their long-term positive contributions to promoting the development of China&#39;s sports industry, especially the preparations for the Hangzhou Asian Games. Xi Jinping pointed out that the Olympic Council of Asia has long been committed to promoting the Asian Olympic Movement and promoting peace and development in Asia, and has achieved positive results. China is willing to strengthen cooperation with the Olympic Council of Asia to jointly promote the cause of the Asian Olympic Movement and enhance the unity of the Asian people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping emphasized that with the joint support of the Olympic Council of Asia and the Asian Olympic family, the Hangzhou Asian Games is about to kick off. This is the third time China has hosted the Asian Games after the 1990 Beijing Asian Games and the 2010 Guangzhou Asian Games. The number of participating athletes, event settings, and overall scale of this Asian Games have all reached record highs. The Chinese government and people have the confidence and ability to host a sports event with &quot;Chinese characteristics, Asian style, and splendid&quot; to enhance the unity and friendship of the Asian people and leave unforgettable memories of Hangzhou to the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Singh said, on behalf of the Olympic Council of Asia, I would like to express my gratitude to the Chinese government for its long-term support for the development of the Olympic cause in Asia and for hosting the Hangzhou Asian Games. The various venues and facilities in Hangzhou are very beautiful, advanced and impressive, and the athletes are very satisfied. The Chinese people are very warm and friendly, making athletes and guests from all over the world feel at home. I believe that the Hangzhou Asian Games will be a wonderful success! We look forward to China continuing to make important contributions to the development of sports in Asia. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cai Qi, Ding Xuexiang, Wang Yi, Chen Yiqin and others attended the meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平会见国际奥林匹克委员会主席巴赫]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/23/nw.D110000renmrb_20230923_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, September 23, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-09/23/01/rmrb2023092301p17_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of September 22, President Xi Jinping met at the West Lake State Guesthouse in Hangzhou with International Olympic Committee President Bach, who was in China to attend the opening ceremony of the 19th Asian Games. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Liu Bin&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;This newspaper, Hangzhou, September 22&amp;nbsp ;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Wang Hailin, Gu Chun) On the afternoon of September 22, President Xi Jinping met at the West Lake State Guesthouse in Hangzhou with International Olympic Committee President Bach, who was in China to attend the opening ceremony of the 19th Asian Games. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping expressed his gratitude to Bach and the International Olympic Committee for their long-term support for the development of China&#39;s Olympic movement and sports. Xi Jinping pointed out that in the face of the severe challenges posed by the combined changes of a century and the epidemic of the century, the International Olympic Committee adheres to the original intention of the Olympics, carries forward the Olympic spirit, practices the Olympic purposes, opposes the politicization of sports, and promotes the international Olympic movement to overcome difficulties and move forward for the future. It has played a unique and important role in safeguarding world peace and development and promoting human unity and progress. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping emphasized that China has always attached great importance to the development of sports, actively participated in international Olympic affairs, and practiced the Olympic motto of &quot;Faster, Higher, Stronger - More United&quot;. Last year, China overcame challenges such as the COVID-19 epidemic and presented a &quot;simple, safe and exciting&quot; Beijing Winter Olympics to the world. Beijing became the world&#39;s first &quot;Double Olympic City&quot;. China will never stop spreading the Olympic spirit and is willing to work with the International Olympic Committee to adhere to the principle of non-politicization of sports, make full use of the legacy of the Beijing Winter Olympics, and make new and greater contributions to advancing the Olympic cause and building a community with a shared future for mankind. At present, preparations for the Hangzhou Asian Games are in place. The Chinese government and people have full confidence in presenting a sports event with &quot;Chinese characteristics, Asian style and splendid brilliance&quot; and making new contributions to promoting the development of the Olympic movement and promoting the unity and friendship of the Asian people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;bach said that every time he visits China, he is full of sincerity and surprises. The Chinese government attaches great importance to the development of sports and has made important contributions to the international Olympic movement. The Beijing Winter Olympics was very exciting and successful, and the Chinese people and people around the world will continue to benefit from the legacy of the Beijing Winter Olympics. The world is currently facing various difficulties such as geopolitical conflicts. The International Olympic Committee is committed to safeguarding multilateralism and opposing the politicization of sports. It appreciates China&#39;s correct stance in this regard. The International Olympic Committee is satisfied with the successful cooperation with China, thanks China for its support of the international Olympic movement, and hopes to further strengthen cooperation with China. I believe that the Hangzhou Asian Games will be successful and exciting, and will promote unity and friendship in Asia. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cai Qi, Ding Xuexiang, Wang Yi, Chen Yiqin and others attended the meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平将出席开幕式并宣布本届亚运会开幕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/23/nw.D110000renmrb_20230923_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, September 23, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, September 22nd&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The opening ceremony of the 19th Asian Games on the evening of September 23rd Held in Hangzhou City, Zhejiang Province. President Xi Jinping will attend the opening ceremony and declare the opening of this Asian Games. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;At that time, China Central Radio and Television will broadcast live, and Xinhuanet will broadcast live with pictures and texts. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 共绘亚运新的画卷  共创亚洲美好未来（社论）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/23/nw.D110000renmrb_20230923_7-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, September 23, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;At this moment, passion and power bloom; at this moment, hopes and dreams rise. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the evening of September 23, the 19th Asian Games grandly opened in Hangzhou, Zhejiang Province. During the autumnal equinox in the Chinese lunar calendar, which symbolizes harvest, athletes from all over Asia gathered at the West Lake and joined hands to play the passionate melody of &quot;Love, Live, Share&quot; and jointly write a new chapter of peace, friendship, and progress. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Hangzhou Asian Games is the largest and highest-level international comprehensive sports event held in my country after the victory of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, attracting national attention and attracting worldwide attention. This is the third time that the Asian Games has been held in a Chinese city after Beijing and Guangzhou. General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out: &quot;The Chinese government and people are full of confidence and will host a splendid Asian Games in Hangzhou.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hosting the Hangzhou Asian Games and the Asian Paralympic Games well is a key part of the work of the party and the country this year. a big thing. Since its successful bid to host the Games, under the strong leadership of the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core, Zhejiang has adhered to the concept of &quot;green, smart, frugal and civilized&quot; and fully implemented the requirements of &quot;simple, safe and exciting&quot; to host the Games. We will continue to strive for excellence and do a good job in preparing for the entire chain and all links. After eight years of unremitting efforts, we have the confidence and ability to present a sports event with &quot;Chinese characteristics, Asian style, and excitement&quot; to the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sports is an important symbol of social development and human progress, and a bond that enhances friendship between people. As the largest comprehensive sports event in Asia, the Asian Games inspires sportsmanship, showcases Asian style, promotes friendship and unity, continuously improves the level of competitive sports in Asia, and has become an important platform for Asian sports unity and cooperation. The Chinese people love sports and the Asian Games, and have always been a staunch participant, active promoter and important contributor to Asian sports. The Asian Games inspired the Chinese people&#39;s enthusiasm for participating in sports and witnessed China&#39;s achievements in sports. The number of participants in the Hangzhou Asian Games is the highest ever. It is the largest event with the most projects and the widest coverage in the history of the Asian Games. It fully demonstrates the diversity and inclusiveness of Asian sports culture and will definitely leave a mark in the history of the Asian Games. , injecting new vitality into this important sports event. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Asian Games is a stage for sports competition and a platform for athletes to strive hard and break through themselves. At the Hangzhou Asian Games, more than 12,000 athletes from delegations from 45 Asian countries and regions signed up to compete. We look forward to athletes respecting each other, motivating each other, breaking through limits, showing the charm of sports in passionate competitions, and achieving a wonderful life. China sent a sports delegation of 1,329 people to participate in competitions in 38 major events and 407 minor events. Vigorously promote the Olympic spirit and the Chinese sports spirit, take the responsibility of &quot;the mission is on the shoulders, and the struggle is me&quot;, work hard, surpass ourselves, and win glory for the country, and we will surely be able to show the world the powerful power of Chinese-style modern sports practice. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Currently, changes in the world, the times, and history are unfolding in an unprecedented way. Building a community with a shared future for mankind is the future of people all over the world. General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized that “we must continue to develop and build Asia well, demonstrate Asia’s resilience, wisdom, and strength” and “promote the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind by moving towards an Asian community with a shared future.” The slogan of the Hangzhou Asian Games &quot;Heart to heart, love the future&quot; is highly consistent with the Olympic motto of &quot;Faster, Higher, Stronger - More United&quot;, embodying the good wishes of facing the future and jointly building a community with a shared future for Asia and mankind. . From the opening ceremony with the theme of &quot;Tide Asia&quot;, to the design of torches, mascots, medals and other designs that are immersed in China&#39;s excellent traditional culture, to the Chinese Sports Culture Exhibition, &quot;Gathering the Light of Sports&quot; and heading towards a better future together &quot;Exhibition and other supporting activities... paving the way and building bridges through sports to promote exchanges and mutual learning among civilizations will certainly help create a new situation in Asia&#39;s cultural exchanges, cultural integration, and people-to-people bonds, and inject profound and lasting cultural power into the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The wind blows from the east, the Qianjiang River surges, and the string songs are majestic. Tonight, the &quot;Light of Civilization&quot; from the ruins of Liangzhu Ancient City ignites the sports fire that symbolizes the unity of Asia. The long-standing Chinese civilization and the passionate sports event complement each other. Let us use dreams as sails and struggle as oars to draw a new picture of the Asian Games and create a better future for Asia. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I wish the 19th Asian Games a complete success! &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 辛勤的耕耘  丰收的喜悦]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/23/nw.D110000renmrb_20230923_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, September 23, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;&quot;Do a solid job in the work of &#39;agriculture, rural areas and farmers&#39; in the new era and new journey, comprehensively promote rural revitalization, and accelerate the pace of agricultural and rural modernization&quot; &quot;Let farmers&#39; pockets become bigger and bigger, their lives become better and better, and a new picture of a livable, industrial and beautiful countryside will be created!&quot; On September 22, on the occasion of the sixth &quot;Chinese Farmers&#39; Harvest Festival&quot;, General Secretary Xi Jinping addressed the The vast number of farmers across the country and comrades working on the &quot;agriculture, rural areas and farmers&quot; front extend holiday congratulations and sincere greetings. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The majority of farmers and &quot;agriculture, rural areas and farmers&quot; workers said that they will keep in mind General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s instructions, actively participate in accelerating the practice of agricultural and rural modernization, consolidate the foundation of food security, comprehensively promote rural revitalization, and contribute to building a strong agricultural country and We will continue to work hard to ensure a livable, industrial and beautiful countryside. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Efforts to ensure a stable and safe supply of food and important agricultural products&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the golden autumn season, Li Dianyou, a villager in Longwangmiao Village, Laojieji Township, Shangzhi City, Heilongjiang Province, is busy in the yard Maintaining agricultural machinery. He planted more than 200 acres of rice this year, but due to the heavy rainfall in August, 20 acres were affected. With the help of the local government and agricultural technicians, the stagnant water was drained and foliar fertilizers were sprayed, and the rice growth basically recovered. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Every year during the Harvest Festival, General Secretary Xi Jinping sends us holiday greetings, which makes our hearts warm.&quot; Li Dianyou said that the harvest will be harvested in more than ten days, and we must race against time to prepare for the autumn harvest. , try your best to &quot;snatch&quot; the losses back. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;This year, we have overcome the impact of disasters such as the rare &#39;bad rain&#39; in the Huanghuai River, severe local flooding in North and Northeast China, and local drought in the Northwest, and we are expected to have another bumper harvest in grain production throughout the year.&quot; - The bumper harvest is hard-won , General Secretary Xi Jinping’s words spoke to the hearts of farmers. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhao Yanjie, a major grain grower in Yifengbeijie Village, Yangzhuang Township, Xiping County, Henan Province, said: &quot;The General Secretary and we are very considerate. We encountered continuous rain during the wheat harvest this year. After the wheat was harvested and dried, we pressed Corn was planted as soon as possible. The county plant protection station sent experts to guide the sowing, and carried out unified prevention and control of pests and diseases.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The General Secretary attaches so much importance to food production and cares about farmers, we must work hard Plant more grain and plant more grain.&quot; Zhao Yanjie said that his corn is currently growing well. &quot;I have made an appointment with the agricultural machinery cooperative for harvesting time, and I feel at ease.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the northern Anhui Plain, the picture of harvest continues to expand. In Woyang County, Anhui Province, the fields are already golden and the bean pods are full. In less than a week, more than one million acres of soybeans will be harvested. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After in-depth study and understanding of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s holiday message, Feng Fei, deputy county magistrate of Woyang County, felt a heavy responsibility on his shoulders: “As a major grain-producing county in the country, we must follow the General Secretary’s requirements and tighten food supply at all times. To ensure safety, we must take practical and detailed measures to firmly shoulder the responsibility for food security and make every effort to ensure the supply of food and important agricultural products.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Accelerate the pace of agricultural and rural modernization&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;“Accelerate the pace of agricultural and rural modernization”, General Secretary Xi Jinping’s request made Li Xinsheng, secretary of the Party branch of Dongzheguan Village, Luocheng Street, Shouguang City, Shandong Province, more confident. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The application rate of Internet of Things management technology in newly built local greenhouses has reached 90%. Vegetable farmers can monitor the growth of vegetables in the greenhouse in real time through mobile APP at any time, truly achieving high yield, efficiency and high income. &quot;The key to agricultural modernization depends on technological modernization. We must follow General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s requirements and strive to promote applicable technologies so that farmers can use the latest technology to grow the best fields.&quot; Li Xinsheng said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Lishu County, Jilin Province, a major grain-producing county in the country, corn is swaying gently in the wind in the green gauze tent, and a bumper harvest is in sight. &quot;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized anchoring the goal of building an agricultural power, which has pointed out the direction of development for us. We will be more determined to follow the agricultural development path of large-scale operation, high quality and efficiency.&quot; Lu Wei, head of Lu Wei Agricultural Machinery Farmers Professional Cooperative said made his own plans. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, Lu Wei Agricultural Machinery Farmers&#39; Professional Cooperative has purchased several large-scale intelligent agricultural machines and built a new small grain processing plant. It has gradually developed from single grain planting to industrial chain management, and the cooperative members have also grown from the original six households. to more than 200 households. &quot;In the future, more villagers will be required to participate, and through modern agriculture we can protect farmland, increase food production, and increase farmers&#39; income,&quot; he said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Seeds are the foundation for agricultural modernization. Accelerate the collection, protection, identification and utilization of germplasm resources such as wild rice and wild cotton, strengthen crop phenotypic research, and accelerate the construction of big data intelligent breeding teams... In Sanya, Hainan, seed industry researchers are continuing to tackle key problems for the revitalization of the seed industry. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The National Southern Breeding Research and Breeding Base is a valuable national agricultural scientific research platform. &quot;We must conscientiously implement the requirements of General Secretary Xi Jinping, strive to achieve autonomous and controllable seed sources, and be self-reliant in seed industry science and technology, grasp China&#39;s seeds with our own hands, and stabilize China&#39;s rice bowl.&quot; National Institute of Southern Propagation, Chinese Academy of Agricultural Sciences Chang Pengjun said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Strive to build a livable, industrial and beautiful countryside&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Huili City, Sichuan Province, the large pomegranates of Liu Yuhao, a big planter in Kuige Village, Zhangguan Town, have matured . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“General Secretary Xi Jinping’s emphasis on doing everything possible to broaden the channels for farmers to increase their income and become rich makes me feel more promising in my future life.” Liu Yuhao said. In recent years, under the guidance of the local government, he and nearby villagers have grown pomegranates according to local conditions. The varieties have been upgraded from hard-seeded pomegranates to soft-seeded pomegranates. The sales method has expanded to e-commerce. His family&#39;s annual sales revenue has reached 300,000 to 400,000 yuan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huili Municipal Party Committee Secretary Chen Fangyong said that we must resolutely implement General Secretary Xi Jinping’s requirements and insist on increasing farmers’ income as the central task of “agriculture, rural areas and farmers”. &quot;We must strengthen the leading position, replenish the chain, develop business formats, build brands, promote the upgrading of the entire industry chain, and do a good job in &#39;local specialties&#39;, so that the lives of ordinary people will become more and more prosperous.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Flowers blooming on both sides of the road Dezheng is prosperous, with eye-catching murals on the walls, and people are busy picking vegetables in the small vegetable garden... Walking into Luhei Village, Jinning District, Kunming City, Yunnan Province, a harmonious rural scene emerges before your eyes. Fang Xingyang, deputy secretary of the village party branch, is busy preparing for the harvest festival activities. He wants to use this to let more people feel the achievements of beautiful and livable rural construction. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The General Secretary proposed to make farmers&#39; pockets richer and their lives better and better, and to draw a new picture of livable, industrial and beautiful countryside. This is exactly what we hope for.&quot; Fang Xingyang said, these The environment in the village has changed greatly in 2018. I will keep in mind General Secretary Xi Jinping’s instructions and continue to work with young talents who have returned home to make suggestions for rural development and contribute to the construction of a livable, industrial and beautiful countryside. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, September 22)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 庆丰收  促和美（人民论坛）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/23/nw.D110000renmrb_20230923_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, September 23, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;On the occasion of the sixth &quot;Chinese Farmers Harvest Festival&quot;, General Secretary Xi Jinping expressed his sincere wishes to the vast number of farmers across the country and those working in the &quot; Comrades on the &quot;Three Rural Areas&quot; front extended holiday congratulations and sincere greetings, pointing out that &quot;grain production throughout the year is expected to have another bumper harvest, which will provide strong support for promoting the continued economic recovery, accelerating the construction of a new development pattern, and promoting high-quality development.&quot; ”, emphasizing that “it will make farmers’ pockets richer and their lives better and better, and create a new picture of livable, industrial and beautiful countryside.” &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;At the autumnal equinox, rice, yellow croakers are fat, and melons and fruits are fragrant. People celebrate the harvest and share the joy. Full harvests, beautiful scenery, and stretched smiling faces jointly outline the harvest picture of &quot;watching thousands of waves of rice and rice&quot;, showing the beautiful scene of rural revitalization in the new era. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Of all things, eating is the most important thing. For thousands of years, people have written their prayers for a good harvest into poems, left them on paintings, and integrated them into unique customs and rituals all over the world. Waves of wheat rolling in and warehouses full of rice are the foundation for a happy life and the cornerstone of national security. A bumper agricultural harvest has always been on General Secretary Xi Jinping’s mind. It pointed out that &quot;food security is the &#39;biggest thing in the country&#39;&quot;, emphasized that &quot;food security should always be tightened&quot;, and demanded that &quot;adhere to solving the &#39;three rural&#39; issues as the top priority of the whole party&#39;s work&quot;... In General Secretary Xi Jinping Under the guidance of the &quot;Three Rural Areas&quot;, more attention has been paid to &quot;agriculture, rural areas and farmers&quot;, more resources have been invested in &quot;agriculture, rural areas and farmers&quot;, and more efforts have been made to build &quot;agriculture, rural areas and farmers&quot;. my country&#39;s agriculture and rural areas have made historic achievements and undergone historic changes. my country&#39;s comprehensive grain production capacity continues to improve, and its total grain output ranks first in the world. The food security of more than 1.4 billion people has been effectively guaranteed. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“Farming is the foundation of the world, and there is no greater service.” Our country is a large agricultural country, and focusing on agriculture is the foundation for people&#39;s security and the key to governing the country. Taking the Chinese Farmers&#39; Harvest Festival as an opportunity, we pay tribute to the hard work and tell good harvest stories, so that more people can deeply understand the true meaning of &quot;every grain is hard work&quot; and strengthen their awareness of loving, cherishing and saving food; we have launched a series of A series of policies and measures to strengthen and benefit agriculture and carry out caring actions to support and revitalize agriculture have continuously improved the enthusiasm, initiative and creativity of hundreds of millions of farmers in focusing on agriculture; we organize colorful farming and farming activities to promote Chinese farming civilization and excellent culture Traditions are better promoted and passed on... paying tribute to farmers and praising the harvest help China in the new era write a heavy harvest answer sheet, and also promote the whole society to increasingly form a strong atmosphere of paying attention to agriculture, caring for the countryside, and caring for farmers. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;It is gratifying to have a good harvest every year, and a good harvest is hard-won. Since the beginning of this year, we have overcome the impact of disasters such as the rare &quot;bad rain&quot; in the Huanghuai River, severe local floods in North and Northeast China, and local drought in the Northwest, and we have the joy of today&#39;s promising harvest. This also reminds us that we must not relax our efforts to ensure food security. Food security for the world, agriculture and society. In the face of major changes in the world that have not been seen in a century, stabilizing the fundamentals of agriculture and maintaining the foundation of &quot;agriculture, rural areas and farmers&quot; are the &quot;ballast stone&quot; to respond to the situation and open up a new game. On the new journey, the role of ballast for “agriculture, rural areas and farmers” will become even more prominent. Only by taking multiple measures to do a good job in &quot;agriculture, rural areas and farmers&quot;, strengthening food security, stabilizing the basic agricultural market, ensuring strong protection of &quot;rice bags&quot; and sufficient supply of &quot;vegetable baskets&quot; and &quot;fruit plates&quot; can we effectively respond to various risks and challenges at home and abroad. Add sufficient confidence and confidence. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;If the nation is to rejuvenate, the countryside must be revitalized. In the report of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized &quot;comprehensive promotion of rural revitalization&quot; and made it clear that &quot;building a beautiful countryside that is livable, suitable for industry, and beautiful&quot;. On the way forward, we must target the new needs of farmers for a better life and solidly advance key tasks such as rural development, rural construction, and rural governance to make the countryside richer, life happier, and the countryside more beautiful. This year&#39;s China Farmers&#39; Harvest Festival takes &quot;Celebrating Harvest and Promoting Harmony and Beauty&quot; as its theme. It organizes colorful celebrations to show the bright prospects of agricultural and rural modernization. It will surely further stimulate the enthusiasm of hundreds of millions of farmers to create a better life and gather together to comprehensively promote rural development. A powerful synergy to revitalize and accelerate the construction of an agricultural power. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;With the National Day approaching, flower baskets with the theme of &quot;Blessings to the Motherland&quot; were unveiled in Tiananmen Square. This year, for the first time, the flower baskets include grains symbolizing harvest. This creative design is full of beautiful expectations for the motherland’s abundant flowers and abundant harvests. The harvest season in golden autumn and September is the most pleasing to the people. In this joyful festival, let us work together to focus on the work of &quot;agriculture, rural areas and farmers&quot;, work hard and continue to work hard in the field of hope, and strive to create one good harvest year after another, and draw a bright future together. A bright future for comprehensive rural revitalization. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 丰收中国舒展美丽画卷]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/23/nw.D110000renmrb_20230923_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, September 23, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;The rice and millet are golden, the melons and fruits are fragrant, and the fertile fields are full of harvest scenes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the Jin Ruilai fresh corn planting base in Qingfeng Township, Youyi County, Heilongjiang Province, a harvester drove past, rows of straw were quickly cut and crushed, and the golden ears of corn filled the carriage. &quot;150 acres are harvested every day, and mechanization has greatly improved efficiency.&quot; said Sun Liming, the person in charge of the base. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the mountains of Miaoling in Taijiang County, Guizhou Province, terraced fields are busy. &quot;This year we have a good harvest of both rice and fish. It is estimated that the yield per mu will be 650 kilograms of rice and 45 kilograms of rice and fish. We are in good times for farming!&quot; Pan Nianchong, a grain farmer in Jiahao Village, Laotun Township, told reporters. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In response to the farming season, busy with farm work and enjoying a good year, hundreds of millions of farmers ushered in the sixth &quot;Chinese Farmers&#39; Harvest Festival&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping attaches great importance to the work of &quot;agriculture, rural areas and farmers&quot; and promotes the establishment of the &quot;Chinese Farmers Harvest Festival&quot;. Every year during the Harvest Festival, he sends holiday congratulations to hundreds of millions of farmers. On the occasion of the sixth &quot;Chinese Farmers&#39; Harvest Festival&quot;, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized that &quot;anchoring the goal of building an agricultural power, stabilizing the basics of agriculture, doing a solid job in the &#39;three rural&#39; work in the new era and new journey, and comprehensively promoting rural revitalization&quot; , accelerate the pace of agricultural and rural modernization, insist on increasing farmers&#39; income as the central task of &quot;agriculture, rural areas and farmers&quot;, and do everything possible to broaden farmers&#39; income and get rich channels, so that farmers&#39; pockets will become more and more abundant, their lives will become better and better, and they will create a place where they can live, work, and be beautiful. A new picture of the countryside!&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To strengthen a country, we must first strengthen agriculture, and only then can the country be strong. This year is the first year to fully implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China. It is also a critical year to comprehensively promote rural revitalization and accelerate the construction of an agricultural power. All regions and departments have shouldered their responsibility for food security, and the modernization of agriculture and rural areas has reached a new level. Agriculture is high-quality and efficient, the countryside is livable and suitable for work, farmers are prosperous, and China has a beautiful harvest. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Policies support science and technology&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Harvest answers are hard-won&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Everyone worked together and finally Winning a bumper harvest.&quot; Liu Jinlong, head of the Sun Laole Rice Planting Professional Cooperative in Xinfa Village, Ping&#39;an Town, Shulan City, Jilin Province, frowned. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In early August, which was a critical period for the formation of autumn grain production, Shulan City suffered from floods. The local area immediately carried out drainage dredging, pest control and &quot;one spray, multiple boost&quot; operations. At present, crops are growing normally, and 750,000 acres of rice in the city are gradually entering the harvest period. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the beginning of this year, China has fought against spring drought, floods, and insects to seize grain, and has overcome many obstacles. my country’s summer grain output has reached 292.3 billion kilograms, ranking the second highest in history; early rice has increased by 430 million kilograms compared with last year, an increase of 0.8%. The latest agricultural conditions show that autumn grain crops in the field are growing well across the country, and there is a foundation for a bumper autumn grain harvest. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The hard-won harvest results reflect the strong signal of focusing on agriculture and grain and the solid actions of the whole team. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking at policies, the country has improved the &quot;three-in-one&quot; policy system of price, subsidies, and insurance, implemented &quot;one spray for three preventions&quot; for summer grains, and &quot;one spray for multiple promotions&quot; for autumn grains, and issued a one-time subsidy of 10 billion to farmers who actually grow grains. Yuan, the central government released various flood prevention and relief funds in a timely manner, and the People&#39;s Bank of China increased the re-loan quota to support agriculture and small businesses... The policy measures are solid, stabilizing expectations and enhancing confidence. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking at the area, all regions have fully implemented the joint responsibilities of the party and the government for food security, and the area sown for grain has increased steadily throughout the year. This year’s autumn grain sowing area is expected to reach 1.31 billion acres, an increase of about 7 million acres from the previous year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In charge of field management, teams of experts and agricultural technical teams went to the front line to guide production, and key technical measures were accurately implemented according to the location and seedlings.农业农村部组织专家下沉一线参加包省包片“奋战100天夺秋粮丰收行动”。中国农业科学院以玉米和大豆产业专家团为基础，组织30多位专家组成科技小分队赴粮食主产省份提供科技支撑。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来之不易的丰收答卷，凸显农业现代化“金扁担”的硬支撑。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;黑龙江北大荒农垦集团引龙河农场有限公司今年大面积推广根瘤菌喷淋技术，给大豆“吃上营养餐”。公司农业发展部副部长杜朝霞说：“运用这项技术，节省氮肥25%，大豆增产5%—10%。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年，我国实施新一轮千亿斤粮食产能提升行动，各地以大豆、玉米为重点，大力推广优质耐密品种，配套密植精准调控技术模式和适宜高性能机械，推动大面积提高单产落地见效。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;农业现代化，关键是农业科技现代化。目前，我国农业科技进步贡献率达到62.4%，农作物良种覆盖率超过96%，自主选育品种面积占比超过95%，全国农作物耕种收综合机械化率超过73%。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来之不易的丰收答卷，见证农业社会化服务体系的组织优势。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;重庆市璧山区广普镇周家村的稻谷熟了，村民华成群点开手机下单机收服务。第二天一早，3台联合收割机便在他家的田里马力全开。 “种粮户发布需求，平台就近组织对接，让各家各户及时用上先进农机。”重庆智慧农服集团璧山公司负责人刘波说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前，全国近400万个家庭农场、220多万家农民合作社提高农业组织化程度。超过107万个各类农业社会化服务组织成为贴心“田保姆”，服务带动小农户9100多万户，覆盖超19.7亿亩次，推动农业生产专业化、标准化、集约化水平不断提高。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;富了口袋富脑袋&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;农民更加富裕富足&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;推进农业农村现代化，不仅物质生活要富裕，精神生活也要富足。各地区各部门加大强农惠农富农力度，千方百计拓宽农民增收致富渠道，扎实推进农村精神文明建设，农民更加富裕富足。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乡村特色产业发展壮大，“土特产”带火乡亲好日子。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“新拓展的电商渠道让我的葡萄年销量增加35%以上。”河北省邯郸市永年区现海葡萄专业合作社负责人伊现海说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;洛川苹果、赣南脐橙、定西马铃薯、遮放贡米、柞水木耳……一个个“土特产”成为乡亲们增收致富的大产业；农事体验、观光采摘、特色民宿等新业态成为农民增收新动力。今年上半年，全国农产品网络零售额0.27万亿元，同比增长13.1%。 8月，全国农副食品加工业增加值同比增长3.1%。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就业渠道不断拓宽，“技能饭”越吃越香。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“嗒嗒嗒……”河北省魏县前大磨乡怡怡爱心箱包微工厂里，电动缝纫机的声响不绝于耳。 “培训上岗，家门口务工，一天能挣100多元。”刘屯村村民闫运英说。在魏县，近百家箱包微工厂吸纳就业4000余人。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前全国共有农村实用人才2200多万人，越来越多的农民靠知识、靠技术勤劳致富。今年上半年，全国建设50个国家现代农业产业园、40个优势特色产业集群、200个农业产业强镇，更多农民实现了家门口就业。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;产业旺，就业稳，今年上半年农村居民人均可支配收入达到10551元，实际增长7.2%，高于城镇居民2.5个百分点。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;富了口袋富脑袋，农民精神风貌不断提升。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;福建省安溪县城厢镇经兜村农家书屋，一排排图书分门别类，整齐摆放，村民孙启思一边翻着书，一边在本子上记要点。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;农家书屋成了乡亲们的“文化粮仓”。目前，全国所有行政村都有了农家书屋、电子阅览室和文化活动室，农民文化生活更加丰富多彩。各地大力培育文明乡风、良好家风、淳朴民风，农民精神面貌焕然一新。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 加快推进乡村振兴&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;建设宜居宜业和美乡村&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;农村现代化是建设农业强国的内在要求和必要条件，各地区各部门扎实开展乡村建设行动，建设宜居宜业和美乡村。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;提高基础设施完备度，乡村宜居宜业。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“村子美了，日子好了。”安徽省天长市金集镇益民村村民翁基龙说，“清沟塘、建小广场，散步休闲有了好去处。”近年来，天长市加强乡村建设，生活垃圾收集、无害化处理接近100%。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在江西省永丰县潭头乡樟树埠村，硬化路蜿蜒在连绵青山。 “出门有了沥青路，还装上了路灯，方便得很。大货车从田头拉着脐橙和油茶卖到了大城市。”村民戴景河说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;看全国，基础设施加快完善，既方便农民生活，又促进乡村发展。农村自来水普及率接近88%，乡镇和建制村通客车率分别达到99.8%和99.7%。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;提高公共服务便利度，农民乐享生活。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;床垫随时监测心率，运动鞋可定位轨迹防止走失……河北省邯郸市峰峰矿区新坡镇羊南社区提供智慧养老服务。 “我们提供托养护理、医养结合等多种服务，让老人安度幸福晚年。”新坡镇党委书记沈涛说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一系列惠民生、暖民心的政策，逐步补上农村公共服务短板。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全国县乡村三级农村养老服务网络建设不断加强，2023年紧密型县域医共体建设从试点阶段转入全面推进阶段。截至去年底，农村义务教育阶段本科以上学历专任教师比例达76.01%，比上年增长3.78个百分点。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;家园山绿水清，乡村环境更优美。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;湖北省秭归县九畹溪镇槐树坪村，绿树掩映农房。村民张明义的家被评为“最美庭院”，“我精心设计，房前屋后种树栽花，石磨子、陶罐子当成装饰品，院子不仅干净美丽，还很有格调。”九畹溪镇在重点改造农村道路、管网的同时，鼓励农民建设美丽庭院。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年以来，中央财政安排74亿元对农村厕所革命实施奖补，安排30亿元中央预算内资金支持农村人居环境基础设施建设。目前，全国农村卫生厕所普及率超过73%，91%以上的自然村生活垃圾得到收运处理，14万个村庄进一步绿化美化。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乡村振兴，关键在人，关键在干。在全面建设社会主义现代化国家新征程上，亿万农民撸起袖子加油干，昂首阔步迈向更加美好的新生活。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（本报记者高云才、顾仲阳、王浩、常钦、郁静娴）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 完善投资对接的高效平台（权威发布）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/23/nw.D110000renmrb_20230923_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月23日星期六&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;第四届跨国公司领导人青岛峰会将于10月10日至12日举办。 9月22日，国务院新闻办召开新闻发布会介绍峰会有关情况。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;商务部部长助理陈春江表示，中国政府历来重视跨国公司在华投资兴业，持续出台了一系列针对性强、含金量高的稳外资政策。商务部也持续强化外资政策支持，深入贯彻落实国务院《关于进一步优化外商投资环境&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;加大吸引外商投资力度的意见》，合理缩减外资准入负面清单，进一步取消或放宽外资准入限制，举办“投资中国年”招商引资系列活动，推动各项政策落地见效，提升外资企业获得感。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;陈春江说，举办第四届跨国公司领导人青岛峰会，是贯彻落实党中央、国务院关于更大力度吸引和利用外资部署的具体举措，旨在进一步推动完善投资对接的高效平台，做好政策宣介。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;本届峰会将继续以“跨国公司与中国”为主题，围绕更大力度吸引和利用外资、跨国公司在华发展新实践、产业投资布局新趋势、打造营商环境新成效、数字经济国际合作、绿色低碳高质量发展设置了六大议题，致力于把本届峰会打造成更加精彩、更富成效、更具影响力的沟通渠道和交流平台。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;峰会期间，将配合开展“投资中国年”活动，举办“创新发展&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;合作共赢”中国吸引外资政策说明和项目推介会，对国务院最新一批“稳外资”政策进行详细介绍，同时回应当前外资企业在华发展的关切问题，助力外资企业长期稳定发展。峰会期间还将继续发布《跨国公司在中国》系列研究报告。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;山东省副省长宋军继介绍，峰会已报名嘉宾500多人，预计与会嘉宾将超过800人；已有316家跨国公司报名，峰会品牌影响力进一步增强。 &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 23 Sep 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>