<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/<item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 谋长远之势、行长久之策、建久安之基]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20231015_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Sunday, October 15, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;The autumn mood is in full swing in Jiangxi. From Jiujiang, Jingdezhen, Shangrao, and then to Nanchang, General Secretary Xi Jinping inspected the actual situation, observed progress, and planned for the future. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The development strategy of the Yangtze River Economic Belt is a major national strategy proposed after the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, covering 11 provinces and cities along the Yangtze River. This economic belt spans the three major sectors of my country&#39;s east, middle and west, accounting for &quot;half of the country&#39;s&quot; population size and total economic output. What it carries is not only the vivid practice of Chinese-style modernization, but also the answers of the times on how people get along with nature. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In commemoration of General Secretary Xi Jinping, he has visited the Yangtze River coast more than 30 times in more than 10 years. The river is rolling eastward, the river banks are turning yellow and green, and the appearance of the Yangtze River is also changing with day after day&#39;s efforts. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The great river goes eastward and stretches thousands of miles. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The symposium with the theme of the development of the Yangtze River Economic Belt was held for the first time nearly 8 years ago. After that, every two or three years, the second, third, and fourth symposium was held in Nanchang during this inspection period. Consistent attention embodies the Party Central Committee’s governance philosophy of “seeking long-term trends, implementing long-term strategies, and building a foundation for long-term stability.” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This time, General Secretary Xi Jinping reviewed the development process of the Yangtze River Economic Belt at the symposium and was quite emotional: &quot;If you do it, you must do it well and keep doing it firmly. Do it diligently, be consistent, and achieve success over time.&quot; ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Protection&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“Insist on putting joint efforts and protection first”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Jiujiang is the mouth of three rivers and the thoroughfare of seven provinces, covering the entire 152-kilometer coastline of the Jiangxi section of the Yangtze River. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping climbed up to the Pipa Pavilion in the rain and looked up into the distance. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The river is winding and the grass is long. The sky is vast, the sky is high, and the imagination is endless! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For more than 10 years, the &quot;green content&quot; of the upper, middle and lower reaches has become higher and higher. &quot;It is indeed a great change!&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The pain of the Yangtze River in the past was the result of reform The ecological costs of rapid development since opening up. The General Secretary once painfully described the Yangtze River as “sick, and not very sick.” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the first symposium in 2016, the General Secretary set rules for the development of the Yangtze River Economic Belt: &quot;Work together to protect the Yangtze River and not engage in large-scale development.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nearly eight years have passed, and the report card of &quot;protection&quot; is obvious to all. &quot;The water quality ratio is 94.5%, and the main stream of the Yangtze River has Class II water quality for three consecutive years.&quot; The general secretary said with emotion: &quot;Combining the figures one by one, we can see that since the implementation of the Yangtze River Economic Belt development strategy, strategic benefits have been achieved.&quot;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;The Jiujiang City section of the Yangtze River National Cultural Park is a vivid example. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the Pipa Pavilion, a picture comparing the past and the present was placed in front of the General Secretary. Before the treatment, the area was &quot;covered in ashes on sunny days and covered in mud on rainy days.&quot; The sand mining boats on the river and the exposed mine pits on the riverside make the green mountains white and the Yangtze River covered with dust. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Watch, hear, ask, and implement policies based on categories. At the end of 2021, the construction of the Yangtze River National Cultural Park was officially launched, and the Jiangxi section of the Yangtze River was listed as one of the seven key construction areas. Jiujiang is taking advantage of the situation and striving to build the &quot;most beautiful coastline&quot; of the 100-mile Yangtze River. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping inquired in detail about the local pollution control, bank management, and fishing management, and warned: &quot;The Yangtze River is the link of the Yangtze River Economic Belt. No matter how the Yangtze River Economic Belt develops in the future and at what stage it develops, it will not matter. It is possible to leave the nurturing of the Yangtze River.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From &quot;leaning on the river to eat the river&quot; to &quot;leaning on the river to protect the river&quot;, not only the clear water of the river and the greenery on both sides have changed, but also the concept:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &quot;In the past, we talked about &#39;discussing heroes based on GDP&#39; and cared about &#39;gold content.&#39; Now the ideological concepts have changed, and the problem of understanding can be said to be solved. The Yangtze River Economic Belt was born and prospered because of the Yangtze River. We must clearly understand this causal relationship. &quot;The general secretary said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is really a touching change! Behind the changes lies the strategic determination and historical foresight of “settling big accounts and long-term accounts”. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the symposium, the General Secretary affirmed the achievements of the ban on fishing in the Yangtze River and demanded that the policy of banning fishing should not be shaken and should be continued resolutely. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The general secretary spoke with sincerity: &quot;Ecological and environmental protection is a long-term task. We cannot relax for a while, and then start thinking wrong when things get better. The current Yangtze River can only be said to be &#39;recovering from a serious illness&#39;. We should unswervingly adhere to the principle of &quot;jointly focusing on large-scale protection and not engaging in large-scale development&quot;, and make greater efforts on high-level protection to provide more solid support for the high-quality development of the Yangtze River Economic Belt.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Development &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“The path is right now and we must continue to walk on it” &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In previous symposiums, General Secretary Xi Jinping made a profound discussion The dialectical relationship of &quot;protection during development and development during protection&quot; is explained thoroughly: &quot;The success or failure of ecological environment protection ultimately depends on the economic structure and economic development mode.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Enterprises are the key to ecological and environmental protection in the Yangtze River The main body and important force of construction. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bordered by the Yangtze River to the north, Lushan Mountain to the south, and Pohu Lake to the east, Sinopec Jiujiang Branch is under heavy pressure in the battle to crack the &quot;chemical industry encirclement of the river.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The problems on the river have their roots on the shore. Jiujiang Petrochemical has &quot;environmental online monitoring real-time data&quot;, which is updated every 20 seconds. For atmosphere, water, and soil, one column is the national standard, and the other column is the actual emission situation of the company. General Secretary Xi Jinping watched while listening to the company&#39;s introduction on how to &quot;prevent a drop of oil and a drop of excessive sewage from entering the Yangtze River&quot; and how to strive to prevent &quot;stinky odors&quot;. If it doesn’t go to heaven, the dirty oil won’t fall to the ground.” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The general secretary encouraged: &quot;The standards are set high, and we are working step by step. I hope you will follow the Party Central Committee&#39;s deployment requirements for new industrialization, adhere to the green and smart direction, and be down-to-earth and forge ahead.&quot; , making new contributions to ensuring national energy security and promoting the high-quality development of the petrochemical industry.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From point to point, the focus is on &quot;treating both the existing disease and the pre-existing disease&quot;: &quot;In the construction of new industrialization , we must put greening and low-carbonization on the agenda, and we also hope that the industrial front will take more practical actions.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If the eastern coastline is like a long bow gathering momentum, the Yangtze River The economic belt is a sharp arrow that breaks through the sky. The Yangtze River Economic Belt, as one of the regions with the richest scientific and technological resources in my country, the most vigorous scientific and technological innovation and the ability to transform scientific and technological achievements, has unique conditions to &quot;promote the chain extension of advantageous industries and the construction of emerging industries.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the second day of the inspection, General Secretary Xi Jinping came to Changhe Aircraft Industry (Group) Co., Ltd. in Jingdezhen. In the final assembly workshop, the slogan &quot;Aviation Serves the Country&amp;nbsp;Aviation Power&quot; is particularly eye-catching; at the test flight station, various helicopters are lined up under the blue sky, which is a spectacular sight. The General Secretary boarded a helicopter and listened carefully to the introduction. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We must adhere to the innovation drive, make greater efforts in independent research and development of key core technologies, produce new products for future needs, strive to build an advanced manufacturing system, and build a world-class helicopter enterprise.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &quot;&#39;Not engaging in large-scale development&#39; means not to engage in random development, low-level development, extensive development, or destructive development, but to take a path of high-quality development, green and low-carbon development. The path is right now, and we must continue to follow it. .&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Inheritance&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Let China&#39;s excellent traditional culture carry forward&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The river is rushing and majestic.礴, civilization is deep and meaningful. Yangtze River culture is like a dazzling star river in the Chinese culture that is as bright as stars. Among them, the Yangtze River water soaks the porcelain clay, and Jingdezhen shines brightly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Walking into Jingdezhen, there is the prosperity of &quot;Thirteen miles of Taoyang, hundreds of thousands of fireworks&quot;, and the hustle and bustle of &quot;kiln fires are bright every night, and porcelain rises every day&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beside the Nanlu ruins, the General Secretary looked carefully. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The round one is the windlass pit, and the square one is Chennichi. Ceramics from the Song and Yuan Dynasties are on the bottom, while ceramics from the Ming and Qing Dynasties are stacked on top. There are 17 horseshoe kilns lined up, and 24 more ancient horseshoe kilns and 4 egg-shaped kilns are buried underneath. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fire in the kiln has been burning for thousands of years. General Secretary Xi Jinping said with emotion: &quot;China&#39;s excellent traditional culture has never stopped flowing since ancient times. Ceramics are Chinese treasures and an important business card of Chinese civilization.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;400 meters west of here, the Changjiang River passes through the city. Pass. The river flows for 180 miles, flows into Poyang Lake, and then reaches the sea. &quot;Traveling in the nine regions, giving to foreign countries.&quot; In the smoke and mirrors of history, Jingdezhen&#39;s porcelain traveled on the waves of the Maritime Silk Road and was exported to the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ming and Qing Dynasty kiln groups hand-made porcelain art gallery, ceramic intangible inheritors gathered here, it is &quot;craftsmen come from all directions, the world&#39;s pottery&quot;, some are white-haired, some are gray-haired, In his prime. They enthusiastically showed their special skills to the General Secretary. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Stepping on the mud, kneading the mud, drawing the blank, printing the blank, sharpening the blank, painting the blank, applying glaze, glazing... &quot;Seventy-two hands have been passed, and the craftsmanship can be completed.&quot; Records in &quot;Tiangong Kaiwu&quot; , also reflects today’s craftsman spirit. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The general secretary talked with an old master. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Hello, master! You have great skills in your hands! Do you have a pattern, or do you just rely on your feel?&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;It&#39;s all in my heart.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This The master learned to make porcelain from his father at the age of 13. He is the fourth generation of his family and has been working for 40 years in the blink of an eye. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;You are the inheritor of this land and a reflection of the craftsman spirit.&quot; The general secretary praised. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Jingdezhen, there are more than 20,000 young people busy working on the front line of porcelain making. Behind them, they are leveraging a huge ceramic industry chain. The general secretary was quite emotional:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;I am very happy to see that the ceramic industry has so many inheritors and heirs. This industry must continue to develop.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Do one thing for a lifetime , it is not an easy thing for our ancestors to do one thing for generations. We must stick to our own path and not change when we see other people. We must continue to hold on to the excellent traditional culture passed down by our ancestors, keep pace with the times, and let it carry forward.&quot;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;The thousand-year porcelain making road has left behind not only azure memories, but also embodies the past and present of Chinese civilization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Revitalization&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“The people in the old areas are what we care about most”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rivers and villages, Depend on each other for thousands of years. The Rao River originates nearby, passes through villages, skirts mountains, and finally flows through Poyang Lake into the Yangtze River. On the afternoon of the second day of the inspection, General Secretary Xi Jinping walked into Shimen Natural Village, Wangcun, Qiukou Town, Wuyuan County, Shangrao City. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ecology is the village’s business card. In the village, the green reflections of ancient camphor, bitter locust, and maple poplars, as well as photos of the critically endangered blue-crowned babbler playing on the branches, are the epitome of the harmonious symbiosis between man and nature. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than four years ago, also in Jiangxi, General Secretary Xi Jinping instructed that we should do a good job in managing the mountains and rivers, showing the mountains and rivers, and creating a &quot;Jiangxi model&quot; for beautiful China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The small village is a corner of the model. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wherever he goes, common prosperity is a matter of concern to the General Secretary. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When visiting the old revolutionary areas this time, the General Secretary emphasized: “Whether we are fighting poverty, building a moderately prosperous society in all respects, or building modernization and promoting common prosperity, the people in the old areas are our greatest concern.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Watch as you walk along the streets. &quot;When you see an old person, respect them; when you see a young person, love them.&quot; The motto of the sages on self-cultivation and family management is posted on the door of every house. The courtyard walls are painted, and the corners are filled with flowers and plants. Ecology and humanity complement each other. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the village, smooth stone roads connect the streets and alleys; outside the village, wide highways extend in all directions. &quot;The ancient village now has convenient transportation, and local industries have also developed, especially tourism, which is very lively. I am very concerned about our next development and revitalization, and hope that the sesame seeds will bloom more and more.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the enthusiastic greetings of the villagers Amidst the applause, the General Secretary said cordially: &quot;Chinese-style modernization requires both urban modernization and agricultural and rural modernization. I am very concerned about rural revitalization. I hope you will protect the natural ecology and combine traditional village style with modern elements. Adhere to the aesthetic taste of the Chinese nation, build the countryside more beautiful, and make life happier and happier as time goes by!&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the symposium on further promoting the high-quality development of the Yangtze River Economic Belt held on the 12th, the general secretary pointed out : &quot;We are promoting rural revitalization and building beautiful countryside, and the Yangtze River Economic Belt has great advantages. There are both ancient villages and modern villages along the coast. It is necessary to integrate the history and culture of the Yangtze River, landscape culture and urban and rural development to highlight local characteristics.&quot;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;Water and village share the beauty. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Integration&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“The Yangtze River Economic Belt is related to the overall development of the country”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Following the winding Looking from the bank of the river, there are fertile plains and beautiful peaks; there are international gateways and deep mountains and dense forests. The huge size and complexity of the Yangtze River Economic Belt present both challenges and opportunities. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From a broader perspective, General Secretary Xi Jinping’s thinking on the development of the Yangtze River Economic Belt focuses on China’s yesterday, today and tomorrow. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To the east is the vast Pacific Ocean; to the west is the vast Eurasian continent. The huge development gradient, superimposed on the endless expansion space, has shaped the Yangtze River Economic Belt’s huge resilience, potential and room for maneuver. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The all-round opening up of the Yangtze River Economic Belt to the outside world is accelerating. In the current era of thousands of sails competing and hundreds of teams vying for success, the General Secretary further emphasized:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;To do a better job Give full play to the unique advantages of the Yangtze River Economic Belt that traverses the east and west, connects the north and the south, and connects the river and the sea, better connects the two domestic and international markets, makes good use of both resources, enhances the endogenous power and reliability of the domestic cycle, and enhances its attractiveness to the international cycle. Promoting force to provide strategic support for building a new development pattern.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Is it a matter of fighting each other and beggar-thy-neighbor, or is it a &quot;game of chess&quot; to plan the layout? It authenticates the performance concept of a place, a department, and a team. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping further put forward requirements: “We must insist on strengthening regional coordination and integration as the focus. Provinces and cities along the Yangtze River must adhere to inter-provincial consultation, ecological co-governance, whole-region co-construction, development and sharing, and enhance regional transportation. interconnection, policy unity, rule consistency, and execution synergy, steadily promote the construction of ecological communities and interest communities, and promote coordinated regional development.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the meeting, the general secretary cordially asked people from 11 provinces and cities Comrade in charge, how long it took them to get to Nanchang. What used to be a long journey over mountains and rivers now only takes two or three hours. &quot;The convenient transportation between you shows that the construction achievements in these years have been remarkable.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the longest and most extensive economic belt in my country, the Yangtze River Economic Belt is related to the overall development of the country. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Development and security cannot be ignored; one area and the overall situation need to be dialectically coordinated. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the symposium, the General Secretary expected that the Yangtze River Economic Belt would &quot;play a greater role in maintaining national food security, energy security, important industrial chain supply chain security, water security, etc., and take the stability of one region as the overall situation Make a contribution to the safety of the country.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Four security, building foundation for development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When it comes to food, responsibilities are consistent. “Whether they are the main food production areas, main sales areas, or production and marketing balance areas, provinces and cities along the Yangtze River must shoulder the responsibility for food security”; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Talk about energy , planning with a high-level focus, &quot;adhere to the national &#39;one game of chess&#39;, and continue to deepen energy cooperation between upstream regions and mid- and downstream regions&quot;; Adjust the abundance and dryness of regional water resources to improve the disaster prevention and reduction capabilities of the river basin&quot;;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A broad vision and overall consideration, and a big idea leads the direction. For the protection and development of the Yangtze River, the General Secretary must think carefully and act diligently, &quot;seeking long-term trends, implementing long-term strategies, and building a foundation for long-term stability.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thousands of waves, thousands of sails. The east of the great river is as powerful as a rainbow. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 共同把这条造福世界的幸福之路铺得更宽更远]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20231015_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Sunday, October 15, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Ideology is the beacon of the times. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The construction of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; is rooted in history, but faces the future&quot;;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The construction of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; is a great undertaking and requires great practice&quot;;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot;The construction of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; adheres to the principles of extensive consultation, joint construction and sharing. It is not closed, but open and inclusive&quot;...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the autumn of 2013, General Secretary Xi Jinping proposed &quot;joint construction&quot; Silk Road Economic Belt&quot; and &quot;21st Century Maritime Silk Road&quot;. From proposing the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative and the &quot;Five Connectivity&quot; concept, to passing relevant plans and establishing the principle of extensive consultation, joint contribution and shared benefits; from convening relevant symposiums three times to holding the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum twice; from The report of the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China proposed that &quot;we should focus on the construction of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39;&quot; and &quot;form an open pattern of linkage between land and sea, and mutual assistance between the East and the West.&quot; The report of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China proposed to &quot;promote the joint construction of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39;&quot; &quot;High-quality development&quot;... Under the personal planning, deployment and promotion of General Secretary Xi Jinping, China adheres to the principle of extensive consultation, joint contribution and shared benefits, adheres to the concepts of openness, greenness and integrity, and strives to achieve high standards, sustainability and people&#39;s livelihood goals. , the joint construction of the “Belt and Road” has achieved fruitful results. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past ten years, my country has signed more than 200 cooperation documents on the Belt and Road Initiative with more than 150 countries and more than 30 international organizations, forming more than 3,000 cooperation projects and driving nearly US$1 trillion in investment. scale, it has created &quot;national landmarks&quot;, &quot;people&#39;s livelihood projects&quot; and &quot;cooperation monuments&quot; one after another, injecting strong impetus into the joint development of the country, and has become the most popular international public product and the largest international cooperation platform. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past ten years, General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important expositions on the joint construction of the “Belt and Road” have continuously enriched and developed the profound connotation of the joint construction of the “Belt and Road” initiative, emphasizing the persistence of peaceful cooperation, openness and inclusiveness, mutual learning and mutual learning. With the Silk Road spirit at the core of learning, mutual benefit and win-win, we will build the “Belt and Road” into a road of peace, prosperity, openness, green, innovation and civilization, and promote the joint construction of the “Belt and Road” Go deep and be practical, make steady progress and go far. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &quot;Discussing the construction of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; is a continuation of the historical trend and a correct choice for the future&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;September 23, 2023 , in the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center Stadium on the bank of the Qiantang River, &quot;thousands of streams turned into water and surged into tides.&quot; The third Asian Games held in China opened grandly, and Zhejiang Zhejiang ushered in another historic moment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before the opening of the Hangzhou Asian Games, General Secretary Xi Jinping met with a number of international dignitaries. His sincere words deeply moved China&#39;s old and new friends. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the meeting, General Secretary Xi Jinping and the distinguished guests mentioned the same word many times: &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; -&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Both sides should continue to promote the joint construction of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; and deepen Cooperation in the four key areas of industrial revitalization, infrastructure construction, food independence, and improvement of people&#39;s livelihood&quot;;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;China-Nepal cooperation in jointly building the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; has continued to achieve positive results, and the Trans-Himalayan three-dimensional interconnection network has begun to take shape. &quot;...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The major initiative of jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; has gone through 10 years. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping once said: &quot;History always gives people the strength to draw wisdom and move forward in some special years.&quot; 2013 is such a year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On September 7 of that year, the melons and fruits were fragrant in Astana, Kazakhstan. General Secretary Xi Jinping delivered a speech at the auditorium of Nazarbayev University, proposing the major initiative of the &quot;Silk Road Economic Belt&quot; -&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;In order to make our Eurasian countries&#39; economic ties closer and mutual cooperation deeper , the development space is broader, and we can use innovative cooperation models to jointly build the &#39;Silk Road Economic Belt&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;October 3, 2013, Coconut Palm Peng Peng, Jakarta, Indonesia. General Secretary Xi Jinping elaborated on the concept of the &quot;21st Century Maritime Silk Road&quot; in his speech to the Indonesian Parliament - &quot;Southeast Asia has been an important hub of the &#39;Maritime Silk Road&#39; since ancient times. China is willing to work with ASEAN countries Strengthen maritime cooperation, make good use of the China-ASEAN Maritime Cooperation Fund established by the Chinese government, develop maritime cooperative partnerships, and jointly build the 21st century &#39;Maritime Silk Road&#39;.&quot;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Take the road as the road With the earth as the paper and cooperation as the pen, a magnificent picture of friendly cooperation emerges on the paper. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Why did China propose the major initiative of jointly building the “Belt and Road”? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On May 14, 2017, General Secretary Xi Jinping gave the answer in his speech at the opening ceremony of the “Belt and Road” International Cooperation Summit Forum:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“From a historical perspective, humankind Society is in an era of great development, transformation and adjustment. The world is becoming multi-polar, economic globalization, social informatization and cultural diversification are developing in depth. The general trend of peaceful development is becoming stronger and stronger, and the pace of reform and innovation continues to move forward. Between countries The connection between the world has never been as close as it is today, the yearning of people around the world for a better life has never been as strong as it is today, and the means for mankind to overcome difficulties have never been as abundant as it is today.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;From a practical perspective, we We are in a world with frequent challenges. World economic growth needs new impetus, development needs to be more inclusive and balanced, and the gap between the rich and the poor needs to be bridged. Regional hot spots continue to be turbulent, and terrorism is spreading and raging. Peace deficit, development deficit, governance deficit, It is a serious challenge facing all mankind.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking around the world, changes in the world, changes in the times, and changes in history are unfolding in an unprecedented way. The world has entered a new period of turbulence and change, and mankind is once again standing at the crossroads of history. At this important historical juncture, General Secretary Xi Jinping has a far-sighted vision and proposed the major initiative of jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; to solve global development problems with China&#39;s solutions and encourage countries around the world to join hands in taking the road ahead. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;How to understand the major initiative of jointly building the “Belt and Road”? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping gave this profound explanation:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Inheritance. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Historically, the Overland Silk Road and the Maritime Silk Road were the major channels for economic, trade and cultural exchanges between my country and Central Asia, Southeast Asia, South Asia, West Asia, East Africa, and Europe. The ‘Belt and Road’ initiative is The inheritance and improvement of the ancient Silk Road have been widely recognized.&quot; On November 4, 2014, General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out at the eighth meeting of the Central Financial and Economic Leading Group. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The ancient Silk Road stretched thousands of miles and lasted for thousands of years, accumulating the Silk Road spirit with peace and cooperation, openness and tolerance, mutual learning, and mutual benefit as its core. This is a precious heritage of human civilization. &quot;History is the best teacher. This history shows that no matter how far apart we are, as long as we bravely take the first step and insist on walking toward each other, we can find a path of encountering each other, mutual development, and moving towards happiness, tranquility, harmony, and beauty.&quot; the distance.&quot; On May 14, 2017, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized in his speech at the opening ceremony of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Today, we inherit the spirit of the ancient Silk Road and jointly discuss the construction of the ‘Belt and Road’, which is a continuation of the historical trend and a correct choice for the future.” On May 14, 2017, President Xi Jinping The secretary pointed out in his toast at the welcome banquet of the “Belt and Road” International Cooperation Summit Forum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;I proposed the joint construction of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; initiative to inherit the spirit of the Silk Road, work together to create an open cooperation platform, and provide new impetus for the cooperative development of various countries.&quot; On June 23, 2021, President Xi Jinping The secretary pointed out in his written speech to the “One Belt, One Road” high-level conference on international cooperation in the Asia-Pacific region. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Open. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Building the Silk Road Economic Belt and the 21st Century Maritime Silk Road is a major strategic decision made by the Party Central Committee to oversee the overall political, diplomatic, and economic and social development. It is also an important step in implementing a new round of opening up. It is also an important measure to create a favorable surrounding environment. To put it figuratively, this &#39;Belt and Road&#39; initiative is to give our roc two more wings. Once it is built, the roc can fly higher. Further. This is also a commitment we make to the international community, and we must do it well.&quot; On December 10, 2013, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized at the Central Economic Work Conference. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;China hopes to use the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; as its two wings to achieve take-off together with South Asian countries.&quot; On September 18, 2014, General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out in his speech at the Indian World Affairs Council. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Win-win. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“With the increase in comprehensive national strength, China has the ability and willingness to provide more public goods to the Asia-Pacific and the world, especially to propose new initiatives and new ideas to promote the in-depth development of regional cooperation. China is willing to work with other countries to promote The construction of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; will engage more deeply in the regional cooperation process and make new contributions to Asia-Pacific connectivity, development and prosperity.&quot; On November 9, 2014, General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out in his speech at the opening ceremony of the APEC Business Leaders Summit. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the spirit of openness and inclusiveness, we will work together with all relevant parties who are willing to participate to build the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; into a &#39;road to poverty reduction&#39; and a &#39;road to growth&#39;, and move towards common prosperity for mankind. Make positive contributions.&quot; On April 20, 2021, General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out in a video keynote speech at the opening ceremony of the Boao Forum for Asia 2021 Annual Conference. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;China has proposed the initiative of building the Silk Road Economic Belt, adhering to the concepts of common development and common prosperity, linking the two major markets of Asia and Europe, and giving the ancient Silk Road a new era connotation.&quot; On March 29, 2014, General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out when visiting the Port of Duisburg, Germany. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Chinese people are working hard to realize the Chinese Dream of the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation. The Chinese Dream is a dream of peace, development, cooperation, and win-win. We pursue the well-being of the Chinese people and the common well-being of people of all countries. &quot;On April 19, 2015, General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out in a signed article titled &quot;Long Live the Friendship between the People of China and Pakistan&quot; published simultaneously by Pakistan&#39;s &quot;Battle&quot; and &quot;Daily News&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Everything can be born if it has its own way, and everything can be achieved if it has its own way. &quot;The joint construction of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; conforms to the historical trend of economic globalization, the requirements of the times in the transformation of the global governance system, and the strong desire of people of all countries to live a better life.&quot; On April 26, 2019, General Secretary Xi Jinping said on the 1st pointed out in the keynote speech at the opening ceremony of the second &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We must climb high and look far, but also keep our feet on the ground.” In the past ten years, the joint construction of the “Belt and Road” has gone from top-level design to project implementation, from planning plans to specific practices, from “general freehand” to “ &quot;Gongbi Painting&quot;, this road of happiness that benefits the world is getting wider and wider. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &quot;This road is not a private road for one party, but a sunshine avenue for everyone to move forward hand in hand.&quot; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Mohan, Yunnan, a formerly unknown port Now it is getting more and more lively. Since the opening of the China-Laos railway, it has been 10 hours from Kunming to Vientiane, the capital of Laos, and the time for Thai fruits to enter China has been greatly reduced to less than 15 hours. As of August 31 this year, the China-Laos Railway has completed a cumulative freight volume of 25.22 million tons, and the transportation network has radiated to 13 countries and regions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On December 3, 2021, when General Secretary Xi Jinping attended the opening ceremony of the China-Laos railway via video link, he emphasized: “Both parties must continue their efforts and do well to maintain and operate the railway well, and develop it along the line. , build it well and create a golden line to benefit the people of the two countries.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The road is never isolated, and together we can go a long way. Over the past ten years, General Secretary Xi Jinping has coordinated both domestic and international situations, deeply observed and thought about the world situation, and elaborated on the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; construction on many important international and domestic occasions, looking for points of convergence of interests, points of resonance with policy concepts, and points of complementary cooperation. , seeking the greatest common denominator for the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative and demonstrating the wisdom and magnanimity of the great powers. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2014, the &quot;Strategic Plan for the Construction of the Silk Road Economic Belt and the 21st Century Maritime Silk Road&quot; was adopted; in 2015, the &quot;Strategic Plan for Promoting the Joint Construction of the Silk Road Economic Belt and the 21st Century Maritime Silk Road&quot; was issued Vision and Actions&quot;; promote the establishment of financial platforms such as the Silk Road Fund and the Asian Infrastructure Investment Bank; the China International Import Expo, the China International Fair for Trade in Services, and the China Import and Export Fair, with international guests arriving one after another...&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;In March 2015, sails danced on the vast sea in Boao, Hainan. In his keynote speech at the 2015 Boao Forum for Asia Annual Conference, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: “We must grasp the general trend of the world, keep up with the trend of the times, and jointly create a regional order that is more beneficial to Asia and the world. By moving towards Asia A community with a shared future for mankind and promote the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past ten years, starting from Beijing and crossing mountains and seas, General Secretary Xi Jinping has traveled across five continents. His frequent diplomatic schedule has marked the development of China&#39;s relations with the world. Brand new coordinates -&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The &#39;Belt and Road&#39; is open and is a vast &#39;circle of friends&#39; that runs through Africa and connects Asia and Europe. All interested countries can be added to the &#39;circle of friends&#39;.&quot; The Belt and Road Initiative is diverse, covering various fields of cooperation, and the forms of cooperation can also be diverse. The Belt and Road Initiative is a win-win situation where all countries participate together and follow the principle of extensive consultation, joint contribution and shared benefits to achieve common development and prosperity. This road is not A private road for one party is a sunshine avenue for everyone to move forward hand in hand.&quot; On October 21, 2015, General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out in his speech at the China-UK Business Summit in London, England. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China’s development has benefited from the international community, and it is also willing to provide more public goods to the international community.” On September 3, 2016, in the keynote speech at the opening ceremony of the G20 Business Summit , General Secretary Xi Jinping introduced the original intention of jointly building the “One Belt, One Road” initiative. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China is willing to develop friendly cooperation with all participating countries in the Belt and Road Initiative on the basis of the Five Principles of Peaceful Coexistence. China is willing to share development experience with other countries around the world, but will not interfere in other countries’ internal affairs and will not We will export social systems and development models, let alone impose them on others. When we promote the construction of the Belt and Road Initiative, we will not repeat the old routine of geopolitical games, but will create a new model of win-win cooperation; we will not form small groups that undermine stability. And we will build a big family of harmonious coexistence.&quot; On May 14, 2017, General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out in his speech at the opening ceremony of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We must uphold the principle of extensive consultation, joint contribution and shared benefits, advocate multilateralism, discuss everyone’s affairs, and promote all parties to make full use of their strengths and capabilities through bilateral cooperation, trilateral cooperation, Through various forms such as multilateral cooperation, we can give full play to everyone&#39;s advantages and potential, and gather sand to form a tower and water to form an abyss.&quot; On April 26, 2019, General Secretary Xi Jinping spoke at the opening ceremony of the second &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum pointed out in the keynote speech. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The ‘One Belt, One Road’ initiative initiated by China is not a slogan or a legend, but a successful practice and wonderful reality.” On November 11, 2019, General Secretary Xi Jinping visited COSCO Shipping Piraeus What he said during the Hong Kong project is evocative. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thanks to the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, Serbia&#39;s Smederevo Steel Plant has regained its vitality, the Maldives has the first cross-sea bridge in history, Uzbekistan&#39;s cataract patients have regained their sight, and Senegal Villagers in arid areas feel more at ease when drinking water... Each beautiful story witnesses the &quot;hard connectivity&quot; of infrastructure, the &quot;soft connectivity&quot; of rules and standards, and the &quot;heart-to-heart connectivity&quot; that warms people&#39;s hearts. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For the past ten years, General Secretary Xi Jinping has provided guidance and direction, guiding all parts of the country to find their correct position and play a greater role in the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2016 On August 17, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized at the symposium on promoting the construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;: &quot;Summarize experience, strengthen confidence, make solid progress, focus on policy communication, facility connectivity, unimpeded trade, financial integration, and people-to-people connectivity, and focus on building mutual benefit Cooperation networks, new cooperation models, and diversified cooperation platforms focus on jointly building a green Silk Road, a healthy Silk Road, an intellectual Silk Road, and a peaceful Silk Road. We will stick to it with the spirit of nailing and push forward the construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; step by step. go ahead&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After laying foundations and building pillars and beams, the joint construction of the “Belt and Road” has continued to take root and develop sustainably. On August 27, 2018, General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out at the 5th Anniversary Symposium on Promoting the Construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;: &quot;We must make further progress and promote joint construction on the basis of maintaining a healthy and sound development momentum.&quot; The transformation of the Belt and Road Initiative to high-quality development is the basic requirement for promoting the joint construction of the Belt and Road Initiative in the next stage.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On November 19, 2021, General Secretary Xi Jinping attended the third &quot;Belt and Road Initiative&quot; The symposium on the construction of &quot;One Belt and One Road&quot; comprehensively summarized the remarkable achievements of the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, scientifically analyzed the new situation faced by the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, and put forward clear requirements for continuing to promote the high-quality development of the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;: &quot;Complete , accurately and comprehensively implement the new development concept, with the goal of high standards, sustainability, and benefiting people&#39;s livelihood, consolidate the foundation of connectivity cooperation, expand new space for international cooperation, strengthen the risk prevention and control network, and strive to achieve a higher level of cooperation and higher Investment efficiency, higher supply quality, and higher development resilience will continue to achieve new results in promoting the high-quality development of the Belt and Road Initiative.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The sonorous words are resounding. Under the guidance of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important exposition on the joint construction of the “Belt and Road”, the joint construction of the “Belt and Road” continues to move forward in the direction of high-quality development. &quot;Facts have proven that the joint construction of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; not only provides new opportunities for the development of countries around the world, but also opens up a new world for China&#39;s opening up and development.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past ten years, the scale of trade and investment between my country and the co-building countries has been steady Expansion, infrastructure interconnection continues to strengthen, and the level of industrial chain and supply chain cooperation continues to improve. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The World Bank research report predicts that by 2030, the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; will increase trade among participating countries by 2.8% to 9.7%, global trade by 1.7% to 6.2%, and global income by 0.7%. 2.9%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &quot;Co-building the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; is a long-term project and a common cause for partners&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On November 19, 2021, at At the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; construction symposium, General Secretary Xi Jinping recalled a past event more than 20 years ago. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在福建工作期间，习近平同志接待了来访的巴布亚新几内亚东高地省省长拉法纳玛。 “我向他介绍了菌草技术，这位省长一听很感兴趣。我就派《山海情》里的那个林占熺去了。”由此书写了“小小一株草，情接万里长”的佳话。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如今，这个技术已经在100多个国家落地生根，为当地创造了数十万个就业机会。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一项伟大的事业，之所以在世界各地蓬勃发展，关键在于合民愿、惠民生、聚民心。举世瞩目的“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛，之所以越办越好，是因为它深入人心。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2017年和2019年，中国先后举办了两届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛。习近平总书记在会见外国政要时提到此事：“我们本来没有定要举行第二届论坛，看来还&#39;收不住&#39;，将来还会继续举办，这也说明&#39;一带一路&#39;日益深入人心。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022年11月，习近平总书记在出席亚太经合组织领导人非正式会议期间正式宣布，明年中方将考虑举行第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023年7月4日，习近平总书记在上海合作组织成员国元首理事会第二十三次会议上的讲话中表示：“今年是我提出&#39;一带一路&#39;倡议10周年，中方将举办第三届&#39;一带一路&#39;国际合作高峰论坛，欢迎各方参加论坛活动，共同把这条造福世界的幸福之路铺得更宽更远。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到目前为止，来自140多个国家、30多个国际组织的代表已确认与会。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共建“一带一路”的旺盛人气，来自于它的开放与包容。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2017年5月15日，习近平总书记在“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛圆桌峰会上的开幕辞中指出：“&#39;一带一路&#39;建设跨越不同地域、不同发展阶段、不同文明，是一个开放包容的合作平台，是各方共同打造的全球公共产品。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2019年4月26日，习近平总书记在第二届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛开幕式上的主旨演讲中表示：“从亚欧大陆到非洲、美洲、大洋洲，共建&#39;一带一路&#39;为世界经济增长开辟了新空间，为国际贸易和投资搭建了新平台，为完善全球经济治理拓展了新实践，为增进各国民生福祉作出了新贡献，成为共同的机遇之路、繁荣之路。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2019年4月27日，习近平总书记在第二届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛记者会上的讲话中指出：“共建&#39;一带一路&#39;倡议源于中国，机会和成果属于世界。共建&#39;一带一路&#39;是一项长期工程，是合作伙伴们共同的事业。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“世界上的事情越来越需要各国共同商量着办”“国际上的事情由各国商量着办”……“商量着办”的中国方式，深深镌刻在中国与世界频繁互动的轨道上，鲜明地映照在共建“一带一路”的进程中。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十年来，共建“一带一路”为世界发展带来新机遇。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年8月21日至24日，习近平总书记出席金砖国家领导人第十五次会晤并对南非进行国事访问期间，中国与南非签署了《中南关于同意深化“一带一路”合作的意向书》。习近平总书记明确表示：“中方将扩大进口南非产品，鼓励更多中国企业赴南非投资兴业。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中南应急电力合作、新能源电力投资合作、电网升级改造合作……每个项目都着眼于南非燃眉之急。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十年来，共建“一带一路”为中国发展注入新活力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022年7月，习近平总书记在新疆考察时指出：“共建&#39;一带一路&#39;倡议提出这些年来，硕果累累。随着共建&#39;一带一路&#39;深入推进，新疆不再是边远地带，而是一个核心区、一个枢纽地带，你们做的是具有历史意义的事情，已经取得很好的成绩，再接再厉，前途光明。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如今的新疆霍尔果斯铁路口岸，中欧（中亚）班列经此通行，满载着“中国制造”源源不断走向中亚、欧洲市场。千年前的古丝路要冲，成为共建“一带一路”重要枢纽。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十年来，共建“一带一路”为构建人类命运共同体搭建新平台。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与共建“一带一路”国家打造“健康丝绸之路”，为抗击疫情凝聚合力；深化农业、卫生、减灾、水资源等领域合作，同联合国在发展领域加强合作，努力缩小发展差距；制定《“一带一路”绿色投资原则》，实施“一带一路”应对气候变化南南合作计划……共建“一带一路”不仅是经济合作，而且是完善全球发展模式和全球治理、推进经济全球化健康发展的重要途径。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们将建设更紧密的卫生合作伙伴关系”“我们将建设更紧密的互联互通伙伴关系”“我们将建设更紧密的绿色发展伙伴关系”“我们将建设更紧密的开放包容伙伴关系”……2021年4月20日，在博鳌亚洲论坛2021年年会开幕式上，习近平总书记的精彩演讲，描绘出人类命运共同体的未来图景。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;岁月不居，时节如流。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当前，全球经济复苏乏力，地缘政治冲突仍在持续，不确定不稳定因素增多。关键时刻，中国以身作则，展现大国担当，给世界注入更多信心和力量。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1月31日，习近平总书记在二十届中共中央政治局第二次集体学习时指出：“推动共建&#39;一带一路&#39;高质量发展，积极参与国际经贸规则谈判，推动形成开放、多元、稳定的世界经济秩序，为实现国内国际两个市场两种资源联动循环创造条件。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4月6日，习近平总书记在出席中法企业家委员会第五次会议闭幕式时指出：“我提出构建人类命运共同体倡议、共建&#39;一带一路&#39;倡议、全球发展倡议、全球安全倡议、全球文明倡议，就是希望让团结代替分裂、合作代替对抗、包容代替排他，共同建设持久和平、普遍安全、共同繁荣、开放包容、清洁美丽的世界。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5月17日，习近平总书记在听取陕西省委和省政府工作汇报时强调：“更加主动融入和服务构建新发展格局，更加深度融入共建&#39;一带一路&#39;大格局，在扩大对内对外开放中强动力、增活力，打开发展新天地。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5月19日，习近平总书记在中国—中亚峰会上发表主旨讲话强调：“我们要继续在共建&#39;一带一路&#39;合作方面走在前列，推动落实全球发展倡议，充分释放经贸、产能、能源、交通等传统合作潜力，打造金融、农业、减贫、绿色低碳、医疗卫生、数字创新等新增长点，携手建设一个合作共赢、相互成就的共同体。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7月4日，习近平总书记在上海合作组织成员国元首理事会第二十三次会议上发表重要讲话指出：“我们要加强高质量共建&#39;一带一路&#39;同各国发展战略和地区合作倡议对接，深入推进贸易和投资自由化便利化，加快口岸基础设施和区域国际物流大通道建设，保障区域产业链供应链稳定畅通。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一带一路”，这条承载着人类对文明交流的渴望、对和平安宁的期盼、对共同发展的追求、对美好生活的向往的阳光大道，越走越宽广，越走越深入人心。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十年扬帆再起航。中国将在习近平总书记关于共建“一带一路”的重要论述指引下，以举办第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛为契机，同国际社会一道总结经验、开辟未来，推动高质量共建“一带一路”持续向前发展，共同把这条造福世界的幸福之路铺得更宽更远，书写国家互利共赢、人民相知相亲、文明互学互鉴的丝路新篇。 &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 奋力谱写中国式现代化江西篇章]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20231015_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月15日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;10月10日至13日，习近平总书记先后来到江西省九江、景德镇、上饶等地，深入长江岸线、企业、历史文化街区、农村等进行调研，听取江西省委和省政府工作汇报并作重要讲话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记江西考察重要讲话在当地干部群众中引发热烈反响。大家表示，要认真学习领会、深入贯彻落实习近平总书记重要讲话精神，紧紧围绕新时代新征程党的中心任务，完整准确全面贯彻新发展理念，牢牢把握江西在构建新发展格局中的定位，立足江西的特色和优势，着眼高质量发展、绿色发展、低碳发展等新要求，解放思想、开拓进取，扬长补短、固本兴新，努力在加快革命老区高质量发展上走在前、在推动中部地区崛起上勇争先、在推进长江经济带发展上善作为，奋力谱写中国式现代化江西篇章。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;努力构建体现江西特色和优势的现代化产业体系&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记指出，“构建现代化产业体系，既要有雄心壮志，积极抢位发展，又要立足实际，善于错位发展。要找准定位、明确方向，整合资源、精准发力，加快传统产业改造升级，加快战略性新兴产业发展壮大，积极部署未来产业，努力构建体现江西特色和优势的现代化产业体系。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“习近平总书记重要讲话，为我们进一步指明了前进方向。”江西省工业和信息化厅厅长应炯说，“要着力优化全省产业布局，统筹发展传统产业、战略性新兴产业和未来产业，加快建设制造业强省，努力构建体现江西特色和优势的现代化产业体系。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;江西省科技厅厅长宋德雄表示，要深入实施创新驱动发展战略，加快推进创新江西建设，努力打造一批高新技术产业，形成在全国有影响力的产业集群，为奋力谱写中国式现代化江西篇章提供科技支撑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;昌河飞机工业（集团）有限公司是我国直升机科研生产基地和航空工业骨干企业，带动江西省内外一大批上下游企业协同发展。“深入贯彻落实习近平总书记重要讲话精神，我们将坚持创新驱动，努力构建先进制造体系，为推动我国直升机产业高质量发展贡献力量。”公司董事长周国臣表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;鹰潭市万成光学科技有限公司总经理叶建军说：“习近平总书记要求&#39;积极推进数字经济和实体经济融合，发展壮大数字经济&#39;。我们将在企业生产实现智能化、数字化转型升级的基础上，更有针对性地实施研发升级，不断挖掘发展潜力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;景德镇市委书记刘锋说：“牢记习近平总书记嘱托，我们要加大力度集聚各方面人才，加强创意设计和研发创新，在做大日用陶瓷、做精艺术陶瓷的基础上，主攻先进陶瓷，进一步把陶瓷产业做大做强，把&#39;千年瓷都&#39;这张靓丽的名片擦得更亮。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“深入贯彻落实习近平总书记重要讲话精神，我们将坚持绿色、智能方向，进一步探索数字技术赋能产业绿色转型发展路径，为保障国家能源安全、推动石化工业高质量发展作出新贡献。”中国石化九江分公司党委书记谢道雄表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;打造内陆地区改革开放高地，主动服务和融入新发展格局&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记强调，“江西联通东西、承接南北、通江达海，多个国家重大战略叠加。要深化对内对外开放，以开放促发展，打造内陆地区改革开放高地，主动服务和融入新发展格局。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;九江市委书记刘文华说：“深入贯彻落实习近平总书记重要讲话精神，我们要进一步发挥九江港&#39;江海直达、服务全省、辐射周边&#39;的综合功能，依托九江综合保税区、跨境电商综合试验区等开放平台，吸引更多人流、物流、资金流、信息流加速向九江集聚，努力打造区域性物流枢纽和商贸中心，推动长江经济带重要节点城市建设取得新进展。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;江西近年来加快培育发展南昌都市圈，引领带动全省区域协调发展。南昌市副市长赵捷说：“我们将加快&#39;一枢纽四中心&#39;建设，进一步加大与长三角、粤港澳大湾区的交流合作，夯实都市圈融合发展基础支撑，强化聚集效应、发挥带动功能。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;赣南大地橘黄橙绿，油茶果挂满枝头。赣州市农业农村局局长孙晖表示，将更好发挥赣州绿色生态等优势，以全域创建绿色有机农产品基地为抓手，把粤港澳大湾区作为农产品主销地、农业招商主阵地，不断做大做强农产品优势品牌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“习近平总书记重要讲话，为江西进一步深化改革、扩大开放提供了科学指引。”江西省发展改革委主任王前虎说，“我们将统筹推进深化改革攻坚，努力营造市场化、法治化、国际化一流营商环境；依托江西内陆开放型经济试验区建设，对接国际高标准经贸规则，推动要素配置更加高效畅通；有序扩大民间投资市场准入，促进民营经济健康发展。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 加快农业农村现代化建设步伐，全面推进乡村振兴&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记指出，“要坚持农业农村优先发展，加快农业农村现代化建设步伐，牢牢守住粮食安全底线，推进农业产业化，推动农村一二三产业融合发展，全面推进乡村振兴。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;赣鄱大地稻浪金黄，丰收在望。“深入贯彻落实习近平总书记重要讲话精神，我们要坚持产业兴农、质量兴农、绿色兴农，进一步巩固粮食主产区地位，在生产端、加工端、流通端、销售端&#39;四端&#39;发力，把农业建设成为大产业，加快建设农业强省。”江西省农业农村厅厅长孙朝辉说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;抚州市近年来着力将生态优势转化为产业优势和发展优势，形成具有地域特色的林下种养主导产业。抚州市委书记魏晓奎说：“我们要加大力度推动林下种养业质量提升，做大做强生态旅游、森林康养产业，塑造林下经济特色品牌，进一步发展壮大林业经济。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“习近平总书记指出，&#39;巩固拓展脱贫攻坚成果，要更多依靠产业发展，不断增强内生发展动力。&#39;”赣州市上犹县乡村振兴局局长黄骥说，“我们将抓住产业这一关键，大力发展乡村旅游等生态富民产业，巩固拓展脱贫攻坚成果，全面推进乡村振兴。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上饶市委常委、副市长帕塔尔·胡加买提表示，要进一步做大做强农村特色产业，优化农村公共服务供给，推进乡村环境整治，提升乡村文明水平，建设宜居宜业和美乡村，让群众得到实实在在的好处。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“村两委班子带领村民发展生态旅游和茶产业，现在村里环境更好了，村民收入增加了，日子过得红火又舒心。”上饶市婺源县秋口镇王村石门自然村村民许美玲说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;确保老区人民共享改革发展成果，过上幸福生活&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记强调，“确保老区人民共享改革发展成果，过上幸福生活，是推进全体人民共同富裕的底线任务。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;江西省人力资源和社会保障厅厅长蒋斌说：“深入贯彻落实习近平总书记重要讲话精神，我们要持续强化就业优先政策，加大对就业容量大的服务业、小微企业等的支持力度，促进新就业形态健康发展，最大程度扩容就业&#39;蓄水池&#39;。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;南昌市近年来不断优化学校布局，发挥优质教育资源的辐射带动作用。南昌市委教育工委书记、市教育局局长黄琰说：“深入贯彻落实习近平总书记重要讲话精神，我们要把促进教育公平融入深化教育领域综合改革的各方面各环节，不断提高基本公共教育服务水平。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们将持续深化&#39;三医联动&#39;改革，促进医保、医疗、医药协同发展和治理，强化城乡卫生健康服务能力，确保老区人民共享改革发展成果。”江西省卫生健康委主任龚建平表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吉安市卫生健康委主任李发芽说：“吉安将加大力度推进紧密型县域医共体建设，建立健全全市健康教育网络，普及全民健康知识，提升居民健康素养，不断强化城乡卫生健康服务能力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;总结运用第一批主题教育的成功经验，高质量开展第二批主题教育&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记指出，“要总结运用第一批主题教育的成功经验，高质量开展第二批主题教育”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;井冈山上，苍松翠柏、枫叶似火，人们从四面八方来到这里缅怀先烈，感悟井冈山精神。中国井冈山干部学院副院长汪建新教授说：“深入贯彻落实习近平总书记重要讲话精神，要总结运用第一批主题教育的成功经验，切实发挥干部教育培训主渠道主阵地作用，用井冈山精神、苏区精神、长征精神砥砺党员、干部，教育引导党员、干部坚定理想信念、牢记初心使命、积极开拓进取、勇于担当作为。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“习近平总书记指出，&#39;要把实的要求贯穿主题教育全过程，坚决防止和克服形式主义、官僚主义&#39;。”宜春市委常委、组织部部长徐云涌说，“我们要善于运用第一批主题教育的成功经验，实实在在抓好理论学习和调查研究，实实在在检视整改突出问题，实实在在办好惠民利民实事，求真务实、担当实干，确保第二批主题教育取得扎扎实实的成效。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“习近平总书记重要讲话，为高质量开展第二批主题教育指明了方向。我们将把开展主题教育与优化营商环境、壮大产业集群等工作紧密结合起来，以深入的调查研究抓问题，以有力的政策举措促改革，努力把主题教育成果体现到高质量发展的成效上、体现到促进中心工作上。”上饶市余干县委书记胡斌说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上饶市铅山县委书记危岩表示，将结合第二批主题教育的深入开展，加大生态环境保护、修复力度，持续推进生态环境质量改善，用实干推动发展、取信于民，不断增强人民群众获得感、幸福感、安全感。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（本报记者郑少忠、朱磊、王丹、杨颜菲）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 进一步推动长江经济带高质量发展]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20231015_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月15日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;10月12日下午，习近平总书记在江西省南昌市主持召开进一步推动长江经济带高质量发展座谈会并发表重要讲话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记重要讲话在广大干部群众中引发热烈反响。大家表示，要认真学习领会、深入贯彻落实习近平总书记重要讲话精神，完整、准确、全面贯彻新发展理念，坚持共抓大保护、不搞大开发，坚持生态优先、绿色发展，以科技创新为引领，统筹推进生态环境保护和经济社会发展，加强政策协同和工作协同，谋长远之势、行长久之策、建久安之基，进一步推动长江经济带高质量发展，更好支撑和服务中国式现代化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 毫不动摇坚持共抓大保护、不搞大开发，在高水平保护上下更大功夫&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记指出，“从长远来看，推动长江经济带高质量发展，根本上依赖于长江流域高质量的生态环境。要毫不动摇坚持共抓大保护、不搞大开发，在高水平保护上下更大功夫。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们要以习近平总书记重要讲话精神为指引，继续加强生态环境综合治理，统筹减污降碳协同增效，从源头上降低污染物排放总量，严守生态环境安全底线。”江西省生态环境厅厅长李军表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;湖南省岳阳市君山区委书记雷欣说，深入贯彻落实习近平总书记重要讲话精神，君山将坚定推进长江“十年禁渔”，巩固好已经取得的成果。君山区钱粮湖镇六门闸社区生态渔村退捕渔民靠制作销售养殖鱼干走上致富路。“现在洞庭湖水更清、鱼更多了，我们要用实际行动保护好生态环境。”退捕渔民刘静说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“深入贯彻落实习近平总书记重要讲话精神，我们要厚植高质量发展的绿色底色，继续努力提高经济绿色化程度。”上海市发展改革委副主任、长三角生态绿色一体化发展示范区执委会副主任张忠伟介绍，环境价值正在成为示范区的品牌和财富，在浙江省嘉善县祥符荡创新中心，竹小汇双碳聚落通过风能、地热能、太阳能、生物质能、氢能等多能互补，正致力于打造低碳环保的新标杆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;浙江省生态环境厅厅长郎文荣说：“我们将持续深化生态保护补偿，与安徽共同推进新安江—千岛湖生态保护补偿样板区建设，不断完善省内流域生态保护补偿机制，统筹水资源、水环境、水生态，强化政策引导，形成责任清晰、合作共治的流域保护和治理长效机制。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 积极开辟发展新领域新赛道，塑造发展新动能新优势&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记强调：“要坚持创新引领发展，把长江经济带的科研优势、人才优势转化为发展优势，积极开辟发展新领域新赛道，塑造发展新动能新优势。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“深入贯彻落实习近平总书记重要讲话精神，我们将围绕产业基础高级化和产业链现代化，加快打造一批高质量新型研发机构，加强原创性引领性科技攻关。同时，加快推进科技成果转化，前瞻布局量子科技、聚变能源、深空探测等未来产业。”安徽省合肥市科学技术局局长范进说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“为加快构建以先进制造业为骨干的现代化产业体系，苏州将推动制造业高端化、智能化、绿色化发展，提升产业集群竞争力，完善制造业创新体系，培育更多专精特新、&#39;隐形冠军&#39;企业。”江苏省苏州市工业和信息化局局长万利说，“我们将进一步推动数字经济与实体经济深度融合，全面启动智能化改造、数字化转型、网络化连接新三年行动计划。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;湖北省武汉市东湖高新区在光电子信息产业领域独树一帜，享有“中国光谷”的美誉。“习近平总书记要求&#39;加强产业链协同合作，推动优势产业延链、新兴产业建链&#39;。东湖高新区将加强产业链协同合作，创新联合技术攻关体制，突破一批关键核心技术；推动优势产业延链，巩固光通信、激光等领域领先优势；推动新兴产业建链，面向量子科技、人工智能等前沿领域前瞻布局战略性新兴产业和未来产业。”武汉市委常委、东湖高新区党工委书记杜海洋说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 更好发挥独特优势，为构建新发展格局提供战略支撑&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记指出：“要更好发挥长江经济带横贯东西、承接南北、通江达海的独特优势，更好联通国内国际两个市场、用好两种资源，提升国内大循环内生动力和可靠性，增强对国际循环的吸引力、推动力，为构建新发展格局提供战略支撑。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安徽省马鞍山市近年来承接江苏省南京市优质产业转移，形成新能源、集成电路等多个产业集群。“习近平总书记要求&#39;在产业发展上，沿江省市既要各展优势，又要协同发展、错位发展、联动发展&#39;。我们将聚焦南京主导产业做好产业补链延链强链，引导产业链跨区域布局和产业集群融合共建，以合作园区为突破口加快与南京产业协同发展。”马鞍山市委常委、常务副市长黄化锋说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;云南省昭通市委书记苏永忠表示，要深入贯彻落实习近平总书记重要讲话精神，主动承接东部地区产业转移，打造绿色能源、绿色硅铝、磷化工及新材料、现代服务业等产业集群，助推高质量跨越式发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“成立长三角自贸试验区联盟，是加快推动长三角自贸试验区联动发展的创新举措。长三角自贸试验区联盟将充分发挥三省一市自贸试验区的特色优势，以制度创新为主线，以优化营商环境与市场环境为重点，以共同推进改革开放创新发展为目标，推动联盟资源共建共享，努力为建设更高水平开放型经济新体制积累新经验、探索新路径。”长三角自贸试验区联盟秘书处成员、上海市浦东新区发展改革委主任吴伟平说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;坚持把强化区域协同融通作为着力点，促进区域协调发展&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记强调，“要坚持把强化区域协同融通作为着力点，沿江省市要坚持省际共商、生态共治、全域共建、发展共享，增强区域交通互联性、政策统一性、规则一致性、执行协同性，稳步推进生态共同体和利益共同体建设，促进区域协调发展。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;湖北省交通运输厅综合交通处处长高波表示，湖北将依托推动长江经济带交通运输发展部省联席会议、长江中游三省协同推动高质量发展座谈会等平台机制，共同谋划武汉至南昌高速铁路、京港澳高速公路改扩建等跨区域重大交通项目，合力推进沪渝蓉等高速铁路建设，加快推进武汉至重庆、通山至武宁等高速公路建设，大力发展多式联运，提升区域交通一体化水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们要充分发挥浙江数字经济优势，统筹推进数字长三角建设，加快建设长三角工业互联网一体化发展示范区。”浙江省发展改革委长三角一体化发展处副处长杜彬俊表示，“要持续共建科创共同体，依托海量数据规模和丰富应用场景优势，持续推进长三角公共服务共建共享，促进区域协调发展。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;重庆市文化旅游委主任冉华章说：“我们要深入贯彻落实习近平总书记重要讲话精神，系统梳理长江重庆段文化脉络，积极推进文化和旅游深度融合发展，为打造长江国际黄金旅游带贡献力量。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 统筹好发展和安全，以一域之稳为全局之安作出贡献&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记指出，“长江经济带事关全国发展大局。要统筹好发展和安全，在维护国家粮食安全、能源安全、重要产业链供应链安全、水安全等方面发挥更大作用，以一域之稳为全局之安作出贡献。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“深入贯彻落实习近平总书记重要讲话精神，四川将坚决扛稳粮食、油料等重要农产品稳产保供责任，抓好&#39;良田&#39;建设、&#39;良机&#39;推广、&#39;良法&#39;集成、&#39;良种&#39;繁育和&#39;良制&#39;保障，努力打造新时代更高水平的&#39;天府粮仓&#39;。”四川省农业农村厅厅长徐芝文说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;贵州省能源局局长陈华表示，贵州将围绕加强煤炭等化石能源兜底保障能力，全力推进煤炭产业结构战略性调整，抓好煤炭清洁高效利用，加快打造西南地区煤炭保供中心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“习近平总书记重要讲话，为进一步推动长江经济带高质量发展指明了方向。我们要统筹好发展和安全，坚持旱涝同防同治，根据长江流域水情变化，加快构建现代化流域防洪抗旱减灾体系；强化流域治理管理，加快复苏河湖生态环境，强化流域水资源集约节约利用，推动水土流失综合治理，加快数字孪生长江建设，提升管理效能；全力推进国家水网建设，强化流域水工程统一联合调度，加强跨区域水资源丰枯调剂，充分发挥三峡、丹江口水库等控制性水工程综合效益，持续提升流域水安全保障能力。”水利部长江水利委员会负责同志说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 坚持中央统筹、省负总责、市县抓落实的工作机制&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记强调，“要坚持中央统筹、省负总责、市县抓落实的工作机制”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家发展改革委地区经济司副司长蔡长华说：“深入贯彻落实习近平总书记重要讲话精神，我们将积极发挥中央区域协调发展领导小组办公室作用，会同有关部门研究制定进一步推动长江经济带高质量发展的政策措施，在生态环境保护、绿色低碳发展、创新能力建设等方面推动一批重大改革和创新事项，加强政策协同和工作协同，建立健全科学高效的工作机制，狠抓工作落实，持续用力、久久为功。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;四川省宜宾市委书记方存好表示，宜宾市委和市政府将切实履行主体责任，牢固树立上游意识，自觉扛起上游担当，持续改善生态环境质量，扎实推进产业转型升级，加快形成绿色生活方式，进一步筑牢长江上游生态屏障。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们要以主题教育为契机，教育引导广大干部树立和践行正确政绩观，力戒形式主义、官僚主义，坚持生态优先、绿色发展，加快建设先进制造业核心区和现代服务业集聚区，为进一步推动长江经济带高质量发展作出贡献，努力创造经得起历史和人民检验的实绩。”重庆市渝北区委书记杨晓云说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“进一步推动长江经济带高质量发展，不仅是沿江各地党委和政府的责任，也是全社会的共同事业，要更加有效地凝聚各方面力量，引导各类企业、社会组织积极参与长江经济带发展，发挥好人民群众的积极性、主动性、创造性，实现&#39;人民保护长江、长江造福人民&#39;的良性循环。”南通大学江苏长江经济带研究院院长成长春说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（本报记者王丹、王云娜、巨云鹏、窦皓、李俊杰、王伟健、田豆豆、吴君、徐元锋、谢卫群、王欣悦、王明峰、程焕、刘志强、刘新吾）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 推动构建人类命运共同体的重要实践平台]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20231015_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月15日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;“长安复携手，再顾重千金。”今年5月，首届中国—中亚峰会在古丝绸之路的东方起点陕西西安举行。习近平总书记强调，“要继续在共建&#39;一带一路&#39;合作方面走在前列”“携手建设一个合作共赢、相互成就的共同体”。自2013年提出共建“丝绸之路经济带”倡议以来，中国同中亚国家携手推动丝绸之路全面复兴，倾力打造面向未来的深度合作，将双方关系带入一个崭新时代。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;千载流泽生生不息，丝路精神薪火相传。习近平总书记强调：“我提倡共建&#39;一带一路&#39;和构建人类命运共同体，就是要促进不同文明的交流互鉴和各国之间的互利合作，建设一个持久和平、普遍安全、共同繁荣、开放包容、清洁美丽的世界。”10年来，从亚欧大陆到非洲、美洲、大洋洲，共建“一带一路”坚持以共商共建共享为原则，以和平合作、开放包容、互学互鉴、互利共赢的丝路精神为指引，以打造利益共同体、责任共同体、命运共同体为合作目标，启动了大批务实合作、造福民众的项目，构建起全方位、复合型的互联互通伙伴关系，开创了共同发展的新前景。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共建“一带一路”，关键是互联互通。坚持把基础设施“硬联通”作为重要方向，把规则标准“软联通”作为重要支撑，把同共建国家人民“心联通”作为重要基础，共建“一带一路”架起了各国合作共赢的重要桥梁。深化政策沟通，推动同有关国家协调政策，共建“一带一路”与俄罗斯欧亚经济联盟建设、哈萨克斯坦“光明之路”新经济政策、南非“经济重建和复苏计划”、沙特“2030愿景”等多国战略实现对接；加强设施联通，基本形成“陆海天网”四位一体的互联互通格局，成功建设了中欧班列、西部陆海新通道、中老铁路等一批标志性项目；提升贸易畅通，大力推动贸易和投资便利化，2022年中国与共建国家进出口总额近2.9万亿美元；扩大资金融通，健全多元化投融资体系，亚洲基础设施投资银行成员从创立时的57个增长到目前的106个，丝路基金项目遍及60多个国家和地区；促进民心相通，各类丝绸之路文化年、艺术节、智库对话等人文合作项目精彩纷呈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;通过全方位互联互通，更好融入全球供应链、产业链、价值链，实现联动发展，共建“一带一路”为世界经济增长开辟了新空间，为国际贸易和投资搭建了新平台，为完善全球经济治理拓展了新实践，为增进各国民生福祉作出了新贡献。实践充分证明，共建“一带一路”顺应了全球治理体系变革的内在要求，彰显了同舟共济、权责共担的命运共同体意识，为完善全球治理体系变革提供了新思路新方案，是推动构建人类命运共同体的重要实践平台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;努力建设和平之路、繁荣之路、开放之路、绿色之路、创新之路、文明之路，共建“一带一路”开辟了建设更加美好世界的光明前景。正是因为锚定“和平是我们最大的共同利益，也是各国人民最大的共同期盼”，我们主张建设相互尊重、公平正义、合作共赢的新型国际关系，打造对话不对抗、结伴不结盟的伙伴关系；正是因为抓住“发展是解决一切问题的总钥匙”，我们聚焦发展这个根本性问题，释放各国发展潜力，实现经济大融合、发展大联动、成果大共享；正是因为笃定“开放带来进步，封闭导致落后”，我们坚持普惠共赢，打造开放型合作平台，推动形成开放型世界经济；正是因为践行绿色发展理念，我们加强绿色基建、绿色能源、绿色金融等领域合作，让绿色切实成为共建“一带一路”的底色；正是因为把握创新这个推动发展的重要力量，我们坚持创新驱动发展，促进科技同产业、科技同金融深度融合，优化创新环境，集聚创新资源；正是因为坚持以文明交流超越文明隔阂、文明互鉴超越文明冲突、文明共存超越文明优越，我们积极架设不同文明互学互鉴的桥梁，形成多元互动的人文交流格局。事实充分表明，共建“一带一路”顺应了和平、发展、合作、共赢的时代潮流，正在成为我国参与全球开放合作、改善全球经济治理体系、促进全球共同发展繁荣、推动构建人类命运共同体的中国方案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当今世界是一荣俱荣、一损俱损的命运共同体，构建人类命运共同体是世界各国人民前途所在。始终站在历史正确一边、站在人类文明进步一边，弘扬和平、发展、公平、正义、民主、自由的全人类共同价值，通过高质量共建“一带一路”，携手推动构建人类命运共同体，推动落实全球发展倡议、全球安全倡议、全球文明倡议，就一定能够让和平的薪火代代相传，让发展的动力源源不断，让文明的光芒熠熠生辉，共同开创人类美好未来！&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 图片报道]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20231015_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月15日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231015/1697315251292_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;近日，浙江宁波舟山港运输生产再传捷报：今年前三季度，累计完成货物吞吐量10.15亿吨，同比增长5.85%；完成集装箱吞吐量2726万标准箱，同比增长3.56%。图为10月13日宁波舟山港穿山港区集装箱码头作业场景。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;汤健凯摄（影像中国）&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 谋长远之势、行长久之策、建久安之基]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20231015_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月15日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;江西秋意正浓。九江、景德镇、上饶，再到南昌，习近平总书记一路察实情、观进展、谋未来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;长江经济带发展战略是党的十八大后提出的重大国家战略，覆盖沿江11个省市。这一横跨我国东中西三大板块的经济带，占有全国“半壁江山”的人口规模和经济总量。它所承载的，不仅有中国式现代化的生动实践，也有人与自然如何相处的时代答卷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记念之行之，10多年来30多次来到长江沿岸。江水滚滚东逝，江岸黄了又绿，长江的模样也在日复一日的努力中改变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大江东去，长卷万里。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以长江经济带发展为主题的座谈会，第1次召开于近8年前。此后每隔两三年，第2次、第3次，再到这一次考察期间于南昌第4次召开座谈会。一以贯之的关注，蕴含着党中央“谋长远之势、行长久之策、建久安之基”的治国之道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一次，习近平总书记在座谈会上回顾长江经济带的发展历程，颇为感慨：“做就要做好，坚定做下去。笃行不怠，一以贯之，久久为功。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 保护&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“坚持把共抓大保护摆在第一位”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;九江，三江之口、七省通衢，全揽152公里长江江西段岸线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记冒雨登上琵琶亭，举目远眺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大江逶迤，芳草长堤。天高地广，遐思万千！&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10多年来，上游、中游、下游，“含绿量”越来越高，“确实是沧桑巨变啊！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;昔日的长江之痛，是改革开放以来快速发展的生态代价。总书记曾经痛心地形容，长江“病了，而且病得还不轻”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2016年第一次座谈会，总书记为长江经济带发展立下规矩：“共抓大保护，不搞大开发”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近8年时间过去了，“保护”的成绩单有目共睹。“水质优良比例94.5%，长江干流连续3年Ⅱ类水质。”总书记感慨：“归纳一个个数字可以看出，长江经济带发展战略实施以来，取得的是战略性的效益。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;长江国家文化公园九江城区段，一个生动例证。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;琵琶亭上，一幅今昔对比图摆在总书记面前。治理前，当地“晴天一身灰，雨天一身泥”。江上的采砂船，江边裸露的矿坑给青山挂白、让长江蒙尘。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;望闻问切，分类施策。2021年底，长江国家文化公园建设正式启动，长江江西段被列为7个重点建设区之一。九江乘势而上，努力打造百里长江“最美岸线”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记细致询问当地治污、治岸、治渔情况，叮嘱说：“长江是长江经济带的纽带。无论未来长江经济带怎么发展、发展到哪个阶段，都不可能离开长江的哺育。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从“靠江吃江”到“靠江护江”，变化的不仅有一江清水、两岸青翠，还有观念：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“过去我们讲&#39;以GDP论英雄&#39;，关心&#39;含金量&#39;。现在思想观念转变了，认识问题可以说解决了。长江经济带因长江而生、因长江而兴，一定要认清这个因果关系。”总书记说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这真是令人感慨的变化！变化背后，是“算大账、算长远账”的战略定力和历史远见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;座谈会上，总书记肯定长江禁渔取得的成绩，并要求禁渔的政策不能动摇，要坚决地继续做下去。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总书记语重心长：“生态环境保护是一项长期任务，不能抓一阵松一阵，稍有好转又动起歪念头。现在的长江只能说是&#39;大病初愈&#39;，要毫不动摇地坚持&#39;共抓大保护，不搞大开发&#39;，在高水平保护上下更大功夫，为长江经济带高质量发展提供更坚实支撑。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;发展&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“现在路子是对的，要继续走下去”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在前几次座谈会上，习近平总书记深刻论述“在发展中保护、在保护中发展”的辩证关系，讲得透彻：“生态环境保护的成败归根到底取决于经济结构和经济发展方式。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;企业是长江生态环境保护建设的主体和重要力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北濒长江、南临庐山、东枕鄱湖，中国石化九江分公司在破解“化工围江”的战役中，压力重重。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;江上的问题，根子在岸上。九江石化有个“环境在线监测实时数据”，每20秒更新一次。大气、水、土壤，一栏是国标，一栏是企业实际排放情况，习近平总书记一边看，一边听企业介绍是如何“不让一滴油和一滴超标污水进入长江”，是如何力争“臭气不上天，污油不落地”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总书记勉励道：“标准定得高，也在一步一个脚印地干。希望你们按照党中央对新型工业化的部署要求，坚持绿色、智能方向，扎扎实实、奋发进取，为保障国家能源安全、推动石化工业高质量发展作出新贡献。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;由点及面，着眼的是“既治已病，也治未病”：“在新型工业化建设中，我们要把绿色化、低碳化摆进去，摆到日程上，也希望工业战线有更多实际行动。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果说东部海岸线宛如一张蓄势的长弓，长江经济带就是破空的锐箭。长江经济带，作为我国科技资源最富集、最具科技创新活力和科技成果转化能力的区域之一，“推动优势产业延链、新兴产业建链”有着得天独厚的条件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;考察第2天，习近平总书记来到景德镇的昌河飞机工业（集团）有限公司。在总装车间，“航空报国&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;航空强国”标语分外醒目；试飞站，湛蓝苍穹下各类直升机一字儿排开，蔚为壮观。总书记登上一架直升机，细听介绍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“要坚持创新驱动，在关键核心技术自主研发上下更大功夫，面向未来需求出新品，努力构建先进制造体系、打造世界一流直升机企业。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“&#39;不搞大开发&#39;是不要乱开发、低水平开发、粗放开发、破坏性开发，而是走一条高质量发展的道路、绿色低碳发展的道路。现在路子是对的，要继续走下去。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;传承&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“让中华优秀传统文化发扬光大”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大江奔流而磅礴，文明沉厚而隽永。长江文化，在灿若星辰的中华文化中如一条耀眼星河。这其中，长江水浸润着瓷土，景德镇熠熠生辉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;走进景德镇，这里有“陶阳十三里，烟火十万家”的繁盛，有“窑火夜夜明，瓷器日日出”的熙攘。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;南麓遗址旁，总书记仔细端详。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;圆的是辘轳坑，方的是陈泥池。宋元陶瓷在底层，明清陶瓷叠于上，17座马蹄窑一字儿排开，下面还埋藏着更古远的24座马蹄窑、4座蛋形窑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;千年窑火生生不息。习近平总书记有感而发：“中华优秀传统文化自古至今从未断流，陶瓷是中华瑰宝，是中华文明的重要名片。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此地往西400米，昌江穿城而过。江水奔腾180里，注入鄱阳湖，继而通江达海。“行于九域，施及外洋。”历史的烟波里，景德镇的瓷器踏着海上丝路的浪花，远销世界。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;明清窑作群手工制瓷技艺长廊，陶瓷非遗传承人荟萃于此，正是“匠从八方来，器成天下走”，有的白发苍苍，有的风华正茂。他们热情地向总书记展示看家本领。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;踩泥、揉泥、拉坯、印坯、利坯、画坯、施釉、起釉……“过手七十二，方克成器。”《天工开物》的记载，也映照了今天的工匠精神。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总书记与一位老师傅交谈起来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“老师傅好！手上功夫了得啊！有图案吗，还是凭着手感？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“都在心里。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位师傅13岁跟着父亲学做瓷，是家中的第四代传人，转眼就已干了40年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你是这块土地孕育的传承人，是工匠精神的写照啊。”总书记赞许道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在景德镇，有2万多个年轻人忙碌在制瓷一线，他们的背后，撬动的是庞大的陶瓷产业链。总书记颇为感慨：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“很高兴看到陶瓷事业有这么多的传承人、继承人，这个事业要不断发展下去。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一辈子做一件事，祖祖辈辈干一件事，不是简单的事。要坚持走自己的路，不能见异思迁。老祖宗传下来的优秀传统文化，我们要继续攥在手里，与时俱进，让它发扬光大。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;千年制瓷路，留下的不仅是天青色的记忆，更凝聚着中华文明的古与今。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;振兴&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“老区人民都是我们最牵挂的”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;河流与村庄，相依了千年。饶河在附近发源，穿过村庄，绕过山峦，最终流经鄱阳湖注入长江。考察第2天的下午，习近平总书记走进上饶市婺源县秋口镇王村石门自然村。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;生态，是村子的名片。村内，古樟、苦槠、枫杨倒影青翠，还有极度濒危鸟类蓝冠噪鹛在枝头嬉闹的照片，都是人与自然和谐共生的缩影。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4年多前，也在江西，习近平总书记指示要做好治山理水、显山露水的文章，打造美丽中国“江西样板”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;小小的村落，便是样板的一角。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;走到哪里，共同富裕都是总书记关切的事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次到革命老区，总书记强调：“无论脱贫攻坚、全面小康，还是建设现代化、推进共同富裕，老区人民都是我们最牵挂的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沿着街巷边走边看。“见老者，敬之；见幼者，爱之。”家家户户门口张贴着先贤修身治家格言。院墙彩绘，角落花草，生态和人文相映成趣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;村里，平整的石板路串起大街小巷；村外，宽阔的高速路伸向四面八方。“古村落现在交通方便了，本地产业也发展起来，特别是旅游，很热闹。我很关注咱们下一步的发展振兴，希望芝麻开花节节高。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在村民热烈的掌声中，总书记亲切地说：“中国式现代化既要有城市的现代化，又要有农业农村现代化。我很关注乡村振兴。希望你们保护好自然生态，把传统村落风貌和现代元素结合起来，坚持中华民族的审美情趣，把乡村建设得更美丽，让日子越过越开心、越幸福！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;12日召开的进一步推动长江经济带高质量发展座谈会上，总书记指出：“我们推进乡村振兴，建设美丽乡村，长江经济带很有优势。沿岸既有古村落，又有现代乡村。要将长江的历史文化、山水文化与城乡发展相融合，突出地方特色。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;水与村，共隽美。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;融通&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“长江经济带事关全国发展大局”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;循着逶迤的江岸望去，有平畴沃野，也有峰峦竞秀；有国际门户，也有深山密林。长江经济带体量之庞大，情况之复杂，是挑战，亦是机遇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;站在更宏阔视角，习近平总书记对长江经济带发展的思考，着眼于中国的昨天、今天和明天。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;向东，是浩渺太平洋；向西，是广袤的亚欧大陆。巨大的发展梯度，叠加一望无垠的延展空间，塑造了长江经济带巨大的韧性、潜力和回旋空间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;长江经济带全方位对内对外开放态势正加速形成，千帆竞发、百舸争流的时代洪流中，总书记进一步强调：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“要更好发挥长江经济带横贯东西、承接南北、通江达海的独特优势，更好联通国内国际两个市场、用好两种资源，提升国内大循环内生动力和可靠性，增强对国际循环的吸引力、推动力，为构建新发展格局提供战略支撑。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;是各自为战、以邻为壑，还是“一盘棋”谋篇布局？鉴证着一个地方、一个部门、一支队伍的政绩观。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记进一步提出要求：“要坚持把强化区域协同融通作为着力点，沿江省市要坚持省际共商、生态共治、全域共建、发展共享，增强区域交通互联性、政策统一性、规则一致性、执行协同性，稳步推进生态共同体和利益共同体建设，促进区域协调发展。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会上，总书记亲切询问来自11个省市的负责同志，他们花了多长时间到南昌。昔日翻山越岭、跋山涉水的漫长路途，而今不过两三个小时。“你们之间交通方便，说明这些年建设成绩显著。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为我国纵深最长、覆盖最广的经济带，长江经济带事关全国发展大局。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;发展与安全，不可失之偏颇；一域与全局，还需辩证统筹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;座谈会上，总书记期许长江经济带“在维护国家粮食安全、能源安全、重要产业链供应链安全、水安全等方面发挥更大作用，以一域之稳为全局之安作出贡献”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;四个安全，筑基发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;说粮食，责任一以贯之，“沿江省市无论是粮食主产区还是主销区、产销平衡区，都要扛牢粮食安全责任”；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谈能源，谋划高处着眼，“坚持全国&#39;一盘棋&#39;，继续深化上游地区同中下游地区的能源合作”；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;话安澜，风险未雨绸缪，“强化流域水工程统一联合调度，加强跨区域水资源丰枯调剂，提升流域防灾减灾能力”；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大视野统筹兼顾，大思路引领方向。长江的保护与发展，总书记慎而思之、笃而行之，“谋长远之势、行长久之策、建久安之基”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;浪千叠，帆千重。大江东，势如虹。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 共同把这条造福世界的幸福之路铺得更宽更远]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20231015_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月15日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;思想是时代的航标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“&#39;一带一路&#39;建设根植于历史，但面向未来”；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“&#39;一带一路&#39;建设是伟大的事业，需要伟大的实践”；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“&#39;一带一路&#39;建设秉持的是共商、共建、共享原则，不是封闭的，而是开放包容的”……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2013年秋，习近平总书记提出共建“丝绸之路经济带”和“21世纪海上丝绸之路”。从提出共建“一带一路”倡议和“五通”设想，到通过相关规划、确立共商共建共享原则；从三次召开相关座谈会，到两次举办“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛；从党的十九大报告提出“要以&#39;一带一路&#39;建设为重点”“形成陆海内外联动、东西双向互济的开放格局”，到党的二十大报告提出“推动共建&#39;一带一路&#39;高质量发展”……在习近平总书记的亲自谋划、亲自部署、亲自推动下，中国秉持共商共建共享原则，坚持开放、绿色、廉洁理念，努力实现高标准、可持续、惠民生目标，共建“一带一路”取得丰硕成果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十年来，我国已与150多个国家、30多个国际组织签署了200多份共建“一带一路”合作文件，形成3000多个合作项目，拉动近万亿美元投资规模，打造了一个个“国家地标”“民生工程”“合作丰碑”，为共建国家发展注入强劲动力，成为最受欢迎的国际公共产品和最大规模的国际合作平台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十年来，习近平总书记关于共建“一带一路”的重要论述，不断丰富发展共建“一带一路”倡议的深刻内涵，强调坚持以和平合作、开放包容、互学互鉴、互利共赢为核心的丝路精神，将“一带一路”建成和平之路、繁荣之路、开放之路、绿色之路、创新之路、文明之路，推动共建“一带一路”走深走实、行稳致远。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; “共商&#39;一带一路&#39;建设，是历史潮流的沿续，也是面向未来的正确抉择”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023年9月23日，钱塘江畔的杭州奥体中心体育场内“万涓成水，奔涌成潮”，第三次在中国举办的亚运会盛大开幕，诗画浙江迎来又一个历史性时刻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在杭州亚运会开幕前，习近平总书记同多位国际贵宾进行会见，真挚的话语让中国的老友新朋十分感动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会见中，习近平总书记和贵宾们多次提到同一个词：“一带一路”——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“双方要继续推进共建&#39;一带一路&#39;，深化产业振兴、基础设施建设、粮食自主、民生改善四大重点领域合作”；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中尼共建&#39;一带一路&#39;合作不断取得积极成果，跨喜马拉雅立体互联互通网络初具规模”……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共建“一带一路”这一重大倡议，走过了10年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记曾经说：“历史，总是在一些特殊年份给人们以汲取智慧、继续前行的力量。”2013年就是这样的年份。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那一年的9月7日，哈萨克斯坦阿斯塔纳瓜果飘香。习近平总书记在纳扎尔巴耶夫大学礼堂发表演讲，提出“丝绸之路经济带”重大倡议——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“为了使我们欧亚各国经济联系更加紧密、相互合作更加深入、发展空间更加广阔，我们可以用创新的合作模式，共同建设&#39;丝绸之路经济带&#39;。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2013年10月3日，印度尼西亚雅加达椰树芃芃。习近平总书记在印度尼西亚国会的演讲中阐述了“21世纪海上丝绸之路”构想——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“东南亚地区自古以来就是&#39;海上丝绸之路&#39;的重要枢纽，中国愿同东盟国家加强海上合作，使用好中国政府设立的中国—东盟海上合作基金，发展好海洋合作伙伴关系，共同建设21世纪&#39;海上丝绸之路&#39;。”&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以路为轴，以地为纸，合作为笔，政策沟通、设施联通、贸易畅通、资金融通、民心相通，一幅友好合作的壮美画卷跃然纸上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为什么中国提出共建“一带一路”重大倡议？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2017年5月14日，习近平总书记在“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛开幕式上的演讲中给出答案：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“从历史维度看，人类社会正处在一个大发展大变革大调整时代。世界多极化、经济全球化、社会信息化、文化多样化深入发展，和平发展的大势日益强劲，变革创新的步伐持续向前。各国之间的联系从来没有像今天这样紧密，世界人民对美好生活的向往从来没有像今天这样强烈，人类战胜困难的手段从来没有像今天这样丰富。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“从现实维度看，我们正处在一个挑战频发的世界。世界经济增长需要新动力，发展需要更加普惠平衡，贫富差距鸿沟有待弥合。地区热点持续动荡，恐怖主义蔓延肆虐。和平赤字、发展赤字、治理赤字，是摆在全人类面前的严峻挑战。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;放眼全球，世界之变、时代之变、历史之变正以前所未有的方式展开。世界进入新的动荡变革期，人类又一次站在历史的十字路口。在这一重大历史关头，习近平总书记高瞻远瞩，提出共建“一带一路”重大倡议，以中国方案求解全球发展难题，推动世界各国携手同行康庄大道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如何理解共建“一带一路”这一重大倡议？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记给出了这样的深刻阐释：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——传承。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“历史上，陆上丝绸之路和海上丝绸之路就是我国同中亚、东南亚、南亚、西亚、东非、欧洲经贸和文化交流的大通道，&#39;一带一路&#39;倡议是对古丝绸之路的传承和提升，获得了广泛认同。”2014年11月4日，习近平总书记在中央财经领导小组第八次会议上指出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“古丝绸之路绵亘万里，延续千年，积淀了以和平合作、开放包容、互学互鉴、互利共赢为核心的丝路精神。这是人类文明的宝贵遗产。”“历史是最好的老师。这段历史表明，无论相隔多远，只要我们勇敢迈出第一步，坚持相向而行，就能走出一条相遇相知、共同发展之路，走向幸福安宁和谐美好的远方。”2017年5月14日，习近平总书记在“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛开幕式上的演讲中强调。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“今天，我们传承古丝绸之路精神，共商&#39;一带一路&#39;建设，是历史潮流的沿续，也是面向未来的正确抉择。”2017年5月14日，习近平总书记在“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛欢迎宴会上的祝酒辞中指出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我提出共建&#39;一带一路&#39;倡议，旨在传承丝绸之路精神，携手打造开放合作平台，为各国合作发展提供新动力。”2021年6月23日，习近平总书记在向“一带一路”亚太区域国际合作高级别会议发表书面致辞时指出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——开放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“建设丝绸之路经济带、二十一世纪海上丝绸之路，是党中央统揽政治、外交、经济社会发展全局作出的重大战略决策，是实施新一轮扩大开放的重要举措，也是营造有利周边环境的重要举措。形象地说，这&#39;一带一路&#39;，就是要再为我们这只大鹏插上两只翅膀，建设好了，大鹏就可以飞得更高更远。这也是我们对国际社会的一个承诺，一定要办好。”2013年12月10日，习近平总书记在中央经济工作会议上强调。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国希望以&#39;一带一路&#39;为双翼，同南亚国家一道实现腾飞。”2014年9月18日，习近平总书记在印度世界事务委员会的演讲中指出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——共赢。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“随着综合国力上升，中国有能力、有意愿向亚太和全球提供更多公共产品，特别是为促进区域合作深入发展提出新倡议新设想。中国愿意同各国一道推进&#39;一带一路&#39;建设，更加深入参与区域合作进程，为亚太互联互通、发展繁荣作出新贡献。”2014年11月9日，习近平总书记在亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会开幕式上的演讲中指出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们将本着开放包容精神，同愿意参与的各相关方共同努力，把&#39;一带一路&#39;建成&#39;减贫之路&#39;、&#39;增长之路&#39;，为人类走向共同繁荣作出积极贡献。”2021年4月20日，习近平总书记在博鳌亚洲论坛2021年年会开幕式上的视频主旨演讲中指出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中方提出建设丝绸之路经济带倡议，秉承共同发展、共同繁荣的理念，联动亚欧两大市场，赋予古丝绸之路新的时代内涵”。2014年3月29日，习近平总书记在参观德国杜伊斯堡港时指出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国人民正在努力实现中华民族伟大复兴的中国梦。中国梦是和平、发展、合作、共赢的梦，我们追求中国人民的福祉，也追求各国人民共同的福祉。”2015年4月19日，习近平总书记在巴基斯坦《战斗报》和《每日新闻报》同时发表的题为《中巴人民友谊万岁》的署名文章中指出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;万物得其本者生，百事得其道者成。“共建&#39;一带一路&#39;，顺应经济全球化的历史潮流，顺应全球治理体系变革的时代要求，顺应各国人民过上更好日子的强烈愿望。”2019年4月26日，习近平总书记在第二届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛开幕式上的主旨演讲中指出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们既要登高望远，又要脚踏实地。”十年来，共建“一带一路”从顶层设计到项目落实，从规划方案到具体实践，从“大写意”到“工笔画”，这条造福世界的幸福之路越走越宽广。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; “这条路不是某一方的私家小路，而是大家携手前进的阳光大道”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;云南磨憨，一个从前默默无闻的口岸如今愈发热闹了起来。中老铁路开通运营以来，昆明到老挝首都万象10小时可通达，泰国水果进入中国的时间也大大缩减至不到15小时。截至今年8月31日，中老铁路全线累计完成货运量2522万吨，运输网已辐射至13个国家和地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021年12月3日，习近平总书记通过视频连线出席中老铁路通车仪式时强调：“双方要再接再厉、善作善成，把铁路维护好、运营好，把沿线开发好、建设好，打造黄金线路，造福两国民众。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大道不孤，众行致远。十年来，习近平总书记统筹国内国际两个大局，深刻观察和思考世界形势，在国际国内多个重要场合对“一带一路”建设进行阐述，寻找利益汇合点、政策理念共鸣点、互补合作契合点，为共建“一带一路”倡议寻求最大公约数，彰显大国智慧与气度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2014年，通过《丝绸之路经济带和21世纪海上丝绸之路建设战略规划》；2015年，发布《推动共建丝绸之路经济带和21世纪海上丝绸之路的愿景与行动》；推动成立丝路基金、亚洲基础设施投资银行等金融平台；中国国际进口博览会、中国国际服务贸易交易会、中国进出口商品交易会，国际宾客接踵而至……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2015年3月，海南博鳌，海阔帆舞。在博鳌亚洲论坛2015年年会上的主旨演讲中，习近平总书记强调：“我们要把握世界大势，跟上时代潮流，共同营造对亚洲、对世界都更为有利的地区秩序，通过迈向亚洲命运共同体，推动建设人类命运共同体。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十年来，从北京出发，跨越高山和大海，习近平总书记的足迹遍及五大洲，频密的外交日程，标注了中国与世界关系的崭新坐标——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“&#39;一带一路&#39;是开放的，是穿越非洲、环连亚欧的广阔&#39;朋友圈&#39;，所有感兴趣的国家都可以添加进入&#39;朋友圈&#39;。&#39;一带一路&#39;是多元的，涵盖各个合作领域，合作形式也可以多种多样。&#39;一带一路&#39;是共赢的，各国共同参与，遵循共商共建共享原则，实现共同发展繁荣。这条路不是某一方的私家小路，而是大家携手前进的阳光大道。”2015年10月21日，习近平总书记在英国伦敦中英工商峰会上的致辞中指出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国的发展得益于国际社会，也愿为国际社会提供更多公共产品。”2016年9月3日，在二十国集团工商峰会开幕式上的主旨演讲中，习近平总书记这样介绍共建“一带一路”倡议的初衷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国愿在和平共处五项原则基础上，发展同所有&#39;一带一路&#39;建设参与国的友好合作。中国愿同世界各国分享发展经验，但不会干涉他国内政，不会输出社会制度和发展模式，更不会强加于人。我们推进&#39;一带一路&#39;建设不会重复地缘博弈的老套路，而将开创合作共赢的新模式；不会形成破坏稳定的小集团，而将建设和谐共存的大家庭。”2017年5月14日，习近平总书记在“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛开幕式上的演讲中指出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们要秉持共商共建共享原则，倡导多边主义，大家的事大家商量着办，推动各方各施所长、各尽所能，通过双边合作、三方合作、多边合作等各种形式，把大家的优势和潜能充分发挥出来，聚沙成塔、积水成渊。”2019年4月26日，习近平总书记在第二届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛开幕式上的主旨演讲中指出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国倡议的&#39;一带一路&#39;不是口号和传说，而是成功的实践和精彩的现实。”2019年11月11日，习近平总书记在参观中远海运比雷埃夫斯港项目时说的一句话，令人回味。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;得益于共建“一带一路”，塞尔维亚斯梅代雷沃钢厂重现活力，马尔代夫有了历史上第一座跨海大桥，乌兹别克斯坦白内障患者重获光明，塞内加尔干旱地区村民饮水更安心……一个个美好的故事，见证着基础设施的“硬联通”、规则标准的“软联通”、温暖人心的“心联通”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十年来，习近平总书记高屋建瓴、领航定向，指导全国各地在共建“一带一路”大格局中找准定位、发挥更大作用——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2016年8月17日，习近平总书记在推进“一带一路”建设工作座谈会上强调：“总结经验、坚定信心、扎实推进，聚焦政策沟通、设施联通、贸易畅通、资金融通、民心相通，聚焦构建互利合作网络、新型合作模式、多元合作平台，聚焦携手打造绿色丝绸之路、健康丝绸之路、智力丝绸之路、和平丝绸之路，以钉钉子精神抓下去，一步一步把&#39;一带一路&#39;建设推向前进”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;经过夯基垒台、立柱架梁，共建“一带一路”不断落地生根、持久发展。2018年8月27日，习近平总书记在推进“一带一路”建设工作5周年座谈会上指出：“我们要百尺竿头、更进一步，在保持健康良性发展势头的基础上，推动共建&#39;一带一路&#39;向高质量发展转变，这是下一阶段推进共建&#39;一带一路&#39;工作的基本要求。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021年11月19日，习近平总书记出席第三次“一带一路”建设座谈会，全面总结共建“一带一路”取得的显著成就，科学分析共建“一带一路”面临的新形势，对继续推动共建“一带一路”高质量发展提出明确要求：“完整、准确、全面贯彻新发展理念，以高标准、可持续、惠民生为目标，巩固互联互通合作基础，拓展国际合作新空间，扎牢风险防控网络，努力实现更高合作水平、更高投入效益、更高供给质量、更高发展韧性，推动共建&#39;一带一路&#39;高质量发展不断取得新成效。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;铿锵话语掷地有声。在习近平总书记关于共建“一带一路”的重要论述指引下，共建“一带一路”沿着高质量发展方向不断前行。“事实证明，共建&#39;一带一路&#39;不仅为世界各国发展提供了新机遇，也为中国开放发展开辟了新天地。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十年来，我国与共建国家贸易和投资规模稳步扩大，基础设施互联互通不断加强，产业链供应链合作水平持续提升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界银行研究报告预计，到2030年，共建“一带一路”将使参与国贸易增长2.8%至9.7%，全球贸易增长1.7%至6.2%，全球收入增长0.7%至2.9%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; “共建&#39;一带一路&#39;是一项长期工程，是合作伙伴们共同的事业”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021年11月19日，在第三次“一带一路”建设座谈会上，习近平总书记回忆起20多年前的一件往事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在福建工作期间，习近平同志接待了来访的巴布亚新几内亚东高地省省长拉法纳玛。“我向他介绍了菌草技术，这位省长一听很感兴趣。我就派《山海情》里的那个林占熺去了。”由此书写了“小小一株草，情接万里长”的佳话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如今，这个技术已经在100多个国家落地生根，为当地创造了数十万个就业机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一项伟大的事业，之所以在世界各地蓬勃发展，关键在于合民愿、惠民生、聚民心。举世瞩目的“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛，之所以越办越好，是因为它深入人心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2017年和2019年，中国先后举办了两届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛。习近平总书记在会见外国政要时提到此事：“我们本来没有定要举行第二届论坛，看来还&#39;收不住&#39;，将来还会继续举办，这也说明&#39;一带一路&#39;日益深入人心。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022年11月，习近平总书记在出席亚太经合组织领导人非正式会议期间正式宣布，明年中方将考虑举行第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023年7月4日，习近平总书记在上海合作组织成员国元首理事会第二十三次会议上的讲话中表示：“今年是我提出&#39;一带一路&#39;倡议10周年，中方将举办第三届&#39;一带一路&#39;国际合作高峰论坛，欢迎各方参加论坛活动，共同把这条造福世界的幸福之路铺得更宽更远。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到目前为止，来自140多个国家、30多个国际组织的代表已确认与会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共建“一带一路”的旺盛人气，来自于它的开放与包容。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2017年5月15日，习近平总书记在“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛圆桌峰会上的开幕辞中指出：“&#39;一带一路&#39;建设跨越不同地域、不同发展阶段、不同文明，是一个开放包容的合作平台，是各方共同打造的全球公共产品。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2019年4月26日，习近平总书记在第二届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛开幕式上的主旨演讲中表示：“从亚欧大陆到非洲、美洲、大洋洲，共建&#39;一带一路&#39;为世界经济增长开辟了新空间，为国际贸易和投资搭建了新平台，为完善全球经济治理拓展了新实践，为增进各国民生福祉作出了新贡献，成为共同的机遇之路、繁荣之路。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2019年4月27日，习近平总书记在第二届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛记者会上的讲话中指出：“共建&#39;一带一路&#39;倡议源于中国，机会和成果属于世界。共建&#39;一带一路&#39;是一项长期工程，是合作伙伴们共同的事业。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“世界上的事情越来越需要各国共同商量着办”“国际上的事情由各国商量着办”……“商量着办”的中国方式，深深镌刻在中国与世界频繁互动的轨道上，鲜明地映照在共建“一带一路”的进程中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十年来，共建“一带一路”为世界发展带来新机遇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年8月21日至24日，习近平总书记出席金砖国家领导人第十五次会晤并对南非进行国事访问期间，中国与南非签署了《中南关于同意深化“一带一路”合作的意向书》。习近平总书记明确表示：“中方将扩大进口南非产品，鼓励更多中国企业赴南非投资兴业。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中南应急电力合作、新能源电力投资合作、电网升级改造合作……每个项目都着眼于南非燃眉之急。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十年来，共建“一带一路”为中国发展注入新活力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022年7月，习近平总书记在新疆考察时指出：“共建&#39;一带一路&#39;倡议提出这些年来，硕果累累。随着共建&#39;一带一路&#39;深入推进，新疆不再是边远地带，而是一个核心区、一个枢纽地带，你们做的是具有历史意义的事情，已经取得很好的成绩，再接再厉，前途光明。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如今的新疆霍尔果斯铁路口岸，中欧（中亚）班列经此通行，满载着“中国制造”源源不断走向中亚、欧洲市场。千年前的古丝路要冲，成为共建“一带一路”重要枢纽。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十年来，共建“一带一路”为构建人类命运共同体搭建新平台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与共建“一带一路”国家打造“健康丝绸之路”，为抗击疫情凝聚合力；深化农业、卫生、减灾、水资源等领域合作，同联合国在发展领域加强合作，努力缩小发展差距；制定《“一带一路”绿色投资原则》，实施“一带一路”应对气候变化南南合作计划……共建“一带一路”不仅是经济合作，而且是完善全球发展模式和全球治理、推进经济全球化健康发展的重要途径。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们将建设更紧密的卫生合作伙伴关系”“我们将建设更紧密的互联互通伙伴关系”“我们将建设更紧密的绿色发展伙伴关系”“我们将建设更紧密的开放包容伙伴关系”……2021年4月20日，在博鳌亚洲论坛2021年年会开幕式上，习近平总书记的精彩演讲，描绘出人类命运共同体的未来图景。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;岁月不居，时节如流。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当前，全球经济复苏乏力，地缘政治冲突仍在持续，不确定不稳定因素增多。关键时刻，中国以身作则，展现大国担当，给世界注入更多信心和力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1月31日，习近平总书记在二十届中共中央政治局第二次集体学习时指出：“推动共建&#39;一带一路&#39;高质量发展，积极参与国际经贸规则谈判，推动形成开放、多元、稳定的世界经济秩序，为实现国内国际两个市场两种资源联动循环创造条件。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4月6日，习近平总书记在出席中法企业家委员会第五次会议闭幕式时指出：“我提出构建人类命运共同体倡议、共建&#39;一带一路&#39;倡议、全球发展倡议、全球安全倡议、全球文明倡议，就是希望让团结代替分裂、合作代替对抗、包容代替排他，共同建设持久和平、普遍安全、共同繁荣、开放包容、清洁美丽的世界。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5月17日，习近平总书记在听取陕西省委和省政府工作汇报时强调：“更加主动融入和服务构建新发展格局，更加深度融入共建&#39;一带一路&#39;大格局，在扩大对内对外开放中强动力、增活力，打开发展新天地。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;5月19日，习近平总书记在中国—中亚峰会上发表主旨讲话强调：“我们要继续在共建&#39;一带一路&#39;合作方面走在前列，推动落实全球发展倡议，充分释放经贸、产能、能源、交通等传统合作潜力，打造金融、农业、减贫、绿色低碳、医疗卫生、数字创新等新增长点，携手建设一个合作共赢、相互成就的共同体。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7月4日，习近平总书记在上海合作组织成员国元首理事会第二十三次会议上发表重要讲话指出：“我们要加强高质量共建&#39;一带一路&#39;同各国发展战略和地区合作倡议对接，深入推进贸易和投资自由化便利化，加快口岸基础设施和区域国际物流大通道建设，保障区域产业链供应链稳定畅通。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一带一路”，这条承载着人类对文明交流的渴望、对和平安宁的期盼、对共同发展的追求、对美好生活的向往的阳光大道，越走越宽广，越走越深入人心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十年扬帆再起航。中国将在习近平总书记关于共建“一带一路”的重要论述指引下，以举办第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛为契机，同国际社会一道总结经验、开辟未来，推动高质量共建“一带一路”持续向前发展，共同把这条造福世界的幸福之路铺得更宽更远，书写国家互利共赢、人民相知相亲、文明互学互鉴的丝路新篇。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 推动构建人类命运共同体的重要实践平台]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20231015_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月15日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;“长安复携手，再顾重千金。”今年5月，首届中国—中亚峰会在古丝绸之路的东方起点陕西西安举行。习近平总书记强调，“要继续在共建&#39;一带一路&#39;合作方面走在前列”“携手建设一个合作共赢、相互成就的共同体”。自2013年提出共建“丝绸之路经济带”倡议以来，中国同中亚国家携手推动丝绸之路全面复兴，倾力打造面向未来的深度合作，将双方关系带入一个崭新时代。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;千载流泽生生不息，丝路精神薪火相传。习近平总书记强调：“我提倡共建&#39;一带一路&#39;和构建人类命运共同体，就是要促进不同文明的交流互鉴和各国之间的互利合作，建设一个持久和平、普遍安全、共同繁荣、开放包容、清洁美丽的世界。”10年来，从亚欧大陆到非洲、美洲、大洋洲，共建“一带一路”坚持以共商共建共享为原则，以和平合作、开放包容、互学互鉴、互利共赢的丝路精神为指引，以打造利益共同体、责任共同体、命运共同体为合作目标，启动了大批务实合作、造福民众的项目，构建起全方位、复合型的互联互通伙伴关系，开创了共同发展的新前景。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共建“一带一路”，关键是互联互通。坚持把基础设施“硬联通”作为重要方向，把规则标准“软联通”作为重要支撑，把同共建国家人民“心联通”作为重要基础，共建“一带一路”架起了各国合作共赢的重要桥梁。深化政策沟通，推动同有关国家协调政策，共建“一带一路”与俄罗斯欧亚经济联盟建设、哈萨克斯坦“光明之路”新经济政策、南非“经济重建和复苏计划”、沙特“2030愿景”等多国战略实现对接；加强设施联通，基本形成“陆海天网”四位一体的互联互通格局，成功建设了中欧班列、西部陆海新通道、中老铁路等一批标志性项目；提升贸易畅通，大力推动贸易和投资便利化，2022年中国与共建国家进出口总额近2.9万亿美元；扩大资金融通，健全多元化投融资体系，亚洲基础设施投资银行成员从创立时的57个增长到目前的106个，丝路基金项目遍及60多个国家和地区；促进民心相通，各类丝绸之路文化年、艺术节、智库对话等人文合作项目精彩纷呈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;通过全方位互联互通，更好融入全球供应链、产业链、价值链，实现联动发展，共建“一带一路”为世界经济增长开辟了新空间，为国际贸易和投资搭建了新平台，为完善全球经济治理拓展了新实践，为增进各国民生福祉作出了新贡献。实践充分证明，共建“一带一路”顺应了全球治理体系变革的内在要求，彰显了同舟共济、权责共担的命运共同体意识，为完善全球治理体系变革提供了新思路新方案，是推动构建人类命运共同体的重要实践平台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;努力建设和平之路、繁荣之路、开放之路、绿色之路、创新之路、文明之路，共建“一带一路”开辟了建设更加美好世界的光明前景。正是因为锚定“和平是我们最大的共同利益，也是各国人民最大的共同期盼”，我们主张建设相互尊重、公平正义、合作共赢的新型国际关系，打造对话不对抗、结伴不结盟的伙伴关系；正是因为抓住“发展是解决一切问题的总钥匙”，我们聚焦发展这个根本性问题，释放各国发展潜力，实现经济大融合、发展大联动、成果大共享；正是因为笃定“开放带来进步，封闭导致落后”，我们坚持普惠共赢，打造开放型合作平台，推动形成开放型世界经济；正是因为践行绿色发展理念，我们加强绿色基建、绿色能源、绿色金融等领域合作，让绿色切实成为共建“一带一路”的底色；正是因为把握创新这个推动发展的重要力量，我们坚持创新驱动发展，促进科技同产业、科技同金融深度融合，优化创新环境，集聚创新资源；正是因为坚持以文明交流超越文明隔阂、文明互鉴超越文明冲突、文明共存超越文明优越，我们积极架设不同文明互学互鉴的桥梁，形成多元互动的人文交流格局。事实充分表明，共建“一带一路”顺应了和平、发展、合作、共赢的时代潮流，正在成为我国参与全球开放合作、改善全球经济治理体系、促进全球共同发展繁荣、推动构建人类命运共同体的中国方案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当今世界是一荣俱荣、一损俱损的命运共同体，构建人类命运共同体是世界各国人民前途所在。始终站在历史正确一边、站在人类文明进步一边，弘扬和平、发展、公平、正义、民主、自由的全人类共同价值，通过高质量共建“一带一路”，携手推动构建人类命运共同体，推动落实全球发展倡议、全球安全倡议、全球文明倡议，就一定能够让和平的薪火代代相传，让发展的动力源源不断，让文明的光芒熠熠生辉，共同开创人类美好未来！&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[03版要闻 - 让共同发展繁荣之路越走越宽广]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20231015_1-03.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月15日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛将于10月17日至18日在北京举行。接受本报记者采访的海外华侨华人表示，10年来，共建“一带一路”取得实打实、沉甸甸的成就，成为深受欢迎的国际公共产品和国际合作平台。站在新的起点，相信高质量共建“一带一路”将不断推进，助力推动经济全球化朝着更加开放、包容、普惠、平衡、共赢的方向发展，让共同发展繁荣之路越走越宽广。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; “展现中国不断扩大开放的决心”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“本届高峰论坛是纪念共建&#39;一带一路&#39;倡议提出10周年的隆重活动，世界目光聚焦北京，各方将围绕高质量共建&#39;一带一路&#39;总结过去成就、展望未来发展。”古巴侨领郭昕江对本报记者表示，共建“一带一路”倡议提出10年来，中国始终坚持开放包容、合作共赢，倡导共商共建共享，合作成果造福共建国家人民。围绕“高质量共建&#39;一带一路&#39;，携手实现共同发展繁荣”这一主题，本届高峰论坛将进一步汇聚各方共识和力量，推动共建“一带一路”合作不断走深走实，让“一带一路”成为造福中国同共建国家的“发展带”、惠及人民的“幸福路”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“国际社会的积极响应彰显了共建&#39;一带一路&#39;倡议在国际合作中的重要作用，即将举行的第三届&#39;一带一路&#39;国际合作高峰论坛将展现中国不断扩大开放的决心。”泰国中华总商会主席林楚钦表示，共建“一带一路”倡议是中国的倡议，也是全球合作的机遇。目前，已有来自140多个国家、30多个国际组织的代表确认参会，充分表明国际社会对高质量共建“一带一路”充满信心和期待。以本届高峰论坛为契机，各方将进一步推动共建“一带一路”高质量发展，实现更广泛、更深入的区域合作，为全球经济复苏注入新的动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;肯尼亚华侨华人联合会暨中国和平统一促进会会长高玮表示，10年来，共建“一带一路”落地生根、开花结果，取得了丰硕的成果。本届高峰论坛将承前启后、擘画未来，进一步深化中国与共建国家的互利合作，顺应各国人民对美好生活的追求，推动各国实现共同发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; “积极融入共建&#39;一带一路&#39;大事业”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10年来，共建“一带一路”从谋篇布局的“大写意”到精耕细作的“工笔画”，为共建国家合作注入强劲动力的同时，也为海外华侨华人提供了更多发展机遇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿根廷蓝白律师事务所合伙人罗侨扬认为，在共建“一带一路”推动下，中阿基础设施建设等项目为阿根廷经济发展提供了重要支持。通过文化、教育和旅游等领域的合作，两国人民有机会更深入地了解彼此历史和文化。“阿根廷是距离中国最遥远的国家之一，但共建&#39;一带一路&#39;把中阿两国人民的心拉得更近了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;埃及中华总会会长王培中说，在共建“一带一路”框架下，埃及新行政首都中央商务区、中埃·泰达苏伊士经贸合作区等多个大型项目在埃及落地，成为埃及实现现代化和工业化的响亮名片。这些年，受益于中国与埃及之间的合作，来埃及寻找发展机遇的企业和个人越来越多。许多华侨华人熟悉两国国情，发挥自身优势，在两国经贸合作中获得了个人发展机遇。“中国的发展成果惠及更多国家，海外华侨华人也有了更多更好的发展机会。能够为共建&#39;一带一路&#39;贡献一份力量，我们深感自豪。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“近年来，共建&#39;一带一路&#39;倡议同阿联酋发展战略深度对接，中阿在能源基建、产能合作、工程承包、金融货币、生物医药等领域进行了全方位合作，取得了丰硕成果。”阿联酋华侨华人文化教育协会会长唐振刚表示，“我们一定把握机遇，积极融入共建&#39;一带一路&#39;大事业，为推动两国务实合作添砖加瓦。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“10年来，共建&#39;一带一路&#39;从理念转化为行动，从愿景转变为现实，受到国际社会广泛欢迎。”西班牙马德里官方商会亚太委员会主席陈胜利表示，共建“一带一路”跨越不同地域、不同文明、不同发展阶段，成为构建人类命运共同体的生动实践。“海外华侨华人是共建&#39;一带一路&#39;的见证者、参与者和受益者。未来我们将继续以自己的行动支持和推动共建&#39;一带一路&#39;，讲好精彩的中国故事。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“为实现各国共同发展增添新动力”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10年来的实践充分证明，共建“一带一路”顺潮流、惠民生、得民心、利天下，是各国共同走向现代化之路，也是人类通向美好未来的希望之路，具有强劲的韧性、旺盛的生命力和广阔的发展前景。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“展望未来，一个更加开放的中国将同世界形成更加良性的互动，促进中国和世界的共同发展和进步。”希腊中国和平统一促进会会长吴海龙表示，中国和希腊在海运、绿色能源等领域的合作具有巨大潜力，希望本届高峰论坛增进中希合作，更好惠及两国人民。文明交流互鉴已成为中希共建“一带一路”的重要组成部分，期待共建“一带一路”进一步促进共建国家之间的文化交流，让包容与合作的精神更加深入人心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“高铁、5G、互联网经济……我身边的阿尔及利亚朋友对中国的科技发展十分关注。”阿尔及利亚中华总商会会长庄振龙表示，中阿同意在共建“一带一路”倡议和“新阿尔及利亚”愿景框架下，加强各领域务实合作。中阿双边合作领域宽、前景广、潜力大，在巩固工程承包、贸易、医疗、教育、人文等合作的同时，未来可以积极拓展航空航天、信息技术、数字经济、新能源汽车等领域的合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“相信本届高峰论坛的举办，将有助于在更大范围、更深层次、更高水平上推进高质量共建&#39;一带一路&#39;。”林楚钦表示，“当今世界，各国迫切需要以对话弥合分歧、以团结反对分裂、以合作促进发展，共建&#39;一带一路&#39;的重要意义愈发凸显。”他认为，中国与共建国家不断推进高质量共建“一带一路”，“将为世界经济复苏和全球可持续发展发挥不可替代的积极作用，为实现各国共同发展增添新动力，为构建人类命运共同体作出新贡献”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（本报北京、墨西哥城、曼谷、内罗毕、布宜诺斯艾利斯、开罗、迪拜、马德里、罗马、阿尔及尔10月14日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;记者周輖、彭敏、章念生、黄炜鑫、许放、黄培昭、管克江、颜欢、谢亚宏、郝瑞敏）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[03版要闻 - 助力构建共商共建共享的全球治理格局（国际论坛·共享机遇、共谋发展的阳光大道）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20231015_2-03.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月15日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;国际社会对第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛充满期待。相信本届高峰论坛将取得丰硕成果，为更多国家实现可持续发展开辟合作空间，为推动构建更加公正合理的国际秩序注入更多正能量&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;在国际形势正发生深刻复杂变化的背景下，第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛的举办具有重要意义。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;当前，世界正处于关键转折点，国际格局发生重大变化。是任由少数西方国家将自身意志强加于国际社会其他成员，迫使其遵守西方制定的所谓“规则”，还是在多极化、相互平等、相互尊重的原则基础上建立一个更加公平、民主、包容的国际秩序？国际社会需要对此作出正确回答。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;共建“一带一路”倡议与习近平主席提出的全球发展倡议、全球安全倡议、全球文明倡议相辅相成，为推动建立更加公正合理的国际秩序指明了方向。当前，全球经济面临多重挑战，霸权主义、单边主义、保护主义横行。共建“一带一路”致力于帮助众多国家克服挑战、找到新的经济增长点，为实现更加包容普惠平衡的全球发展、推动构建共商共建共享的全球治理格局不断注入动力。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;共建“一带一路”致力于推动各国加强互联互通、实现共同发展，从不附加政治条件，从不谋求地缘政治私利，已成为深受欢迎的国际公共产品和国际合作平台。国际社会特别是全球南方国家积极支持、深入参与共建“一带一路”，不断收获发展机遇。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;共建“一带一路”对全球南方国家实现可持续发展至关重要。通过参与共建“一带一路”，各国积极在卫生、环保、数字经济、科技等重要领域开展合作，推动建设健康丝绸之路、绿色丝绸之路、数字丝绸之路、创新丝绸之路，努力开创合作共赢的美好未来。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;新时代中国取得了举世瞩目的发展成就，正以高质量发展全面推进中国式现代化。全球南方国家深受鼓舞，对同中国拓展合作、实现共同发展充满信心。在参与共建“一带一路”过程中，越来越多国家因地制宜地借鉴中国发展的成功经验。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;10年来，共建“一带一路”合作收获累累硕果。有关统计显示，共建“一带一路”达成3000多个合作项目，帮助共建国家近4000万人摆脱贫困。共建“一带一路”坚持经济全球化正确方向，有力推动贸易和投资自由化便利化，提升双多边合作水平，促进共建国家和地区经济联动融通。2013至2022年，中国同共建国家货物贸易额从1.04万亿美元增加至2.07万亿美元，年均增长8%。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;俄罗斯是共建“一带一路”的重要支持者和合作伙伴，欧亚经济联盟同共建“一带一路”倡议对接合作卓有成效。2022年，中国与欧亚经济联盟成员国贸易额超2000亿美元，同比增长30%，创历史新高。俄中两国在推动高质量共建“一带一路”方面具有广阔合作前景，相信两国将继续携手为推动欧亚地区发展、促进区域经济一体化作出更多贡献。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;某些西方国家试图抹黑共建“一带一路”，制造谣言、散播谬论，这种行径不会得逞。国际社会对共建“一带一路”高度认可，早已证明此类歪曲抹黑只是徒劳。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;国际社会对第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛充满期待。相信本届高峰论坛将取得丰硕成果，为更多国家实现可持续发展开辟合作空间，为推动构建更加公正合理的国际秩序注入更多正能量。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;（作者为俄罗斯前总理、俄罗斯战略研究所所长）&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 15 Oct 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>