<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平会见白俄罗斯总统卢卡申科]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-12/05/nw.D110000renmrb_20231205_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, December 05, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231205/1701720426768_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On December 4, President Xi Jinping was in Beijing Diaoyutai State Guesthouse met with Belarusian President Lukashenko. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Huang Jingwen&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, December 4&amp;nbsp ;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Sun Yi) On December 4, President Xi Jinping met with President Lukashenko of Belarus at the Diaoyutai State Guesthouse. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that at the end of February this year, Mr. President successfully paid a state visit to China, and we reached an important consensus on promoting the high-level development of China-Belarus relations. Over the past year, political mutual trust between the two countries has been further consolidated, and international cooperation has become closer. China has always viewed China-Belarus relations from a strategic and long-term perspective, firmly supports Belarus in taking a development path that is in line with its national conditions, and opposes external forces interfering in Belarus&#39; internal affairs. China is willing to continue to strengthen strategic coordination with Belarus, firmly support each other, promote practical cooperation, and continue to deepen China-Belarus relations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that ten years ago I proposed the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative, and now more than 150 countries have participated in cooperation. Not long ago, I proposed eight actions for China to support high-quality joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and welcome Belarus to continue to actively participate in it and obtain more tangible development opportunities. Both sides should implement projects such as the China-Belarus Industrial Park and promote China-Belarus industrial cooperation to achieve more results. Both sides should improve cross-border transportation facilitation and promote economic, trade and personnel exchanges. Regularly hold cultural day activities in each other&#39;s country, expand cooperation in education, health, sports and tourism, support the youth of the two countries in exchanges and cooperation, and enhance mutual understanding and friendship between the two peoples. China and Belarus are important forces participating in the reform and construction of the global governance system. China is willing to work with Belarus to strengthen coordination and cooperation within multilateral mechanisms such as the United Nations and the Shanghai Cooperation Organization, promote the implementation of global development initiatives, global security initiatives, and global civilization initiatives, and promote the building of a community with a shared future for mankind. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Lukashenko said that under the leadership of President Xi Jinping, China has made great achievements in development. More than 1.4 billion Chinese people live a happy life and have made important contributions to the world. President Xi Jinping’s successful experience in governing the country has benefited all parties and is worth learning from. Belarus sincerely hopes that China will continue to develop and become stronger, which will be conducive to the cause of peace and progress around the world. Belarus will unswervingly develop friendly relations with China and is willing to intensify high-level exchanges with China, firmly support each other, deepen mutually beneficial cooperation, strengthen international and multilateral strategic coordination, and promote greater development of the Belarus-China all-weather comprehensive strategic partnership. Belarus firmly believes that the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and other global initiatives proposed by President Xi Jinping are great undertakings that truly build consensus and cooperation in the international community, and will continue to actively participate in them. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The two heads of state also exchanged views on the Ukrainian crisis and other issues. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cai Qi and Wang Yi attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 坚定维护宪法权威和尊严推动宪法完善和发展 更好发挥宪法在治国理政中的重要作用]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-12/05/nw.D110000renmrb_20231205_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, December 05, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;■&amp;nbsp;The Constitution is the general charter for governing the country and ensuring national security. It is the fundamental legal basis for our party’s governance and administration. The highest legal norm for political and social life. Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the party has strengthened its overall leadership over constitutional work, enriched and developed socialist constitutional theory and practice with Chinese characteristics, and promoted the construction of our country&#39;s constitutional system and the implementation of the constitution to achieve historic achievements&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■ &amp;nbsp;On the new journey, we must firmly safeguard the authority and dignity of the Constitution, promote the improvement and development of the Constitution, better play the important role of the Constitution in governing the country, and provide a solid guarantee for comprehensively promoting the construction of a strong country and the great cause of national rejuvenation with Chinese-style modernization. We must strengthen our confidence in the political system, uphold the leadership position of the Communist Party of China as determined by the Constitution, and uphold the state system of the people&#39;s democratic dictatorship and the People&#39;s Congress system as determined by the Constitution. It is necessary to implement the socialist rule of law with Chinese characteristics in the new era, adhere to the comprehensive implementation of the provisions of the Constitution, the principles of the Constitution, and the spirit of the Constitution, adhere to the implementation of the Constitution, the interpretation of the Constitution, and the advancement of the system of constitutional supervision, accelerate the improvement of the socialist legal system with Chinese characteristics with the Constitution as the core, and continuously Improve the level of implementation and supervision of the Constitution. It is necessary to strengthen theoretical research and publicity and education on the Constitution, adhere to the popularization of knowledge, theoretical interpretation, and conceptual guidance, vigorously promote the spirit of the Constitution and the spirit of socialist rule of law in the whole society, and promote the implementation of the Constitution to become a conscious action of all people&lt;/P>;&lt;P &lt;P>; The General Charter for the Governance of the Country and Security of the State is the fundamental legal basis for our party’s governance of the country and the highest legal norm for national political and social life. Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the party has strengthened its overall leadership over constitutional work, enriched and developed socialist constitutional theory and practice with Chinese characteristics, and promoted the construction of my country&#39;s constitutional system and the implementation of the constitution to achieve historic achievements. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that on the new journey, we must firmly safeguard the authority and dignity of the Constitution, promote the improvement and development of the Constitution, better play the important role of the Constitution in governance, and comprehensively promote the construction of a strong country with Chinese-style modernization. , provide a solid guarantee for the great cause of national rejuvenation. We must strengthen our confidence in the political system, uphold the leadership position of the Communist Party of China as determined by the Constitution, and uphold the state system of the people&#39;s democratic dictatorship and the People&#39;s Congress system as determined by the Constitution. It is necessary to implement the socialist rule of law with Chinese characteristics in the new era, adhere to the comprehensive implementation of the provisions of the Constitution, the principles of the Constitution, and the spirit of the Constitution, adhere to the implementation of the Constitution, the interpretation of the Constitution, and the advancement of the system of constitutional supervision, accelerate the improvement of the socialist legal system with Chinese characteristics with the Constitution as the core, and continuously Improve the level of implementation and supervision of the Constitution. It is necessary to strengthen theoretical research and publicity and education on the Constitution, persist in the popularization of knowledge, theoretical interpretation, and conceptual guidance, vigorously promote the spirit of the Constitution and the spirit of socialist rule of law throughout society, and promote the implementation of the Constitution as a conscious action of all people. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;On the 4th, the General Office of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, together with the Central Propaganda Department and the Ministry of Justice, held a symposium in Beijing on &quot;Carrying forward the spirit of the Constitution, strengthening the implementation of the Constitution, and providing constitutional guarantees for building a strong country and national rejuvenation.&quot; Important instructions from Xi Jinping were conveyed at the meeting. Zhao Leji, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Chairman of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, attended the symposium and delivered a speech. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In his speech, Zhao Leji emphasized that we must adhere to the guidance of Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, study and implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions, comprehensively promote the implementation of the Constitution and publicity and education, and give full play to the power of the country’s fundamental law. Advantages and effectiveness. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Zhao Leji pointed out that since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping has issued a series of important speeches and articles on the Constitution and its implementation, and made a series of important instructions, which have enriched and developed the theory of socialist constitution with Chinese characteristics. It provides fundamental compliance and action guidelines for writing a new chapter in China&#39;s constitutional practice in the new era. We must deeply understand that upholding the leadership of the Communist Party of China is the most prominent feature and most fundamental requirement of our country’s Constitution, deeply understand the decisive significance of the “two establishments”, achieve “two maintenances”, and ensure the comprehensive, systematic and overall implementation of the party’s leadership to the entire process of all aspects of the party and state’s undertakings. We must deeply understand that our country&#39;s Constitution is a constitution with a distinct socialist nature and a people&#39;s constitution in the true sense, firmly grasp the essential requirements of Chinese-style modernization, use the Constitution to build consensus and gather the strength of unity and struggle. We must deeply understand that our country&#39;s Constitution has the supreme legal status and strong legal power. The comprehensive implementation of the Constitution is the primary task of comprehensively governing the country according to law, and comprehensively building a modern socialist country on the track of the rule of law. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Zhao Leji emphasized that on the new journey, we must thoroughly study and implement the theory of the socialist constitution with Chinese characteristics and continue to deepen the comprehensive implementation of the constitution. It is necessary to improve the socialist legal system with Chinese characteristics, improve the implementation mechanism of relevant provisions of the Constitution, improve the constitutional supervision system, and ensure the implementation of the Constitution with a scientific, effective, systematic and complete system. It is necessary to tell the story of the Chinese Constitution well, carry forward the spirit of the Constitution, strengthen theoretical research on the Constitution, and make all people loyal advocates, conscious adherents, and staunch defenders of the Constitution. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Li Hongzhong, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and vice chairman of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, chaired the symposium. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Relevant responsible comrades from the Central Propaganda Department, the Constitution and Law Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, the Ministry of Justice, the Supreme People&#39;s Court, the Supreme People&#39;s Procuratorate, the Ministry of Education, the China Law Society and representatives of the National People&#39;s Congress spoke at the symposium. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xiao Jie, Hao Mingjin and Zhang Qingwei attended the symposium. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Responsible comrades of the special committees of the National People&#39;s Congress and the Working Committee of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, responsible comrades of relevant departments of the central and state agencies, and experts and scholars from some universities and scientific research institutes in Beijing attended the symposium. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平向“2023从都国际论坛”致贺信]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-12/05/nw.D110000renmrb_20231205_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, December 05, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, December 4th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;On December 4th, President Xi Jinping addressed the &quot;2023 Capital International Forum&quot; sent a congratulatory letter. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that since its establishment, the Congdu International Forum has brought together people of insight from all over the world to conduct in-depth discussions on many issues affecting world peace and stability, sustainable economic development, and cultural exchanges and mutual learning, in order to promote international cooperation and It has played a positive role in enhancing people-to-people connectivity. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that in the face of unprecedented changes in the world, the times and history, human society must unite, adhere to mutual learning, openness and inclusiveness, win-win cooperation, and promote the common values ​​​​of all mankind. , and build a better world together. I hope that all guests will pool their wisdom, speak out and encourage the practice of true multilateralism, and contribute to building a community with a shared future for mankind. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The &quot;2023 Congdu International Forum&quot; opened in Guangzhou, Guangdong Province on the same day, with the theme of &quot;Multilateralism: More Exchanges, More Tolerance, More Cooperation&quot;, hosted by the Chinese People&#39;s Association for Friendship with Foreign Countries, Australia- Co-sponsored by the China Association for Friendship and Exchange, the People&#39;s Government of Guangdong Province and the World Leaders Alliance. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 推动宪法实施成为全体人民的自觉行动]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-12/05/nw.D110000renmrb_20231205_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, December 05, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;On the occasion of the 10th National Constitution Day, General Secretary Xi Jinping made important instructions, pointing out that “the Constitution is the foundation for governing the country and ensuring national security. The General Charter of the Constitution is the fundamental legal basis for our party&#39;s governance and the highest legal norm for national political and social life.&quot; It emphasizes that &quot;vigorously promote the spirit of the Constitution and the spirit of socialist rule of law in the whole society, and promote the implementation of the Constitution to become the consciousness of all people. action&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The constitution is fundamental, overall, stable and long-term. Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, our party has strengthened its overall leadership over constitutional work, enriched and developed socialist constitutional theory and practice with Chinese characteristics, and promoted the significant advantages of our country&#39;s constitutional system to be better transformed into national governance effectiveness. From improving the institutional arrangements for the Party to lead legislation, ensure law enforcement, support the judiciary, and take the lead in observing the law, to promote the institutionalization of the Party&#39;s leadership and the rule of law, from improving the socialist legal system with Chinese characteristics with the Constitution as the core, to strengthening constitutionality review , filing and review system and capacity building, from the establishment of National Constitution Day and the establishment of a system of constitutional oaths to the effective implementation of comprehensive governance rights over the Special Administrative Region in accordance with the Constitution and the Basic Law... All undertakings and work of the party and the country are fully integrated into the rule of law. , the role of the Constitution as the fundamental law of the country is fully brought into play, and the practice of the Constitution becomes richer and more vivid. The historic achievements in the construction of our country&#39;s constitutional system and the implementation of the Constitution are fundamentally due to the leadership and helm of General Secretary Xi Jinping and the scientific guidance of Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China drew up a grand blueprint for comprehensively building a modern socialist country and comprehensively promoting the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation with Chinese-style modernization. To meet high demands, we must better leverage the role of the rule of law in consolidating the foundation, stabilizing expectations, and benefiting the long-term, and comprehensively build a modern socialist country on the track of the rule of law. We must deeply understand that to safeguard the authority of the Constitution is to safeguard the authority of the common will of the Party and the people; to defend the dignity of the Constitution is to defend the dignity of the common will of the Party and the people; to ensure the implementation of the Constitution is to ensure the realization of the fundamental interests of the people. On the new journey, we must firmly safeguard the authority and dignity of the Constitution, promote the improvement and development of the Constitution, better play the important role of the Constitution in governing the country, and provide a solid guarantee for comprehensively promoting the construction of a strong country and the great cause of national rejuvenation with Chinese-style modernization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To persist in governing the country according to the law, we must first persist in governing the country in accordance with the constitution; to persist in governing in accordance with the law, we must first persist in governing in accordance with the constitution. To improve the Party&#39;s ability to govern the country and govern in accordance with the Constitution, the implementation of the Constitution must be implemented into all practices of coordinating and promoting the &quot;Five-in-One&quot; overall layout and coordinating the advancement of the &quot;Four Comprehensives&quot; strategic layout. , govern the party, the country, and the military in all fields and aspects, and comprehensively promote the rule of law in all aspects of the country&#39;s work. The socialist system with Chinese characteristics is the fundamental guarantee for the development and progress of contemporary China. We must strengthen our confidence in the political system, uphold the leadership position of the Communist Party of China as determined by the Constitution, and uphold the state system of the people&#39;s democratic dictatorship and the People&#39;s Congress system as determined by the Constitution. The life of the Constitution lies in its implementation, and the authority of the Constitution also lies in its implementation. It is necessary to thoroughly study and implement Xi Jinping&#39;s thought on the rule of law, adhere to the comprehensive implementation of the provisions of the Constitution, the principles of the Constitution, and the spirit of the Constitution, adhere to the implementation of the Constitution, the interpretation of the Constitution, and the advancement of the system of constitutional supervision, accelerate the improvement of the socialist legal system with Chinese characteristics with the Constitution as the core, and continuously improve the implementation of the Constitution and level of supervision. The foundation of the Constitution lies in the heartfelt support of the people, and the power of the Constitution lies in the sincere belief of the people. It is necessary to strengthen theoretical research and publicity and education on the Constitution, insist on comprehensive efforts in popularizing knowledge, theoretical interpretation, and conceptual guidance, deepen the educational functions of systems such as the Constitution Oath, National Constitution Day, and national symbols and symbols, and promote the normalization and long-term effectiveness of constitutional publicity and education. Make all people loyal advocates, conscious adherents and staunch defenders of the Constitution. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: &quot;The formulation and implementation of the Constitution is a symbol of the progress of human civilization and an important support for the modernization of human society.&quot; Forge ahead on a new journey, under the strong leadership of the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping at the core Next, by thoroughly studying and implementing Xi Jinping Thought on the Rule of Law and General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important expositions on the Constitution, carrying forward the spirit of the Constitution, strengthening the implementation of the Constitution, building the foundation of the rule of law, exercising the power of the rule of law, and accumulating the momentum of the rule of law, we will surely be able to compose the Chinese Constitution in the new era. Practice a new chapter. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 努力创造令世界刮目相看的新奇迹]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-12/05/nw.D110000renmrb_20231205_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, December 05, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;The Yangtze River is like a giant dragon flying towards the vast sea, and Shanghai is like a high-spirited dragon head, rising unstoppably and bravely into the sky forward. This is an image depiction of Shanghai’s geographical location and a vivid portrayal of its economic status. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In late November and early December, General Secretary Xi Jinping came to Shanghai for inspection. When he came this time, he pretended to further promote the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta, a grand strategy related to China&#39;s overall development; he pretended to speed up the construction of &quot;five centers&quot;, an important mission assigned to Shanghai by the Party Central Committee; he cared about the people&#39;s pursuit of a better future. The big things and small things in life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The General Secretary has been inspecting the Shanghai Futures Exchange, the Shanghai Science and Technology Innovation Achievements Exhibition, the Minhang District New Era City Builders and Managers’ Home, or presiding over a symposium on in-depth promotion of the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta. Yes, everything I read, asked, thought about, and talked about never left these topics. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The mission is like a torch&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Building Shanghai into the ‘Five Centers’ is a decision made by the Party Central Committee to comprehensively assess the domestic and international situation and coordinate the overall situation of reform and development. The major decision-making is an important mission entrusted to Shanghai by the Party Central Committee.&quot; General Secretary Xi Jinping is far-sighted. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From the 14th National Congress of the Communist Party of China in October 1992, it was proposed to build Shanghai into &quot;one leader and three centers&quot;, and later &quot;four centers&quot;, to General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s inspection in Shanghai in May 2014. At that time, the overall framework for the construction of the &quot;Five Centers&quot; was clearly proposed. At the end of 2017, the state clarified the functional positioning of Shanghai&#39;s &quot;Five Centers&quot;. In October 2023, the Standing Committee meeting of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee reviewed and approved the &quot;On Supporting Shanghai to Accelerate the &quot;Five Centers&quot; &quot;Opinions on Construction&quot;. The formation of this major decision has gone through a process of continuous expansion and deepening. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This process is also a process in which Shanghai continues to assume more, larger and heavier missions in the overall development of the country. Because of this, Comrade Xi Jinping pointed out when he was working in Shanghai: “We must place Shanghai’s future development in the central government’s strategic positioning of Shanghai’s development, in the general trend of economic globalization, and in the overall development pattern of the country. Think and plan within the country’s overall deployment of the Yangtze River Delta regional development.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Only with a broad vision can we have a big pattern, and with a big pattern can we achieve great achievements. The general secretary’s words fully demonstrated the high position and ambitious pursuit of the strategic plan for the construction of “five centers”. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the construction of Shanghai’s “Five Centers”, Pudong is the forefront. In March 2007, just one week into his tenure as Shanghai Municipal Party Committee Secretary, Comrade Xi Jinping launched a comprehensive survey of 19 districts and counties, and the first stop was Pudong. This time, General Secretary Xi Jinping visited Shanghai for inspection, and his first stop was Pudong. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The changes in Pudong have been earth-shaking. The &quot;Slush Crossing Road&quot; is gone, and what comes into view is the bustling business district, dense financial institutions, numerous R&amp;D buildings, and shuttles and ships... This place is like a strong pulsating heart, continuously transporting goods to all directions. With financial blood and development momentum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the Shanghai Futures Exchange, the General Secretary walked into the futures trading hall. The red and green data on the screen beat the &quot;Shanghai Price&quot; that guides the investment transactions of thousands of upstream and downstream companies. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the booth of listed deliverables, crude oil, paper pulp, rubber, copper, aluminum, nickel... This exchange is still a &quot;post-90s&quot;. It has only been established for more than 20 years, but it has achieved remarkable results and the scale of transactions It has been at the forefront of the world for many years and has become the third largest futures trading market in the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping’s eyes fell on rubber. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Domestic rubber resources were once very scarce, and there was a saying that &quot;a grain of rubber breeds a tael of gold&quot;. Today, my country has become one of the major rubber producing countries in the world, and the &quot;Shanghai Rubber&quot; global pricing center is accelerating. The General Secretary was quite emotional after hearing this: Behind every futures product there is an industry support, and the rapid development of the Shanghai Futures Exchange is inseparable from the growing national strength of China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The General Secretary has been concerned about the construction and development of Shanghai International Shipping Center for many years. Hearing that Container Shipping Index (European Line) futures were launched in August this year, becoming my country&#39;s first service-type and cash-delivered futures product, the General Secretary expressed his affirmation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The past is like a flood. General Secretary Xi Jinping’s thoughts go back to 16 years ago. He told everyone: &quot;When I was working in Shanghai, I took a day to visit several financial institutions, including the Shanghai Futures Exchange. At that time, futures were still in the exploratory stage, but now they have become important in Asia and internationally. We Therefore, we can see that Shanghai’s goal of building an international financial center is correct, the pace is steady, and the future is bright. We must continue to work hard.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The General Secretary always keeps scientific and technological innovation in mind. After leaving the Shanghai Futures Exchange, he came to Zhangjiang Science City to visit the Shanghai Science and Technology Innovation Achievements Exhibition. Blue Sky Dream, innovative drugs, smart manufacturing, future cars... it&#39;s dizzying and exciting. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping carefully inspected each booth and stopped in front of the intelligent robot. He watched with great interest as a robot &quot;showed off&quot; its flexible &quot;fingers&quot; and &quot;walked&quot; over with steady steps. &quot;What is the international level of this technology?&quot; &quot;From a practical point of view, has it been deployed?&quot; The questions were detailed and thoughtful. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After watching the exhibition, the General Secretary said with emotion: &quot;These scientific and technological innovation achievements achieved in Shanghai make me feel very at ease, with greater confidence and confidence.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;From importing even a single screw to a major country using heavy weapons to demonstrate its confidence, after decades of hard work, my country&#39;s science and technology industry has undergone historic, overall, and pattern changes. In the exhibition hall, representatives of scientific researchers from all walks of life gathered together. The general secretary said sincerely: &quot;Promoting Chinese-style modernization cannot be separated from the strategic support of science and technology, education, and talents. Shanghai must be a good leader in this regard and accelerate its progress towards a scientific and technological innovation center with global influence.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;From the &quot;two bombs and one satellite&quot; back then to today&#39;s scientific research field, we have achieved fruitful results and talented people have emerged from generation to generation. The General Secretary recalled the past: &quot;We must strive to cultivate a large number of cutting-edge talents with a sense of mission and create good conditions for them to display their talents.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Writing the glorious chapter of the &quot;Five Centers&quot; construction requires a pen of Lingyun. &quot;To give full play to the leading and exemplary role in promoting Chinese-style modernization&quot; is General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s new expectation for Shanghai, and it has also become the new functional positioning of Shanghai&#39;s &quot;five centers&quot;. With the acceleration of the construction of the &quot;Five Centers&quot;, Shanghai, the &quot;Pearl of the Orient&quot;, will surely shine even brighter. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The original intention is as solid as rock&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shanghai is the birthplace of our party. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Not long after the conclusion of the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping led members of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee to visit the site of the National Congress of the Communist Party of China in Shanghai and review the dream of our party. He meditated in front of the words &quot;The beginning is simple, the end is huge&quot;, sighed in front of a &quot;Current Situation Map&quot; in the late Qing Dynasty, and reviewed the oath of joining the party in front of the huge party flag. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A century of changes and changes. Times are changing, but the original intention remains the same. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past, Shanghai was plagued by the “big city disease” of dense buildings, dense population, crowded houses, narrow roads, and little greening. When he was working in Shanghai, Comrade Xi Jinping was worried about the housing difficulties of citizens. On weekends, he often goes to the old community to walk around, wander around, and think about how to solve the &quot;old and difficult&quot; problems. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the General Secretary first proposed the concept of &quot;people&#39;s cities built by the people and people&#39;s cities for the people&quot; in Shanghai. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This time, General Secretary Xi Jinping made a special trip to Minhang District, which has a high proportion of migrant population, to take a look at the Home of Urban Builders and Managers in the New Era. Shanghai has made steady and rapid progress in increasing the financing and construction of affordable rental housing. At present, the city has completed a total of 316,000 units (rooms), and it is getting closer and closer to the goal of raising 470,000 units (rooms) for new construction planned during the &quot;14th Five-Year Plan&quot; period. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The sun is warm. The general secretary walked into the rental community. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After graduating from university, Zheng Lanyu worked in Shanghai for more than two years and rented a two-bedroom apartment here. She and her mother enthusiastically welcomed the General Secretary into their new rented home. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Is the rent expensive?” “It’s not expensive, and it’s very comfortable to live in.” She opened the window to see the view, and the room was very warmly decorated. Zheng Lanyu smiled brightly, “Thank you to the party and the government for allowing me to live in Shanghai. We have a home.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The multi-level rental housing supply system of “one bed, one room, one suite” is allowing more “new Shanghainese” to realize their “dream of living in peace”. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The other building is a dormitory-type rental house. General Secretary Xi Jinping walked into a double room. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two caregivers from a nursing home live here. Desks, refrigerators, washing machines, induction cookers and other living facilities are all available. Tenant Qian Lili has been in Shanghai for more than ten years and was once worried about the difficulty and high price of renting a house. Today, she said happily: &quot;The rent here is cheap, the hot water in the bathroom is available 24 hours a day, and the commute to and from get off work only takes about ten minutes. We are very satisfied.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is a four-person room next door. The tenants are all security guards from nearby property companies. They opened up the conversation to the General Secretary: &quot;There are public kitchens, laundry rooms, bathrooms, and reception rooms here. There are badminton courts and basketball courts outside. It&#39;s great, great!&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Next step What are your plans?&quot; the general secretary asked kindly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Su Yuanbao from Linyi, Shandong said: &quot;If it develops further, I will take over my wife and children and rent a one-bedroom apartment here.&quot; Wu Tao from Suzhou, Anhui said: &quot;I want to get a certificate. Find a girlfriend and settle down here.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Okay! Take root, settle down, and develop.&quot; The general secretary said with a smile, &quot;You are also the builders and contributors of Shanghai, so Shanghai I also want to care about you.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When he was about to leave, the community residents gathered around him to say goodbye. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;When I was working in Shanghai, I came to Minhang for a day of investigation. This time I came to Minhang and saw that the whole look was completely new.&quot; General Secretary Xi Jinping said seriously, &quot;A city must not only have height, but also There must be warmth. Our socialism is to take the path of common prosperity. Migrant workers who come to Shanghai to contribute are also the masters of the city. We must practice the people&#39;s city concept and continuously meet the people&#39;s diverse and diversified needs for housing. , to ensure that foreign residents can come in, stay, live in peace, and become successful.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A city is a city for the people. The People&#39;s City is built by the people, and the People&#39;s City is for the people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The warmth of a city is accumulated in construction without abandoning the smallest details, and is protected by development day and night. Indoors and outdoors, Shanghai maneuvers in a compact space and strives to provide more public areas for the people. In this city, parks have accelerated their “growth”, increasing from 243 to 670 in 5 years. The general secretary profoundly pointed out: &quot;To build and govern a megacity like Shanghai well, we must have a big pattern and big ideas, as well as refined thinking and &#39;embroidery&#39; skills.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What the people want , the direction of politics. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the process of promoting Chinese-style modernization, General Secretary Xi Jinping has always looked towards the people: &quot;The core essence of building a socialist modern international metropolis with world influence is &#39;socialist modernization&#39;&quot;, Urban construction “must reflect the distinctive characteristics of socialist modernization and the essential attributes of a people’s city.” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The layout is like chess&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping has attached great importance to the Yangtze River Delta for a long time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When he was working in Zhejiang, he actively worked hard to promote the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta; when he was working in Shanghai, he took the initiative to shoulder the leading role; after working in the central government, he promoted the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta to the level of National strategy. Since then, the General Secretary presided over two symposiums with the theme of integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta in August 2020 and this time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the General Secretary’s personal planning and continuous promotion, the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta has achieved remarkable results. At this symposium, the development report cards presented by the participants provided persuasive annotations for the importance of promoting the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For many years, the GDP of the Yangtze River Delta region has accounted for the largest share of the country&#39;s total. The proportion remains at about 1/4, and the contribution rate to the national economic growth is about 30%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2022, the regional industrial added value accounts for 25.4% of the country; the service industry added value accounts for 25% of the country; the total import and export volume accounts for 35.8% of the country; and the actual amount of foreign capital utilized accounts for 40.1% of the country. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the first three quarters of 2023, the output value of high-tech manufacturing accounts for 31.1% of the country; the scale of integrated circuits, biomedicine, and artificial intelligence industries account for 60%, 1/3, and 1/3 of the country respectively. New energy vehicles The output accounts for about 2/5 of the country and 1/4 of the world; the major scientific and technological infrastructure under construction and has been built accounts for about 1/3 of the country; the number of national enterprise technology centers accounts for 26.4% of the country; the total foreign trade accounts for 36.7% of the country; port cargo and Container throughput accounts for about 40% of the country&#39;s total. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The density of high-speed rail is 4.3 times the national average, and the operating mileage accounts for 1/6 of the country. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The General Secretary likened the coordinated development of Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei, the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta, and the construction of the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area to the &quot;three major engines&quot; that lead my country&#39;s development ” Among them, the Yangtze River Delta is one of the regions with the most active economy, the highest degree of openness, and the strongest innovation ability in China. It is one of the most influential and driving growth poles and power sources in my country. “Promote the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta to achieve new and major breakthroughs, be at the forefront of Chinese-style modernization, and better play the role of pioneering, leading and demonstrating, and radiating and driving.” This is the Party Central Committee’s decision for the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta. new goal. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Three years have passed since the two symposiums, from &quot;solid advancement&quot; to &quot;deep advancement&quot;. Behind the difference in the names of the meetings is the requirement of the Party Central Committee to continue to deepen and upgrade this national strategy. How to catch? The general secretary gave the answer: &quot;Close to the two key words of integration and high quality.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For the new arrangements at the symposium, when looking at one area, we also look at the overall situation; we look at the present and plan for the long term. The general secretary proposed four overall plans and five major measures, which are like chess pieces and are far-reaching. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The four coordinations contain profound systemic concepts: &quot;Coordinating technological innovation and industrial innovation&quot;, &quot;Coordinating leading leaders and promoting each other&#39;s strengths&quot;, &quot;Coordinating hardware connectivity and mechanism coordination&quot;, &quot;Coordinating ecological environmental protection and economic development&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The five major measures reflect far-reaching strategic considerations: the Yangtze River Delta must &quot;strengthen cross-regional collaboration in technological innovation and industrial innovation&quot;, &quot;accelerate the improvement of integrated development systems and mechanisms&quot;, &quot;actively promote high-level collaborative opening&quot;, and &quot;strengthen ecological and environmental sharing.&quot; &quot;Protect joint governance&quot; and &quot;strive to improve security development capabilities.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In contrast, the overlapping use of these words, innovation, mechanism, collaboration, ecology, clearly indicates the next development direction, strategic measures and guidance of the Yangtze River Delta. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta is by no means just a formal combination, but a reshaping from the outside to the inside, a profound change. Shanghai, Jiangsu, Zhejiang, and Anhui have given full play to their comparative advantages in dislocated and coordinated development, learned from each other&#39;s strengths, and strengthened their overall strength. This is not simply addition, but multiplication. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking at innovation, the Yangtze River Delta has brought together many of the country’s most strategic technological forces. How to remove blockages, break through stuck points, and turn the reform and innovation of &quot;bold breakthrough, bold experimentation, and independent reform&quot; into regional vitality? The general secretary pointed out the direction: &quot;Build a closer regional innovation community and industrial development community.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking at opening up, we can gain the advantage of location and have the opportunity to open ports and develop cities. The Yangtze River Delta region has always been at the forefront of reform and opening up, with a vast horizon and a vast amount of traffic. The General Secretary emphasized: &quot;Promote high-level opening up with an emphasis on institutional opening up&quot; and &quot;strive to become a powerful engine that smoothes my country&#39;s economic cycle and a strategic hub that connects domestic and international dual cycles.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking at ecology, the Yangtze River Delta region is rich in industries, densely populated, and densely populated. The ecological space is relatively crowded and the resources and environment are under great pressure. At this symposium, based on the current situation, the General Secretary encouraged the three provinces and one city to strengthen the seamless connection of ecological protection red lines, strengthen regional policy coordination on energy conservation and emission reduction, improve the ecological compensation mechanism, build a regional green manufacturing system, and build a harmonious symbiosis between man and nature. play an exemplary role in modernization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The clearer the knowledge, the more earnest the action. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The General Secretary urged everyone: &quot;Promoting the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta is a big article. It requires a lot of effort and a long time. We must persist in making progress while maintaining stability, be down-to-earth, work hard, and take one responsibility after another. Work hard and move forward step by step.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;As long as you are sure that it is the right thing to do, you will do it consistently and unremittingly. You will never give up halfway, never go in the wrong direction, and never look back. Push forward for the long term. This is what major strategies such as triangular integrated development should do, move forward step by step, one item at a time.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Small steps can lead to a thousand miles. This symposium will lead the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta into a new stage of deepening and upgrading. Under the spotlight, three provinces and one city have begun a new struggle, performing a grand concerto of high-quality development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China and the world are looking forward to new miracles here. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.run&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 第二十四次中国—欧盟领导人会晤将在北京举行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-12/05/nw.D110000renmrb_20231205_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, December 05, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, December 4th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Foreign Ministry Spokesperson Hua Chunying announced on the 4th: Via CEIBS The two sides agreed that the 24th China-EU Leaders&#39; Meeting will be held in Beijing on December 7. President Xi Jinping will meet with European Council President Michel and European Commission President von der Leyen. Premier Li Qiang of the State Council will co-chair the meeting with Michel and von der Leyen. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 丁薛祥将与新加坡副总理兼财政部长黄循财共同主持召开中新双边合作机制会议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-12/05/nw.D110000renmrb_20231205_7-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, December 5, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, December 4th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Foreign Ministry Spokesperson Wang Wenbin announced on the 4th: In response to the political At the invitation of Ding Xuexiang, member of the Standing Committee of the State Council and Vice Premier of the State Council, Lawrence Wong, Deputy Prime Minister and Minister of Finance of the Republic of Singapore, will visit China from December 5th to 8th. Vice Prime Minister Ding Xuexiang will co-chair the 19th meeting of the China-Singapore Bilateral Cooperation Joint Committee, the 24th meeting of the China-Singapore Suzhou Industrial Park Joint Coordinating Council, and the China-Singapore Suzhou Industrial Park Joint Coordinating Council meeting with Vice Prime Minister Lawrence Wong in Tianjin on December 7. The 15th meeting of the Joint Coordinating Council of the New Tianjin Eco-City and the 7th meeting of the Joint Coordinating Council of the China-Singapore (Chongqing) Strategic Connectivity Demonstration Project. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 韩正出席“2023从都国际论坛”开幕式并致辞]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-12/05/nw.D110000renmrb_20231205_8-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, December 05, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Xinhua News Agency, Guangzhou, December 4th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Wen Xin, Lu Hao) Vice President Han Zheng attended the ceremony on the 4th Guangzhou attended the opening ceremony of the &quot;2023 Congdu International Forum&quot; and delivered a speech. The forum began with a congratulatory letter from President Xi Jinping. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Han Zheng said that President Xi Jinping has profoundly explained the essence of multilateralism and pointed out the direction for us to maintain and practice true multilateralism. Under the current circumstances, we need more than ever to adhere to the core values ​​and basic principles of multilateralism and practice the global governance concept of extensive consultation, joint contribution and shared benefits. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;First, we must coexist peacefully on the premise of seeking common ground while reserving differences, integrate and develop in the process of equal exchanges, and make common progress on the basis of mutual learning. Under the guidance of the concept of a community with a shared future for mankind, promote the implementation of the global development initiative, global security initiative, and global civilization initiative, and jointly build the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; with high quality. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Second, we must promote global governance in a more equitable and reasonable direction on the basis of consensus and inject more stability and positive energy into the world. Oppose hegemonism and power politics, and oppose unilateralism in the name of multilateralism. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Third, we must adhere to the correct direction of globalization, oppose protectionism and &quot;decoupling and disconnection&quot;, make the pie of mutually beneficial cooperation bigger, and inject more momentum into the recovery of the world economy. Adhere to dialogue and consultation, promote political settlement of hot issues, and jointly respond to risks and challenges. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Han Zheng emphasized that China is an advocate of multilateralism and a pragmatist, and is comprehensively promoting the construction of a powerful country and the great cause of national rejuvenation with Chinese-style modernization. We adhere to the path of peaceful development, adhere to high-quality development and high-level opening up, and are willing to join hands with other countries to create a better future for mankind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huang Kunming attended the opening ceremony. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The forum is co-sponsored by the Chinese People&#39;s Association for Friendship with Foreign Countries, Australia-China Friendship Association, Guangdong Provincial People&#39;s Government and World Leaders Alliance. Former political figures from more than 40 countries, heads of international organizations, foreign envoys to China, experts and scholars, etc. conducted in-depth discussions around the theme of &quot;Multilateralism: More Exchanges, More Tolerance, and More Cooperation&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 在推进中国式现代化中充分发挥龙头带动和示范引领作用]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-12/05/nw.D110000renmrb_20231205_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, December 05, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;From November 28th to December 2nd, General Secretary Xi Jinping inspected Shanghai and delivered an important speech. On December 3, on his way back to Beijing, General Secretary Xi Jinping inspected Yancheng, Jiangsu Province and delivered an important speech. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech aroused enthusiastic response among the cadres and the masses. Everyone said that we must conscientiously study, understand and thoroughly implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech, completely, accurately and comprehensively implement the new development concept, focus on promoting high-quality development, building a new development pattern, and focusing on building an international economic center, financial center, and trade center. The important mission of a shipping center and a scientific and technological innovation center is to take scientific and technological innovation as the guide, reform and opening up as the driving force, national major strategies as the traction, and urban governance modernization as the guarantee. We must be brave in pioneering and active actions to accelerate the construction of a world-influential city. A modern socialist international metropolis, it will give full play to its leading and exemplary role in promoting Chinese-style modernization. We should inherit and carry forward the spirit of not being afraid of difficulties and dangers, having the courage to fight and dare to win, and rely closely on the people to continuously push forward the great cause of building a strong country and national rejuvenation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Focus on accelerating the construction of &quot;five centers&quot; and continue to improve the city&#39;s energy level and core competitiveness&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out that accelerating the construction of &quot; &quot;Five Centers&quot; is an important mission assigned to Shanghai by the Party Central Committee. Shanghai should use this as its main direction to coordinate and guide all aspects of economic and social development, adhere to overall planning and coordinated advancement, make breakthroughs in key areas, and lead areas from point to point, so as to continue to improve the city&#39;s energy level and core competitiveness. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech inspired people and gathered strength.” Gu Jun, deputy secretary-general of the Shanghai Municipal Government and director of the Municipal Development and Reform Commission, said that the main direction of attack should be to speed up the construction of the “five centers” and focus on Pudong New Area&#39;s high-level reform and opening-up and other tasks require it to create a leading area for socialist modernization construction, and continue to improve the city&#39;s energy level and core competitiveness with greater intensity of reform, higher-level opening-up, and deeper innovation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cheng Peng, Secretary of the Party Committee for Economic Informatization of Shanghai Municipality, said: “We must thoroughly implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech, further promote new industrialization, focus on leading industries and future industries, and promote the transformation and upgrading of traditional industries. Accelerate the cultivation of world-class high-end industrial clusters, strive to build a modern industrial system, strive to build an industrial development community, and show new achievements in serving the Yangtze River Delta and the country.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tian, ​​Secretary of the Party Committee and Chairman of the Shanghai Futures Exchange Xiang Yang said that we must keep in mind General Secretary Xi Jinping’s instructions, accelerate the establishment of a world-class exchange, further improve the system of important commodity futures and options varieties, unswervingly promote high-level institutional opening of the futures market, and explore futures regulatory systems and business models with Chinese characteristics. Make greater contributions to building an international financial center. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“To thoroughly implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech, we must strengthen the construction of modern financial institutions and financial infrastructure, accelerate the improvement of financial regulation, markets, institutions, supervision, products and services, and infrastructure systems, and do Five major articles on good technology, green, inclusive, elderly care and digital finance will comprehensively enhance the competitiveness and influence of Shanghai International Financial Center.&quot; said Zhou Xiaoquan, deputy secretary of the Shanghai Financial Work Party Committee and director of the Municipal Local Financial Supervision Bureau. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secretary of the Party Committee of the Shanghai Academy of Social Sciences weighed in: “We must implement high-level financial opening-up, deeply implement the free trade pilot zone improvement strategy, promote the quality and upgrading of the international trade center, and accelerate the completion of high-end shipping services. We should better play the positive role of the national strategy in guiding Shanghai&#39;s high-quality development, and better play the role of Shanghai in radiating and driving the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Comprehensive and comprehensive from a higher starting point. Deepen reform and opening up, enhance development momentum and competitiveness&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized that Shanghai, as the forefront of my country&#39;s reform and opening up and an international metropolis with deep links to the world, must comprehensively develop from a higher starting point. Deepen reform and opening up and enhance development momentum and competitiveness. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wu Jincheng, Deputy Secretary-General of the Shanghai Municipal Government, Deputy Secretary of the Pudong New Area Party Committee, and Acting District Mayor, said that it is necessary to be guided by the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech, benchmark against the highest international standards, and vigorously promote innovation in all aspects Sexual reforms and leading openness, solidly promote the pilot reform of the comprehensive reform of the Pudong New District, accelerate the implementation of the first batch of authorization list matters, and achieve new breakthroughs in offshore transactions, cross -border data flow, value -added telecommunications, medical care, and international talent agglomeration. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China (Shanghai) Free Trade Zone Lingang New Area has formed more than 100 typical institutional innovation cases in 4 years since its establishment. Zhao Yihuai, a member of the Party Working Committee of the Lingang New Line District and the full -time deputy director of the Management Committee, said that it is necessary to take the lead in carrying out pressure tests to steadily expand the institutional types of rules, regulation, management, and standards, and strive to build a new highland. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;We must thoroughly implement the spirit of General Secretary Jinping&#39;s important speech, take the initiative to connect with high standards of international economic and trade rules, expand institutional openness, create high -level open portals, enhance the attractiveness of international goods and resource elements , Accelerate the construction of an international economic organization agglomeration area, establish and improve the international economic and trade exchange network, and further enhance the capacity level of Hongqiao International Open Hub. &quot;Said Bao Bingzhang, secretary of the party group and executive deputy director of the Shanghai Hongqiao International Central Business District Management Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasizes&#39; continue to run a two -way open platform such as the Expo. We are deeply responsible and glorious.&quot; Sun Chenghai, deputy director of the China International Import Expo Bureau The window function of building a new development pattern, give full play to the role of high -level open platform, and better provide a hard work to provide global public product services that are shared worldwide to promote the more and more better than entering the Expo. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;We must adhere to the two unshakable &#39;, deepen the reform of state -owned enterprises, focus on improving the core competitiveness of the enterprise, enhance the core functions, and implement a new round of reforms to deepen and enhance the actions, coordinate scientific and technological innovation With industrial innovation, build a group of world -class companies with benchmarking demonstration significance and special specialized new enterprises. &quot;Said He Qing, secretary of the Party Committee and Director of the Shanghai State -owned Assets Supervision and Administration Commission. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Fully practice the concept of the people&#39;s city, and strive to get out of a new way to govern the modernization of large cities with Chinese characteristics &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Urban concepts, give full play to the significant advantages of the party&#39;s leadership and socialist system, fully mobilize the enthusiasm and initiative of the people, adhere to a blueprint for the end in urban planning and implementation, accelerate the digital transformation of urban urban Transformation, comprehensively promote the construction of tough and safe and safe cities, and strive to get out of a new way to govern modernization of large cities with Chinese characteristics. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s important speech has further pointed out the direction of the progress for us. We must take the improvement of people&#39;s livelihood as the starting point and end point of urban construction and governance. Resource elements guarantee, etc., adhere to the high -quality development path of connotation, intensive, green, and green. &quot;Said Zhang Yuxin, secretary of the party group and director of the Shanghai Planning and Natural Resources Bureau. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The General Secretary came to our residence to inspect, and carefully understand the living conditions of the first -tier workers in the city, so that we will warm up.&quot; Su Yuanbao said that he had completed his undergraduate study in his spare time and had applied for the Shanghai Residence Permit. &quot;Shanghai has created a warm and comfortable living environment for us. We must grow with Shanghai.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Xue Kan, Secretary of the Yangpu District Committee of Shanghai, said that Yangpu District will fully practice the important concept of the people&#39;s city, use high -quality supply to serve the people, and make every effort to run the people&#39;s livelihood practices such as pension, childcare, education, and medical care. Responsible, everyone&#39;s dedication, and shared urban governance community. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Xuhui District will always adhere to the people -centered development ideas, improve the institutional mechanism that leads grass -roots governance with grass -roots party building in the city, enhance the balance and accessibility of basic public services, and create more citizen&#39;s doorsteps. A good place to open up the &quot;last mile&quot; of serving the masses. &quot;Cao Liqiang, Secretary of the Xuhui District Committee of Shanghai. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Xu Liming, director of the Liangcheng New Village Police Station of the Hongkou Branch of the Shanghai Public Security Bureau, said that we must adhere to and develop the &quot;Fengqiao Experience&quot; in the new era and further explore and improve &quot;The mechanism is to prevent the contradictions and disputes reflected by the masses, prioritize, use the rule of law, and solve the foundation on the spot, and build a foundation of harmony and stability of society. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Deepen the reform of the cultural system, stimulate cultural innovation and creative vitality, and vigorously enhance cultural soft power &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Cultural ideas, deepen the reform of the cultural system, stimulate cultural innovation and creativity, and vigorously enhance cultural soft power. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The important speech of General Secretary Xi Jinping provided us with a good follow -up and action guide for publicity and ideology.&quot; Ma Xiaohong, deputy minister of the Propaganda Department of the Shanghai Municipal Party Committee, said that Shanghai is a highland of cultural construction and showing China The window of culture must be courageous to bear the new cultural mission, strive to build the best practice place for Xi Jinping&#39;s cultural ideas, and make new contributions to building the modern civilization of the Chinese nation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the past two years, the main media of Shanghai has launched a series of short video programs such as &quot;The Thought of the People&quot; and &quot;Everyone Talking about Great Change&quot;. The vivid practice of doctrine in Shanghai. Lu Fangming, a reporter from the Jiefang Daily and the main creator of the series of &quot;The Thought of the People&quot; series, said: &quot;We will continue to explore new media communication methods through the&quot; People&#39;s Narrative &quot;model, keep positive innovation, and consolidate the public opinion of mainstream thoughts.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt; P>; &quot;We must adhere to the cultural and plastic travel and travel to the text, and promote the deep integration of high -quality development of cultural tourism.&quot; Implement the cultural benefit project and create a sample of Shanghai where cultural self -strengthening and self -improvement. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Yu Yong, Secretary of the Shanghai Jing&#39;an District Committee and director of the Civilization Practice Center of the New Era of the District, said that it is necessary to thoroughly implement the spirit of General Secretary Jinping&#39;s important speech, solidly promote the creation of the spiritual spirit of the masses, deepen the expansion of the practice of civilization in the new era The construction of the center, closely integrate the cultivation and implementation of the core values ​​of socialism with the promotion of the city&#39;s spiritual qualities, and continuously enhance the service level of the civilized practice center in the new era. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Adhering to the party&#39;s leadership, providing fundamental guarantee for Chinese -style modernization &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; It is also fundamentally guaranteed. Shanghai is the birthplace of our party. We must make good use of red resources such as the site of the National Congress, carry forward the great spirit of party building, educate and guide party members and cadres to keep in mind the &quot;three musts&quot;, and pioneer and innovate, forge ahead and work hard on the new journey. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Shanghai is the birthplace of our party, and promoting the spirit of the great party to build the party is our responsibility and mission.&quot; Xue Feng, secretary of the party committee and director of the CCP Memorial Hall, said that it is necessary to continue to promote the great exhibition of the great spirit of the party In various places, we have carried out in -depth series of &quot;100 things into hundreds of schools, a hundred years of analogy&quot; series, carefully creating brand activities, and inheriting and promoting red culture. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Cao Yuanfeng, Executive Deputy Minister of the Organization Department of the Shanghai Municipal Party Committee, said that it is necessary to implement the party&#39;s organizational route in the new era, implement the standards of good cadres in the new era, and build a high -quality professionalism that matches the socialist modern metropolis city. The cadre team has continuously improved the political ability, thinking, and practical ability of party members and cadres. In the development of Shanghai, it further exerts its organizational advantages, demonstrates its responsibilities, and promotes the city&#39;s party members and cadres to create new performance and hand over new answers. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out, &#39;We must resolutely oppose and punish corruption, and promote the political ecology of dare not rot, be corrupted, don&#39;t want to rot, and keep the wind. The work of anti -corruption in Suji, unifying strict management, supervision and encouraging the responsibility as a high degree, and promoting Shanghai to further form a good environment for the political ecology and entrepreneurship of the officers. &quot; Ma Le Sheng, deputy director of the Municipal Supervision Committee. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Chen Yujian, secretary of the Minhang District Committee of Shanghai Municipality: &quot;The second batch of theme education is close to the finals. The Minhang District must adhere to the standards and the energy. The high -level development of the International Central Business District, the high -quality innovation development of the scientific and technological innovation of the &quot;Dali Zero Bay&quot;, the &quot;construction picture &#39;&#39;&quot; real scene painting &#39;of the theme educational results into the practice of Chinese -style modern Minhang practice. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Inheritance and carry forward the spirit of not being afraid of difficulties, fear of hardships, courageous struggle, daring to win &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized that the history of the New Fourth Army fully explains that the people&#39;s hearts are back to their backs. To determine the choice of history, Jiangshan is the people and the people. This is a vivid teaching material for carrying out revolutionary traditional education and patriotism education. We must make good use of this teaching material to educate and guide party members and cadres to inherit and carry forward the spirit of not being afraid of difficulties and dangers, having the courage to fight and dare to win, relying closely on the people, and strengthening the country. The great cause of construction and national rejuvenation continues to advance. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The chief of the New Fourth Army Memorial Hall said: &quot;We must thoroughly implement the spirit of the important speech of General Secretary Jinping, and more solidly carry out the protection, research utilization, and display of red cultural relic collection, inherit the red gene, and continue the red blood. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>;&quot; We will focus on the relics of the revolutionary ruins of Yancheng, 128 martyrs named town villages, 60 provincial, cities, and county -level party history education bases to expand the depth and breadth of party history research, and continue to tap the new four forces The connotation characteristics of glorious history and the value of the times. &quot;Zhang Bo, director of the Party History Office of the Yancheng Municipal Committee of Jiangsu Province. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Sun Yihai, the first -level sheriff at the Guo Meng Police Station of the Yandu Branch of Yancheng Public Security Bureau, said: &quot;Guo Mengzhen is named after the name of the new four armed martyrs Guo Meng. , The spirit of courage to struggle and dare to win, take root in the front line, serve the grassroots, resolutely fight against various illegal crimes, and protect the safety of the lives and property of the people. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>;&quot; Yancheng is a red mark engraved The city of heroes. We must keep in mind that General Secretary Xi Jinping has instructed to better play the role of red culture and soul -casting people, effectively strengthen revolutionary traditional education, patriotism education, and rely on the people to do a good job of economic and social development. Continuously meet the people&#39;s longing for a better life. &quot;Zhou Bin, secretary of the Yancheng Municipal Party Committee, said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; (Reporter Liu Shi&#39;an, He Cong, Jiang Hongbing, Xie Weiqun, Cao Lingjuan, Tian Hong, Huang Xiaohui, Ju Yunpeng, Shen Wenmin, Fang Min, Ji Jue Su) &lt;/p>; &lt;!-/ enpcontent->; &lt;br>; &lt;hr>; &lt;div>; Get more RSS: &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:oraange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https:/ /feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;cone&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.run &lt;/a>; &lt;bR >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 以宪法凝聚共识，汇聚团结奋斗力量]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-12/05/nw.D110000renmrb_20231205_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>; Tuesday, December 05, 2023 &lt;/div>; &lt;!-ENPCONTENT->; &lt;p>; &quot;In the new journey, we must firmly maintain the authority and dignity of the constitution, promote the improvement and development of the Constitution, and better play the constitution in governing the country in governing the country. The important role in rational governance provides a solid guarantee for the comprehensive promotion of strong country construction and the great cause of national rejuvenation with Chinese -style modernization. &quot;On the occasion of the Tenth National Constitution Day, General Secretary Xi Jinping made important instructions to fully implement the new era and new journey in the new era. The implementation of the constitution to make clear requirements, which caused a warm response among the masses of cadres. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Everyone said that it is necessary to use the important instructions of General Secretary Xi Jinping as the fundamental follow, learn to implement Xi Jinping&#39;s thinking of the rule of law, fully implement the 20th spirit of the party, strengthen the awareness of the Constitution, promote the spirit of the Constitution, promote the implementation of the Constitution. Good play in the important role of the Constitution in comprehensively building a socialist modernization country and a Chinese -style modernization to comprehensively promote the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the party has strengthened the comprehensive leadership of the constitutional work, enriched and developed the theory of the Constitution of the Constitution and Constitution of the Constitution of Socialism with Chinese characteristics, and promoted historical achievements in the construction of my country&#39;s constitutional system and the implementation of the Constitution. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; In this regard, Zhang Xiangshen, vice chairman and secretary general of the Constitutional Research Association of the Chinese Law Society: &quot;From the establishment of the Constitution and Legal Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, to the establishment of the Constitution Office of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, one The series of measures allow the constitutional implementation and constitutional supervision to achieve breakthroughs at the level of standardization and system. The important role of the Constitution in governing the country and governing the country is more prominent, and the institutional system that ensures the comprehensive implementation of the Constitution is continuously improved. &quot; With strengthening the party&#39;s comprehensive leadership, historic achievements have been achieved in the construction of my country&#39;s constitutional system and the implementation of the Constitution. &quot;Long Xingye, Dean of the People&#39;s Court of Wangcheng District, Changsha, Changsha, Hunan Province, said that in the new era and new journey, we must strengthen institutional self -confidence and adhere to the Constitution to determine the Constitution to determine the constitution. The leadership of the Communist Party of China is unshakable, actively promotes the party&#39;s leadership institutionalization and rule of law, and penetrates party leadership throughout the constitutional implementation. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; The life of the Constitution lies in implementation, and the authority of the Constitution lies in implementation. General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized that the constitutional provisions, the principles of the Constitution, and the spirit of the constitution are comprehensively implemented, and the implementation of the constitution, the constitutional interpretation, and the advancement of the constitutional supervision system. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &quot;The important instructions of General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out the direction of the implementation and supervision work of the new era and the constitution of the new era.&quot; Huang Yufei, director of the Constitutional Office of the Standing Committee of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, said The comprehensive leadership of the constitution work, accelerate the improvement of the socialist legal system with the constitution as the core, improve the institutional system that ensures the comprehensive implementation of the Constitution, improves the ability and quality of constitutional review, filing review, promote constitutional review work, implement the constitutional constitution Explain the procedure mechanism and continuously improve the implementation of the constitution and supervision. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; The People&#39;s Procuratorate is a national legal supervision agency stipulated by the Constitution. After studying the important instructions of General Secretary Xi Jinping, Zhang Yun, the procurator of the People&#39;s Procuratorate of Zhuji City, Zhejiang Province, felt heavy responsibility and mission. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &quot;We must resolutely based on the constitutional positioning, adhere to the integration of duties in accordance with the law, comprehensively perform their duties, can perform their duties, dare to supervise, supervise, and do every case with high quality. Implement, go into details, and be good to the requirements of the constitutional governance. &quot;Zhang Yun said. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &quot;I swore: loyal to the Constitution of the People&#39;s Republic of China, maintain constitutional authority, and fulfill legal duties ...&quot; On December 4, the Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region Judicial Department held a solemn constitutional oath ceremony Promoting the spirit of the Constitution and fulfilling the mission of the Constitution. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &quot;In accordance with the important instructions of the General Secretary, promote the implementation of the party&#39;s central government&#39;s comprehensive decision -making and implementation in accordance with the law, the awareness of the Chinese nation community, further strengthen the constitutional propaganda, and strive to make the spirit of the constitution and the concept of the rule of law rooting all ethnic groups. In the hearts of the masses, everyone will respect the law of law and law in work and life. &quot;Wang Xiangdong, the head of the Secretariat of the Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region Party Committee and the second -level inspector of the Department of Justice, said. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; The implementation of the constitution in an all -round way is the primary task and basic task of governing the country in accordance with the law and building a socialist country. In recent years, Tianjin Baozhen District has introduced a number of systems such as the rules of the legitimacy of major administrative decision -making, and has penetrated the rule of law and the rule of law to the entire process of performing duties. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &quot;We will implement the spirit of the important instructions of the General Secretary, in accordance with the constitution, continue to strengthen the administrative law enforcement supervision mechanism and capacity building, and strive to make things in accordance with the law to become a conscious action of cadres.&quot; Liu Jian, Secretary of the Political and Legal Committee, said. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &quot;Strengthening the study and publicity of constitutionalism is the key to strengthening the awareness of the Constitution, promoting the spirit of the Constitution, and building a culture of socialist rule of law. In the new era and new journey, strengthen research, in -depth summary, and in -depth publicity and explanation of the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core to promote the improvement of the Constitution to improve the development and implement the constitution in an all -round way, and enhance the confidence of the Constitution. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; On the occasion of the Tenth National Constitution Day, Li Yan, the police of the Erlong Road Police Station of the West City Branch of the Beijing Public Security Bureau, recorded a vivid education course for rule of law and guided students in the district to strengthen the study of the constitutional legal knowledge. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &quot;Young people are the future of the motherland, and letting the spirit of the Constitution take root in their hearts is our sacred mission.&quot; Li Yan said, &quot;It is necessary to seriously implement the important instructions of General Secretary Jinping, and in daily work Persevere and do a good job of publicity and education of constitutional laws, encourage children to start from small things, start with them, learn about constitutional legal knowledge, and improve the awareness of the constitutional legal. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; (Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, December 4, &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; Reporter Xiong Feng, Liu Shuo, Bai Yang, Liu Yizhan, Qi Qi, Huang Jianglin) &lt;/p>; &lt;!-/enpcontent->; &lt;br>; &lt;hr>; &lt;div>; Get more RSS: &lt;br >; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href = &quot;https:///////////// Feedx.run &quot;style =&quot; color: orange &quot;target =&quot; _blank &quot;>; https://feedx.run &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 推动宪法实施成为全体人民的自觉行动]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-12/05/nw.D110000renmrb_20231205_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>; Tuesday, December 05, 2023 &lt;/div>; &lt;!-ENPCONTENT->; &lt;p>; On the arrival of the Tenth National Constitution Day, General Secretary Xi Jinping made an important instructions to point out that &quot;the constitution is to govern the country and Anbang The general charter is the fundamental legal basis for our party&#39;s governing the country and the highest legal norms of national politics and social life. &quot;It emphasizes that&quot; vigorously promotes the spirit of the Constitution and the spirit of socialist rule of law in the whole society, and promotes the implementation of the Constitution to become the consciousness of all people&#39;s consciousness. action&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Constitution is fundamental, global, stable, and long -term. Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, our party has strengthened the comprehensive leadership of the constitutional work, enriched and developed the theory and constitutional practice of socialist constitution with Chinese characteristics, and promoted the significant advantage of my country&#39;s constitutional system to better transform into national governance efficiency. From the institutional arrangements of improving party leadership legislation, ensuring law enforcement, supporting justice, and taking the lead in law -abiding, to the promotion of the party&#39;s leadership institutionalization and rule of law, from improving the socialist legal system with the constitution as the core, to strengthening constitutional review . The record and review system and capacity building. From the establishment of the National Constitution Day, establish a constitutional oath system, to effectively implement the comprehensive governance power of the special administrative region in accordance with the Constitution and Basic Law ... The role of the national fundamental law of the Constitution has been fully played, and the constitutional practice is more vivid and vivid. The reason why my country&#39;s constitutional system construction and the implementation of the Constitution have achieved historic achievements, which is based on the guidance of General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s leadership, and it is the guidance of Xi Jinping&#39;s ideological sciences of socialism with Chinese characteristics in the new era. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China has painted the grand blueprint for comprehensively building a socialist modern country and a Chinese -style modernization to comprehensively promote the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation. High requirements, we must better play the role of the rule of law, stabilizing expectations, and long -term guarantee, and comprehensively build a socialist modern country on the track of the rule of law. It is necessary to deeply realize that maintaining the authority of the constitution is the authority of maintaining the common will of the party and the people; defending the dignity of the constitution is to defend the dignity of the party and the people; to ensure the implementation of the Constitution to ensure the realization of the people&#39;s fundamental interests. In the new journey, we must firmly maintain the authority and dignity of the constitution, promote the improvement and development of the Constitution, and better play the important role of the Constitution in governing the country and governing the country, and provide a solid guarantee for comprehensively promoting the construction of a strong country with Chinese -style modernization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; To adhere to the rule of law according to law, we must first adhere to the constitutional governance of the country, and adhere to the governance according to law. To improve the Party&#39;s ability to govern the country and govern in accordance with the Constitution, the implementation of the Constitution must be implemented into all practices of coordinating and promoting the &quot;Five-in-One&quot; overall layout and coordinating the advancement of the &quot;Four Comprehensives&quot; strategic layout. 2. Governing the party and governing the country and governing the army in all aspects, and comprehensively promoting the rule of governance of all aspects of the country. The socialist system with Chinese characteristics is the fundamental guarantee for the development and progress of contemporary China. We must strengthen our confidence in the political system, uphold the leadership position of the Communist Party of China as determined by the Constitution, and uphold the state system of the people&#39;s democratic dictatorship and the People&#39;s Congress system as determined by the Constitution. The life of the Constitution lies in its implementation, and the authority of the Constitution also lies in its implementation. It is necessary to thoroughly study and implement Xi Jinping&#39;s thinking, adhere to the constitutional provisions, the principles of the constitution, and the spirit of the constitution, adhere to the implementation of the constitution, the constitutional interpretation, the constitutional supervision system, and accelerate the improvement of the socialist legal system with the constitution as the core, and continuously improve the implementation of the constitutional implementation And the level of supervision. The foundation of the Constitution lies in the heartfelt support of the people, and the power of the Constitution lies in the sincere belief of the people. It is necessary to strengthen the theoretical research and publicity and education of the Constitution, adhere to the popularization of knowledge, theoretical interpretation, concept guidance, and deepen the educational functions of the Constitution&#39;s Oath, National Constitution Day, National Symbols and Labels, and promote the normalization of the constitutional publicity and education. Make all the people&#39;s loyal and admirables, consciously obey, and firm defenders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: &quot;The formulation and implementation of the constitution is the symbol of the progress of human civilization and an important support for human society to modernize.&quot; For the new journey, in the strong leadership of the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core Below, in -depth study and implementation of Xi Jinping&#39;s thinking and General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s important expositions on the Constitution, promote the spirit of the Constitution, strengthen the implementation of the Constitution, build the foundation of the rule of law, do the power of the rule of law, and accumulate the rule of law. Practice a new chapter. &lt;/p>; &lt;!-/enpcontent->; &lt;br>; &lt;hr>; &lt;div>; Get more RSS: &lt;br>; &lt;a href = &quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style = &quot;color: orange&quot; target = &quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.net &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.run&quot; style=&quot;cone&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https:///// feedx.run &lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 05 Dec 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>