<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 建设人与自然和谐共生的美丽家园]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20230922_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, September 22, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Zhijiang Dadi’s 65 Asian Games venues and office spaces all use green electricity, and citizens have participated in the &quot;I plant trees for the Asian Games&quot; ” and other activities. The Hangzhou Asian Games, which takes &quot;green&quot; as one of its hosting concepts, is striving to become the first carbon-neutral Asian Games. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than half of the world’s new energy vehicles are driving in China. It only took 17 months for China’s new energy vehicles to go from producing the 10 millionth vehicle to exceeding 20 million vehicles. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The pace of green and low-carbon development is solid and powerful. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On September 22, 2020, at the general debate of the 75th United Nations General Assembly, General Secretary Xi Jinping solemnly announced: “China will increase its nationally determined contributions and adopt more powerful policies and measures to reduce carbon dioxide emissions. Emissions will strive to peak before 2030 and strive to achieve carbon neutrality before 2060.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This means that China, as the world&#39;s largest developing country, will complete the world&#39;s highest reduction in carbon emission intensity and use From carbon peak to carbon neutrality in the shortest time in global history. This is undoubtedly a tough battle and requires extremely arduous efforts. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Be true to your word and do what you say. Over the past three years, the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping at its core has incorporated carbon peaking and carbon neutrality into the overall layout of ecological civilization construction and the overall economic and social development, and promoted the &quot;double carbon&quot; work to achieve a good start and positive results. my country has built a &quot;1+N&quot; policy system for carbon peaking and carbon neutrality, deployed and implemented the &quot;Ten Major Actions for Carbon Peaking&quot;, and continuously consolidated the foundation for statistical accounting, standard measurement, technological innovation, and talent training; it has built the world&#39;s largest As for the clean power generation system, as of the first half of this year, the country&#39;s renewable energy installed capacity has exceeded 1.3 billion kilowatts, historically surpassing coal power; the number of new energy vehicles exceeds 16.2 million, and production and sales have ranked first in the world for eight consecutive years. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Promote the responsibility of building a community with a shared future for mankind and achieve the inherent requirements of high-quality development&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Temperatures have hit record highs, heat waves and droughts are frequent, and heavy rains and floods are frequent. ...Since the industrial revolution, climate change caused by massive emissions of greenhouse gases such as carbon dioxide has been a severe challenge facing all mankind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In response to climate change, China’s ambition and strength have attracted worldwide attention. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On December 12, 2020, General Secretary Xi Jinping further announced at the Climate Ambition Summit: By 2030, China’s carbon dioxide emissions per unit of GDP will fall by more than 65% compared with 2005, and non-fossil energy will account for The proportion of primary energy consumption will reach about 25%, the forest stock volume will increase by 6 billion cubic meters compared with 2005, and the total installed capacity of wind power and solar power will reach more than 1.2 billion kilowatts. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The international community generally believes that at a critical moment in the global climate governance process, China has made major commitments to reach carbon peak and carbon neutrality, promote high-quality development, and accelerate green and low-carbon transformation, which reflects China’s initiative. Assumed important responsibilities and played a positive role in setting an example. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;How difficult is it to achieve peak carbon neutrality? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It generally takes developed countries more than 40 or even 70 years to go from carbon peak to carbon neutrality, while China only takes about 30 years. China is in the context that the historical tasks of industrialization and urbanization have not yet been completed. The process of carbon reduction has begun, and the energy structure is skewed towards coal and the industrial structure is skewed towards coal. Carbon reduction is more difficult and time is tight than ever before.&quot; said Zhou Hongchun, a researcher at the Development Research Center of the State Council. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Advance despite difficulties and move forward with courage. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The report of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China clarified the overall goals of my country&#39;s development by 2035. One of them is to &quot;extensively form a green production and lifestyle, carbon emissions will steadily decrease after peaking, and the ecological environment will fundamentally improve.&quot; , the goal of Beautiful China has been basically achieved.” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Actively and steadily promoting carbon peak and carbon neutrality is the responsibility to promote the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind, and is also an inherent requirement for my country to achieve high-quality development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Think long-term, anchor goals, and strive for progress while maintaining stability. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping earnestly warned when participating in the deliberation of the Inner Mongolia delegation during the National Two Sessions in 2022: &quot;We must be based on the national conditions, insist on making progress while maintaining stability, and gradually realize it. We must not be divorced from reality, eager for success, and engage in sports-style &#39;Reducing carbon&#39; and applying the &#39;sudden brake&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping proposed at the National Ecological and Environmental Protection Conference held in July this year: &quot;The &#39;double carbon&#39; goal we are committed to is unwavering. , but the path and method, rhythm and intensity to achieve this goal should and must be decided by ourselves.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping made important instructions on the occasion of the first National Ecology Day and emphasized: &quot;With the &#39;dual carbon&#39; work as the guide, we will promote the dual control of energy consumption and gradually shift to the dual control of carbon emissions, and continue to promote the production methods and Green and low-carbon lifestyle transformation”. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Reduce emissions for the earth and add greenness to your home. A &quot;broad and profound change&quot; is accelerating. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Construct and implement the “1+N” policy system for carbon peak and carbon neutrality. The Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council issued the &quot;Opinions on Completely, Accurately and Comprehensively Implementing the New Development Concept and Doing a Good Job in Carbon Peaking and Carbon Neutrality&quot;. The State Council issued the &quot;Action Plan for Carbon Peaking before 2030&quot;, making a top-level design and clarifying a timetable and roadmap. . Relevant departments have issued 12 implementation plans for key industries in key areas such as energy, industry, construction, transportation, agriculture and rural areas, as well as 11 support plans for scientific and technological support, financial support, statistical accounting, and ecological carbon sinks. 31 provinces have formulated carbon peaks Implementation plan, the &quot;dual carbon&quot; policy system has been completed and implemented continuously. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A series of powerful measures for green, low-carbon and circular development have taken effect. Improve the regulation of the total amount and intensity of energy consumption, and gradually shift to a dual control system for the total amount and intensity of carbon emissions; implement preferential tax and fee policies, and the central government has allocated a total of 1.78 trillion yuan in ecological and environmental protection-related funds since 2020; the national carbon emissions trading market has officially Launched online trading, it has become the world&#39;s largest carbon market covering greenhouse gas emissions. By the end of 2022, the cumulative transaction volume of carbon emission quotas has reached 230 million tons, and the cumulative transaction volume has reached 10.475 billion yuan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2020, my country’s carbon dioxide emissions per unit of GDP will be reduced by approximately 48.4% compared with 2005, exceeding the first-stage nationally determined contribution commitment. On this basis, in the first two years of the “14th Five-Year Plan”, my country’s carbon dioxide emission intensity has further declined, and energy conservation and carbon reduction have achieved remarkable results. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the past ten years in the new era, my country has supported an average annual economic growth of more than 6% with an average annual energy consumption growth rate of 3%, and its carbon emission intensity has dropped by more than 35% cumulatively, reversing the rapid growth of carbon dioxide emissions. situation.&quot; introduced the relevant person in charge of the Ministry of Ecology and Environment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Green production methods are widely promoted, and the green background of high-quality development is deeply planted.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;12,000 heliostats follow the sun and move the sunlight. Reflected onto the collector tower. The 100-megawatt molten salt tower solar thermal power station in the Gobi Desert in northwest China has a designed annual power generation of 390 million kilowatt hours. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Extended reach wells with a horizontal displacement of more than 3,000 meters send carbon dioxide to the seabed. my country&#39;s first offshore carbon dioxide storage demonstration project, built in the Pearl River Mouth Basin, is expected to store about 300,000 tons per year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: “We must accelerate the green and low-carbon transformation of development methods, adhere to green and low-carbon development as the fundamental solution to ecological and environmental problems, accelerate the formation of green production methods and lifestyles, and cultivate The green background of high-quality development.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the three years since the &quot;double carbon&quot; goal was proposed, our country has accelerated the construction of a green, low-carbon and circular economic system, vigorously promoted green production methods, and promoted the energy revolution and resource conservation and intensification. Utilize and coordinate pollution reduction and carbon reduction to achieve synergies, reduce carbon emissions during development, and achieve higher quality development while reducing carbon emissions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——The green and low-carbon transformation of energy is steadily advancing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Carbon emissions from my country’s energy activities account for more than 80% of overall carbon emissions. Carbon reduction in energy production is crucial to achieving the “double carbon” goal. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On August 31, the world&#39;s first 630 degrees Celsius secondary reheat thermal power project started construction in Yuncheng, Shandong Province. The main steam that the generator unit has generated once will be used again for boiler circulation heating. &quot;Compared with conventional coal power units, it saves 350,000 tons of standard coal and reduces carbon dioxide emissions by 945,000 tons every year.&quot; said Lin Yue, general director of the construction of the Datang Yuncheng project. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;my country has carried out the &quot;three-reform linkage&quot; of coal power energy-saving and carbon-reducing transformation, flexibility transformation, and heating transformation. New coal power units have implemented stricter energy-saving standards, and power generation efficiency and pollutant emission control have reached the world&#39;s leading level. level. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The level of clean and efficient utilization of fossil energy has been greatly improved, and non-fossil energy has achieved leapfrog development. There are six cascade power stations on the main stream of the Yangtze River, including Wudongde and Baihetan, with a total installed capacity of over 71 million kilowatts, and the average annual power generation can meet the annual electricity needs of more than 300 million people. In the Zhangbei grassland, photovoltaic panels and a typhoon machine complement the blue sky and white clouds, and a steady stream of green electricity lights up the lights of Beijing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As of 2022, coal’s proportion in national primary energy consumption has dropped significantly from 68.5% in 2012 to 56.2%, and the proportion of clean energy consumption has increased to 25.9%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The relevant person in charge of the National Energy Administration said: &quot;Our country has built the world&#39;s largest clean power generation system. Among them, the scale of hydropower, wind power, photovoltaic, biomass power generation and nuclear power under construction has ranked first in the world for many years. In the first half of this year, the installed capacity of renewable energy reached 1.322 billion kilowatts, historically surpassing coal power and accounting for approximately 48.8% of my country&#39;s total installed capacity.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;my country has vigorously developed renewable energy and made positive contributions to global emission reductions. contribute. In 2022, my country&#39;s renewable energy power generation is equivalent to reducing domestic carbon dioxide emissions by approximately 2.26 billion tons. The exported wind power and photovoltaic products will reduce carbon dioxide emissions for other countries by approximately 573 million tons. The total emission reduction exceeds 2.8 billion tons, accounting for approximately 1% of the world&#39;s renewable energy emissions during the same period. 41% of energy-converted carbon emission reductions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Vigorously implement carbon reduction and pollution reduction actions in key industries and areas. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Industrial production, building operations, transportation, etc. are the main links that consume energy and generate carbon emissions. The report of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China proposed to promote clean and low-carbon transformation in industry, construction, transportation and other fields. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Promote the green development of industry. Jiangsu Lishui Tianshan Cement Co., Ltd. and the local power supply department have worked together to explore &quot;comprehensive carbon management&quot;. By developing an online carbon emission monitoring and management system, combined with the construction of distributed photovoltaic and energy storage power stations, they can reduce carbon emissions by nearly one million tons per year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Continue to deepen supply-side structural reform. We must resolutely curb the blind launch of high-energy-consuming, high-emission, and low-level projects and promote the continuous optimization of the industrial structure. By the end of 2022, the country has eliminated backward and eliminated overcapacity about 300 million tons of steel, 400 million tons of cement, and 150 million weight boxes of flat glass. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strategic emerging industries develop and grow. The &quot;three new products&quot; represented by solar cells, lithium batteries and electric passenger vehicles have become new drivers of foreign trade growth. In the first half of this year, the total exports of the &quot;three new products&quot; increased by 61.6%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vigorously develop green buildings. In Tongzhou District, Beijing, at the project site of Lot 160 of the China Construction First Engineering Bureau Urban Sub-center, builders are busy testing the thermal insulation of the building. Project manager Xu Youyue said: &quot;The application proportion of green building materials exceeds half, and green waterproof and air-proof membranes alone can reduce carbon emissions by more than 15%.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2022, the area of ​​newly built green buildings in my country will account for The ratio has increased from 77% at the end of the “Thirteenth Five-Year Plan” to 91.2%; green and low-carbon transformation of existing buildings has been promoted, and energy-saving buildings account for more than 65% of urban civil construction area. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Build a green transportation system. my country&#39;s first transportation and energy integration demonstration project was completed in Jining, Shandong Province in May this year and officially connected to the grid for power generation. It uses open spaces such as highway slopes to build photovoltaic power generation facilities to provide green power for highway service areas and new energy vehicles. &quot;As of the beginning of August, the cumulative power generation has exceeded 5 million kilowatt-hours, saving about 1,800 tons of standard coal.&quot; said Gao Kang, technical director of China Energy Construction and Energy Integration Zaohe Project. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Continue to optimize the transportation structure and promote the green transformation of transportation tools. In 2022, the national railway freight volume will increase by 4.4% year-on-year, and the waterway freight volume will increase by 3.8% year-on-year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——The research, promotion and application of green and low-carbon science and technology continue to be strengthened. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In August, Xinjiang Kuqa Green Hydrogen Demonstration Project was completed and put into operation. This is my country&#39;s largest direct green hydrogen production project from photovoltaic power generation. Overcoming difficulties and innovating independently, all major equipment and core materials such as photovoltaic modules and electrolyzers used in the project have been domestically produced. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In June, the National Energy Group’s Jiangsu Taizhou Power Plant Carbon Dioxide Capture Utilization and Storage (CCUS) project was officially put into operation. This is Asia’s largest thermal power CCUS project and can capture and absorb 500,000 tons of carbon dioxide per year. &quot;We have independently developed a new generation of high-capacity, low-energy-consumption absorbers that integrate new fillers, efficient amine recovery and other technologies, with a carbon dioxide capture rate of greater than 90%,&quot; said Liu Jiandong, chief engineer of Jiangsu Taizhou Power Plant. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To promote &quot;dual carbon&quot; work, technological innovation is the key support. The company leads the world in the construction capacity of million-kilowatt hydropower units. The conversion efficiency of mass-produced monocrystalline cells has repeatedly set world records. The world&#39;s first ultra-large-capacity 16-megawatt offshore wind turbine has been successfully connected to the grid to generate electricity. It has its own brand of &quot;Hualong One&quot;, etc. The third generation of large-scale advanced pressurized water reactor technology has been applied in batches, and cutting-edge technologies such as hydrogen energy, fuel cells, new energy storage, and carbon capture, utilization and storage have continued to make new breakthroughs...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the &quot;double carbon&quot; goal was proposed, China has strengthened green and low-carbon scientific and technological innovation, built five national key laboratories in the &quot;dual carbon&quot; field, implemented key research and development projects such as renewable energy technology, and formed green technology and equipment covering energy conservation, water conservation, environmental protection, renewable energy and other fields. The manufacturing system, green technology equipment and product supply capabilities have been significantly enhanced. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The whole society takes active actions to coordinately promote carbon reduction, pollution reduction, green expansion and growth&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;my country’s ecological civilization construction has entered a strategic direction focusing on carbon reduction. During this critical period, promoting green and low-carbon economic and social development is a key link in achieving high-quality development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized in the report of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China: &quot;Coordinate industrial structural adjustment, pollution control, ecological protection, and response to climate change, and coordinately promote carbon reduction, pollution reduction, green expansion, and growth, and promote Ecological priority, conservation and intensiveness, green and low-carbon development.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The whole society has taken active actions to solidly promote carbon peak carbon neutrality and accelerate the modernization of harmonious coexistence between man and nature. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Build a forest “carbon bank” and steadily improve the ecosystem’s carbon sink capacity. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On April 4 this year, General Secretary Xi Jinping braved the rain and came to the tree planting site in Dongba Central Park, Chaoyang District, Beijing, and participated in voluntary tree planting with people in the capital. General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out that forests are not only reservoirs, money depots, grain depots, but also carbon depots. Afforestation is a very meaningful thing. It is a noble cause that serves the present and will benefit the future. It must be done consistently and continuously. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Not only do we plant patches of green in the vast land of our motherland, but we also sow green seeds in the hearts of the people. From on-site tree planting to &quot;responsibility&quot; and &quot;cloud tree planting&quot;, people actively participated in voluntary tree planting activities. The responsible forms of voluntary tree planting have been expanded to more than 50 types in 8 categories, achieving year-round, diversification and convenience. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Everyone planted trees to form a forest. Since the &quot;14th Five-Year Plan&quot;, the country has completed more than 100 million acres of land greening every year, with a forest coverage rate of 24.02% and a forest stock volume of 19.493 billion cubic meters. The national forest coverage rate and forest stock volume have maintained &quot;double growth&quot; for many consecutive years, and China has become the country with the largest and fastest growing forest resources in the world. In 2021, the annual carbon sink of forests and grasslands nationwide will exceed 1.2 billion tons, ranking first in the world. China’s contribution to greening our home planet and improving global climate change has won world praise. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The public actively participated, and a simple, moderate, green and low-carbon lifestyle became popular. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Piaoying Garden Community, Jiaxing Road Street, Hongkou District, Shanghai, residents carry garbage bags to the garbage bin room, sorting and placing, automatic weighing, voice prompts... it only takes 10 seconds to complete Classify garbage and put it in, and you can also learn about data about your own domestic garbage. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, Shanghai has carried out solid waste classification work, and the overall level of waste classification and resource utilization has been improved throughout the entire process. From &quot;unwilling to separate, unable to separate&quot; to &quot;active and intelligent separation&quot;, now the city&#39;s residential areas and units&#39; garbage classification compliance rate has reached 95%, and more and more citizens are voluntarily classifying their garbage. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;my country&#39;s waste classification work continues to advance in depth. 297 cities at or above the prefecture level have fully implemented domestic waste classification, and the average coverage rate in residential areas has reached 82.5%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Green travel has increasingly become a new trend in low-carbon life, driving the rapid development of new energy vehicles, with production and sales ranking first in the world for eight consecutive years. On July 3, my country’s 20 millionth new energy vehicle rolled off the production line of Guangzhou GAC Aian. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From participating in the &quot;Operation CD&quot; and opposing food waste, to setting the air conditioner temperature to no lower than 26 degrees Celsius in summer, from opening a personal carbon account, to not using disposable tableware when ordering takeout... simple and moderate, green and low The carbon lifestyle has gradually become the new trend of the times, gathering surging power to protect green waters and green mountains. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By unswervingly implementing the national strategy of actively addressing climate change, China has become an important participant, contributor and leader in global climate governance. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Signs of “Zero Carbon Services&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Shared by Everyone” can be seen everywhere in the exhibition hall. Visitors can join green actions by scanning the QR code and obtain the “CFIT Carbon Neutral Certificate”. At the China International Fair for Trade in Services held in Beijing in early September, the National Stadium was used as the main venue for the first time to launch a special exhibition on environmental services. Four special areas were set up for low-carbon energy, carbon neutrality and green technology, climate and carbon economy, and circular economy. Establish a special low-carbon technology travel area in Shougang Park. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The green exhibition is a mirror that reflects that as carbon peaks and carbon neutrality continue to advance, my country&#39;s economic and social development will usher in profound changes, which will have a profound impact on the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Actively and constructively participate in the multilateral process of climate change, continue to deepen South-South cooperation in addressing climate change, and promote the green and low-carbon development of the “Belt and Road”. Overseas non-fossil energy investment has exceeded fossil energy, and a number of clean energy projects have been built one after another. , efficient, high-quality green energy cooperation landmark projects... China unswervingly implements the national strategy of actively addressing climate change and has always actively contributed to the sustainable development of the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China is an activist in promoting global climate governance.” Xie Zhenhua, China’s special envoy for climate change affairs, said that China has achieved remarkable results in its green and low-carbon transformation and embarked on a path of green, low-carbon and sustainable development that is in line with its national conditions. It has provided experience and reference for developing countries with practical actions and results, and contributed to global climate governance. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although the road is long, you will get there if you go; although the task is difficult, you will succeed if you do it. Adhere to Xi Jinping Thought on Ecological Civilization as the fundamental guideline and guide for action, maintain the strategic determination to strengthen the construction of ecological civilization, actively and steadily promote carbon peak carbon neutrality, jointly build a beautiful home where man and nature coexist harmoniously, and promote high-level protection with high-level protection. Quality development and creation of high-quality life. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平将出席杭州第19届亚洲运动会开幕式并举行系列外事活动]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20230922_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, September 22, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, September 21: Ministry of Foreign Affairs Spokesperson Hua Chunying announced on the 21st: President Xi Jinping will attend the opening ceremony of the 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou from September 22 to 23, and hold a welcome banquet and bilateral activities for foreign leaders coming to China to attend the opening ceremony. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The foreign leaders who came to China to attend the opening ceremony include: King Sihamoni of Cambodia, President Bashar of Syria, Crown Prince of Kuwait Mishal, Prime Minister of Nepal Prachanda, Prime Minister of East Timor Shanana, Prime Minister of South Korea Han Deok-soo, Speaker of the House of Commons of Malaysia Johari Tun Openg. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In addition, Prince Sufri, the representative of the Sultan of Brunei, Prince Jiao An, the representative of the Emir of Qatar, Prince Faisal of Jordan, Princess Siriwanvali of Thailand, Deputy Prime Minister of Kyrgyzstan Baisalov, etc. also Will attend relevant activities. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 共赴亚运之约  奏响时代强音]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20230922_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, September 22, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;In the golden autumn, magnificent Asian Games scrolls are slowly spreading across the land of Zhijiang; osmanthus is fragrant, and sports are the media , the host opens his arms to welcome guests and friends from all over the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Hangzhou Asian Games is the largest and highest-level international comprehensive sports event held in my country after the victory of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, and has attracted much attention. General Secretary Xi Jinping has shown close concern and attached great importance to the preparations for the Hangzhou Asian Games, and has made important instructions on many occasions, providing fundamental guidance for the preparations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking back on the 8 years of preparations for the Asian Games, Hangzhou has joined hands with the five co-organizing cities of Ningbo, Wenzhou, Huzhou, Shaoxing and Jinhua, and has always adhered to the concept of &quot;green, smart, frugal and civilized&quot;. Following the requirements of &quot;simple, safe and exciting&quot; games, we strive to create an Asian Games with &quot;Chinese characteristics, Asian style and splendid&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Now, the Asian Games is about to open, and the world’s attention is focused on Hangzhou. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;The long-awaited Asian Games begins&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The clock goes back to September 16, 2015, at the Olympic Games in Ashgabat, the capital of Turkmenistan. Center, Prince Ahmed, then Chairman of the Olympic Council of Asia, announced that Hangzhou, China, had won the right to host the 19th Asian Games. Suddenly, the audience burst into warm applause. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fire of the Asian Games ignites the passion of the Chinese people, and the light of the Asian Games shines on the land of China. From the 1990 Beijing Asian Games to the 2010 Guangzhou Asian Games, and now to the current Hangzhou Asian Games, my country&#39;s comprehensive national strength has continued to rise, and its economic and social development has advanced by leaps and bounds. The Yangtze River Delta region, where Zhejiang is located, is one of the regions with the most active economic development, the highest degree of openness, and the strongest innovation capabilities in my country. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When the baton of the Asian Games was handed over to Hangzhou, the preparation work started simultaneously and in an orderly manner. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Asian Games is a systematic project. Since the preparations have been made, party committees and governments at all levels from the central government to Zhejiang and then to Hangzhou have attached great importance to this——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On April 9, 2016, the Hangzhou Asian Organizing Committee was formally established, setting up &quot;one office and nineteen departments&quot; &quot;Organizational structure, focusing on planning and deployment, the preparations for the Asian Games have begun. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On October 15, 2017, the construction of Asian Games venues and facilities started. A total of 56 competition venues, 31 training venues, 1 Asian Games village and 5 Asian Games sub-villages have been set up in the 6 cities hosting the games. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On September 2, 2018, the Jakarta Asian Games came to an end. With the completion of the handover of the Olympic Council of Asia flag, the Asian Games officially entered &quot;Hangzhou time&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the cordial care of the Party Central Committee and the State Council, command organization systems have been established at the national, provincial and municipal levels. At the national level, a leading group for the 19th Asian Games and the 4th Asian Paralympics was established. The Zhejiang Provincial Party Committee and the Provincial Government have established a leading group for the Asian Games and the Asian Paralympic Games, and the Hangzhou Asian Games General Headquarters and co-organizer city sub-headquarters have been established at the same time, marking that the preparations for the Asian Games have entered a critical stage, gradually shifting from &quot;preparation&quot; to &quot;preparation&quot;. &quot;Do&quot; is fully transformed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Command from the front, promote personally, and actively supervise. Anchor the goal of &quot;hosting a successful Asian Games&quot;, the broad masses of cadres and the masses have always devoted themselves to the preparations for the Asian Games. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asian Games venues, volunteer services, traffic security... The Hangzhou Asian Games General Headquarters holds scheduling meetings every week to study and solve specific problems one by one to ensure that all preparations are carried out solidly and effectively. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“From venue renovation to team entry, we continue to optimize and improve, hoping to welcome the Asian Games with a higher level.” The person in charge of Hangzhou Huanglong Sports Center said, from venue upgrades to event operation and maintenance, and then During the stress test, the staff worked day and night and went all out. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After eight years of hard work, the preparations for the Hangzhou Asian Games have achieved fruitful results——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This Asian Games has 40 major events, 61 sub-events, and 481 minor events. A total of the host city Hangzhou and 5 co-hosting cities participated in hosting the competition. All 45 national and regional Olympic committees in Asia signed up to participate, with more than 12,000 athletes signing up. The Hangzhou Asian Games has become the largest Asian Games in history, with the most projects and the widest coverage. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;56 competition venues and 31 training venues have been put into operation, and more than 10,000 full-time personnel and more than 20,000 venue volunteers from 41 venue teams are all in place. In addition to 1 Asian Games village and 5 Asian Games sub-villages, the Hangzhou Asian Games Organizing Committee has also added Shaoxing City, Hangzhou Lin&#39;an District and Xiaoshan District as accommodation points for participating athletes to ensure their participation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From the careful preparation of the overall plan for the torch relay and the performance plan for the opening and closing ceremonies, to the continuous improvement of the urban transportation system and the all-round improvement of the quality of the city&#39;s appearance, all aspects of the Asian Games preparations have been carefully polished. With first-class venue facilities, smooth event organization, and thoughtful service guarantee, it is a firm commitment of Hangzhou and Zhejiang to build a stage for Asian athletes to showcase their style. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Now, Hangzhou is ready. This Asian Games event will let the world see the beautiful Hangzhou, the vibrant Zhejiang, and the beautiful China.” Executive Secretary-General of the Hangzhou Asian Games Organizing Committee, Hangzhou Asian Games Events Chen Weiqiang, deputy director of the general headquarters office, said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Overcoming difficulties&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Progressing in an orderly manner&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The preparation process for the Hangzhou Asian Games has not been smooth sailing. In May 2022, affected by the epidemic, the Asian Games and Asian Para Games decided to postpone their holdings for one year, which brought great challenges to the preparation work. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We are united as one to overcome difficulties, and the broad masses of cadres and the masses have concentrated their efforts to promote the orderly launch of various preparations for the Asian Games. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shaoxing Baseball (Softball) Sports and Culture Center is responsible for the baseball and softball events of this Asian Games. During the epidemic prevention and control period, the on-site project leader of the project construction party and all units coordinated and coordinated with each other to pay close attention to the work and ensure that nothing went wrong. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the preparation process of the Asian Games, there are many examples like this. Optimize the construction process, adjust the construction plan, improve related processes, and strengthen on-site organization... Most of the competition venues will be completed and delivered in March 2021, and test competitions will be carried out one after another. Publicity and promotion activities such as the &quot;Ten Asian Games Tour&quot; and &quot;Hangzhou Asian Games Fun Run&quot; were also successfully held. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hangzhou and Zhejiang have withstood the test and not only won the tough battle in organizing the Asian Games, but also trained their teams and improved their level in the practice of hosting the games. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Urban management is more refined. During the Asian Games, Hangzhou will fully rely on the &quot;City Brain&quot; transportation system to detect urban traffic conditions in real time, diagnose congestion in real time, proactively prevent congestion, and quickly alleviate congestion. During the games, Hangzhou will also activate Asian Games digital dedicated lanes on the commuter roads between Asian Games service-related facilities. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;City infrastructure has jumped significantly. On August 8 this year, the Tianmushan Road Tunnel, which Hangzhou citizens have long awaited, was put into trial operation, marking the opening of the Qiantang Expressway, the longest east-west expressway in Hangzhou. In the future, this expressway that &quot;crosses the river and connects the city&quot; will strengthen block communication and connection, improve the traffic efficiency of the road network, and release the vitality of urban development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The principle of &quot;sports benefiting the people&quot; has been implemented. The Hangzhou Asian Games set a precedent for domestic comprehensive sports event venues to be opened to the public before the game. By building urban embedded sports facilities and opening reservations for primary and secondary school sports venues, a &quot;10-minute fitness circle&quot; was created for citizens. In November 2022, the Qiantang River Greenway, with a total length of more than 1,000 kilometers, will be fully opened. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This journey of struggle and journey is not easy. The preparation process for the Hangzhou Asian Games has once again demonstrated the institutional advantages of socialism in concentrating its efforts on major things. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;The concept of hosting the competition&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;is deeply rooted in the hearts of the people&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As night falls, the lights begin to turn on. Overlooking the south bank of the Qiantang River from the air, the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center gymnasium and swimming pool are like colorful butterflies fluttering about to fly, complementing the &quot;Big Lotus&quot; of the Hangzhou Olympic Sports Center main stadium. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the successful bid to host the Hangzhou Asian Games in September 2015, the Hangzhou Asian Games has established the concept of &quot;green, smart, frugal and civilized&quot;. Green has become the main color and distinctive feature of the Hangzhou Asian Games. From venue planning and construction, overall energy utilization, to transportation support, and event organization and operation, the strong &quot;greenness&quot; is highlighted. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the birthplace of the concept of &quot;lucid waters and lush mountains are invaluable assets&quot;, Zhejiang has always put &quot;green&quot; at the top of its agenda during the preparation process. The &quot;Waste-Free Asian Games Action Plan&quot; was released, and the construction of 16 &quot;Waste-Free Asian Games Cells&quot; demonstration sites was promoted, striving to create the world&#39;s first large-scale &quot;Waste-Free&quot; event; &quot;scenery&quot; thousands of miles away was sent to the Asian Games venue , &quot;green electricity&quot; lights up 56 competition venues... Green concepts are integrated into every aspect of the Asian Games preparations, allowing the world to see &quot;China&#39;s innovation and action in using green to depict the future.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The concept of smart hosting was proposed for the first time in the history of the Asian Games. Many scientific and technological achievements and cutting-edge technologies have been widely used in the entire process of Asian Games preparations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At this Asian Games, the power of intelligence can be fully felt in all aspects such as venue security, event operation, and cloud services. The Asian Games core system built on cloud computing technology builds a powerful data processing platform for athletes, staff, spectators, etc.; spectators enjoy the Asian Games through the &quot;Smart Asian Games One-Stop&quot;; the &quot;Asian Games PASS&quot; realizes scenic spots, cultural museums and public transportation One-yard pass on the subway; &quot;Digital Torchbearers&quot; allow everyone to participate in the Asian Games...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Hangzhou Asian Games is not only &quot;high-end&quot;, but also particularly &quot;down-to-earth&quot;. From plans for renovating and building new venues, to recycling a piece of paper or a pen, the concept of &quot;running the Asian Games frugally&quot; is deeply rooted in the hearts of the people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The construction of venues generally follows the principle of &quot;renovation if possible, not construction&quot;. 44 of the 56 competition venues are renovated or temporarily built venues, and all 31 training venues are renovated venues; event-related facilities and equipment &quot;can &quot;Borrow or rent, rent or buy&quot; and recycle as much as possible; staff bring their own water bottles and eat simple buffet meals to reduce paper waste; the low-carbon version of the mascot of the franchised product retail store reduces the outer packaging of the carton... Simple and simple Simple, put more resources into optimizing services, and the host&#39;s clever &quot;subtraction&quot; has greatly &quot;added points&quot; to the competition. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first thing guests who come from afar feel is the atmosphere of the host city. In today&#39;s Zhijiang land, everyone is a host, there is Asian flavor everywhere, and the city is full of civilization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hangzhou has carried out in-depth the three major improvement actions of &quot;urban quality, urban governance, and urban civilization&quot; in preparation for the Asian Games, holding more than 10,000 related activities; Ningbo has overall planned and promoted urban civilization improvement actions to demonstrate urban civilization, rural A new look for civilized customs and civilized competitions; the renovation and upgrade of the Shaoxing Olympic Sports Center Gymnasium focuses on humanistic care, and people with disabilities can smoothly reach barrier-free seats through assistive devices... Both internal and external improvements give the city a new look. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strive for excellence in big things, consider every little detail in small details, and the four major game hosting concepts have been implemented from paper to reality. Welcoming guests and friends from all over the world with the best appearance and the best environment, the Hangzhou Asian Games delivered high scores. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Urban development&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;More steps forward&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On September 16, the Fuxing Asian Games smart EMU train was officially put into operation carrying passengers. From car body painting to interior decoration, urban landscape elements such as Hangzhou&#39;s white walls and black tiles and the surging Qianjiang River are perfectly integrated with the Asian Games emblem, sports patterns and the main image color &quot;Rainbow Purple&quot;. During the Asian Games, this &quot;special train&quot; will connect the six cities hosting the games, making the interconnection between the various venues smoother. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A train reflects the changes brought to the host place by the Asian Games. Hold a meeting well and improve a city. From infrastructure renovation and comprehensive environmental management to the improvement of public services and the improvement of urban appearance, Hangzhou and the five co-organizing cities are advancing simultaneously. People living here are not only participants, witnesses, but also beneficiaries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In April 2020, the &quot;Hangzhou Asian Games City Action Plan Outline&quot; was released, proposing to create a healthy city, promote urban internationalization, upgrade infrastructure, protect green waters and green mountains, empower digital governance, and promote industrial development. There are 8 specific actions including quality, cultural city dissemination, and urban civilization co-construction. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Walking in today’s Zhejiang, urban portal areas and main roads have been fully optimized, streetscape facades, back streets and alleys have been comprehensively improved, and citizens’ civilized qualities have been comprehensively improved. Closely integrate the preparations for the Asian Games with accelerating the improvement of urban functions and enhancing people&#39;s livelihood and well-being to promote urban development to a new level. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Asian Games also brings about the further implementation of &quot;sports benefiting the people&quot;. At present, 51 Asian Games venues have determined their post-game operating units to &quot;return the venues to the people.&quot; On the &quot;Zheli Fitness&quot; application platform, 100% of public sports venues have been included in the &quot;National Fitness Map&quot;, and the vacancy rate of venues has been significantly reduced. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March this year, the 2023 Hangzhou Archery League was held at the Asian Games Shooting, Archery and Modern Pentathlon Competition Venue at the Silver Lake Sports Center in Fuyang, Hangzhou, allowing enthusiasts to feel the atmosphere of the Asian Games in advance. So far, more than 8 million people have participated in fitness exercises at various Asian Games venues. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taking the preparations for the Asian Games as an opportunity, building a higher-level national fitness public service system has blossomed in many places in Zhejiang. A large number of fitness venues are embedded in the &quot;people&#39;s living circle&quot;, and the idle space in the city has become a &quot;gold corner and silver edge&quot; for people to participate in daily exercise. The radiation effect of &quot;sports makes life better&quot; continues to be released. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Asian Games preparation practices that serve the people, benefit the people, facilitate the people, and benefit the people not only strongly promote the construction of a strong sports country and the construction of a healthy China, but also greatly enhance the happiness and sense of gain of urban and rural residents. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Asia Gathering&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Showing Unity&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2018, at the closing ceremony of the Asian Games in Jakarta, the stunning &quot;Hangzhou 8 Minutes&quot; A warm invitation from all Asia - the Hangzhou Asian Games is a stage for sports competitions, a platform for cultural exchanges, and a fun gathering. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一理念得到全亚洲的广泛支持和热烈响应。亚奥理事会45个国家和地区奥委会的代表团如约而至。多名外国领导人来华出席杭州亚运会开幕式。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;体育铺路搭桥，文明交流互鉴。一个个文化符号，勾勒出杭州亚运会的独特韵味——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从杭州良渚古城遗址公园大莫角山采集的亚运会火种，通过“薪火”火炬手手传递；吉祥物“江南忆”由“琮琮”“宸宸”“莲莲”3个机器人组成，分别代表良渚古城遗址、京杭大运河和西湖；会徽“潮涌”取自钱塘潮，奖牌“湖山”带有西湖意向……传统文化融入亚运设计，尽显杭州历史人文之美。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;杭州富阳水上运动中心以“山”为形、以“水”为韵，仿佛现代版《富春山居图》；绍兴柯桥羊山攀岩中心形似“蚕茧”，注入丝绸文化意蕴……亚运场馆融合地域特色，“诗画江南”的文化底蕴让人流连忘返。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;杭州亚运村里设置了“文化小屋”，从体验宋绣技艺、青瓷烧制，到品茶会友、欣赏篆刻，为各代表团成员开启“文化之旅”；钱塘江畔的亚洲花卉主题园，200余种花卉组成“亚洲花毯”；杭州市内各类“亚运人文体验点”共有50处……人文景观遍布街头，营造出浓浓的亚运氛围。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;透过亚运会这扇窗，世界再一次感知中国、读懂中国。泱泱大国的文化自信与时代内涵，借助亚运故事娓娓道来。这条筹办之路，既是兑现承诺、推动发展的过程，更是展示新时代中国历史性成就的过程。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奋进的中国与亚运会第三次携手，使得杭州亚运会筹办伊始就显示出勃勃生机。从3.76万名赛会志愿者“小青荷”，到148万余名城市志愿者，他们的微笑面庞，让杭州亚运会展现着阳光、开放、充满希望的蓬勃气息。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;杭州亚运会的筹办成果赢得国际社会广泛赞许。在第四十二届亚奥理事会全体大会上，新当选的亚奥理事会主席谢赫·塔拉勒·法赫德·萨巴赫说：“我相信杭州已经准备好了，这将是一届出色的亚运会。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在亚运会舞台上，体育精神与人文精神交相辉映，一曲和平与友谊的交响曲正在奏响——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;杭州亚运会项目数量多，涵盖武术、藤球、板球、卡巴迪等不同地域特色项目，彰显亚运体育文化的多元性和包容性，为70余年历史的亚运会注入新的活力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“心心相融，@未来”的杭州亚运会口号与“更快、更高、更强——更团结”的奥林匹克格言高度契合，寄托着面向未来、共建亚洲和人类命运共同体的美好愿望。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚运会凝聚起亚洲人民团结奋进之心。亚洲各国家和地区奥委会都把杭州亚运会列为本年度重要赛事，并期盼未来与中国进行更多体育合作。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以体育传递友谊，以文化凝聚力量，以交流共筑和平。当亚运圣火燃亮夜空，杭州亚运会正成为亚洲和全世界携手同行的重要契机，凝聚起同力共赢、同向未来的磅礴力量。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（本报记者李中文、郑轶、孙龙飞、窦皓、刘军国）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 聚力科技创新  深耕细分领域  为推进科技自立自强稳定产业链供应链发挥更大作用]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20230922_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月22日星期五&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;新华社北京9月21日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;中共中央政治局常委、国务院总理李强9月21日在北京市调研专精特新企业发展情况。他强调，要深入贯彻落实习近平总书记重要指示精神，进一步坚定信心、保持定力，支持广大专精特新企业聚力科技创新、深耕细分领域，为推进科技自立自强、稳定产业链供应链发挥更大作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李强首先来到北京长木谷医疗科技股份有限公司，听取骨科人工智能与手术机器人创新医疗器械产业发展情况介绍，走进模拟数字化手术室察看相关场景演示，对他们取得的技术创新成果表示赞赏，希望他们进一步加强人工智能辅助诊疗技术研发，推出更多优质产品和服务，让科技更好造福于民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在北京国科天迅科技股份有限公司，李强听取公司研发情况汇报，了解公司产品在重大装备、新能源汽车等领域的应用情况，对他们多年坚持自主研发给予充分肯定，勉励企业围绕国家重大需求，在前沿科技攻关上取得更大成果。李强要求有关方面在新产品新技术应用推广上加大支持力度，更好带动相关产业发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在北京华卓精科科技股份有限公司，李强详细了解关键核心技术攻关与产业化进展，并走进车间，细致察看产品核心部件和设备集成调试情况，与企业负责人就集成电路产业创新发展深入交流。他强调，必须坚定不移把一些关键技术、关键环节建立在能够独立自主的基础上，把发展的主动权牢牢掌握在自己手中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;座谈交流时，李强指出，我国经济正处在高质量发展爬坡过坎的重大关口，必须进一步增强发展信心，保持转型升级定力。专精特新企业的快速发展，充分体现了我国经济的强大韧性和活力。对专精特新企业来说，创新是灵魂所在。希望大家聚焦主业、咬定青山、苦练内功，大力推动科技创新，坚持走精耕细作之路，不断向高端化智能化绿色化转型，向产业链创新链价值链高端攀升。他强调，要进一步完善全要素的资源保障体系、全生命周期的服务管理体系和梯度成长的培育体系，针对企业在融资支持、税收优惠、准入门槛、产权保护、人才培养等方面的诉求，推出更加精准有效的政策，提供更加及时便利的服务。李强充分肯定北京市培育发展专精特新企业的举措和成效，希望北京市发挥科教资源丰富、产业基础雄厚等优势，进一步营造良好创新生态，为推进科技自立自强、推动高质量发展多作贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴政隆陪同调研。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 坚持稳中求进推动地方立法工作高质量发展]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20230922_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月22日星期五&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;新华社济南9月21日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;中共中央政治局常委、全国人大常委会委员长赵乐际近日在山东出席全国地方立法工作座谈会并调研。他强调，要深入学习贯彻习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想特别是习近平法治思想，全面贯彻党的二十大精神，认真实施新修改的立法法，总结地方立法工作成果和经验，稳中求进推动新时代地方立法工作高质量发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在19日召开的全国地方立法工作座谈会上，赵乐际指出，地方性法规是中国特色社会主义法律体系的重要组成部分，在全面依法治国中发挥着重要作用。要把握好地方立法工作正确政治方向，深刻领悟“两个确立”的决定性意义，增强“四个意识”、坚定“四个自信”、做到“两个维护”，把坚持党的全面领导贯彻落实到地方立法工作全过程各方面。把握好提高地方立法质量这个关键，遵循客观规律、立法规律，因需、应时、统筹、有序开展立法工作，成熟一个，出台一个。把握好地方立法的问题导向、实践导向、目标导向，坚持不抵触、有特色、可操作原则，保证各项法规立得住、行得通、真管用。把握好地方立法践行全过程人民民主要求，使立法过程成为满足人民需要、扩大人民参与、接受人民监督的生动民主实践。把握好人大在地方立法工作中的主导作用，把好立项关、起草关、审议关。把握好维护国家法治统一的宪法原则，坚持依宪立法、依法立法，在职责范围内做好监督法律实施、备案审查、法规清理等工作。把握好地方立法能力建设的重要任务，突出抓好人才培养、智力支持、技术支撑，提高地方立法工作队伍和人才队伍建设水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;18日至21日，赵乐际先后到济南、威海、潍坊等地进行调研。在省人大常委会机关，看望机关干部，了解预算国资联网监督、代表工作情况；深入基层人大代表工作站、联络站，走进村民家中，与代表和群众深入交流，听取大家的意见建议。他强调，人民代表大会制度是国家根本政治制度，人大工作是党和国家工作的重要组成部分，一定要自觉坚持稳中求进，努力实现高质量发展。要紧紧围绕新时代新征程中心任务，守正创新、求真务实，认真行使宪法法律赋予的各项职权，扎实做好每一项工作。地方人大工作要服从服务党和国家事业全局，结合实际，讲求实效，更好助力经济社会发展和改革攻坚任务。要以“两个联系”为抓手深化拓展代表工作，支持人大代表更好联系群众，发挥好“纽带”作用和专业特长，加强各级代表协同联动，共同推动解决群众关心的突出问题。全国人大和地方人大要同题共答、同向发力，不断提升新时代人大工作质量和水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 第九次全国对口支援新疆工作会议召开]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20230922_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月22日星期五&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;本报喀什9月21日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者赵兵）第九次全国对口支援新疆工作会议19日至21日在新疆喀什召开。中共中央政治局常委、全国政协主席王沪宁出席并讲话。他表示，要以习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想为指导，完整准确全面贯彻新时代党的治疆方略，牢牢把握新疆社会稳定和长治久安总目标，聚焦铸牢中华民族共同体意识主线，以高度责任感和使命感推动对口援疆工作更高质量开展，在中国式现代化进程中更好建设美丽新疆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王沪宁表示，新时代对口援疆工作取得显著成效，积累了宝贵经验。中央有关部门、支援省市和中央企业同新疆加强协调配合，对口援疆投入资金之巨、参与人员之多、覆盖领域之广、取得成效之大前所未有，彰显了党的领导的政治优势和中国特色社会主义制度的巨大优越性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王沪宁表示，对口援疆是国家战略，必须坚持全面援疆、精准援疆、长期援疆。要持续深入推进以就业为导向的产业援疆，加快构建体现新疆特色优势的现代化产业体系，推动新疆经济高质量发展。要持续深入推进教育援疆，助推新疆建设高质量教育体系。要持续深入推进干部人才交流合作，推动援疆干部人才担当作为。要持续深入推进各民族交往交流交融，坚持增进民族团结、广泛凝聚人心的定位，有形有感有效铸牢中华民族共同体意识。要持续深入推进文化润疆，增进各族群众对伟大祖国、中华民族、中华文化、中国共产党、中国特色社会主义的认同。要加强对口援疆工作组织领导，不断提升对口援疆综合效益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马兴瑞、姜信治出席会议。石泰峰主持会议并作总结讲话。他表示各地区各部门要提高政治站位，全面贯彻落实习近平总书记重要讲话精神，准确把握新疆工作在强国建设、民族复兴全局中的战略定位，切实把思想和行动统一到党中央决策部署上来，科学谋划、扎实推进新时代新征程对口援疆工作。坚持问题导向，聚焦重点领域，营造良好环境，完善工作规划，推动对口援疆在天山南北取得新的更大成效。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;19个援疆省市、中央有关部门和单位、新疆维吾尔自治区、新疆生产建设兵团及地州市师和有关部门负责同志出席会议。中央组织部、中央宣传部、国家发展改革委、工业和信息化部和北京、天津、上海、江苏、浙江、福建、山东、河南、广东、新疆维吾尔自治区、新疆生产建设兵团负责同志在会上发言。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在新疆期间，王沪宁还到伊犁、喀什、克孜勒苏和兵团第四师等地调研，看望援疆干部和基层群众。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 图片报道]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20230922_7-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月22日星期五&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20230922/1695328280469_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;近年来，江西省上栗县坚持生态优先、绿色发展，积极推进生态文明建设，不断厚植高质量发展绿色底色。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;上栗县开展低碳村、社区试点创建工作，实施“绿化上栗”工程，去年完成植树造林2万亩，管护天然林3.9万亩，生态环境持续向好，群众获得感、幸福感不断增强。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;图为近日上栗县上栗镇的良好生态风貌。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;本报记者&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;陈&amp;nbsp;斌摄&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 读懂中国之理  凝聚奋进之力（今日谈）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20230922_8-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月22日星期五&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;近日，由中央宣传部理论局组织编写的《中国式现代化面对面》在全国发行。作为“理论热点面对面”系列通俗理论读物的最新读本，该书用朴素语言阐释深刻道理，用生动故事讲解时代主题，有助于帮助广大干部群众更好把握中国式现代化的中国特色、本质要求和重大原则。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;理论只要彻底，就能说服人。从如何理解习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想是全面推进强国建设、民族复兴的科学指引，到如何理解以中国式现代化全面推进中华民族伟大复兴，《中国式现代化面对面》集中回答和阐释了17个重大问题，力求讲清讲透中国式现代化深厚的历史底蕴、广泛的现实基础和光明的发展前景。以丰富多样的形式、深入浅出的解读，解思想之渴，答实践之惑，就能更好地让党的创新理论“飞入寻常百姓家”。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;读懂中国之理，凝聚奋进之力。在中国式现代化这条强国建设、民族复兴的康庄大道上，每个人都是参与者，每个人都是追梦人。用党的创新理论武装头脑，在理论上更清醒，在行动上更坚决，我们定能汇聚起万众一心、攻坚克难的强大力量，谱写出中国式现代化更加绚丽的华章。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 可持续交通取得长足进步（权威发布）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20230922_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月22日星期五&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;“交通是经济的脉络和文明的纽带，可持续交通是高质量发展的重要内容。党的十八大以来，在以习近平同志为核心的党中央坚强领导下，我国可持续交通取得长足进步，迈入高质量发展新阶段。”在9月21日举行的国务院新闻办新闻发布会上，交通运输部副部长李扬介绍了我国交通可持续发展情况并回应社会关切。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 国家综合立体交通网主骨架空间格局基本形成&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“可持续交通，更多是把安全、便捷、绿色、高效、经济、包容、韧性作为发展方向。”李扬介绍，近年来，我国可持续交通发展主要呈现以下特点——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;看硬件，现代化高质量综合立体交通网加快建设。我国已建成全球最大的高速铁路网、高速公路网、邮政快递网和世界级港口群，“6轴7廊8通道”国家综合立体交通网主骨架空间格局基本形成，各种运输方式衔接效率不断提升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;看服务，综合交通运输服务水平不断提升。当前，我国已成为世界上运输最繁忙的国家之一，铁路、公路、水路、民航的客货周转量、港口货物吞吐量等指标均居世界前列。具备条件的乡镇和建制村全部通硬化路、通客车、通邮路，空铁等旅客联程运输服务不断完善。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;看科技，交通运输科创能力持续提高。杭绍甬智慧高速公路、京杭运河智慧航道等一批交通新基建应用场景逐步落地。国产大飞机C919正式交付。智慧物流技术在邮政快递业加快应用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;看绿色，交通运输绿色低碳发展成效显著。一方面，通过大力发展多式联运，持续深化运输结构调整；另一方面，低碳交通设施装备也在加快应用。截至去年底，全国铁路电气化率达73.8%，新能源城市公交车超过54万辆，新能源出租汽车超30万辆，新能源城市配送车辆超过80万辆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;看国际化，交通运输国际交流合作持续深化。目前，中欧班列已通达欧洲25个国家和地区的200多个城市，中国国际道路运输协定合作范围拓展至21个国家，水路国际运输航线已覆盖100多个国家和地区，民航与64个国家保持定期客货运通航，邮政快递业务通达220多个国家和地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;全球可持续交通高峰论坛将在京举办&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，可持续交通已成为全球的共同行动。9月25日至26日，以“可持续交通：携手合作助力全球发展”为主题的2023全球可持续交通高峰论坛将在北京举办。李扬介绍，论坛预计将取得以下重要成果——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一是发布中方关于推进全球发展倡议、落实联合国2030年可持续发展议程、推动可持续交通发展自主贡献的“北京倡议”，目前已有多个国家同意加入倡议。二是发布《2022年中国可持续交通发展报告》。三是发起设立全球可持续交通创新联盟。目前已有42家国内外知名企业同意共同作为发起单位。四是签署多个交通领域双多边合作文件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全球可持续交通高峰论坛举行期间，以“交通天下&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;创新引领”为主题的第十五届国际交通技术与设备展览会也将同步举办。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“展会致力于展示交通先进技术设备和最新创新成果，为国内外综合交通及相关领域企业和地方政府部门交流合作搭建平台，促进全球交通交流合作。”交通运输部科技司司长岑晏青介绍，此次展览有两大看点：一是领域全。展会设置了综合交通基础设施建设、交通运输高端制造、国际物流供应链系统、绿色低碳交通、地方交通高质量发展、未来交通等六大展区，全方位展示全球综合交通运输可持续发展的最新成果。二是层次高。来自14个国家的88家交通运输头部企业和机构参展，涵盖了铁路、公路、水运、民航、邮政等各种交通运输方式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 自动驾驶技术实现一定规模应用&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为智能交通的创新热点，自动驾驶既是加快建设交通强国的重要引擎，也是发展可持续交通的主要领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“近年来，我国自动驾驶技术不断提升，产业体系逐步完善。”岑晏青介绍，经过产学研用各方共同努力，目前，面向部分场景的自动驾驶技术逐渐进入细分领域，特别是在城市出行服务、港口作业等场景，自动驾驶技术已实现一定规模应用，场景级解决方案加速成熟。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为更好发挥场景创新对技术和产业的带动作用，去年，交通运输部启动实施了智能交通先导应用试点。“首批试点在自动驾驶领域布局了14项试点任务，上百家创新主体积极参与，投入各类自动驾驶车辆千余台，试点工作取得阶段性成效。”岑晏青说，在论坛期间，交通运输部将同步举办自动驾驶主题边会，并集中发布一批典型案例。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，以国家公交都市建设和绿色出行创建为载体，交通运输部深入实施城市公共交通优先发展战略，鼓励引导绿色出行，加快构建以公共交通为主体的城市绿色出行服务体系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据介绍，目前，全国74个城市通过验收并被命名为“国家公交都市建设示范城市”，全国97个城市通过绿色出行创建考核评价，绿色出行比例达到70%以上，绿色出行服务满意率达到80%以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，我国可持续交通发展步伐加快，下一步将从加快建设现代化高质量综合立体交通网、着力提升服务品质和效率、大力发展智慧交通和智慧物流、推动交通绿色低碳转型及深化交通运输国际合作交流等方面继续发力，全力推进可持续交通高质量发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 强筋壮骨  铸就发展新优势]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20230922_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月22日星期五&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;这是持续夯实的发展根基——制造业规模连续13年居世界首位，2022年我国全部工业增加值突破40万亿元大关……实体经济持续壮大，让大国发展固本培元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是不断构筑的竞争优势——加快建设现代化产业体系，持续放大创新第一动力，新动能不断积蓄，为实现高质量发展注入动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;党的十八大以来，我国将推进新型工业化作为全面建成社会主义现代化强国的关键支撑。做强做优做大实体经济，加快构建以先进制造业为骨干的现代化产业体系。工业体系更健全、产业结构更优、数字技术与实体经济加速融合。新型工业化扎实推进，为中国经济强筋壮骨，不断培育起新的竞争力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;把牢实体经济这个着力点，现代化产业体系迈出坚实步伐&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;8月份，全国规模以上工业增加值同比增长4.5%，增速比上月加快0.8个百分点。集成电路、光电子器件、新能源汽车等先进制造业增幅明显，凸显引擎作用。正是因为工业的持续恢复，牢牢稳住了中国经济的基本盘。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;工业是综合国力的根基、经济发展的“压舱石”。越是面对复杂多变的外部环境和风险挑战，越要筑牢这个坚实支撑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;党中央高度重视实体经济特别是制造业的发展，明确坚持把发展经济的着力点放在实体经济上，深入推进新型工业化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以制造业为根本、巩固完整产业体系优势、加快建设现代化产业体系、推进信息化和工业化深度融合，我国制造大国地位更加稳固，新型工业化步伐不断加快。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;看基本面：2012年到2022年，我国全部工业增加值从20.9万亿元增长到突破40万亿元大关，占GDP比重达到33.2%；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;看体系：拥有41个工业大类、207个工业中类、666个工业小类，500种主要工业产品中有四成以上产品产量位居世界第一；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;看竞争力：新能源汽车、光伏产量连续多年保持世界第一，45个国家先进制造业集群纵横铺设，构建全球最大5G商用网络，不断拓展物联网、人工智能等创新应用……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从实施产业基础再造工程，增强产业链韧性，到大力推进重大技术装备攻关工程，提高产业链核心能力，再到引导中小企业向专精特新发展，塑造发展新动能新优势，我国把打造自主可控、安全可靠、竞争力强的现代化产业体系作为推进新型工业化的重点，坚定不移筑牢实体经济根基。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“党的十八大以来，我国新型工业化步伐显著加快。”工业和信息化部部长金壮龙表示，工业规模稳步壮大、产业结构持续优化、数字化绿色化转型不断推进，聚焦新型工业化持续发力，不断夯实中国经济根基。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 向“新”而行，加快推动中国制造向中国创造转变&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;红色工业机器人挥舞手臂，精准对上百公斤工件抓取、定位、安放；移动机器人，有条不紊地进行仓储、物流、装配、检测……走进沈阳新松机器人自动化股份有限公司的车间，不同种类的机器人和高度自动化的产线，让智能制造的体验扑面而来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是我国加快制造业高端化发展的生动写照。工业和信息化部数据显示，2022年，我国高技术制造业、装备制造业占规模以上工业增加值的比重分别为15.5%、31.8%，65家制造业企业入围世界500强企业榜单。截至目前已累计培育5批1.2万余家专精特新“小巨人”企业，带动地方培育近9万家专精特新中小企业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以创新作为新型工业化的核心驱动力，中国制造加速奔向中国创造。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;C919大型客机投入商业运营；国产首艘大型邮轮顺利出坞；“东数西算”工程8个国家算力枢纽节点建设全部开工……近年来，一系列重大工程亮相，成为我国工业重点领域不断突破、产业结构持续优化的生动写照。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;杭州亚运会召开在即，9月16日7时35分，一道“虹韵紫”穿梭于山海间，串联起杭州与宁波、温州、金华、绍兴、湖州5座亚运协办城市，复兴号亚运智能动车组列车正式载客运营。新方案缓解列车跨越丘陵山地颠簸感、车内气压与温度自动调节……高铁领域不断突破的新技术，印证着中国制造创新的步伐。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;化解过剩产能、加快技术改造，传统产业焕发新活力；工业互联网、大数据等新一代信息技术与制造业融合发展，不断催生新产业新业态新模式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数据显示，近年来，我国技术改造投资占工业投资比重持续稳定在40%以上，重点领域研究与试验发展经费投入强度稳步提高。2022年规模以上工业企业研究与试验发展经费达19361.8亿元，比上年增长10.5%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国务院发展研究中心宏观经济研究部研究室主任杨光普表示，我国工业向高端化和高附加值方向积极迈进，向智能化和服务化转型步伐日益加快。“通过提高制造业&#39;含金&#39;&#39;含智&#39;&#39;含绿&#39;量，进一步夯实中国经济根基。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 补短板锻长板，持续构筑竞争新优势&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“2021年，我第一次参加论坛闭门会时，会场上50%的厂商是我们的客户；去年则是70%。这次闭门会我又算了一下，是100%。”7月在上海举行的2023中国汽车论坛上，国产车规级AI芯片厂商地平线创始人余凯感慨良多，“这个进步是实实在在的！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从50%到100%，是产业链不断走向自主可控的生动缩影。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大国工业，拥有稳定且高竞争力的产业链至关重要。新型工业化，关键要打造新竞争力。我国已拥有全球最完整的产业体系，但大而不强、全而不精的问题依然存在。夯实产业基础，努力在重点领域、关键环节实现自主可控，成为推进新型工业化的重要着力点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;提高产业链核心能力，实施产业基础再造工程和重大技术装备攻关工程；增强产业链控制力，培育更多具有国际竞争力的龙头企业和单项冠军企业，引导中小企业向专精特新发展；补齐短板、拉长长板、锻造新板，增强产业发展的接续性和竞争力……近年来，一系列着眼于夯实产业基础、提升产业韧性、增强内生动力的重要举措不断推出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我国高度重视产业链稳定性和竞争力，增加研发投入，国内相关行业已取得一定突破和成就。”中国企业联合会标准化工作委员会副主任陈玉涛说，新能源汽车产业链中的262个重点环节，国内厂商可供给的环节比例已达85.88%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新型工业化，同样“新”在格局的重塑。近年来，不少地方打破传统思维，积极构建创新生态，将自身融入区域协调发展，拓宽拓深发展空间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在湖北武汉东湖高新区的“中国光谷”，多家光电子信息产业领军企业拔节生长；安徽合肥加快布局“芯屏器合”产业战略；湖南工程机械、先进轨道交通产业竞争力显著增强……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;最新数据显示，我国在新一代信息技术、高端装备、新材料、新能源等领域建成了45个国家先进制造业集群，主导产业总产值达20万亿元。“我们把发展先进制造业集群摆到更加突出位置，更加着眼于产业基础能力和产业链整体实力的提升，加快建设现代化产业体系。”工业和信息化部有关负责人说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我国拥有庞大的市场、完整的产业体系和齐备的配套能力，其中蕴藏了无数创新的力量。紧紧扣住高质量这个关键词，扎实推进新型工业化，将不断增强工业发展新动能，谱写制造强国建设新篇章。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（新华社北京9月21日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;记者张辛欣、魏玉坤、邹多为、高亢）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - “江淮粮仓”动力足（打好夺取秋粮丰收这场硬仗）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20230922_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月22日星期五&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;稻田青青，一带山田放水声。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;早上6点刚过，安徽省霍邱县扈胡镇新六里村种粮大户李华东就下田忙着灌水。“现在正是水稻生长关键时期，扬花、灌浆最不能缺的就是水。”李华东用手机打开闸口阀门，“入秋以来，光热条件好，雨水又充沛，我种的1100多亩水稻分蘖多、长势好。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安徽是粮食主产省，也是粮食净调出大省。“茬茬压实、环环紧扣、一招不落，眼下全省6400多万亩秋粮长势良好，夺取秋粮丰收有基础、有条件、有信心。”安徽省农业农村厅厅长汪学军说，据农情调度，预计全年完成粮食播种面积10990万亩，产量有望超820亿斤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;严格落实粮食安全党政同责，稳面积、提单产、增效益，创新农业经营方式，推动种植业结构调整，安徽各地粮食生产动力澎湃，正向着全面建成“千亿斤江淮粮仓”目标奋力迈进。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 建良田、广示范、强服务&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;夯实粮食产能基础&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;站在丰乐河支流肖小河河堤上，农田一眼望不到边。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这个示范项目有5600多亩。以前这里田块高低不齐、大小不一，最小的仅0.2亩。”从“零碎”到“平川”，肥西县丰乐镇农办副主任张健见证了变化：田成方、路成网、渠相通、沟相连，粮食产量明显提升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高标准农田建设、高产示范区创建多管齐下，小田变大田。截至2022年底，全省已建成高标准农田超6000万亩。按照规划，到2030年，安徽将完成6750万亩高标准农田的建设目标，加快建设一批旱涝保收、稳产高产示范田。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;做给农民看，带着农民干。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“丰两优香1号”“乐优香丝1号”……霍邱县扈胡镇和平村，一块种子试验田里有34个优质水稻品种。粮农自发来观摩，自己“挑”来年要选种的品种。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安徽省农业农村厅种植业局二级调研员吴志伟说：“专业化生产，就要把农技送到田间地头。每个品种都是农业科技工作者的心血，他们把农业科技论文写在大地上。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;和平村5000亩省级粮食生产指挥田里，再生稻长势喜人。安徽省农技总站高级农艺师孔令娟说：“通过选播良种、科学管理，今年平均亩产预计能达900公斤，每亩节本增效200元。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据了解，“江淮粮仓”加快科技强农，今年全省选派科技特派员1万人以上，实现所有行政村全覆盖。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;深入实施藏粮于地、藏粮于技战略，提升粮食单产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年，安徽在全省建设25个省市县三级共建优质专用粮油指挥田和125个精耕细作示范点。积极开展绿色高产高效行动，突出产能提升最迫切、单产提升潜力最大的玉米和大豆，选择基础条件好、示范带动性强的县，建设21个粮油作物“吨粮田”“吨半粮”优势区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行走在“江淮粮仓”，处处感受到创新农业经营方式的热潮涌动。推进规模化经营、专业化生产、社会化服务，粮农挑上“金扁担”，粮食产能基础越夯越实。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;合作社、家庭农场在社会化服务中大显身手。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在宿州市灰古镇碾盘村，种粮大户张练的50亩早熟玉米已经成熟，穿梭于田间的收割机正把一穗穗玉米棒收入“囊中”。田埂上，张练站在一旁，喜上眉梢。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张练年纪轻、脑筋活，种地之初就向当地的精松农机服务专业合作社购买了社会化服务。“买种、田管、收割……合作社全程负责。”张练说，通过托管，种子、肥料更便宜，每亩成本省下60多元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安徽各地因地制宜，支持各类服务主体集中连片开展单环节、多环节、全程托管等服务，推动节本增效和农民增收。目前，安徽有农业社会化服务组织5.5万个，服务面积2.44亿亩次，带动农户超过450万户。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 稳水稻、稳玉米、扩大豆&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;结构调整不断优化&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;调整种植结构，向种植结构要粮食生产能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一垄地，4排玉米，6排大豆，这样的带状复合种植，我是经验不足。多亏技术人员一直跟进指导，不然哪来这么好的长势？”宿州市埇桥区杨庄弘宇家庭农场负责人朱洪甫说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“有搞头！你看，光种玉米一亩收600公斤，今年这一亩地能收550公斤玉米、120公斤大豆，算大账，一亩地能多挣600元。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;带状复合种植先选种。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在埇桥区农业科技示范展示基地，70个玉米品种、70个大豆品种、40种大豆玉米带状复合种植品种组合正在进行实验。“种子必须选好，玉米要找能密植、抗倒伏的，大豆要挑能密植、抗病强的。”埇桥区农科所副所长李永说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;接下来，是田管。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“从去年开始，我们搞了不少新种法，效果不错，比如及时处理前茬、种肥同播、水肥管理。”埇桥区农技推广中心主任程立军说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前，埇桥区镇两级农业技术部门都下沉一线，街镇包村，村组包户，做到技术人员到户、技术要领到人、技术措施到田，全区带状复合种植的面积超过8.9万亩。据了解，今年“三秋”生产，安徽在皖北等主产区落实了110万亩大豆玉米带状复合种植。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大豆玉米带状复合种植，一田双收，提高了粮食综合生产能力。稳玉米，扩大豆，今年安徽省财政统筹11亿元用于支持粮食生产，安排2.5亿元对300亩以上的种粮主体进行专项支持。在国家对带状复合种植每亩补贴150元的基础上，省级财政每亩叠加补贴50元，还每亩补贴保费10元，并鼓励市县每亩各叠加补贴50元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多打粮，打好粮，结构调整要向绿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如何种好优质稻米？“江淮粮仓”突出绿色导向。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;走进霍邱县三流乡双塔村种粮大户李德龙家，墙边整齐地摆着一排排虾笼。问到秋粮生产情况，老李笑着说：“俺流转了300多亩稻田，今年风调雨顺，稻子好，虾也好。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;老李说：“俺种的优质稻预计亩产能到1300斤。绿色种养，稻田不投化肥农药，病虫害少。刚收了18万斤中稻，大头在晚稻，正在灌浆呢！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三流乡水稻面积10.3万亩，其中稻虾田面积9.8万亩，再生稻面积1.2万亩左右。乡里积极探索农业产业结构调整，大力推行“无环沟繁养一体稻虾综合种养”模式，成了当地的“龙虾第一乡”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至8月底，安徽全省新增稻渔综合种养面积84万亩，总面积达到717万亩。紧紧依托当地资源禀赋，因地制宜推进结构调整，给“江淮粮仓”添了新动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;稳预期、种好粮、卖好价&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;让农民种粮有钱赚&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;提高农民种粮积极性，是加快建设“千亿斤江淮粮仓”的一道必答题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政策给力，稳定农民种粮预期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“购置农机补贴30%，种粮还有补贴，这种粮呀，很踏实！”走进凤阳县小溪河镇小岗村种粮大户程夕兵家的稻田，沁人心脾的稻花香扑鼻而来。这些年，一系列强农惠农政策直达田间地头，让程夕兵劲头越来越足。今年，他流转了750多亩地，其中620亩种上了水稻，订单早就落实了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“土地确权颁证，推动经营权流转，让新型农业经营主体吃上定心丸。”小岗村党委第一书记李锦柱说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;眼下，小岗村1.4万亩秋粮长势喜人，又将迎来粮食丰收。据凤阳县农技人员测产，预计全村秋粮总产量可达760万公斤，其中，1万亩水稻单产有望创历史新高，总产量可达600万公斤以上，优质专用品种达100%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;好粮食卖出好价格，粮农种粮心气高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“再生稻生长期短、成本低，最大特点是一稻两收，省时省工，降低了种植成本。”站在田埂上，郎溪县钟桥街道金桥村村民岑六子跟记者算起了账，“今年头茬稻产量每亩1200多斤，二茬稻预估达400多斤，刨去插秧、除草、收割等成本，亩均可增收300元。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;话里话外，听得出岑六子对再生稻信心满满。钟桥街道在确保双季稻面积的基础上，依托辖区种粮大户、专业合作社，今年因地制宜推广再生稻1450亩，预计增加收入40万元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;富了脑袋才能富口袋，粮农的日子一年更比一年好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;眼下，太湖县40万亩水稻陆续进入抽穗灌浆期。排水清沟、统防统治，太湖县徐桥镇桥东村种植大户刘小保忙个不停。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我流转的850亩地中，500亩被选作安徽省精耕细作示范田，每亩至少提产100斤。”联系好订单生产，是刘小保很得意的事。今年通过订单生产，水稻每斤高出6分钱，里里外外算下来，至少多挣10多万元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我今年提前参加了农机收割减损培训，也来当新农人！”凤台县丁集镇考庄村粮农考传书深有感触。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有甜头才会有干劲。近年来，安徽省全面推行“按图索粮”和订单化生产，发展优质专用粮，有效对接供需。今年秋粮结构中，优质专用稻占比超过八成，为粮食增产、农民增收打下了坚实基础。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;江淮大地，“三秋”正忙。安徽各地干部群众奋力扛起粮食安全责任，全力夺取秋粮丰收，为大国粮仓贡献更多更优质“安徽粮”。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 22 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>