<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 数字技术赋能江苏制造转型升级]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/10/nw.D110000renmrb_20231110_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 10, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: “We must insist on focusing our economic development on the real economy and further promote new industrialization. Strengthen the reengineering of the industrial base and research on major technical equipment, promote the high-end, intelligent, and green development of the manufacturing industry, accelerate the construction of a strong manufacturing province, vigorously develop strategic emerging industries, and accelerate the development of the digital economy.&quot;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Jiangsu Deeply implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech and the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, regard the digital economy as a key increment of transformation and development, comprehensively promote industrial digitalization and digital industrialization, promote the integrated development of the digital economy and the real economy, accelerate industrial transformation and upgrading, and focus on Create an internationally competitive advanced manufacturing base. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Accelerating the intelligent transformation and digital transformation of traditional manufacturing industries is an important focus for Jiangsu to promote high-quality development of manufacturing industries. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;On the inspection assembly line, there is only a flash of bright light. 60 sets of visual probes continuously scan relevant parts, and some small defects can be accurately captured. This is the production workshop of Jiangsu Jingyan Technology Co., Ltd. in Changzhou, which uses testing equipment provided by Changzhou Weiyi Intelligent Manufacturing Technology Co., Ltd. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“This kind of metal injection molded parts are mainly used in mobile phones and smart wearable devices. In the past, manual inspection was time-consuming and laborious.” Pan Zhengyi, head of Weiyi Intelligent Manufacturing, said that with the help of big data and artificial intelligence, Automation equipment can now inspect 9,000 products per hour, &quot;equivalent to the workload of 1,200 skilled workers. Digital empowerment can increase efficiency by about 30 times.&quot;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The changes do not stop here. With the support of the local party committee and government, Weiyi Intelligent Manufacturing also provides intelligent testing solutions to more than 200 industrial enterprises. In the past, it took brand owners more than half a year to select products, customize designs, find manufacturers, and go to market. Now, in the &quot;virtual factory&quot; created by Weiyi Intelligent Manufacturing, these procedures can be completed online in one stop. It will be put into production within days. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Grebo (Jiangsu) Co., Ltd. relies on the data advantages of Weiyi Intelligent Manufacturing to &quot;reverse&quot; from the consumer side and &quot;reuse&quot; the off-season production lines. Greebo produces small household appliances washing machines during idle periods. The all-in-one machine received orders for 50,000 units in a single month. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;To provide solid support for the intelligent transformation and digital transformation of the manufacturing industry, Jiangsu is planning ahead and promoting the construction of new infrastructure such as industrial Internet platforms and logo analysis, data centers, and 5G. In the past three years, Jiangsu has invested more than 100 billion yuan in the construction of new information infrastructure, deeply promoted the transformation and upgrading project of the industrial Internet &quot;enterprise-enterprise connection&quot;, and accelerated 5G and gigabit optical fiber services to &quot;connect parks, enter enterprises, enter workshops, connect equipment, Expand the market”. Jiangsu ranks among the top in the country in terms of industrial Internet application development. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Adhering to efforts from both the research and development and application levels, Jiangsu is accelerating to improve the independent controllability of intelligent hardware, equipment, and industrial software. At Xuzhou Handler Special Vehicle Co., Ltd., an automatic working robot can carry out intelligent operations such as maintenance and replacement when the power grid is uninterrupted. All its parts are independently developed. In Nanjing, an industrial control operating system owned by Yihui Information Group has achieved 100% independent code rate after more than 10 years of independent research and development. At present, Jiangsu is focusing on researching a number of key core technologies of industrial software, promoting their demonstration applications in agricultural machinery, intelligent equipment, electric power and energy and other industries to help industrial development. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Jiangsu classification promotes the overall improvement of the digitalization, networking and intelligence level of the manufacturing industry in stages. For leading enterprises in the industry, implement the construction of smart manufacturing demonstration factories, formulate guidelines for the construction of industrial Internet benchmark factories, carry out the cultivation of 5G fully connected factories, and create a digital leading enterprise with international leadership. For small and medium-sized enterprises, we have compiled implementation guidelines for intelligent transformation and digital transformation in 12 industries, including mechanical processing, clothing, and chemicals, and implemented an intelligent manufacturing consulting system for specialized, specialized, and innovative small and medium-sized enterprises. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In Wuxi, &quot;Xuelangyun&quot; provides the &quot;factory brain&quot; for the transformation and upgrading of the manufacturing industry. In Suzhou, the application of big data enables automatic matching of &quot;policy gift packages&quot;. Through ten major actions such as docking diagnosis, benchmarking demonstration, and classification promotion, the manufacturing industry is accelerating the completion of intelligent transformation and digital transformation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Since last year, Jiangsu industrial enterprises have implemented more than 50,000 intelligent transformation and digital transformation projects, of which 19,000 enterprises have completed transformation projects, driving about 400,000 small and medium-sized enterprises to migrate to the cloud. &quot;Made in Jiangsu&quot; is accelerating its transformation into &quot;Made in Jiangsu Intelligent Manufacturing&quot;, and 10 national advanced manufacturing clusters have emerged, including engineering machinery, the Internet of Things, and new nanomaterials. In 2022, the added value of the province&#39;s manufacturing industry will be approximately 4.6 trillion yuan, accounting for 37.3% of the regional GDP, ranking among the top in the country in both total volume and proportion. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平就柬埔寨王国独立70周年分别向柬埔寨国王西哈莫尼、柬埔寨人民党主席洪森致贺电]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/10/nw.D110000renmrb_20231110_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 10, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 9th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;On November 9th, President Xi Jinping announced the 70th anniversary of the independence of the Kingdom of Cambodia. Send a congratulatory message to Cambodian King Norodom Sihamoni on the anniversary. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that in recent years, the Cambodian people have adhered to a development path that suits their own national conditions and have continuously made new achievements in national construction. As a traditional friendly neighbor, China will, as always, firmly support Cambodia in maintaining stability, promoting development and improving people&#39;s livelihood. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that this year marks the 65th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and Cambodia and the Year of China-Cambodia Friendship. We met cordially in Beijing and Hangzhou to jointly draw up a blueprint for a China-Cambodia community with a shared future. I attach great importance to the development of China-Cambodia relations and am willing to work with King Norodom Sihamoni to strengthen strategic guidance on the relations between the two countries and jointly build a high-quality, high-level and high-standard China-Cambodia community with a shared future in the new era. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;On the same day, Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, sent a congratulatory message to Hun Sen, Chairman of the Cambodian People’s Party. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 发展优先  安危与共  文明互鉴]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/10/nw.D110000renmrb_20231110_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 10, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;On November 8, President Xi Jinping delivered a video speech to the opening ceremony of the Wuzhen Summit of the 2023 World Internet Conference. Guests at the meeting and people from all walks of life said that President Xi Jinping&#39;s video speech fully reflected his profound thinking on the development wave of global digitalization and informatization, strengthened confidence and pointed out the direction for the development of the world&#39;s Internet, and will promote the construction of a more inclusive and prosperous, peaceful, secure, and equal world. An inclusive cyberspace allows digital civilization to continue to benefit mankind and the results of Internet development to benefit people of all countries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Prioritize development and build a more inclusive and prosperous cyberspace&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping pointed out that we advocate giving priority to development and build a more inclusive and prosperous cyberspace. Deepen international exchanges and cooperation in the digital field and accelerate the transformation of scientific and technological achievements. Accelerate the popularization of information services, narrow the digital divide, protect and improve people&#39;s livelihood in the development of the Internet, and allow more countries and people to share the fruits of Internet development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“President Xi Jinping’s important exposition on ‘building a more inclusive and prosperous cyberspace’ is far-sighted.” Xu Mengzhou, professor and director of the Business Administration Teaching and Research Department of the Zhejiang Provincial Party School Party School, said that with the current rapid development of the Internet and information technology, digital technology The existence of the gap has affected the overall level of social progress. Our country adheres to the inclusive development of the Internet, allowing more people to benefit from the development of the Internet and share digital dividends. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sun Maosong, a professor in the Department of Computer Science at Tsinghua University, said that development is the eternal theme of human society. In today&#39;s world, the Internet is an important platform to promote and ensure development. Countries must make good use of this platform to strengthen scientific research on new-generation digital technologies such as artificial intelligence and big data. They must move with the trend, take advantage of the trend, gather momentum, and ride on the momentum to build a more inclusive and prosperous cyberspace. continue trying. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Yang Jun, deputy general manager of China Electronics Technology Group, said that the group will accelerate the promotion of digital industrialization and industrial digital construction, give full play to its own advantages, and work together with all sectors of society to deepen the application and vigorous development of my country&#39;s digital economy. and make greater contributions to inclusive sharing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yu Liang, Secretary of the Party Committee and Chairman of the Aerospace Cloud Network affiliated to China Aerospace Science and Industry Corporation, said that the Aerospace Cloud Network will further strengthen technological innovation, focus on value creation, and deepen platform applications in the new era of accelerating the popularization of information services. Be the main force in the journey. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In President Xi Jinping’s video speech, important contents such as “development first” and “inclusive prosperity” deeply impressed the heads of Internet platform companies present at the meeting. &quot;Important discussions such as &#39;Building a more inclusive and prosperous cyberspace&#39; and &#39;Deepening international exchanges and cooperation in the digital field&#39; have strengthened Alibaba&#39;s confidence in being an open technology platform company.&quot; Wu Yongming, CEO of Alibaba Group, said that the group will Continue to build a stable and efficient AI basic service system and an open and prosperous AI ecosystem, and continue to help more small and medium-sized enterprises and developers innovate at lower costs and with higher efficiency. Didi Chairman and CEO Cheng Wei said that as a member company of the World Internet Conference, Didi will contribute more public welfare projects to people&#39;s livelihood, actively assume social responsibilities, and make travel more convenient and enjoyable for more people. Internet development results. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sharing weal and woe, building a more peaceful and secure cyberspace&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping pointed out that we advocate sharing weal and woe, and building a more peaceful and secure cyberspace. Respect network sovereignty and respect the Internet development paths and governance models of each country. We must abide by international rules in cyberspace and refrain from pursuing cyber hegemony. We will not engage in cyberspace camp confrontation or arms race. Deepen pragmatic cooperation on network security, effectively combat illegal and criminal activities on the Internet, and strengthen data security and personal information protection. Properly respond to rule conflicts, social risks, and ethical challenges brought about by technological development. China is willing to work with all parties to implement the Global Artificial Intelligence Governance Initiative and promote the safe development of artificial intelligence. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“President Xi Jinping’s initiative to ‘build a more peaceful and secure cyberspace’ reflects an accurate grasp of the development of the world’s Internet.” Liu Dong, director of the National Engineering Center for Next Generation Internet and vice chairman of the Global IPv6 Forum, said, In recent years, network infrastructure, data, artificial intelligence, etc. have become core issues in global cyberspace security. The necessity and urgency of international cooperation have become increasingly prominent. Countries must strengthen international cooperation in the field of network security on the basis of respecting network sovereignty. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xu Zhen, a researcher at the Institute of Information Engineering, Chinese Academy of Sciences, said: &quot;From a global perspective, cyber crimes, information fraud, cyber confrontations, hackers and other behaviors occur from time to time, which requires us to continuously strengthen our ability to prevent crises. capabilities, thereby ensuring peace and security in cyberspace and achieving rapid development in the cyber field.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping’s video speech specifically mentioned the “Global Artificial Intelligence Governance Initiative”. In this regard, Wu Fei, executive vice president of the Shanghai Institute for Advanced Study of Zhejiang University and director of the Institute of Artificial Intelligence, said that the release of the &quot;Global Artificial Intelligence Governance Initiative&quot; is of far-reaching significance. Technological empowerment requires the overall support of a healthy ecology. A good and healthy ecology will organically connect ethics and morality, technology and industry, capital and market. The whole world should join hands, adhere to the principle of equal emphasis on development and security, and promote science and technology to better benefit the people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping’s emphasis on “security” in his video speech inspired many relevant practitioners. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;In the video speech, President Xi Jinping mentioned the word &#39;security&#39; many times. As network security practitioners, we deeply feel the great responsibility.&quot; Zhou Hongyi, founder of 360 Group, said that he will keep in mind President Xi Jinping&#39;s instructions and Make “security” an important support for digital construction in China and around the world. Under the new situation, the cybersecurity industry must achieve self-breakthroughs and self-upgrades to safeguard the construction of a powerful cyber nation and digital China. Fan Yuan, chairman of Anheng Information, said that Anheng Information should fully sum up its experience and promote the construction of a more peaceful and secure cyberspace. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mutual learning among civilizations to build a more equal and inclusive cyberspace&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping pointed out that we advocate mutual learning among civilizations and build a more equal and inclusive cyberspace. Strengthen online exchanges and dialogues to promote mutual understanding and mutual understanding among people of all countries, promote tolerance and symbiosis of different civilizations, and better promote the common values ​​of all mankind. Strengthen the construction of Internet civilization, promote the production and dissemination of high-quality Internet cultural products, fully demonstrate the outstanding achievements of human civilization, actively promote the inheritance and development of civilization, and jointly build an online spiritual home. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wushour Slam, an academician of the Chinese Academy of Engineering and a professor at the School of Computer Science and Technology of Xinjiang University, said that currently, the trend of the information revolution era is advancing deeply, and President Xi Jinping has proposed to &quot;advocate mutual learning among civilizations and build a more equal and inclusive society.&quot; cyberspace” is very important. As a scholar engaged in research in the fields of informatization and intelligence in border areas, I must always keep in mind President Xi Jinping’s instructions, do a solid job in scientific and technological innovation, deepen international cooperation in the digital field, serve the construction of the core area of ​​​​the “Belt and Road”, and promote the inclusive symbiosis of different civilizations. Better promote the common values ​​of all mankind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Zhiqing, Executive Deputy Director of the National Library, said: &quot;The National Library has built a Chinese ancient book resource database, allowing 103,000 pieces (pieces), 26.4 million pages, and 1,013TB of ancient book resources to be put on the Internet. The next step is to We need to build a smart library, open up excellent book resources from ancient and modern times, both at home and abroad, and make positive contributions to further disseminating and promoting China&#39;s excellent traditional culture.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Gaofei, CEO of Sina Weibo, said that in the future, Weibo will continue to Strengthen the construction of Internet civilization, tell Chinese stories well, showcase the outstanding achievements of human civilization, and create an open and inclusive online social space. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen Chouyong, chief expert of the Zhejiang Information Development Research Institute of Hangzhou University of Electronic Science and Technology, said that the current Internet is increasingly becoming a new platform for mutual learning among civilizations. Countries should build more international communication bridges through the Internet, promote exchanges and mutual learning of the world&#39;s outstanding cultures, and promote emotional exchanges and spiritual communication between people of all countries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Our reporters Jin Xin, Gu Chun, Liu Junguo, Liu Shiyao, Ma Yuan, Cao Xuemeng, Li Chenyang, Deng Jianyang, Cui Yan)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 周铁农同志遗体在京火化]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/10/nw.D110000renmrb_20231110_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 10, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/10/01/rmrb2023111001p9_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;November 9, Zhou Tienong The remains of the comrade were cremated at the Babaoshan Revolutionary Cemetery in Beijing. Xi Jinping, Li Qiang, Zhao Leji, Wang Huning, Cai Qi, Ding Xuexiang, Li Xi and others went to Babao Mountain to bid farewell. This is Xi Jinping shaking hands with Zhou Tienong’s relatives to express his deep condolences. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Xie Huanchi&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 9 &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;A well-known social activist, an outstanding leader of the Revolutionary Committee of the Chinese Kuomintang, a close friend of the Communist Party of China, Vice Chairman of the Standing Committee of the 11th National People&#39;s Congress, the 9th and 10th Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference The body of Comrade Zhou Tienong, Vice Chairman of the National Committee and Chairman of the 11th Central Committee of the Chinese Kuomintang Revolutionary Committee, was cremated at the Babaoshan Revolutionary Cemetery in Beijing on the 9th. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Comrade Zhou Tienong died in Beijing at 16:15 on November 3, 2023 due to illness. He was 85 years old. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;When Comrade Zhou Tienong was seriously ill and after his death, comrades Xi Jinping, Li Qiang, Zhao Leji, Wang Huning, Cai Qi, Ding Xuexiang, Li Xi, Han Zheng, Hu Jintao and other comrades went to the hospital to visit Comrade Zhou Tienong or paid tribute to Comrade Zhou Tienong in various ways. I express my deep condolences on his death and express my deep condolences to his relatives. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;On the morning of the 9th, the auditorium of Babaoshan Revolutionary Cemetery was solemn and solemn, with low sorrow and joy. A banner with white characters on a black background &quot;deeply mourns Comrade Zhou Tienong&quot; hangs above the main hall. Below the banner is Comrade Zhou Tienong&#39;s portrait. Comrade Zhou Tienong&#39;s body lies among flowers and cypresses. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;At about 9:30 a.m., Xi Jinping, Li Qiang, Zhao Leji, Wang Huning, Cai Qi, Ding Xuexiang, Li Xi, etc., amid the sound of mourning music, slowly came to the body of Comrade Zhou Tienong and stood in silence to pay their respects to Zhou Tienong. The body of Comrade Zhou Tienong bowed three times and shook hands with Comrade Zhou Tienong&#39;s relatives one by one to express condolences. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Relevant leading comrades of the party and the state went to bid farewell or express condolences in various ways. Responsible comrades from relevant departments of the central and state agencies, Comrade Zhou Tienong&#39;s friends and representatives from his hometown also went to see him off. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 中国将始终是世界发展的重要机遇]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/10/nw.D110000renmrb_20231110_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 10, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;The river surges and the tide rises in the east. On the banks of the Huangpu River, guests from all over the world went to the &quot;International Expo&quot; again, and the world once again focused on China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Currently, the world&#39;s economic recovery lacks momentum and requires all countries to work together and seek common development. China will always be an important opportunity for world development, will firmly promote high-level opening up, and continue to promote economic globalization toward a more open , inclusive, universally beneficial, balanced and win-win development.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On November 5, President Xi Jinping sent a letter to the Sixth China International Import Expo, once again declaring to the world that China is firmly promoting high-level opening up. , determination to continue to promote economic globalization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The CIIE will become better and better, relying on China’s large market advantages and giving full play to its functions as a platform for international procurement, investment promotion, cultural exchanges, and open cooperation. It has become a window for China to build a new development pattern and promote high-level Open platforms and international public goods shared by the world not only help China&#39;s high-quality development and high-quality life, but also inject strong positive energy into the world&#39;s economic growth. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This CIIE has an exhibition area of ​​approximately 367,000 square meters. The number of exhibitors from the world&#39;s top 500 companies and industry leading companies exceeds previous levels, and more than 400 new products, new technologies, and new services are on display. Through the window of the CIIE, the world sees that China is taking a more open and confident attitude, providing new opportunities for the world with China&#39;s new development, making China&#39;s big market a big market shared by the world, helping to build an open world economy, and allowing cooperation and common development. Win and benefit the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;(1)&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;History always gives people the power to draw wisdom and move forward in some special years. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On November 5, 2018, President Xi Jinping solemnly declared in his keynote speech at the opening ceremony of the first China International Import Expo: &quot;The China International Import Expo must not only be held every year, but also be held at a high level and The results will be achieved and the results will be better.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After that, in November every year, the CIIE was held every year, and old and new friends came as scheduled. The fruitful &quot;CIIE stories&quot; and the &quot;two-way rush&quot; of win-win cooperation gathered together into a magnificent picture of deep integration and common development between China and the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first five CIIEs have showcased more than 2,000 representative new products, new technologies, and new services for the first time, with a cumulative intended transaction volume of nearly US$350 billion. At this CIIE, the &quot;circle of friends&quot; continues to expand, with more than 3,400 exhibitors, and the number of Fortune 500 and industry leading companies reaches 289, the highest ever. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Born and prospered because of opening up, the CIIE is a platform to promote high-level opening up, and it also witnesses China’s resolute pursuit of high-level opening up. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Market access continues to expand, confirming China’s openness. In the China Pavilion at the National Exhibition of the Sixth China International Import Expo, the “10th Anniversary Achievements Exhibition of the Construction of China Free Trade Pilot Zone” attracted many visitors. A negative list has been reduced seven times, from the original 190 items to the current 27 items. The free trade pilot zone version of the negative list for foreign investment access continues to slim down... China continues to expand high-level opening up to the outside world and develops itself. It also benefits the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Openness is a distinctive symbol of contemporary China. Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, China has implemented a more proactive opening-up strategy and has become a major trading partner of more than 140 countries and regions. Its total trade in goods ranks first in the world, and it ranks among the top in attracting foreign capital and outbound investment, forming a larger-scale, Opening up to the outside world in a wider scope and at a deeper level. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The continuously optimized business environment confirms the depth of China’s opening up. Milk produced on foreign farms on Monday can be boarded on planes on Tuesday and reaches Chinese consumers’ dining tables on Wednesday... As one of the first pilot companies to facilitate customs clearance and trade, separation of inspection and release and border inspection and release, New Zealand New Zealand participated in the CIIE. Lan Dairy felt the &quot;speed of entering the Expo&quot;: &quot;This shows China&#39;s attitude of continuously optimizing the business environment through institutional innovation and process improvement.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Optimizing the business environment is an inevitable choice for comprehensively deepening reforms. Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, China has firmly promoted high-level opening up, continued to promote the reform of &quot;decentralization, regulation and service&quot;, significantly reduced administrative approval and other matters, vigorously reduced taxes and fees, and created a first-class business environment that is market-oriented, rule-by-law and international. , a series of measures have effectively stimulated the vitality of various business entities. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The continuous enrichment of high-quality consumer goods confirms China’s openness. At this CIIE, many exhibitors presented new products, bringing consumers more choices. At Goodfarm&#39;s booth, a golden Ecuadorian unicorn fruit attracted the attention of the audience; at Abbott&#39;s booth, the new generation of Abbott&#39;s safe nutritional products is suitable for the nutritional needs of China&#39;s elderly and recovering people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The people’s yearning for a better life is our goal. This year, my country has implemented temporary import tax rates on more than 1,000 commodities. Based on the free trade agreements and preferential trade arrangements that have been signed and come into effect, the tax rate level will be further reduced to continue to release the import potential of consumer goods and better meet the people&#39;s high-quality life needs. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;(2)&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Commodities, enterprises, and resources gather here, and the distance between export and import, production and consumption is narrowed here. The CIIE has become a window for China to build a new development pattern and witness the market opportunities, investment opportunities, and growth opportunities that China&#39;s high-quality economic development has brought to the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The &quot;Green CIIE&quot; highlights the trend. This CIIE will implement an all-green electricity exhibition. The lighting, shuttle buses and other venue facilities will be powered by new energy sources such as wind power and photovoltaics. The CIIE has purchased 8 million kilowatt-hours of green power, which is expected to reduce carbon emissions by approximately 3,360 tons. BearingPoint exhibited a carbon emission calculator that can assess the carbon emissions of products throughout the life cycle; Toyota demonstrated an energy-saving and environmentally friendly hydrogen fuel cell system for commercial vehicles; Michelin launched greener tires made of sustainable materials. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Green has become a distinctive background for high-quality development. Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, my country has accelerated the construction of a green, low-carbon and circular economic system and vigorously promoted green production and lifestyle. Wind power installed capacity has ranked first in the world. The energy consumption of the added value of industrial units above designated size has dropped by more than 36% in 10 years. China has embarked on a path of civilized development featuring developed production, prosperous life, and good ecology. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;World premieres, Asian debuts, and China first exhibitions. New products and technologies at the CIIE highlight the importance of technological innovation in the hearts of global companies. At the L&#39;Oreal booth, a dexterous robotic arm accurately grasped cosmetics and applied them intelligently; at the Kärcher booth in Germany, a wireless fabric cleaning machine absorbed the soy sauce stains on the sofa in a few seconds. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Innovation is the first driving force for high-quality development. As the concept of innovative development takes root in the hearts of the people, the innovation environment is getting better and better, and more advanced global technologies and innovative resources are gathering in China. In the first three quarters of this year, the actual amount of foreign capital used in my country&#39;s manufacturing industry increased by 2.4% year-on-year, of which the actual use of foreign capital in high-tech manufacturing increased by 12.8% year-on-year, highlighting the &quot;gold content&quot; of investment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Cooperation&quot; and &quot;win-win&quot; are common topics. Specialty products from more and more countries are taking the “CIIE Express” and entering the Chinese market. We provide some free standard stalls and free transportation services for exhibitors from the least developed countries, and hold special supply and demand matchmaking meetings, including Rwandan peppers and Madagascar deep sea lobsters... There are countless stories of mutual benefit and win-win at the CIIE. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The CIIE will introduce enterprises from the least developed countries to enterprises in China and around the world, giving them opportunities to integrate into the global trading system.” A relevant person from the WTO commented. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The &quot;CIIE effect&quot; continues to be released, and the CIIE &quot;circle of friends&quot; continues to expand, further demonstrating the demand advantage of China&#39;s ultra-large-scale market, China&#39;s economy has huge development resilience and potential, and its long-term fundamentals are good No change. On the new journey of promoting Chinese-style modernization, China promotes high-quality development and constantly creates new momentum and new advantages for development, which will surely generate more new cooperation opportunities and inject more positive energy into global economic development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;(3)&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping emphasized: &quot;Economic globalization is a historical trend. The Yangtze River, the Nile River, the Amazon River, and the Danube River rush towards the Yangtze River day and night. In the future, although there will be some turning waves and although we will encounter many dangerous shoals and reefs, no one can stop the momentum of the rivers rushing forward.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Currently, the world is undergoing major changes that have not been seen in a century. As the world economy evolves, the recovery of the world economy is sluggish. As a global platform for sharing international public goods, the CIIE continues to promote the sharing of a bigger cake and is injecting vitality into the world economy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One by one, mutually beneficial and win-win cooperation results have continuously improved people’s livelihood and well-being. Kenyan fresh avocados enter the Chinese market, benefiting thousands of local farmers; an Afghan wool carpet is sold in China, increasing the income of four or five carpet weaver families... The vivid stories of the CIIE illustrate that China&#39;s development continues to benefit all countries people’s reality. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The signing of free trade agreements one after another has made the flow of products and services smoother. On the eve of this CIIE, China and Serbia officially signed a free trade agreement. The two sides will mutually cancel tariffs on 90% of tax items. China will include beef, wine, nuts, etc. as zero tariffs. This year, China signed free trade agreements with Ecuador, Nicaragua and Serbia. So far, China has signed 22 free trade agreements with 29 countries and regions. China continues to promote trade and investment liberalization and facilitation with practical actions to better achieve common development between China and other countries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;International forums are held one after another to make China&#39;s plan more deeply rooted in the hearts of the people. This CIIE has more than 120 supporting on-site activities scheduled, covering policy interpretation, trade docking, investment promotion, research release and other categories. &quot;The CIIE is a high-standard open platform and a public product for the whole world. It creates more dialogue opportunities for countries around the world and allows developed and developing countries to interact better.&quot; Globalization of the United Nations Conference on Trade and Development Ke Ruizhi, Director of the Department of Development Strategy, said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Exhibits have turned into commodities, and exhibitors have turned into investors. On the one hand, the CIIE smoothes the domestic circulation, and on the other hand, it connects the domestic and international dual circulations. It has made positive contributions to accelerating the construction of a new development pattern and promoting the development of the world economy. contribute. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Not only the my country International Import Expo, but also the Consumer Expo, Trade in Services Fair, Canton Fair... Since the beginning of this year, our country has held many major international exhibitions, constantly conveying the message that &quot;we open the door, and whoever comes to cooperate with us will be welcome.&quot; The sincerity of &quot;Welcome&quot; and the continuously expanding areas of economic and trade cooperation have strengthened the confidence of global companies to deeply explore the Chinese market. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the CIIE, the mascot &quot;Jinbao&quot; attracted many guests to take photos. The energetic &quot;Jinbao&quot; wears a yellow and blue scarf, where the yellow represents the &quot;Silk Road Economic Belt&quot; and the blue represents the &quot;21st Century Maritime Silk Road&quot;. From making the CIIE a high-level, effective and better one, to promoting high-quality joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, China has used solid actions to firmly promote the construction of an open world economy and contribute Chinese solutions and efforts to building a community with a shared future for mankind. China power. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;If the world is good, China will be good; if China is good, the world will be better.&quot; On the new journey, China will expand high-level opening up with practical actions and solidly promote Chinese-style modernization with high-quality development. Let win-win cooperation benefit the world and create a bright future of openness and prosperity. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 切实担起责任   密切协调配合]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/10/nw.D110000renmrb_20231110_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 10, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 9&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Ding Xuexiang, Member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Vice Premier of the State Council 9 On the same day, he attended a video and telephone conference on maintaining warmth and supply this winter and next spring in Beijing and delivered a speech. The meeting conscientiously studied and implemented the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions, implemented the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee and the State Council, and made arrangements for ensuring warmth and supply this winter and next spring. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Ding Xuexiang pointed out that the work of keeping warm and ensuring supply is a major people&#39;s livelihood project and a public support project. Through the joint efforts of relevant parties, my country&#39;s energy supply capacity has been steadily enhanced, resource reserves have become more abundant, and energy security for people&#39;s livelihood has been strengthened, laying a good foundation for maintaining warmth and supply. It is necessary to further integrate thoughts and actions into the decisions and deployments of the Party Central Committee and the State Council, adhere to the people-centered development idea, and have a sense of responsibility to &quot;always be assured&quot; to do a solid job in ensuring warmth and supply this winter and next spring. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Ding Xuexiang emphasized that we must focus on the production and supply of coal and natural gas, support enterprises to increase production and supply, actively expand resource imports, and stabilize the basic energy supply guarantee. We will give full play to the regulating role of reserve resources, further improve coal storage in coal storage bases, focus on power plants with low coal storage and increase coal storage capacity, and do a solid job in natural gas storage. Strictly implement the signing and performance of medium- and long-term energy contracts to ensure stable supply and stable prices. Priority should be given to ensuring residents&#39; daily energy use, improving work plans to deal with the impact of extreme cold weather and emergencies, strengthening energy supply guarantees for &quot;coal-to-gas&quot; and &quot;coal-to-electricity&quot; users, and doing a good job in keeping people warm and supplied in disaster-stricken areas. Carry out safety production work in depth and detail, strengthen the investigation and management of hidden dangers and inspection and maintenance of facilities, and prevent and contain major safety production accidents. All regions, relevant departments, units, and enterprises must effectively shoulder their responsibilities and coordinate closely to ensure a safe and stable supply of energy and a warm winter for the people. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Responsible comrades from relevant departments and units of central and state agencies and relevant central enterprises attended the meeting at the main venue. Responsible comrades from provinces (autonomous regions and municipalities) and the Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps and responsible comrades from relevant departments and units attended the meeting at the branch venue. . Responsible comrades from the National Development and Reform Commission and the people&#39;s governments of Hebei, Heilongjiang and Yunnan provinces made speeches. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 前三季度新设经营主体2480.8万户]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/10/nw.D110000renmrb_20231110_7-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 10, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, November 9th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Lin Lili) The State Administration for Market Regulation released data It shows that in the first three quarters of this year, 24.808 million new business entities were established across the country, a year-on-year increase of 12.7%. Among them, 7.518 million new enterprises were established, a year-on-year increase of 15.4%; 17.196 million individual industrial and commercial households were newly established, a year-on-year increase of 11.7%. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In the first three quarters, under the guidance and drive of a series of policies and measures to expand domestic demand, boost confidence, and promote the development of the private economy, the internal dynamic energy of my country&#39;s business entities continued to increase, and the economy continued to recover, with high The foundation for quality development is continuously consolidated. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;New enterprises in the accommodation and catering industry are growing rapidly. In the first three quarters, newly established enterprises in various industries achieved steady growth. Newly established enterprises in the primary industry increased by 23.6% year-on-year, the fastest growth rate. The number of newly established enterprises in the secondary industry increased by 5.3% year-on-year, with a steady development momentum. Newly established enterprises in the tertiary industry increased by 17.2% year-on-year, among which the accommodation and catering industry increased by more than 40% year-on-year. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Private and foreign-funded enterprises have good momentum of development. In the first three quarters, the number of newly established private enterprises increased by 15.3% year-on-year, and the number of newly established foreign-funded enterprises increased by 29.3% year-on-year. The good development trend of enterprises with multiple ownerships shows that market expectations continue to improve and investment confidence is gradually increasing. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The total number of operating entities has reached a new level. As of the end of September this year, there were 181 million registered business entities across the country, an increase of 6.7% from the end of 2022. Among them, there were 56.737 million enterprises, 122 million individual industrial and commercial households, and 2.240 million farmer cooperatives, an increase of 7.4%, 6.5%, and 0.1% respectively compared with the end of last year. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 时刻铭记总书记重要训词  忠诚履行防风险保安全使命担当]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/10/nw.D110000renmrb_20231110_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 10, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 9&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; General Secretary Xi Jinping presented the flag to the national comprehensive fire rescue team On the occasion of the fifth anniversary of the speech, the Ministry of Emergency Management held a symposium in Beijing on November 9 to review the spirit of the General Secretary’s important speech and summarize and exchange emergency management and the reform, construction and development of the fire rescue team. Zhang Guoqing, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Vice Premier of the State Council, attended the symposium and delivered a speech. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Zhang Guoqing fully recognized the achievements in emergency management and fire rescue work in the past five years. He pointed out that the General Secretary’s important precepts are the fundamental guide for the development of emergency management and fire rescue in the new era. We must always bear in mind the leader’s instructions, insist on using bacon to build the soul, and build political loyalty, strengthen mission responsibility, and cultivate deep roots in continuous learning and understanding. People&#39;s sentiments, tempering their bloody courage, and constantly drawing political nutrition and confidence from them. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Zhang Guoqing emphasized that to perform our duties and forge ahead in the new era and new journey, we must faithfully implement the general secretary’s team-building policy of loyalty to the party, strict discipline, risking through fire and water, and serving the people wholeheartedly, and adhere to the party’s absolute leadership. Comprehensively implement the political responsibility of strictly managing the party and the team, and always obey the command of General Secretary Xi Jinping and the Party Central Committee.要加快推进各项改革任务，深化队伍整合和业务融合，严格训练、严格管理，提升全灾种、大应急综合救援能力，科学高效防范化解重大安全风险、应急处置各类灾害事故。各有关方面要给予消防救援队伍更多关心支持，帮助解决实际困难。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;中央和国家机关有关部门负责同志及消防救援队伍指战员、专家代表参加会议。 &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 进一步恢复和扩大消费，全力稳住外贸外资基本盘（权威访谈）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/10/nw.D110000renmrb_20231110_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月10日星期五&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;商务工作是国内大循环的重要组成部分，是联结国内国际双循环的重要枢纽，在构建新发展格局中发挥重要作用。前三季度，我国商务运行总体平稳，特别是进入三季度以来呈现回稳向好态势。怎样进一步恢复和扩大消费？如何继续稳住外贸外资基本盘？记者采访了商务部党组书记、部长王文涛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;着力提振信心，政策效果持续显现&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：前三季度商务领域出台了哪些政策措施？有哪些特点和考虑？效果如何？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王文涛：今年以来，我们按照中央统一部署，在稳外贸、稳外资、促消费等方面及时出台一系列措施，着力强化三方面：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一是注重靠前发力。比如外贸方面，今年初，我们综合考虑去年基数高、外需转弱等因素，于4月份推动出台《关于推动外贸稳规模优结构的意见》。此后，系统出台跨境电商海外仓发展、加工贸易、新能源汽车贸易、扩大进口等政策措施，形成了“1+N”政策体系，全力保障全年外贸保持基本稳定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;二是强化问题导向。我们通过召开外资企业圆桌会议等方式，充分了解外资企业诉求。同时，会同29个部门进行研究，提出了解决办法和措施。7月，国务院出台《关于进一步优化外商投资环境&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;加大吸引外商投资力度的意见》，有关部门和地方正在全力抓好落实。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三是着力提振信心。按照中央部署，我们组织开展了“投资中国年”“消费提振年”系列活动，在境内外共举办近20场重点活动，各省区市组织配套招商活动500多场，展示全国各地方的投资机遇，擦亮“投资中国”这个金字招牌。“消费提振年”活动通过举办全国消费促进月、国际消费季、金秋购物节等系列主题活动、专题活动，推出40多个特色消费场景，形成消费热潮，增强消费信心，激发消费活力，释放消费潜力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从目前看，这些政策效果持续显现。三季度，我国社会消费品零售总额增速逐月加快，分别增长2.5%、4.6%、5.5%。以人民币计，货物进出口降幅逐步收窄，9月份微降0.7%。下一步，我们一方面要继续抓好政策落实，另一方面要加强政策储备，出台实施新的政策措施，进一步恢复和扩大消费，全力稳住外贸外资基本盘，努力完成全年各项目标任务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;全力以赴抓好消费促进工作，巩固消费回升势头&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：商务部把今年确定为“消费提振年”。如何看待全年消费走势？未来还会从哪些方面推动消费持续恢复和扩大？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王文涛：今年以来，消费持续恢复提升，前三季度全国社会消费品零售总额达34.2万亿元，同比增长6.8%，最终消费支出对GDP的贡献增强。但也要看到，消费恢复还不平衡，居民消费意愿仍显不足，消费能力尚需提升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从全年来看，随着扩内需、促消费各项政策效应持续显现，叠加岁末年初消费旺季的拉动作用，四季度消费有望继续呈现稳步恢复态势，完成全年目标任务是有基础的。我们将全力以赴抓好消费促进工作，巩固消费回升势头。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一是着力促进重点消费，也就是汽车、家电、家居、餐饮消费，重点是要落实好已出台的政策措施。比如，汽车方面将持续推动新能源汽车下乡，推动汽车赛事、房车露营等后市场发展，全链条促进汽车消费；家居方面聚焦绿色、智能、适老三个方向，加快释放家居消费潜力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;二是优化消费环境和场景。我们将深入推进国际消费中心城市培育建设，引领和促进消费升级。扎实推进城市一刻钟便民生活圈和县域商业体系建设三年行动，指导各地建设更多智慧商圈、智慧商店，打造高质量消费载体，持续营造良好消费环境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三是办好促消费活动。将继续办好“消费提振年”活动，结合时令特色和消费热点，开展“百城联动”汽车节、老字号嘉年华等重点活动，推出秋日暖居、欢乐跨年、冬日美食等消费场景，营造浓厚消费氛围。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;持续推动外贸稳规模优结构，继续抓好稳外资政策落实，优化营商环境&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：我国外贸目前整体情况如何？助力外贸企业发展还有哪些举措？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王文涛：今年以来，我国外贸运行面临的压力不小。面对复杂严峻的形势，商务部全力以赴帮助企业稳订单、拓市场，持续推动外贸稳规模、优结构，前三季度我国外贸顶住压力，展现出较强韧性，总体保持平稳运行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“稳”的基础不断夯实。前三季度，我国货物进出口总额超30万亿元，与去年同期基本持平；有进出口实绩的外贸企业增至59.7万家，接近去年全年水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“进”的势头逐步显现。从时间维度看，进出口规模逐季扩大，9月单月创年内新高。从地区维度看，前三季度我国对共建“一带一路”国家货物进出口14.3万亿元，增长3.1%，超过我国整体增速，对美欧有所改善。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“新”的动能加快聚集。“新三样”出口保持增长态势，前三季度同比增长41.7%。新业态蓬勃发展，跨境电商进出口1.7万亿元，增长14.4%。数字贸易和服务贸易快速发展，今年1—8月分别增长10.4%和8%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;四季度通常是外贸旺季，是全年外贸的“大头”。我们将重点做好两方面工作：一方面，帮助企业稳订单拓市场。全力以赴办好第六届进博会、第二届数贸会，优化供采对接，更好服务外贸企业拓市场。另一方面，继续加大贸易政策支持力度。进一步落实好《关于推动外贸稳规模优结构的意见》，加快推动出台支持新能源汽车贸易合作、支持二手车出口、提升加工贸易发展水平等多项政策措施，做好新政策的研究储备，稳定重点产品出口优势，有序引导加工贸易梯度转移。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：外资政策落地见效情况如何？如何进一步更大力度吸引和利用外资？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王文涛：今年以来，我们会同相关部门陆续出台了一系列专项外资政策，引导外资更多投向先进制造、科技创新等领域。下一步，我们将继续抓好稳外资政策落实，深化改革开放，持续优化营商环境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一是持续打造“投资中国”品牌。在第六届进博会期间，举办“投资中国年”高峰会议。我们将积极支持各地开展外商投资促进活动，持续打造“投资中国”品牌，让中国始终成为外商投资兴业的热土。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;二是持续优化服务。我们将依托外贸外资协调服务机制，继续完善外资企业圆桌会议制度，完善外资投诉工作机制，用好外资企业问题诉求收集办理系统等，让外资企业不仅有信心投资中国，更能安心扎根中国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三是进一步扩大开放。我们将合理缩减外资准入负面清单，全面取消制造业领域外资准入限制措施，扩大电信、旅游等服务领域对外开放，与各方共享中国发展红利、开放红利。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：今年是我国自贸试验区建设十周年。我国自贸试验区在对接国际高标准推进制度型开放方面有哪些进展和亮点？下一步还有哪些政策和考虑？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王文涛：十年来，中央先后部署设立了21个自贸试验区，近期，国务院又批准设立了新疆自贸试验区，形成了覆盖东西南北中的改革开放创新格局。我们将深入实施自贸试验区提升战略，努力建设更高水平自贸试验区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第一，高标准对接国际经贸规则，推进制度型开放。6月，国务院出台文件，支持上海、广东、天津、福建、北京等5个自贸试验区和海南自由贸易港试点对接国际高标准经贸规则，在制度型开放上先行探索。下一步，我们将深入实施首批试点措施，推动规则、规制、管理、标准等制度型开放。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第二，加强改革系统谋划和系统集成。我们将在贸易、投资、金融、数据跨境流动等重点领域，集中推出一批引领性、集成性改革举措，支持自贸试验区在更广领域、更深层次开展改革探索。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第三，推动全产业链创新发展。我们将推动自贸试验区开展差别化探索，鼓励各自贸试验区围绕生物医药、海洋经济、大宗商品贸易等重点领域和重点产业，开展全链条集成创新。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 着力绘就祖国北疆发展新蓝图（权威发布）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/10/nw.D110000renmrb_20231110_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月10日星期五&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;近期，国务院印发《关于推动内蒙古高质量发展奋力书写中国式现代化新篇章的意见》（以下简称《意见》）。11月9日，国务院新闻办召开发布会，有关部门和地区负责人介绍相关情况。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“内蒙古地处祖国北疆，发展潜力巨大，战略地位重要。”内蒙古自治区党委常委、自治区常务副主席黄志强介绍：内蒙古草原、森林和湿地面积分别占全国的20.5%、10.3%和8.6%，其中森林面积全国第一，草原面积全国第二；横跨“三北”、地近京畿，边境线4200多公里，是祖国的“北大门”和首都的“护城河”；风能资源全国第一、太阳能资源全国第二，外运煤、外送电和新能源发电量均居全国第一；粮食产量全国第六，牛奶、羊肉、牛肉和羊绒产量全国第一，是名副其实的“粮仓”“肉库”“奶罐”“绒都”；拥有对外开放口岸20个，公路口岸货运量全国第一。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“《意见》对内蒙古提出五个战略定位，包括&#39;两个屏障&#39;&#39;两个基地&#39;&#39;一个桥头堡&#39;，即我国北方重要生态安全屏障、祖国北疆安全稳定屏障、国家重要能源和战略资源基地、国家重要农畜产品生产基地、我国向北开放重要桥头堡。《意见》还就内蒙古经济社会发展提出2027年、2035年两个阶段目标。其中到2027年的目标是，综合经济实力进入全国中等水平，城乡居民收入达到全国平均水平，产业结构优化升级，防沙治沙成果显著，向北开放重要桥头堡作用充分发挥，&#39;模范自治区&#39;建设取得明显成效等。”国家发展改革委党组成员郭兰峰介绍，《意见》具有突出生态优先绿色发展、突出发挥内蒙古优势产业特色、突出服务国内国际双循环、突出保障和改善民生等特点，“我们将认真贯彻落实党中央、国务院决策部署，与各部门一道做好沟通协调和跟踪服务，全力支持内蒙古落实好《意见》。”&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;内蒙古是中蒙俄经济走廊的重要节点、国家西部陆海新通道的重要门户。“近年来，我们积极参与高质量共建&#39;一带一路&#39;和中蒙俄经济走廊建设。去年，全区口岸进出境货运量5842.2万吨，增长14.7%；进出境中欧班列7337列，增长19.1%。”内蒙古自治区党委常委、宣传部部长郑宏范表示，将从三方面发力推动向北开放重要桥头堡提质升级，“一是强化开放大通道建设，以满洲里口岸和二连浩特口岸为基础，构建内连京津冀、外接俄蒙至欧洲的开放大通道；二是加快发展开放型经济，提升互市贸易区、综合保税区等平台功能，深化与蒙古国、俄罗斯的经贸合作；三是加强区域协作互动，积极融入京津冀协同发展，加强与长三角、粤港澳大湾区等区域互惠合作。”&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“内蒙古资源富集、工业基础较好，是国内重要的原材料和中间产品生产基地。今年前三季度，规模以上工业增加值增长7.6%，工业发展势头良好。”工业和信息化部规划司司长陈克龙介绍，《意见》就推动内蒙古构建现代化产业体系进行了专门部署，工业和信息化部将从加快推动产业创新发展、加快产业结构优化升级、加快新型基础设施布局建设等方面支持内蒙古产业高质量发展。具体举措包括：推进国家稀土功能材料创新中心高水平建设；支持钢铁、建材、有色金属等行业开展节能减污降碳技术改造，支持高质量建设高铝粉煤灰综合利用示范基地、鄂尔多斯现代煤化工产业示范区；支持内蒙古新能源汽车产业发展和推广应用，引导光伏制造规范有序发展，支持民用航空产业发展等。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;内蒙古是我国重要的农畜产品生产大区，生产全国19%的牛奶、15%的牛羊肉、5.7%的粮食和4.6%的油料。“《意见》对内蒙古建设国家重要农畜产品生产基地作出系统部署。”农业农村部发展规划司负责人潘扬彬表示，将会同有关部门从四方面抓好落实：一是建强设施夯基础，加强高标准农田建设，发展设施农业；二是科技创新提产能，推动育种创新、技术集成；三是产业壮链增效益，大力发展农畜产品精深加工，创响一批“蒙字号”品牌；四是深化改革激活力，深化土地制度改革，巩固和完善农村牧区基本经营制度，壮大农业经营主体。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“内蒙古将把落实《意见》作为当前和今后一个时期的重要政治任务，持续推进、久久为功，为全面建设社会主义现代化国家贡献力量、展现担当。”黄志强表示。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 一揽子措施稳定产业链供应链（政策解读）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/10/nw.D110000renmrb_20231110_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月10日星期五&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;为顺应企业现代化生产经营现实需求，近日，海关总署出台《海关总署关于推动加工贸易持续高质量发展改革实施方案》（以下简称《方案》），围绕提升便利化水平、促进区域协同发展、筑牢安全发展防线3个方面，研究提出一揽子改革措施，进一步优化监管模式，稳定市场预期、稳住外贸基本盘、稳定产业链供应链。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;创新监管模式，提升加工贸易内通外联优势&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加工贸易随改革开放而生，经过40余年的发展，成为我国开放型经济发展的重要组成部分。1981年至今，我国加工贸易进出口年平均增长率近20％，累计增长近500倍。今年1—9月，全国加工贸易进出口总值5.57万亿元，占外贸进出口总值的18.1％。此次海关总署出台改革措施，进一步提升加工贸易便利化监管水平，持续优化营商环境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国是制造业大国，货物贸易量排名全球第一，企业对出口货物的售后服务需求较高。《方案》放宽深加工结转集中申报时限。允许企业每月底前对上月深加工结转核注清单及报关单进行集中申报，优化加工贸易成品出口退换管理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;海关总署企业管理和稽查司副司长黄伶俐表示，按原有规定，已经核销的加工贸易账册项下的出口成品，不能按照“成品退换”方式进行申报。改革后，企业如果因为出口成品品质、规格或其他情况，无法在同一核销周期内办理“成品退换”手续的，经海关批准，可在同一账册项下跨一个核销周期办理“成品退换”相关手续。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从“两头在外、大进大出”转向积极开拓“两个市场、两种资源”，近年来，越来越多高品质消费品源源不断从加工贸易工厂输入国内市场。2022年，加工贸易内销货值超2700亿元，较10年前增长约84％，今年1—9月，加工贸易内销货值已超2022年全年，达2900亿元，加工贸易对构建国内国际双循环相互促进的新发展格局作用明显。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;促进区域协同发展，推动加工贸易梯度转移&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，贯彻落实党中央、国务院关于持续引导加工贸易梯度转移的决策部署，中西部地区发挥比较优势积极承接加工贸易产业转移。今年1—9月，中西部地区加工贸易占全国比重从2008年的2.8％上升到24.8％。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“《方案》支持梯度转移与综合保税区转型升级协同发展。支持原油、煤炭、天然气等能源性商品和铁矿石、铜精矿等资源性商品以及粮食等大宗商品进口，在中西部和东北地区主要进口地设立保税仓库，就地开展加工贸易。”黄伶俐表示，此举有助于推动中西部和东北地区依托综合保税区政策优势，将综合保税区打造为承接加工贸易产业转移的示范区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;海关总署高度重视推动加工贸易转型升级，支持加工贸易向“微笑曲线”两端延伸。支持符合条件的综合保税区外企业开展自产产品保税维修试点，加快推动一批维修项目落地，支持加工贸易新兴业态发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;黄伶俐介绍，今年1—9月，全国保税维修进出口2459.17亿元，同比增长105.9％。保税维修等业务的开展，可帮助企业以较低的成本整合全产业链，形成以生产订单带动维修订单、以维修订单促进生产订单的良性循环。例如，厦门海关有力助推厦门市打造航空维修基地。今年1—9月，厦门市航空保税维修实现进出口货值1253.11亿元，同比增长12.43倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;打造智慧监管系统，促进产业发展再上新台阶&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我国企业通过加工贸易参与全球分工，加工贸易从整体上带动了我国加工制造业水平的提升，增强了创新能力，促进了产业转型升级。如今，在广东东莞，已有约三成加工贸易企业设立了研发机构，500多家申请成为高新技术企业，超过2000家建立起自主品牌，累计拥有品牌数超过1.3万个，ODM（自主研发设计）+OBM（自主品牌）产品出口比重从2009年的40.8％提升至75.3％。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《方案》提出，实施“保税+ERP（企业资源计划）”监管改革。推进智慧保税监管系统建设。完善保税业务系统生态，实现保税业务全流程信息化办理，强化信息互通和系统互联，构建数字化、智能化的智慧保税监管体系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;黄伶俐介绍，受新一轮科技革命和产业变革影响，我国外贸企业加快推进数字化转型，引入现代化ERP系统。前期，海关总署已在深圳、合肥等13个直属海关开展试点，对接企业ERP系统直接抓取数据，企业只需一次报备，不再需要逐票办理，每月可减少重复申报数据超过220万条，账册设立、变更和报核准备时间压缩一半以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 10 Nov 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>