<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 为党和国家事业发展]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20231022_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Sunday, October 22, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Congratulatory letter&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the occasion of the 110th anniversary of the establishment of the European and American Alumni Association, I On behalf of the Party Central Committee, I would like to extend my warm congratulations to the European and American Alumni Association (China Overseas Students Association) and my sincere greetings to all overseas students and workers working there! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The European and American Alumni Association is a mass, intellectual, and united people&#39;s organization under the leadership of the Party. Since its establishment 110 years ago, it has always held high the banner of studying abroad to serve the country and made positive contributions to uniting the majority of overseas students to serve the motherland and serve the people. . On the new journey, the European and American Alumni Association should strengthen its political, progressive and mass nature, continue to play its role as a talent pool for studying abroad and serving the country, a think tank for advice and suggestions, and a new force in non-governmental diplomacy, strengthen ideological guidance and organizational building, and gather together for the development of the cause of the party and the country. Talents from all over the world gather together to create great power. It is hoped that the vast number of overseas students will carry forward the tradition of studying abroad to serve the country, be patriotic for the people, be confident and self-reliant, pioneer and forge ahead, be open and inclusive, devote themselves to innovation and entrepreneurship to create the current of the times, contribute to exchanges and mutual learning between Chinese and foreign civilizations, and write a chapter in their lives while promoting the construction of a strong country and the great cause of national rejuvenation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;October 21, 2023&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 21) &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Our newspaper, Beijing, October 21 (Reporter Li Changyu) On the occasion of the 110th anniversary of the establishment of the European and American Alumni Association, the General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee , President Xi Jinping, Chairman of the Central Military Commission, sent a congratulatory letter, expressing warm congratulations on behalf of the Party Central Committee to the European and American Alumni Association (China Overseas Students Association), and extending sincere greetings to the vast number of overseas students and workers working there. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out in his congratulatory letter that the European and American Alumni Association is a mass, intellectual, and united people&#39;s organization under the leadership of the Party. Since its establishment 110 years ago, it has always held high the banner of studying abroad and serving the country, uniting the majority of overseas students to serve the motherland. , serve the people and make positive contributions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping emphasized that on the new journey, the European and American Alumni Association should strengthen its political, progressive and mass nature, continue to play its role as a talent pool for studying abroad and serving the country, a think tank for advice and suggestions, and a new force in people-to-people diplomacy, and strengthen ideological leadership and organization Construction, gathering talents from all over the world and creating great power for the development of the cause of the party and the country. It is hoped that the vast number of overseas students will carry forward the tradition of studying abroad to serve the country, be patriotic for the people, be confident and self-reliant, pioneer and forge ahead, be open and inclusive, devote themselves to innovation and entrepreneurship to create the current of the times, contribute to exchanges and mutual learning between Chinese and foreign civilizations, and write a chapter in their lives while promoting the construction of a strong country and the great cause of national rejuvenation. (The full text of the congratulatory letter will be sent separately)&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 110th anniversary celebration meeting of the European and American Alumni Association was held in Beijing on the 21st. Wang Huning, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Chairman of the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference, attended and delivered a speech. He said that General Secretary Xi Jinping specially sent a congratulatory letter to the 110th anniversary of the establishment of the European and American Alumni Association, fully affirming the positive contributions made by the European and American Alumni Association, profoundly clarifying the mission and tasks of the European and American Alumni Association, and raising ardent expectations for the majority of overseas students to do a good job in the new era. The work of the Times’ overseas students provides basic guidance. We must study and understand in depth and implement them well. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Huning said that the new era is a great era that calls for and cultivates talents. He hopes that the majority of overseas students will remember General Secretary Xi Jinping’s instructions, carry forward the tradition of studying abroad to serve the country, and write a chapter in their lives on the journey of studying the world and realizing their dreams of China. We must keep in mind patriotism and the people, consciously integrate patriotism and aspirations to serve the country into the cause of reform and development of the motherland, into the people&#39;s struggle to create history, and serve the motherland and the people with patriotic enthusiasm. We must keep in mind self-confidence and self-improvement, the ambition to be self-reliant, the backbone of perseverance and self-reliance, the confidence to be independent and independent, and inspire forward momentum with firm confidence and conviction. We must keep in mind pioneering and forging ahead, strive to be the first with the courage to surpass our predecessors, dare to lead the times, dare to create miracles in the world, and shoulder the great responsibility of national rejuvenation with even more tenacious struggle. We must keep in mind openness and inclusiveness, serve as a bridge to promote friendly exchanges between China and foreign countries, and actively promote foreign exchanges and exchanges by leveraging our advantages in internal and external cooperation. The European and American Alumni Association should uphold the party&#39;s overall leadership, enhance its political, progressive and mass nature, give full play to the role of a talent pool for studying abroad and serving the country, a think tank for advice and suggestions, and a new force in non-governmental diplomacy, so as to better unite the vast number of overseas students around the party. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shi Taifeng, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and director of the United Front Work Department of the CPC Central Committee, read Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter at the meeting. Ding Zhongli, Vice Chairman of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress and President of the European and American Alumni Association, made a report. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yang Wanming, Party Secretary and President of the Chinese People&#39;s Association for Friendship with Foreign Countries, delivered a congratulatory message on behalf of the people&#39;s organizations. Pan Jianwei, Vice President of the European and American Alumni Association and Executive Vice President of the University of Science and Technology of China, spoke on behalf of the overseas students. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Responsible comrades of relevant departments of central and state agencies and relevant people&#39;s organizations, central leaders of all democratic parties, some diplomats from embassies in China, heads of various organizations at all levels of European and American alumni associations, and representatives of students studying abroad at home and abroad Waiting to attend the conference. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 06:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - “这是我们这一代政治家对当代人和后代人的责任”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20231022_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Sunday, October 22, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Beijing gathers global attention. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On October 18, the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum opened in Beijing. Guests and friends from all over the world come in droves across mountains and seas. In an era of intertwined events, it is extremely precious that countries with different cultural backgrounds, different social systems, and different stages of development can sit together to discuss cooperation and friendship. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;People lamented China&#39;s cohesion and influence, and the vigorous vitality of the &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; initiative. From President Xi Jinping&#39;s keynote speech at the opening ceremony, as well as the endless applause at the scene, foreign guests stood up one after another. The shot of shaking hands with him makes me feel. The diplomacy of major powers embodies the profound thinking of &quot;China is to the world and the world is to China.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is a summary of the journey. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ten years is a drop in the ocean, but it has created tremendous changes. As if to be a symbol, the first guest that President Xi Jinping met after the launch of the “Belt and Road Initiative” was President Tokayev from Kazakhstan. Ten years ago, it was there that the initiative to jointly build the &quot;Silk Road Economic Belt&quot; was proposed. Today, &quot;more than 150 countries and more than 30 international organizations have signed cooperation documents on jointly building the &#39;One Belt, One Road&#39;&quot;, and the scale and effectiveness far exceed what was originally imagined. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is the beginning of a journey. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the welcome banquet the night before the opening ceremony, President Xi Jinping spoke full of longing: &quot;We are in our prime, and we must forge ahead with high spirits towards the next golden decade!&quot; After crossing the &quot;Jindel&quot; In the expectation of &quot;Burger Trap&quot;, the world is looking to China and looking forward to the &quot;next golden decade&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the next ten years, there will be hardships and hardships, and there will be a long journey, but also the joint efforts of colleagues and the firmness of our steps. When President Xi Jinping said that &quot;this is the responsibility of our generation of politicians to the present and future generations,&quot; he was full of philosophical thoughts: &quot;Throughout the history of human development, only by continuous self-improvement and unremitting struggle can we reap numerous fruits and build interests. It is a long-lasting contribution that will benefit all people for thousands of years.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Continuous self-improvement and unremitting struggle are what China knows and does. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Get together&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;On the evening of the 17th, welcome banquet&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A century of changes superimposed on a century of epidemic. As the wheel of time reaches today, the world&#39;s desire for economic recovery and yearning for peace and tranquility are even stronger. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Welcome banquet on the evening of the 17th. The Great Hall of the People, which has witnessed countless major events, has more than 150 national flags and United Nations flags of countries co-constructing the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; lined up on both sides of the red carpet, making it a spectacular sight. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The foreign guests walked through the flag array and walked towards President Xi Jinping and his wife Peng Liyuan at the other end of the red carpet with smiles. They shook hands, exchanged pleasantries, and laughed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The group photo freezes the historical moment and is destined to be remembered by history. President Xi Jinping and his wife stood side by side with the guests, just as the countries and international organizations they represent walk side by side in the construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the banquet hall, a vivid story of the times was told. &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; is the story of China and the story of the world. President Xi Jinping’s toast brought people’s thoughts back to those days and nights of struggle:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Spring brings its glory, and autumn brings its harvest.” “These achievements did not fall from the sky, nor were they given by anyone. , but what governments, enterprises and people of all countries have done with hard work, wisdom and courage! Let us pay tribute to all the participants and builders of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39;!&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Salute, on the barren mountains , on the islands, and on every inch of land in the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, countless participants and builders traveled over mountains and rivers, looking at the desert like smoke, the crescent moon like a hook; looking at the vast expanse of blue waves and high cloud sails. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“One Belt, One Road” is a story of the past and a story of the future. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping used three &quot;unstoppable&quot; words to illustrate China&#39;s confidence in facing a world that is not peaceful: We firmly believe that &quot;the historical trend of peace, development, cooperation, and win-win is unstoppable, and the people The yearning for a better life is unstoppable, and the desire of all countries to achieve common development and prosperity is unstoppable.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Leverage the general trend and pursue the high road. Under the &quot;irresistible&quot; trend, there is the ascendant &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the banquet hall, there was a joyous song of poetry and dance, a dialogue between Eastern and Western cultures. The Chinese national instrumental music &quot;Li Shan Le He&quot; meets the passionate Argentinian dance music &quot;One Step Away&quot;, the passionate Russian song &quot;Kalinka&quot; resonates with the cheerful Chinese dance &quot;Tea Picking&quot;... &quot;One Belt and One Road&quot; is also an exchange of civilizations The road to learning. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The power of culture moisturizes things silently. Cooperation in global governance must first seek cultural recognition; the revitalization of the global economy must also explore ways of co-promotion through cultural exchanges. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“If you are close to someone before you have seen them, you can go; if you have not forgotten them for a long time, you can come.” Throughout the process of human civilization, the ancient Silk Road has spanned history because of its connection with many forms of civilization. It is famous for its long period. The &quot;One Belt and One Road&quot; concept of world harmony, harmony and symbiosis is also reflected in the visits of President Xi Jinping&#39;s wife Peng Liyuan and the wives of foreign leaders. In the experience of intangible cultural heritage, they quietly comprehended the richness and diversity of Chinese culture. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Discuss together&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;On the morning of the 18th, the opening ceremony&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking back at the rise of great powers in the past hundreds of years , there are wars and sufferings, plunder and resistance. When China&#39;s development becomes recognized as a &quot;landmark event of the 21st century,&quot; how does the largest developing country get along with the world? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; is based on the principles of consultation, joint construction and sharing, is characterized by openness and inclusiveness, and pursues mutual benefit and win-win. It is precisely the best answer to the world&#39;s attention. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The opening ceremony on the 18th attracted worldwide attention. The foreign guests walked along the red carpet, climbed the steps, walked past the energetic ceremonial guards, and entered the Great Hall of the People again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Everyone took a group photo, standing in front of the painting &quot;So Many Beauties&quot;, the scene blended together. Isn&#39;t the picturesque vision of the country the reason why they gathered here? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the music of &quot;Peace-A Community with a Shared Future&quot; played, President Xi Jinping walked into the venue together with the foreign guests. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The applause started and lasted for a long time. The magnificent diplomatic history has recorded countless &quot;influential moments&quot;. This scene is one of them. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping stepped onto the podium, and hundreds of millions of eyes gathered. The keynote speech &quot;Building an Open, Inclusive, Interconnected, and Common Development World&quot; clearly highlighted China&#39;s proposition. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China is already taking action. Looking around the world, the Belt and Road Initiative is creating countless stories of &quot;openness, inclusiveness, interconnection, and common development&quot; in the honking of ships, loading and unloading at docks, building bridges, cultivating fields, and roaring factories. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chairman Xi Jinping’s narration outlines the process from “big freehand brushwork” to “meticulous brushwork” and opens up a magnificent picture. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We can work together to promote this. &quot;The camel bell and sail shadow of international trade in the new era&quot;, &quot;the oasis and lighthouse of sustainable development in the new era&quot;, &quot;the commercial avenue and post station in the new era&quot;... The joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; has unleashed unprecedented vitality and potential. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We share weal and woe. &quot;China has provided tens of billions of masks and 2.3 billion doses of vaccines to various countries, and cooperated with more than 20 countries to produce vaccines, making a unique contribution to the fight against the epidemic by the partners of the Belt and Road Initiative.&quot; The world has seen a responsible big country in the fight against the epidemic. Step forward at critical moments. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The three &quot;we deeply realize&quot; are related to a shared destiny, win-win cooperation, and the spirit of the Silk Road. They are President Xi Jinping&#39;s profound summary of ten years of experience and are useful inspiration for planning the future. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The keynote speech was broadcast through the lens across thousands of rivers and mountains:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The 10-year process has proved that the joint construction of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; is on the right side of history, in line with the logic of the progress of the times, and on the right path. This is the right path in the world.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Follow the great path and the world will go forward. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the podium, President Xi Jinping spoke confidently and calmly about &quot;China&#39;s eight actions to support high-quality joint construction of the Belt and Road Initiative.&quot; At the top of the list is &quot;building a three-dimensional interconnection network for the &#39;One Belt, One Road&#39;&quot;. Thinking back ten years ago, when the joint construction of the &quot;Silk Road Economic Belt&quot; was first proposed, the first emphasis was on the &quot;five links&quot;. Accumulating steps will lead you to a thousand miles. From infrastructure construction to green development and technological innovation, from traditional business formats to new fields, it is precisely in this way that we have climbed mountains and crossed ridges. The media vividly described the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; as entering the 2.0 era. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One detail made many foreign media sigh with emotion. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When President Xi Jinping finished his speech and walked off the podium, the foreign guests stood up one after another, shook hands with him and congratulated him. One commentator said: &quot;These handshakes are full of power and speak a thousand words.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Six foreign guests took the stage one after another. Their speeches expressed the broad resonance of the countries working together to build the “Belt and Road”. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Russian President Vladimir Putin said: &quot;The joint construction of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; is a general trend and has global significance. When this grand initiative was proposed, some people had doubts. But we have seen that it has achieved complete success. Benefiting all our countries.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Tokayev, who studied in China, started his speech with a well-spoken Chinese: &quot;The &#39;Belt and Road&#39; initiative has become a popular international project and the largest cooperation. platform. This project reflects China&#39;s economic strength and its desire to reach new heights at the global level. The achievements of this project are obvious to all.&quot; This video won the praise of many netizens: &quot;Mandarin is very standard!&quot;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;Argentine President Fernandez, who comes from the other side of the world, detailed the benefits of jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and said: &quot;&#39;Alone is fast, and together we are far.&#39; In such a severe moment, we move forward together, step by step. To a world that everyone hopes for.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Coming from the &quot;Ancient Camel Bell Road&quot;, the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; brings unlimited possibilities to the world and allows the world to have a deeper understanding of its value for the future. Some foreign media praised highly: &quot;The importance of this forum cannot be overstated.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Hand in hand&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;From the 17th to the 20th, bilateral activities&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The rhythm is intensive, starting from the people This can be seen in the frequently changing national flags outside the East Hall of the General Assembly Hall. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping’s talks and meetings began on the morning of the 17th and ended at noon on the 20th, with as few as three or five meetings and as many as eight or nine meetings per day. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Friends from Asia, Africa and Europe have arrived after a long journey. Friends from America and Oceania, who are far away across the oceans, have come across mountains and seas. Accompanied by the melody of &quot;Beijing Welcomes You&quot;, they walked down the gangway and stepped onto the land of China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I know you from afar, but I don’t know how deep the clouds are.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Many of them are old friends. Take the bilateral meeting on the 17th as an example:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kazakhstan President Tokayev and Uzbekistan President Mirziyoyev just visited China in May this year. &quot;We have a lot of gold&quot;;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I met with Chilean President Boric in Bangkok, Thailand, in November last year. President Xi Jinping was deeply impressed: &quot;We had a very good talk that time&quot;;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Ethiopian Prime Minister Abiy came and &quot;met again after less than two months&quot;;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hungarian Prime Minister Orban attended the summit forum for three consecutive years. President Xi Jinping praised: &quot;This shows your firm support &#39;Belt and Road&#39; construction&quot;;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Indonesian President Joko visited China again. President Xi Jinping said to him cordially: &quot;We met during the opening ceremony of the Chengdu Universiade more than two months ago. The scene at that time was vivid. &quot;At the moment&quot;;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Serbian President Vucic is also an old friend of China. President Xi Jinping commented: &quot;Serbia has become a die-hard friend of China&quot;;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, the circle of friends who have pooled their wisdom and strength to jointly build the “One Belt, One Road” has become wider and wider. Adhering to openness and inclusiveness, every meeting and meeting with leaders of countries co-building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; has yielded new progress and new gains, which vividly proves that &quot;when everyone adds fuel, the flames will rise&quot;. For example, in February last year, Serbia “reached important consensus on opening direct flights between China and Serbia and negotiating and signing a bilateral free trade agreement during the meeting.” This time, President Xi Jinping mentioned, “I am happy to see that these consensuses have been implemented, and I believe that they will It will inject new momentum into the development of China-Serbia relations in the new era.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Indonesia&#39;s Jakarta-Bandung high-speed railway is known as &quot;China&#39;s first high-speed railway to go overseas.&quot; After the talks, the heads of state of China and Indonesia jointly inaugurated the official opening of the Jakarta-Bandung high-speed railway. What is “One Belt, One Road”? It is a grand initiative and a warm feeling for people of all countries. In the town of Mahazaza in Madagascar, it is the &quot;egg road&quot; built with China&#39;s aid; in the Mekong River countries, it is a &quot;safe well&quot;; in more than 100 countries such as Papua New Guinea and Fiji, it is a &quot;well&quot;. &quot;Chinese Juncao&quot;... There are large projects, large projects, and also &quot;small but beautiful&quot; and &quot;beneficial but practical&quot; livelihood projects to help local people solve their urgent needs. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some people describe cooperation between countries as a bridge. On a fast-flowing river, building bridges and paving roads is of great significance. &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; is just a bridge and a road connecting each other. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The last time the heads of state of China and Russia met in Moscow, this time they shook hands in Beijing. President Xi Jinping recalled the past: &quot;In the ten years since 2013, we have met 42 times and established a good working relationship and a profound friendship.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Putin also expressed a lot of gratitude: &quot;In my last visit After a year and a half of visiting China, I brought a large delegation to Beijing and saw with my own eyes the prosperity and development of Beijing.&quot; &quot;Seeing that Chinese friends have made great achievements, I also hope that more countries can Participate in the joint construction of the &#39;One Belt, One Road&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This cooperation belt with the longest span and the most potential in the world has gathered the greatest consensus that the jointly built countries aspire to develop and is in line with the jointly built countries&#39; economic upgrading. The most urgent desire. One road and one bridge span not only mountains and rivers, but also development gaps; one port and one corridor smooth not only business exchanges, but also international destiny. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is a plan for the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pakistani Prime Minister Kakkar said to President Xi Jinping emotionally: &quot;We often say that China-Pakistan friendship is higher than mountains, deeper than seas, and sweeter than honey. I believe that as you said, when China can When things go well, other countries in the world will also live better. This is also an opportunity for Pakistan, and we will seize it.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Be optimistic about China and believe in China. When the world is eager to understand China and get closer to China, the &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; opens a door. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the meeting, after hearing President Xi Jinping’s praise, Hungarian Prime Minister Orban responded with a smile: “I supported your initiative from the beginning. I firmly believe that this initiative can change the world, change the world economy, and also It can bring benefits to more people.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Moving forward&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The past ten years and the bright future&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;History is made by the brave. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking back on that autumn ten years ago, President Xi Jinping went west to Kazakhstan and south to Indonesia. The &quot;Silk Road Economic Belt&quot; and the &quot;21st Century Maritime Silk Road&quot; traveled through time and space, and dreams came from the depths of history. Come. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ancient Silk Road was glorious, with Zhang Qian riding a horse and Zheng He sailing on long voyages, a period of vicissitudes that makes people feel nostalgic. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It was a prosperous time in Chinese history. The rise and fall of the ancient Silk Road followed the ups and downs of China&#39;s national destiny. When the mountains and rivers are reduced to the survival of the nation, only rolling yellow sand and huge waves are left. Today, with the great cause of rejuvenation, the ancient Silk Road has been awakened, and those who have responded are gathering. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When placing chess pieces, time and momentum are important. The joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative coincides with a new era, a time when the international order and global governance are undergoing major changes unseen in a century, and a time when the international status of countries in the &quot;Global South&quot; is constantly improving and the future It&#39;s an exciting time, it&#39;s the right time, it&#39;s the right moment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This time, President Xi Jinping met with Rousseff, President of the New Development Bank. In 2014, when Rousseff was president, they jointly witnessed the birth of the New Development Bank in Brazil. Today, President Rousseff said that there has never been any initiative in history that can bring more than 150 countries together like the Belt and Road Initiative, and she is &quot;willing to actively participate in co-building the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; cooperation.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It seems that the foreshadowing is inadvertently laid, but in fact it is a historical necessity. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the world’s second largest economy, the largest trader of goods, and the largest foreign exchange reserve country, China’s opportunities not only provide the most promising future, but also “stand on the right side of history and stand on the right side of history.” &quot;On the side of progress of human civilization&quot; is the right path in the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Congolese President Sassouaux told President Xi Jinping that the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; is a great project that provides the world with a new model of inclusive development. China is a major contributor to world economic growth, and Congo sincerely admires China&#39;s great achievements in development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is a renewal of the form of civilization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A country that used to be poor, weak, and full of waste, has explored a Chinese-style modernization path that is very different from the West, and created a new form of human civilization. The joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; has built a tangible road of connectivity and reshaped the intangible way of thinking. Many political figures have expressed their admiration for President Xi Jinping&#39;s strategic vision. They regard China as a role model and are eager to learn from China&#39;s experience. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Illuminate the way forward with the light of thought. Global development initiatives, global security initiatives, global civilization initiatives, every voice of China has stirred up the world for a long time. This time is no exception. Many foreign dignitaries expressed their appreciation and support for the three major global initiatives proposed by President Xi Jinping, which &quot;will definitely bring more hope to the world.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 20th is the last day of this home diplomatic schedule. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On this morning, President Xi Jinping met successively with Sri Lankan President Wickremesinghe, Vietnamese President Vo Van Thang, and General Secretary of the Central Committee of the Lao People&#39;s Revolutionary Party and President Thongloun Sisoulith. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;They once again talked about the &quot;eight actions&quot; proposed by President Xi Jinping at the opening ceremony, believing that this was a pragmatic move for the future. &quot;The &#39;One Belt, One Road&#39; and three major global initiatives you proposed reflect the responsibility of a major power and party, as well as China&#39;s charisma and positive role in leading world peace, cooperation and development.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Full of heavy expectations Harvest, one after another special planes took off. The third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum consolidated international consensus, enriched cooperation results, expanded bright prospects, and also allowed people to once again see the value of the public goods that China provides to the world today. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; is like a magnificent painting, writing the legend of the times of a community with a shared future for mankind. Ten years, a hundred years... the prologue is brilliant, and the future is promising. The right path in the world leads to a long way. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 06:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 昂扬奋进，奔向下一个金色十年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20231022_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Sunday, October 22, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;History always inspires people in some special years. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ten years ago, President Xi Jinping proposed the concept of building a community with a shared future for mankind, and later proposed the initiative of jointly building the &quot;Silk Road Economic Belt&quot; and the &quot;21st Century Maritime Silk Road&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the golden autumn of this year, President Xi Jinping and old and new friends from all over the world gathered in Beijing to attend the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum. The eyes of the world are once again focused on Beijing and China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From October 17th to 20th, 4 days and nearly 30 bilateral and multilateral activities. In the intensive schedule, there are profound thoughts, grand plans, solemn declarations, in-depth exchanges, broad consensus, and fruitful results. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping’s third “One Belt, One Road” International Cooperation Summit Forum announced to the world that the joint construction of “One Belt, One Road” has ushered in a new stage of higher quality and higher level development, and also marked the following It is a new starting point for China on its new journey to make new and greater contributions to the cause of peace and development of mankind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;A common moment&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;——“We firmly believe that the historical trend of peace, development, cooperation and win-win is unstoppable, and the people’s pursuit of a better future The yearning for life is unstoppable, and the desire of all countries to achieve common development and prosperity is unstoppable.&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Hello, President Xi, nice to meet you!&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;A long way to go. Come, welcome!”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On October 17th, the lanterns were lit for the first time. In front of the white marble steps on the first floor of the Great Hall of the People, there are flowers and flowers and laughter. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping and his wife Peng Liyuan warmly welcome here the more than 20 foreign heads of state, heads of government, heads of international organizations and their spouses who attended the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum, and join them one by one. Shake hands and exchange greetings. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These foreign leaders and heads of international organizations come from Asia, Europe, Africa, Latin America, Oceania and other different regions of the world, and are representatives of partners in building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. Photographers pressed their shutters one after another to capture this unforgettable moment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum is China&#39;s most important home diplomacy this year and the most solemn event in the 10th anniversary of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative. Representatives from 151 countries and 41 international organizations actively participated in the conference, including leaders of relevant countries, heads of international organizations, ministerial officials, and people from all walks of life such as the business community, academic institutions, and non-governmental organizations. The number of registered people exceeded 10,000. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So many friends from all walks of life from all over the world gathered in Beijing to participate in this grand event, which clearly shows the aspirations of the international community. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping’s schedule is full during and around the summit forum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In addition to attending the opening ceremony of the summit forum, delivering a keynote speech, and holding a welcome banquet, President Xi Jinping arranged seven and a half days from the 17th to the 20th to hold separate talks with all foreign leaders attending the forum. Meetings often work from early morning until late at night. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; to strengthening bilateral cooperation in various fields, from the current international and regional situation to the exchange of experience in state governance... There are too many topics to talk about, and we have passed the meal several times. . President Xi Jinping has always treated friends and partners from all over the world with sincerity and sincerity. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This year marks the 10th anniversary of my proposing the Belt and Road Initiative. The original intention of proposing this initiative was to learn from the ancient Silk Road, take interconnection as the main line, and strengthen policy communication and facility connectivity with other countries. , unimpeded trade, financial integration, and people-to-people connectivity will inject new momentum into world economic growth, open up new space for global development, and create a new platform for international economic cooperation.&quot; President Xi Jinping recalled the past. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past 10 years, under the planning, guidance and promotion of President Xi Jinping, the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; international cooperation has grown from scratch, transformed from &quot;general freehand brushwork&quot; to &quot;meticulous painting&quot;, and transformed from planning diagrams to real scenes. Picture, from hard connectivity to soft connectivity, from dream seeds to towering trees. More than 150 countries and more than 30 international organizations have signed cooperation documents on the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, launched thousands of pragmatic cooperation projects, and harvested tangible and heavy results. Through consultation, joint contribution and sharing, we have connected the world and created a beautiful world. A magnificent picture shared by all. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The joint construction of the ‘One Belt, One Road’ has gone through the first ten years of vigorous development, and it is now in its prime. We must forge ahead with high spirits and head towards the next golden decade!” at the People’s Assembly on the evening of the 17th At the welcome banquet held in the Golden Hall of the National People&#39;s Congress, President Xi Jinping delivered an affectionate speech. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Those who share the same ambition should not let the mountains and seas be far away. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Although President Tokayev of Kazakhstan and President Joko of Indonesia have met with President Xi Jinping in China this year, as part of the joint efforts to build the &quot;Silk Road Economic Belt&quot; and the &quot;21st Century Maritime Silk Road&quot; &quot;The heads of state who initiated it all decided without hesitation to come to China again to attend the summit forum;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Russian President Vladimir Putin has been looking forward to it since he received President Xi Jinping&#39;s state visit to Russia in March. Once again had face-to-face and in-depth exchanges with President Xi Jinping. He said with deep feeling that not all national plans will produce results, but Chinese friends have made great achievements in this regard. President Xi Jinping never makes decisions based on one moment, but looks to the future and makes long-term considerations. He is a true world leader and a firm, calm, pragmatic and reliable partner;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hungarian Prime Minister Viktor Orban has attended continuously held three “One Belt, One Road” International Cooperation Summit Forum. He told President Xi Jinping that the reason why Hungary has firmly supported the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative from the beginning is because it firmly believes and sees that this initiative can change the world, change the world economy, and bring benefits to more people;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;Due to the sudden escalation of the regional situation and being unable to attend the forum in China as originally planned, Egyptian President Sisi and UAE President Mohammed sent their prime ministers and special representatives to attend the forum respectively to express their country&#39;s firm support for the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;In the guest list, people also saw Raffarin, an old friend of the Chinese people and former French Prime Minister, who came to the meeting as President Macron’s special representative; Greek Prime Minister Mitsotakis High Representative and Minister of Development Skrekas; saw former Japanese Prime Minister Yukio Hatoyama...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From Asia to Europe, from Africa to Latin America, and then to the Pacific Island countries; from being connected to China&#39;s mountains and rivers from developing countries to developed countries; from the world&#39;s largest intergovernmental international organization to emerging multilateral financial institutions... The house was full of distinguished guests and guests, demonstrating the &quot;Belt and Road Initiative&quot; &quot;The attraction, influence and cohesion. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Ten years of weathering the wind and rain, and ten years of spring blossoms and autumn harvests. The joint construction of the Belt and Road Initiative originated from China, and the results and opportunities belong to the world.” President Xi Jinping’s sincere words show that a country with ancient history and civilization and a major developing country have A broad mind that seeks progress for mankind and great harmony for the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Common cause&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;——“Only by persevering in self-improvement and unremitting struggle, can we reap abundant fruits and build a future that will benefit the future and bring happiness to the future. The long-lasting contribution of all people. This is the responsibility of our generation of politicians to the current and future generations.&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the morning of the 18th, more than 150 people jointly built the grand banquet hall on the second floor of the Great Hall of the People. The spectacular flag formation composed of the national flags of the “Belt and Road” countries and the United Nations flag was magnificent. More than 1,000 representatives from all walks of life from various countries came to the venue early to participate in the opening ceremony of the summit forum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Reviewing the ten-year achievements of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, summarizing the experience of jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, and announcing major measures to promote the high-quality development of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;... President Xi Jinping&#39;s keynote speech won wide recognition from international dignitaries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the end of the speech, the audience burst into thunderous applause. Leaders of various countries and heads of international organizations sitting in the front row of the venue stood up one after another, warmly shook hands with President Xi Jinping to express their congratulations, and paid tribute to China&#39;s outstanding contributions to promoting the high-quality development of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After shaking hands with all the foreign leaders and heads of international organizations in the front row, President Xi Jinping took his seat with everyone. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Why is the “Belt and Road” international cooperation thriving and growing? The answer may lie in this scene. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; conforms to the aspiration of people of all countries to live a better and happier life, and conforms to the common expectations of developing countries to jointly realize modernization; it is not a solo act of China, but The chorus of all countries in the world is not a private territory of China, but a common cause of the international community. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Congratulations! Mr. President.&quot; On the evening of the 18th, United Nations Secretary-General Guterres said enthusiastically when he saw President Xi Jinping in the East Hall of the Great Hall of the People. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Thank you for coming to this forum.” President Xi Jinping responded with a smile. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I have to come!” Guterres said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is the third time that Guterres has attended the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum as the Secretary-General of the United Nations, representing the United Nations&#39; support for the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. He said that driven by the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative, countries have gained more opportunities in the field of infrastructure and accelerated the implementation of sustainable development goals. &quot;This brings hope and progress to billions of people and the planet we share.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the cordial exchange, President Xi Jinping expressed his thoughts:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The ‘Belt and Road Initiative’ has a history of 10 years. We sorted it out at this forum and found that we are still on the earth.做了不少事情，而且做的都是建设性的事情。所以&#39;一带一路&#39;才展现出蓬勃生机活力，成为广受欢迎的全球公共产品和国际合作平台。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当然，这个过程中也有杂音、唱衰的声音，但是都经不起推敲。否则为什么这么多国家都希望参与&#39;一带一路&#39;呢？应了中国一句老话，酒香不怕巷子深，还有一句话，桃李不言，下自成蹊。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“建设性的事情”，饱含深意。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在开幕式主旨演讲中，习近平主席深刻指出，共建“一带一路”注重的是众人拾柴火焰高、互帮互助走得远，崇尚的是自己过得好、也让别人过得好，践行的是互联互通、互利互惠，谋求的是共同发展、合作共赢。不搞意识形态对立，不搞地缘政治博弈，也不搞集团政治对抗，反对单边制裁，反对经济胁迫，也反对“脱钩断链”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国古语云：执大象，天下往。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;开幕式前一天，习近平主席先后同8位来华与会的外国领导人进行了双边会晤。在同印度尼西亚总统佐科会谈后，两国元首有一项特殊安排：共同为雅万高铁正式开通运营揭幕。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会谈中，习近平主席对佐科总统说：“雅万高铁是中印尼共建&#39;一带一路&#39;合作的&#39;金字招牌&#39;，中方愿同印尼总结成功经验，做好后续高质量运营，培育雅万高铁经济带。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从一条高铁，到一个经济带。不只有沉甸甸的成果，更有值得期待的未来。像这样以一个基础设施项目为依托，久久为功推动一个地区经济发展和现代化建设的故事，在共建“一带一路”实践中不胜枚举。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同巴布亚新几内亚总理马拉佩谈到菌草技术，谈到莫尔斯比港独立大道、布图卡学园建设；同塞尔维亚总统武契奇谈到河钢斯梅戴雷沃钢厂，谈到匈塞铁路；同肯尼亚总统鲁托谈到蒙内铁路，谈到蒙巴萨油码头；同老挝人民革命党中央总书记、国家主席通伦谈到中老铁路圆了老挝变“陆锁国”为“陆联国”的梦想；同巴基斯坦总理卡卡尔谈到承载着巴经济发展梦想的中巴经济走廊；同尼日利亚副总统谢蒂马谈到两国合作建设的铁路、港口、电站、通信骨干网、自由贸易区……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;却顾所来径，苍苍横翠微。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这些成就不是天上掉下来的，也不是什么人恩赐施舍的，而是各国政府、企业和人民用勤劳、智慧、勇气干出来的！让我们向共建&#39;一带一路&#39;所有的参与者、建设者致敬！”习近平主席的话充满温度和力量。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;回首不凡历程，品味累累果实，规划光明未来，新朋老友的相聚时间，充实而难忘。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;塞尔维亚总统武契奇，对习近平主席2016年访塞期间到访河钢斯梅戴雷沃钢厂的情景记忆犹新。这一次来北京，同习近平主席会见，他的一番真情告白令人动容：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“您的那次访问对塞尔维亚而言具有至关重要的意义。在塞尔维亚遇到巨大困难时，是中国给了我们支持，为塞尔维亚人民带来了巨大福祉”；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在所有涉及中国的问题上，塞尔维亚都坚定地同中国站在一起。这并不容易，但是我们为此倍感自豪”；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我期待着您再次访问塞尔维亚，塞尔维亚人民将给予您最热情的欢迎。因为塞尔维亚人知道，中国为塞尔维亚的发展作了多大的贡献”……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;正如习近平主席在主旨演讲中所言：赠人玫瑰则手有余香，成就别人也是帮助自己。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;共同的远方&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;——“本着对历史、对人民、对世界负责的态度，携手应对各种全球性风险和挑战，为子孙后代创造和平、发展、合作、共赢的美好未来”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大国外交，蕴含着“中国之于世界，世界之于中国”的深邃思索。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;推动共建“一带一路”，习近平主席放眼的是人类历史长河。他在开幕式主旨演讲中指出，和平合作、开放包容、互学互鉴、互利共赢的丝路精神，是共建“一带一路”最重要的力量源泉。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在京期间，37岁的智利总统博里奇专程登上长城，亲身感受灿烂的中华文明。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“修建了万里长城的古代中国不可谓不强大，但并没有因此走上国强必霸的道路，而是在和平与合作的基础上发展对外关系。”博里奇深有感触，“我们可以从这一伟大文明中学到很多东西。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会谈中，他对习近平主席说：“您提出的共建&#39;一带一路&#39;倡议，源自中国5000多年传统文化，基于平等和相互尊重原则，已经成为世界各国开展互利合作的重要平台和实现共同发展的重要机遇，智方高度评价并将继续积极参与。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欢迎仪式、会谈、签字仪式……一个小时很快就过去了，博里奇意犹未尽，同习近平主席边走边谈。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从历史之中国，到今日之中国；从古老悠久的文明，到日新月异的现代化。共建“一带一路”，不仅打通了地理的阻隔，也向世界展现了一个可信、可爱、可敬的中国。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;回首5000多年中华文明史，中华文明突出的连续性、创新性、统一性、包容性、和平性，成为今天共建“一带一路”的深厚文明基因。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;回首2000多年丝绸之路史，这条文明交融之路之所以名垂青史，靠的不是战马和长矛，而是驼队和善意；不是坚船和利炮，而是宝船和友谊。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;回首100多年艰辛探索史，中国人民历经千辛万苦走出的中国式现代化道路，也给共建“一带一路”国家的现代化探索提供了新的借鉴和选择。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;回首10年“一带一路”建设史，这一划时代的重大倡议，跨越不同文明、文化、社会制度、发展阶段差异，开辟了各国交往的新路径，搭建起国际合作的新框架，汇集着人类共同发展的最大公约数……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当前，世界百年未有之大变局加速演进，热点问题此起彼伏，人类社会前进面临新的重大挑战。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“共建&#39;一带一路&#39;站在了历史正确一边，符合时代进步的逻辑，走的是人间正道。我们要有乱云飞渡仍从容的定力，本着对历史、对人民、对世界负责的态度，携手应对各种全球性风险和挑战，为子孙后代创造和平、发展、合作、共赢的美好未来。”习近平主席指出。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这份美好未来里，有中国更好的发展——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“共建&#39;一带一路&#39;就是要再为中国这只大鹏插上两只翅膀，建设好了，大鹏就可以飞得更高更远。”多年来，在北京，在上海，在新疆，在福建，在广西……习近平主席对通过共建“一带一路”为构建新发展格局提供有力支撑寄予厚望。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界好，中国才会好；中国好，世界会更好。共建“一带一路”是新时代中国对外开放和对外合作的管总规划、经济外交的顶层设计，是中国同世界各国互利共赢的合作路线图。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;正如习近平主席所说，通过共建“一带一路”，中国对外开放的大门越开越大，内陆地区从“后卫”变成“前锋”，沿海地区开放发展更上一层楼，中国市场同世界市场的联系更加紧密。中国已经是140多个国家和地区的主要贸易伙伴，是越来越多国家的主要投资来源国……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这份美好未来里，有各国共同的现代化梦想——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;40年前曾在北京语言大学短期进修的哈萨克斯坦总统托卡耶夫回到母校，感慨“当年经常去的五道口、四道口，现代化了”。他对习近平主席说，将继续推动哈萨克斯坦大型经济建设项目同“一带一路”倡议对接；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;肯尼亚总统鲁托正在带领国家努力实现经济转型，他向习近平主席表示，希望能更多学习中国发展的成功经验，助力肯尼亚的现代化事业；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;埃塞俄比亚总理阿比告诉习近平主席，此行发现北京更加清洁美丽、人民更加幸福，希望向中方学习借鉴治党治国理政经验；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年3月到上海履新的新开发银行行长罗塞夫，半年来走访了中国多个省份，中国式现代化建设经验对全球南方国家的借鉴价值给她留下深刻印象。她对习近平主席说，历史上从来没有任何一个倡议像“一带一路”这样，能够把150多个国家凝聚在一起……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们追求的不是中国独善其身的现代化，而是期待同广大发展中国家在内的各国一道，共同实现现代化。世界现代化应该是和平发展的现代化、互利合作的现代化、共同繁荣的现代化。”习近平主席在主旨演讲中指出。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;构建“一带一路”立体互联互通网络、支持建设开放型世界经济、开展务实合作、促进绿色发展、推动科技创新、支持民间交往、建设廉洁之路、完善“一带一路”国际合作机制……习近平主席宣布的支持高质量共建“一带一路”八项行动，为各国共同实现现代化注入强劲动力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;17日举行的企业家大会上，各国企业代表排队签约的盛况传遍社交网络。从企业家大会，到互联互通、数字经济、绿色发展三场高级别论坛，再到贸易畅通、海洋合作、廉洁丝路、智库交流、民心相通、地方合作六场专题论坛……本届高峰论坛期间，各方共达成89项多边合作成果文件、369项务实合作项目，充分表明助力各国现代化事业，共建“一带一路”不开“空头支票”，而是坚定的“行动派”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这份美好未来里，有推动构建人类命运共同体、创造人类文明新形态的历史担当——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在同中方打交道时，我始终能感受到对阿方的极大尊重，这是我决定签署&#39;一带一路&#39;合作谅解备忘录的重要原因”，阿根廷总统费尔南德斯由衷地说；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尼日利亚副总统谢蒂马有同样的感受：“中国对尼日利亚等非洲国家始终予以尊重和平等，从不颐指气使，而是尽力支持非洲人民寻求独立和发展”……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行程万里，初心不忘。大道如砥，行者无疆。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“让我们谨记人民期盼，勇扛历史重担，把准时代脉搏，继往开来、勇毅前行，深化&#39;一带一路&#39;国际合作，迎接共建&#39;一带一路&#39;更高质量、更高水平的新发展，推动实现世界各国的现代化，建设一个开放包容、互联互通、共同发展的世界，共同推动构建人类命运共同体！”习近平主席为共建“一带一路”奔向下一个金色十年开启光明前景。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（新华社北京10月21日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;记者刘华、杨依军、孙奕、许可、温馨、罗鑫）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 06:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 《习近平外交思想学习问答》出版发行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20231022_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月22日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;新华社北京10月21日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;为把学习贯彻习近平外交思想不断引向深入，中央宣传部、外交部组织编写了《习近平外交思想学习问答》（以下简称《问答》）一书，已由学习出版社、人民出版社联合出版，即日起在全国发行。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;《问答》紧跟中国特色大国外交实践发展步伐，聚焦理论热点难点，回应现实关心关切，以问答体形式全面系统、深入浅出展现习近平外交思想的重大意义、科学体系、核心要义、丰富内涵和实践要求，帮助广大党员干部群众更加深入学习领会党的创新理论，更加自觉用以武装头脑、指导实践、推动工作。《问答》共分10个板块、48个问题，内容丰富、形式新颖，图文并茂、通俗易懂，是广大党员干部群众深入学习习近平外交思想的重要辅助读物。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 06:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 共建“一带一路”走的是人间正道]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20231022_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月22日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;大道不孤，众行致远。在第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛开幕式上，习近平主席指出，“10年的历程证明，共建&#39;一带一路&#39;站在了历史正确一边，符合时代进步的逻辑，走的是人间正道”，强调“我们要有乱云飞渡仍从容的定力，本着对历史、对人民、对世界负责的态度，携手应对各种全球性风险和挑战，为子孙后代创造和平、发展、合作、共赢的美好未来”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10年来，在各方的共同努力下，共建“一带一路”取得历史性成就，成果惠及150多个国家，开拓出一条通向共同发展的合作之路、机遇之路、繁荣之路，成为深受欢迎的国际公共产品和国际合作平台。成绩弥足珍贵，经验值得总结。回望10年历程，我们深刻认识到，人类是相互依存的命运共同体；只有合作共赢才能办成事、办好事、办大事；和平合作、开放包容、互学互鉴、互利共赢的丝路精神，是共建“一带一路”最重要的力量源泉。习近平主席高度概括的这三个方面的重要经验，对于深化“一带一路”国际合作，推动共建“一带一路”进入高质量发展的新阶段，激励各国坚守合作初心、牢记发展使命，在共同努力中开创人类更加美好的未来，具有重大指导意义。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界好，中国才会好；中国好，世界会更好。共建“一带一路”既是为了中国的发展，也是为了世界的发展。随着世界多极化、经济全球化、社会信息化、文化多样化深入发展，各国相互联系和彼此依存比过去任何时候都更频繁、更紧密，人类越来越成为你中有我、我中有你的命运共同体。共建“一带一路”以构建人类命运共同体为最高目标，并为实现这一目标搭建实践平台、提供实现路径。10年来，通过共建“一带一路”，中国对外开放的大门越开越大，内陆地区从“后卫”变成“前锋”，沿海地区开放发展更上一层楼，中国市场同世界市场的联系更加紧密。今天，中国已经是140多个国家和地区的主要贸易伙伴，是越来越多国家的主要投资来源国。无论是中国对外投资，还是外国对华投资，都彰显了友谊和合作，体现着信心和希望。中国不断扩大对外开放，不仅发展了自己，也造福了世界。实践充分证明，人类是相互依存的命运共同体，秉承开放精神，推进互帮互助、互惠互利，才能让大家一起发展，实现可持续发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;历史反复证明，开放包容、合作共赢才是人间正道。只要各国有合作的愿望、协调的行动，天堑可以变通途，“陆锁国”可以变成“陆联国”，发展的洼地可以变成繁荣的高地。从中外合作伙伴发起成立20余个专业领域多边对话合作机制，到共建国家依托中国—东盟（10+1）合作、中非合作论坛等重大多边合作机制平台不断深化务实合作，再到加快推进多层次、复合型基础设施网络建设……共建“一带一路”以共商共建共享为原则，积极倡导合作共赢理念与正确义利观，坚持各国都是平等的参与者、贡献者、受益者，推动实现经济大融合、发展大联动、成果大共享。实践充分证明，只有合作共赢才能办成事、办好事、办大事。共建“一带一路”是大家携手前行的阳光大道，只要大家把彼此视为朋友和伙伴，相互尊重、相互支持、相互成就，赠人玫瑰则手有余香，成就别人也是帮助自己。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;古丝绸之路绵亘万里，延续千年，积淀了以和平合作、开放包容、互学互鉴、互利共赢为核心的丝路精神。这是人类文明的宝贵遗产。共建“一带一路”在新的时代背景下传承和发扬丝路精神，不仅唤起人们对过往时代的美好记忆，更激发出各国实现互联互通的极大热情。实践充分证明，丝路精神是共建“一带一路”最重要的力量源泉。习近平主席强调：“共建&#39;一带一路&#39;注重的是众人拾柴火焰高、互帮互助走得远，崇尚的是自己过得好、也让别人过得好，践行的是互联互通、互利互惠，谋求的是共同发展、合作共赢。”面向未来，从古丝绸之路和丝路精神中汲取智慧和力量，沿着历史的方向继续前进，更好地融通中国梦和世界梦，共建“一带一路”必将更好实现各国人民对文明交流的渴望、对和平安宁的期盼、对共同发展的追求、对美好生活的向往。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平主席指出：“共建&#39;一带一路&#39;走过了第一个蓬勃十年，正值风华正茂，务当昂扬奋进，奔向下一个金色十年！”始终站在历史正确一边、站在人类文明进步一边，走人间正道，干正义事业，携手同心、勇毅前行，我们就一定能不断战胜各种风险和挑战，实现更高质量的共商、共建、共享，让共建“一带一路”越来越繁荣、越走越宽广，共同绘制人类命运共同体的美好画卷。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 06:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 十四届全国人大常委会第六次会议举行第二次全体会议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20231022_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月22日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;本报北京10月21日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者黄庆畅）十四届全国人大常委会第六次会议21日上午在北京人民大会堂举行第二次全体会议。赵乐际委员长出席。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李鸿忠副委员长主持会议。常委会组成人员158人出席会议，出席人数符合法定人数。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年6月至9月，全国人大常委会开展了湿地保护法、科学技术进步法执法检查。会议听取了全国人大常委会副委员长丁仲礼作的常委会执法检查组关于检查湿地保护法实施情况的报告。报告介绍了法律实施情况和存在的主要问题，提出加强法律实施的意见建议：加强统筹协调，严格落实法定职责；严格执法司法，确保法律刚性和权威；强化支撑保障，全面提升湿地保护修复水平；完善配套法规制度，织密湿地保护的法制网；深入开展宣传教育，推动形成多元共治的良好格局。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会议听取了全国人大常委会副委员长蔡达峰作的常委会执法检查组关于检查科学技术进步法实施情况的报告。报告介绍了执法检查工作基本情况和法律实施成效，指出了存在的主要问题，提出加强法律实施的意见建议：加大宣传贯彻力度，确保法律制度落地见效；加强顶层设计谋划，增强创新体系整体效能；健全新型举国体制，加快关键核心技术攻关；强化基础研究能力，夯实科技强国建设根基；加快体制机制改革，完善科技创新基础制度；统筹央地创新资源，支持区域科技创新发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会议听取了中国人民银行行长潘功胜受国务院委托作的关于金融工作情况的报告。报告介绍了2022年第四季度以来金融工作主要进展及成效、当前经济金融面临的形势和问题，并提出下一步工作考虑：继续实施稳健的货币政策；全面加强和完善金融监管；持续提高金融服务实体经济的能力；不断深化金融改革和对外开放；积极稳妥防范化解金融风险；着力维护金融市场稳健运行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会议审议了国务院关于2022年度国有资产管理情况的综合报告。报告介绍了国有资产总体情况、管理工作情况，提出下一步工作安排。会议听取了财政部副部长廖岷受国务院委托作的关于2022年度金融企业国有资产管理情况的专项报告。专项报告介绍了金融国有资产总体情况、管理工作情况、服务经济社会发展成效以及存在的问题，提出了完善金融国有资产管理工作的思路与措施：深化落实国有金融资本集中统一管理，持续优化国有金融资本战略布局，不断夯实以管资本为主的金融国有资产管理制度体系，稳步提高金融服务实体经济的效率和水平，有效防范化解金融风险。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会议听取了全国人大财政经济委员会副主任委员、全国人大常委会预算工作委员会主任许宏才作的关于金融企业国有资产管理情况的调研报告。报告介绍了金融企业国有资产管理的基本情况、存在的突出问题，提出了相关建议：全面推动金融国资国企高质量发展；持续优化国有金融职能定位和布局结构；健全国有金融资产管理体制机制；提升金融国资国企管理质效；构建现代金融企业国有资产治理格局。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会议听取了教育部部长怀进鹏受国务院委托作的关于考试招生制度改革情况的报告。报告介绍了改革进展及成效、面临的形势和挑战，并提出下一步工作考虑：努力扩大优质高等教育资源；优化中小学招生规模及方式；稳步提升中西部地区改革保障能力；深化中高考考试内容改革；深化普通高中育人方式改革；深化高中综合素质评价改革；完善职教高考的形式和内容；加强拔尖创新人才选拔培养；强化高考改革外部环境治理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会议听取了国务委员、公安部部长王小洪受国务院委托作的关于打击生态环境和资源保护领域犯罪工作情况的报告。报告介绍了打击环境资源犯罪的主要成效、加强依法打击环境资源犯罪能力建设的主要做法、面临的形势和困难问题，并提出下一步工作措施和建议：深入贯彻落实习近平生态文明思想，坚决扛起打击环境资源犯罪的政治责任；深刻认识和把握“五个重大关系”，创新打击环境资源犯罪工作思路理念；大力加强制度机制和基础性建设，为美丽中国建设提供有力支撑保障；全面加强专业侦查队伍建设，努力锻造适应美丽中国建设要求的公安铁军。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会议听取了最高人民法院院长张军作的关于人民法院环境资源审判工作情况的报告。报告介绍了2018年以来环境资源审判工作取得的积极进展和存在的问题，提出要学思践悟习近平生态文明思想和习近平法治思想，以深化理念变革引领环境资源审判工作高质量发展，树立能动司法理念、绿色发展理念、系统保护理念、最严法治理念、协同治理理念，努力在新征程上推进环境资源审判工作迈向更高水平，为加快推进人与自然和谐共生的现代化提供更加有力司法服务和保障。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会议听取了最高人民检察院检察长应勇作的关于人民检察院生态环境和资源保护检察工作情况的报告。报告介绍了主要工作和成效、面临的挑战和问题，提出要深入贯彻党的二十大和全国生态环境保护大会精神，提高政治站位，自觉服务人与自然和谐共生的现代化；抓实监督办案，不断提升生态环境和资源保护检察工作质效；深化多方协同，持续凝聚生态环境和资源保护工作合力；加强队伍建设，着力提升生态环境和资源保护检察履职能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全国人大常委会副委员长王东明、肖捷、郑建邦、郝明金、何维、铁凝、彭清华、张庆伟、洛桑江村、雪克来提·扎克尔，秘书长刘奇出席会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家监察委员会负责同志，全国人大各专门委员会成员，各省区市人大常委会负责同志，部分副省级城市人大常委会主要负责同志，部分全国人大代表，有关部门负责同志等列席会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 06:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 携手奏响阳光、和谐、自强、共享的华彩乐章]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20231022_7-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月22日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;“心相约，梦闪耀”。10月22日，第4届亚洲残疾人运动会在浙江省杭州市隆重开幕。来自亚洲40多个国家和地区的3000多名残疾人运动员，在这里追逐人生梦想、展现自强风采、共叙团结友谊，携手奏响阳光、和谐、自强、共享的华彩乐章，凝聚起亚洲团结奋进的磅礴力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;办好杭州亚运会、亚残运会是今年党和国家工作中的一件大事。自申办成功以来，在以习近平同志为核心的党中央坚强领导下，亚残运会各项筹办工作顺利推进。总结运用亚运会成功举办宝贵经验，浙江省和杭州市扎实有序做好亚运会、亚残运会转换工作，乘势而上办好杭州亚残运会，确保“两个亚运、同样精彩”。举办杭州亚残运会，不仅为残疾人运动员提供展示竞技水平和精神风貌的舞台，也将搭建起一个残疾人交流的平台，铭刻下中国为国际残疾人体育运动发展作出的新贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对广大残疾人来说，体育具有重要价值，是增强体质、康复身心、参与社会、实现全面发展的有效途径。杭州亚残运会共设22个大项、564个小项，为残疾人运动员追梦圆梦提供了难得机遇。勇于挑战，超越自我，展现自强不息、顽强拼搏的精神，广大残疾人运动员必将成就出彩人生。此次杭州亚残运会，中国残联成立由723人组成的代表团，参加全部22个大项的角逐。自尊、自信、自立、自强，大力弘扬残疾人体育精神，在一个个项目比拼中充分展现生命力量和卓越品格，中国残疾人运动员定能再创佳绩，夺取运动成绩和精神文明双丰收，以挑战极限、锐意进取的精神激励全国人民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关心残疾人，是社会文明的重要标志。习近平总书记强调：“中国对残疾人格外关心、格外关注，在中国式现代化进程中，将进一步完善残疾人社会保障制度和关爱服务体系，促进残疾人事业全面发展。”新时代以来，我们坚持以人民为中心的发展思想，坚持弱有所扶，保障残疾人平等权利，增进残疾人民生福祉，推动残疾人事业发展取得历史性进步和成就。亚残运会筹办和举办过程，是展示残疾人事业发展成就的窗口，也是推动我国残疾人事业发展的重大契机。面向未来，中国将始终坚持人民至上，大力弘扬人道主义精神，切实尊重和保障包括残疾人参与体育运动的权利在内的各项权益，推动残疾人事业向现代化迈进，不断满足广大残疾人对美好生活的向往，并愿同世界各国一道，共同推进国际残疾人事业交流与合作，不断增进人类健康福祉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以体育之名，聚亚洲之力，筑未来之路。当亚残运会的火炬熊熊燃起，不仅照亮了夜空，更点亮了人间大爱，传递出生生不息的力量。西子湖畔，亚残运会的运动员们必将用奋斗和汗水演绎精彩、书写传奇、传播友谊，共同奏响生命的强音。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预祝杭州第4届亚洲残疾人运动会圆满成功！&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 06:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 二十届中央第二轮巡视完成进驻]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20231022_8-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月22日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;本报北京10月21日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者赵成）根据党中央关于巡视工作统一部署，截至10月20日，二十届中央第二轮巡视完成进驻工作。15个巡视组将对26家中管企业和5家职能部门开展常规巡视，对国家铁路局党组、中国国家铁路集团有限公司党组开展巡视“回头看”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被巡视单位分别召开巡视进驻动员会。各中央巡视组组长作动员讲话，对深入学习贯彻习近平总书记关于巡视工作重要讲话精神，扎实开展巡视工作提出要求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;各中央巡视组组长指出，巡视是推进党的自我革命、全面从严治党的战略性制度安排，是发现和推动解决问题的有效方式。中央巡视组将坚持以习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想为指导，全面贯彻中央巡视工作方针，坚守政治巡视职能定位，旗帜鲜明把“两个维护”作为根本任务，紧盯权力和责任，紧盯“一把手”和领导班子，紧盯群众反映强烈的突出问题，紧盯巡视整改和成果运用，从政治上发现问题、查找偏差，把严的基调、严的措施、严的氛围传导下去、一贯到底，以有力有效政治巡视促进高质量发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;各中央巡视组组长要求，要准确把握政治巡视监督重点，聚焦被巡视党组织职能责任，深入了解贯彻落实党的路线方针政策和党中央重大决策部署情况，重点查找坚持和加强党的全面领导、履行主责主业，统筹发展和安全、防范化解重大风险，落实深化改革要求、推进治理体系和治理能力现代化等方面存在的问题；深入了解落实全面从严治党战略部署情况，重点查找“一把手”履行第一责任人责任、班子成员履行“一岗双责”、纪检监察机构履行监督责任，以及作风建设和廉洁自律等方面存在的问题；深入了解落实新时代党的组织路线情况，重点查找加强领导班子自身建设、干部人才队伍建设和基层党组织建设等方面存在的问题；深入了解巡视整改落实和成果运用情况，重点查找履行整改主体责任、监督责任以及重点问题整改等方面存在的问题，释放从严整改的鲜明信号。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;被巡视党组织主要负责人表示，将深入学习贯彻习近平总书记和党中央关于巡视工作重要部署要求，以接受巡视监督为契机，切实提高政治站位、把握职能定位，树立和践行正确政绩观，把主责主业牢牢扛在肩上，以履职尽责的实际行动、具体举措、工作成效践行“两个维护”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据悉，15个中央巡视组将在被巡视单位工作2个月左右，期间设立专门值班电话和邮政信箱，主要受理反映被巡视党组织领导班子及其成员、下一级党组织主要负责人和重点岗位人员问题的来信来电来访，重点是关于违反政治纪律、组织纪律、廉洁纪律、群众纪律、工作纪律和生活纪律以及巡视整改等方面问题反映。巡视组受理信访时间截止到2023年12月20日。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 06:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 弘扬留学报国传统  投身强国复兴伟业]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20231022_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月22日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;“为党和国家事业发展广聚天下英才、广集创造伟力”“在推进强国建设、民族复兴伟业中书写人生华章”……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10月21日，习近平总书记向欧美同学会成立110周年致贺信，充分肯定了欧美同学会作出的积极贡献，深刻阐明了欧美同学会的使命任务，对广大留学人员提出殷切期望，为做好新时代留学人员工作提供了根本遵循。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记的贺信让欧美同学会各级各类组织工作人员倍感温暖、深受鼓舞，引发海内外留学人员强烈共鸣。大家表示，要牢记习近平总书记的殷殷嘱托，自信自强、砥砺奋进，继承和发扬留学报国的光荣传统，将个人梦想融入强国建设、民族复兴的宏伟事业中，在新时代新征程上书写人生精彩篇章。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 继承光荣传统&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;矢志报效祖国&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;成立于民族危难之时的欧美同学会，成立伊始就积极践行爱国思想。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“从习近平总书记在欧美同学会成立100周年庆祝大会上的讲话到这次的贺信，爱国报国始终是关键词。”认真学习了习近平总书记的贺信，欧美同学会研究院高级研究员陶庆华说，留学报国精神是欧美同学会的灵魂，我们将牢记总书记的贺信精神，高举留学报国旗帜，以满腔爱国热情报效祖国、服务人民，为实现中华民族伟大复兴竭诚尽智。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;现场聆听了习近平总书记的贺信，欧美同学会党组书记、秘书长李民深感责任重大：“作为党领导下的具有群众性、高知性、统战性的人民团体，我们坚持把党的政治建设摆在首位，不断加强对留学人员的思想引领，让欧美同学会始终成为党联系广大留学人员的桥梁纽带，进一步把欧美同学会建设成新时代广大留学人员的团结之家、奋斗之家、温暖之家。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;爱国之心不已，报国之志弥坚。习近平总书记的贺信，激荡起海内外留学人员对新时代新征程的强烈责任感使命感。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“作为留学人员，习近平总书记的贺信更加坚定了我对未来发展的信心。”今年新加入欧美同学会的暨南大学国际关系学院办公室副主任温馨表示，作为一名教育工作者，我要在思想上更加笃定自信，将贺信的鼓舞激励转为实际工作的动力，在新征程上奋发前行，彰显我们这一代留学人员的使命担当。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记的贺信让中国留俄学生总会主席钟磊倍感振奋：“牢记习近平总书记对大家的殷切期望，我们将团结带领广大留俄学子怀报国情、立强国志，加强与俄罗斯青年交往交流，为推动构建人类命运共同体贡献青春力量。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 发挥自身优势&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;激发创造伟力&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记希望“欧美同学会要增强政治性、先进性、群众性”，这使得北京市欧美同学会秘书长王璞今后开展工作的方向更加明晰了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“北京是欧美同学会的创始之地，是留学人员的聚集高地。”王璞说，将以总书记贺信精神为指引，听党话、跟党走，坚持首善标准，植根人民、胸怀人民，引导广大留学人才积极投身首都建设、再立新功。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;反复阅读习近平总书记的贺信，浙江省欧美同学会秘书长周涌青开始思考如何更好“继续发挥留学报国人才库、建言献策智囊团、民间外交生力军作用”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周涌青表示，近年来，他们引导广大留学人员在聚焦建设共同富裕示范区、开展与海外高校联谊联络等方面下功夫、求突破，不断织密组织网络。“下一步，我们将落实好总书记的贺信精神，把广大留学人员紧密团结在党的周围，发挥组织优势，不断激发人才的创造活力。”周涌青说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记贺信中“强化思想引领和组织建设”的希望让西安欧美同学会秘书长李峰涛印象深刻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“强化思想政治引领，擘画留学报国同心圆，是欧美同学会一以贯之的使命担当。”李峰涛说，西安欧美同学会通过组织海归创业大赛、乡村振兴调研等活动，让留学人员在学思践悟中增强报效祖国、服务地方的使命感，引导他们在推进中国式现代化的西安实践中作贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新时代是呼唤人才也造就人才的伟大时代。环境好，则人才聚、事业兴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;既是海归创业者，又担任广州欧美同学会副会长的袁玉宇对习近平总书记的贺信很有共鸣。“总书记高度重视人才工作，欧美同学会在其中承担凝聚留学英才、贡献人才力量的重任。”目前正在推进高性能医疗器械核心技术攻关的袁玉宇表示，将继续发挥欧美同学会作用，广聚天下英才于粤港澳大湾区，推动更多科技成果落地转化、惠及时代。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;投身时代洪流&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;书写报国新篇章&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;学习了习近平总书记的贺信，济南市欧美同学会名誉会长、山东元隆生物技术有限公司董事长王革干事创业劲头更足了：“我的科研梦想是祖国铸就的，我要将个人命运融入祖国改革发展事业中、人民创造历史的奋斗中。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对下一步的方向，王革成竹在胸：“伟大时代提供了广阔舞台，我和团队将以高水平科技创新培育高质量发展新动能，发扬科学家精神和企业家精神，勇当中国科技和产业创新的开路先锋。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2016年全职回国后，中国科学院脑科学与智能技术卓越创新中心高级研究员竺淑佳便带领团队聚焦NMDA受体结构和功能的研究，这将有助于新药研发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记的贺信更加坚定了竺淑佳投身科研的决心。“科学研究不是为了发表一两篇论文，而是要解决科学问题、帮助更多患者。”竺淑佳表示，自己和同事们将咬定青山、刻苦钻研，奋力创新创造，以扎实的研究成果交出留学人员的时代答卷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文明因交流而多彩，文明因互鉴而丰富。留学人员是推动中外文明交流互鉴的积极支持者和促进者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“作为一名在英留学人员，我一直将促进中外文明交流互鉴当作自己义不容辞的职责使命。”牛津大学统计学专业博士生、全英中国学生学者联谊会主席张瑞华说，在未来的留学过程中，自己将继续组织开展跨国度、跨学科的学术文化交流活动，让可信、可爱、可敬的中国形象更加真实可感。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“继往开来、薪火相传。欧美同学会将凝聚起新时代留学人员推进强国建设、民族复兴的强大力量。”学习了习近平总书记的贺信，福建中医药大学科技创新与转化中心副主任林尧心潮澎湃，“我们将以贺信精神为指引，在求学世界、圆梦中华的征程上书写人生华章，为以中国式现代化全面推进中华民族伟大复兴贡献更多智慧和力量。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（新华社北京10月21日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;新华社记者）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 06:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 从新的起点再出发]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20231022_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月22日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;国家主席习近平近日在第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛开幕式上发表主旨演讲，宣布中国支持高质量共建“一带一路”的八项行动，强调中方愿同各方深化“一带一路”合作伙伴关系，推动共建“一带一路”进入高质量发展的新阶段，为实现世界各国的现代化作出不懈努力。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;接受本报记者采访的专家学者表示，本届高峰论坛是共建“一带一路”进程中又一个重要里程碑。习近平主席的主旨演讲为深化“一带一路”国际合作注入新动力，为各国携手建设开放包容、互联互通、共同发展的世界贡献智慧和力量。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;10年来，“一带一路”国际合作从无到有，蓬勃发展，取得丰硕成果。“为什么共建&#39;一带一路&#39;能得到国际社会广泛响应？因为它激活了世界各国，尤其是发展中国家独立自主探索现代化道路的梦想。”中国人民大学习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想研究院副院长王义桅说，中国正在以中国式现代化全面推进强国建设、民族复兴。中国追求的不是独善其身的现代化，而是同广大发展中国家在内的各国一道，共同实现现代化。中国式现代化的经验，正通过共建“一带一路”分享给各国，极大鼓舞了广大发展中国家走符合各自国情的现代化道路的信心。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;中国国际问题研究院副研究员苏晓晖表示，当前，世界之变、时代之变、历史之变正以前所未有的方式展开，和平合作、开放包容、互学互鉴、互利共赢的丝路精神显得弥足珍贵。“中国看到，和平发展、合作共赢的时代潮流没有变；个别国家搞单边主义、保护主义，动辄拉&#39;小圈子&#39;、搞&#39;脱钩断链&#39;的做法不可行。共建&#39;一带一路&#39;倡议已经成为中国参与全球开放合作、促进全球共同发展繁荣、推动构建人类命运共同体的中国方案。”苏晓晖说，10年来，共建“一带一路”从理念转化为行动，从愿景转变为现实，成果惠及150多个国家，推动共建国家经济社会发展，成为当今世界最受欢迎的国际公共产品和最大规模的国际合作平台。在共建“一带一路”倡议提出10周年的时间节点举办第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛，既是对过去十年的总结，也是从新的起点再出发。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“八项行动明确了共建&#39;一带一路&#39;在未来一段时间的工作重点，为共建&#39;一带一路&#39;实现更高质量、更高水平的新发展提供了指引。”北京师范大学“一带一路”学院执行院长胡必亮表示，10年来，共建“一带一路”推动基础设施建设，带来新的投资，创造就业机会，提升了共建国家民众的获得感和幸福感，推动经济全球化朝着更加开放、包容、普惠、平衡、共赢的方向发展。他说，互联互通、绿色发展、数字经济等将是未来推动共建“一带一路”高质量发展、促进全球可持续发展的重点方向，中方将每年举办“全球数字贸易博览会”，举办首届“一带一路”科技交流大会、“良渚论坛”，成立丝绸之路旅游城市联盟，成立高峰论坛秘书处等，充分表明中国是坚定的“行动派”。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;10年的历程证明，共建“一带一路”站在了历史正确一边，符合时代进步的逻辑，走的是人间正道。论坛期间，各方共形成了458项成果，数量远远超过第二届高峰论坛。“丰硕成果反映出共建&#39;一带一路&#39;符合各国人民的发展利益。”胡必亮表示，共建“一带一路”走过了第一个蓬勃十年，正值风华正茂，必将昂扬奋进，奔向下一个金色十年，带给共建国家人民更多福祉。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 06:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - “这是我们这一代政治家对当代人和后代人的责任”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20231022_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月22日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;北京汇聚全球目光。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10月18日，第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛在京开幕。五洲四海的宾朋跨山越海、纷至沓来。在一个变乱交织的时代，不同文化背景、不同社会制度、不同发展阶段的国家能够坐在一起，商合作、叙友谊，弥足珍贵。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人们感叹于中国的凝聚力、影响力，感慨于“一带一路”的蓬勃生命力，也从习近平主席在开幕式上的主旨演讲，以及现场经久不息的掌声、外宾纷纷起身同他握手的镜头，去感悟。大国外交，沉潜着“中国之于世界，世界之于中国”的深邃思索。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是一段路途的总结。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十年，沧海一粟，却创造了沧桑巨变。仿佛一个象征，这次“一带一路”时间开启后，习近平主席会见的第一位客人，是来自哈萨克斯坦的托卡耶夫总统。十年前，正是在那里，共建“丝绸之路经济带”倡议提出。如今，“150多个国家、30多个国际组织签署共建&#39;一带一路&#39;合作文件”，规模和成效远远超出了当初的想象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是一段征程的起航。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在开幕式前一晚的欢迎宴会上，习近平主席一席话满怀憧憬：“正值风华正茂，务当昂扬奋进，奔向下一个金色十年！”在跨越“金德尔伯格陷阱”的期盼里，世界寄望中国，期待“下一个金色十年”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;下一个十年，有风雨之艰、有路途之遥，亦有同行之合力、步履之坚定。当习近平主席说起“这是我们这一代政治家对当代人和后代人的责任”时，饱含哲思：“纵观人类发展史，唯有自强不息、不懈奋斗，才能收获累累果实，才能建立利在千秋、福泽万民的长久之功。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自强不息、不懈奋斗，这是中国的知与行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;相聚&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;17日晚，欢迎宴会&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;百年变局叠加世纪疫情。时间的车轮来到今天，世界对经济复苏的渴望、对和平安宁的向往更为强烈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;17日晚，欢迎宴会。见证无数大事件的人民大会堂，150多面共建“一带一路”国家国旗和联合国旗，分列红毯两侧，蔚为壮观。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外宾们走过旗阵，微笑着走向红毯另一端的习近平主席和夫人彭丽媛。握手寒暄，笑语盈盈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;合影，定格历史的时刻，也注定被历史所铭记。习近平主席夫妇同来宾们并肩而立，一如他们所代表的国家和国际组织在“一带一路”建设中肩并肩同行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宴会厅内，一次生动的时代故事的讲述。“一带一路”是中国的故事，也是世界的故事。习近平主席的祝酒辞，将人们的思绪拉回那些奋斗的日夜：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“春发其华，秋收其实。”“这些成就不是天上掉下来的，也不是什么人恩赐施舍的，而是各国政府、企业和人民用勤劳、智慧、勇气干出来的！让我们向共建&#39;一带一路&#39;所有的参与者、建设者致敬！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;致敬，在荒山上、在海岛上、在共建“一带一路”的每一寸土地上，无数参与者、建设者翻山越岭、跋山涉水，望大漠如烟、弯月如钩；望碧波万顷、云帆高张。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一带一路”是过去的故事，也是未来的故事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平主席以三个“不可阻挡”，阐明面对一个并不太平的世界，中国的信心：我们坚信，“和平、发展、合作、共赢的历史潮流不可阻挡，人民对美好生活的向往不可阻挡，各国实现共同发展繁荣的愿望不可阻挡。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乘大势，行大道。“不可阻挡”的大势之下，有方兴未艾的“一带一路”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宴会厅内，一曲诗与舞的欢歌，一场东西方文化的对话。中国民族器乐《礼尚乐合》和热情的阿根廷舞曲《一步之遥》相遇，激昂的俄罗斯歌曲《卡林卡》和欢快的中国舞蹈《采茶》共振……“一带一路”也是文明的互鉴之路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文化的力量润物无声。全球治理的合作，首先要寻求文化的认同；全球经济的振兴，也要从文化交流中探索共促之道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“未之见而亲焉，可以往矣；久而不忘焉，可以来矣。”纵观人类文明进程，古丝绸之路以其连接文明形态之多、跨越历史时期之长而著称于世。“一带一路”所蕴含的天下大同、和合共生，也映射在习近平主席夫人彭丽媛同外方领导人夫人的参观活动中。在非遗传承的体验中，她们静心感悟着中华文化的丰富多姿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;共商&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;18日上午，开幕式&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;回溯过去数百年大国崛起，有战争和苦难、有掠夺和抗争。当中国的发展成为公认的“21世纪标志性事件”，这个最大的发展中国家如何同世界相处？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共建“一带一路”以共商、共建、共享为原则，以开放包容为特征，以互利共赢为追求，恰恰是对世界瞩目的最好回答。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;18日的开幕式世界瞩目。外宾们沿着红毯、登上台阶，走过精神抖擞的礼兵，再次步入人民大会堂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;众人合影，站在《江山如此多娇》的画作前，情景交融。江山如画的愿景，不正是他们相聚于此的缘由？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着《和平—命运共同体》的音乐奏响，习近平主席同外宾们一道，步入会场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;掌声起，经久不息。波澜壮阔的外交史，记载了无数“影响力时刻”。这一幕，是其中之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平主席登上讲台，亿万目光汇聚。《建设开放包容、互联互通、共同发展的世界》的主旨演讲，鲜明亮出中国主张。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国已经在行动。放眼全球，“一带一路”在轮船的鸣笛、在码头的装卸、在桥梁的建造、在田野的耕耘、在工厂的轰鸣中，正创造无数“开放包容、互联互通、共同发展”的故事。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平主席的讲述，勾勒了从“大写意”到“工笔画”的历程，拉开了一幅壮阔画卷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有携手共促。“新时代国际贸易的驼铃、帆影”“新时代可持续发展的绿洲、灯塔”“新时代的商贸大道、驿站”……共建“一带一路”迸发出前所未有的活力和潜力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有患难与共。“中国向各国提供了上百亿个口罩和23亿剂疫苗，同20多个国家合作生产疫苗，为共建&#39;一带一路&#39;合作伙伴抗击疫情作出独特贡献。”世界看到了一个负责任大国在关键时刻的挺身而出。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三个“我们深刻认识到”，事关命运与共、事关合作共赢、事关丝路精神，是习近平主席对十年经验的深刻总结，是谋划未来的有益启迪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;主旨演讲通过镜头传遍万水千山：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“10年的历程证明，共建&#39;一带一路&#39;站在了历史正确一边，符合时代进步的逻辑，走的是人间正道。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;循大道，天下往。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;讲台上，习近平主席自信从容，娓娓道出“中国支持高质量共建&#39;一带一路&#39;的八项行动”。排在首位的，是“构建&#39;一带一路&#39;立体互联互通网络”。遥想十年前，共建“丝绸之路经济带”提出之初，首先强调的是“五通”。积跬步，至千里。从基础设施建设到绿色发展、科技创新，从传统业态到新领域，正是这样爬过一座座山，翻过一道道岭，媒体生动地形容共建“一带一路”步入了2.0时代。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个细节令许多外媒感慨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当习近平主席演讲结束走下讲台，外宾们纷纷起身，同他握手、祝贺。有评价说：“这些握手饱含力量，有万语千言。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6位外宾相继登台。他们的致辞，道出了共建“一带一路”国家的广泛共鸣。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俄罗斯总统普京说：“共建&#39;一带一路&#39;是大势所趋，有全球性意义。提出这一宏大倡议时，有些人会有疑虑。但我们看到它取得了圆满成功，惠及我们所有国家。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;曾在中国留学的托卡耶夫总统，致辞时以一段字正腔圆的中文开场：“&#39;一带一路&#39;倡议已经成为热门国际项目和最大合作平台。该项目体现了中国的经济实力以及在全球水平上达到新高度的愿望。该项目取得的成就是有目共睹的。”这段视频，赢得许多网友点赞：“普通话很标准！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来自地球另一端的阿根廷总统费尔南德斯，细数共建“一带一路”的获益，感言：“&#39;独行快，众行远。&#39;在这样一个严峻时刻，我们共同前进，一步步迈向所有人共同希望的世界。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从“驼铃古道”走来，共建“一带一路”给世界带来无限可能，让世界更深刻认识它对未来的价值。有外媒盛赞：“这个论坛的重要性再怎么强调也不为过”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;携手&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;17日—20日，双边活动&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;节奏之密集，从人民大会堂东大厅外频繁更替的国旗，可见一斑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平主席的会谈会见，自17日早上开始，到20日中午结束，每日少则三五场，多则八九场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚洲、非洲、欧洲的朋友，风尘仆仆赶来了。远隔重洋的美洲、大洋洲的朋友，跨山越海赶来了。伴着《北京欢迎你》的旋律，他们走下舷梯，踏上中国的土地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“与君远相知，不道云海深。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;很多是老朋友。就拿17日这一天的双边会见来说：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哈萨克斯坦总统托卡耶夫、乌兹别克斯坦总统米尔济约耶夫，今年5月刚刚访华，“长安复携手，再顾重千金”；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同智利总统博里奇，去年11月在泰国曼谷见过面，习近平主席印象深刻：“那次我们谈得很好”；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;埃塞俄比亚总理阿比来了，“时隔不到两个月再次会见”；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;匈牙利总理欧尔班连续三届出席高峰论坛，习近平主席赞赏道：“这说明你是坚定支持&#39;一带一路&#39;建设的”；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印尼总统佐科再次访华，习近平主席亲切地对他说：“两个多月前我们在成都大运会开幕式期间相聚，当时的情景历历在目”；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;塞尔维亚总统武契奇也是中国的老朋友，习近平主席评价说：“塞尔维亚已经成为中国的铁杆朋友”；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些年，汇众智，聚合力，共建“一带一路”的朋友圈越来越广。秉持开放包容，每一次同共建“一带一路”国家领导人的会谈会见都有新进展新收获，生动佐证了“众人拾柴火焰高”。比如塞尔维亚，去年2月，“会见时就开通中塞直航、商签双边自由贸易协定达成重要共识”，这一次，习近平主席提到，“我高兴地看到这些共识已经得到落实，相信必将为新时代中塞关系发展注入新动能。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印尼的雅万高铁，被誉为“中国高铁&#39;出海&#39;第一单”。会谈后，中印尼元首共同为雅万高铁正式开通运营揭幕。“一带一路”是什么？它是宏阔的倡议，也是各国人民温热的触感。在马达加斯加马哈扎扎镇，它是中国援建的“鸡蛋路”；在湄公河国家，它是一口口“放心井”；在巴布亚新几内亚、斐济等100多个国家，它是一株株“中国菌草”……有大项目、大工程，也有一个个“小而美”“惠而实”的民生工程，帮助当地民众解燃眉之急。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有人将国与国的合作喻为桥梁。在湍急的大河上，架桥铺路的意义举足轻重。“一带一路”，正是连接彼此的一座桥、一条路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中俄元首上一次在莫斯科相聚，这一次握手北京。习近平主席抚今追昔：“2013年至今的十年里，我们先后42次会晤，建立了良好的工作关系和深厚友谊。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普京总统亦是感念良多：“在我上一次访华，时隔一年半之后，我带了阵容庞大的代表团来到北京，也亲眼看到了北京的繁荣发展。”“看到中国朋友们取得了很大成就，也希望更多国家能参与共建&#39;一带一路&#39;。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这条世界上跨度最长、最具潜力的合作带，凝聚了共建国家渴望发展的最大共识、契合了共建国家经济升级的最迫切意愿。一路一桥，跨越的不仅是山长水远，更是发展鸿沟；一港一廊，畅通的不仅是商贸往来，更是国际命运。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是为天下计的襟怀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴基斯坦总理卡卡尔充满感情地对习近平主席说：“我们经常说中巴友谊是比山高、比海深、比蜜甜，我相信正如您所说的，当中国可以过得好的时候，世界其他国家也能过得更好。这对于巴基斯坦来说也是一个机会，我们会把握住。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;看好中国，相信中国。当世界渴望读懂中国、走近中国的时候，“一带一路”打开了一扇门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会见时，听了习近平主席的赞赏，匈牙利总理欧尔班微笑着回应道：“一开始我就支持您的倡议，我深信这个倡议能改变世界，改变世界经济，也能给更多的人带来福利。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;前行&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;过去十年和广阔未来&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;历史是勇敢者创造的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;回首十年前的那个秋天，习近平主席西赴哈萨克斯坦、南下印度尼西亚，“丝绸之路经济带”和“21世纪海上丝绸之路”穿越时空，梦想从历史深处走来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;古时的丝路辉煌，张骞策马、郑和远航，一段让人感怀的岁月沧桑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那是中国历史上的繁盛之时。古丝绸之路的兴衰，随着中国国运跌宕起伏。当山河沦落民族存亡之时，只剩漫卷黄沙、滔天大浪。今天，伴随复兴伟业，古老丝路一经唤醒，应者云集。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;落棋弈子，讲求时与势。共建“一带一路”倡议提出之际，适逢新时代之时，适逢百年未有之大变局下国际秩序、全球治理发生变革之际，适逢“全球南方”国家国际地位不断提升、未来可期之际，正逢其时、正当其势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次，习近平主席会见了新开发银行行长罗塞夫。2014年，正是在罗塞夫担任总统时，在巴西，他们共同见证了新开发银行的诞生。而今，罗塞夫行长表示，历史上从来没有任何一个倡议像“一带一路”这样，能够把150多个国家凝聚在一起，“愿积极参与共建&#39;一带一路&#39;合作”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;看似不经意处埋下伏笔，实则历史的必然。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全球第二大经济体、第一大货物贸易国、第一大外汇储备国，中国机遇里不仅有最值得期许的未来，也有“站在历史正确的一边，站在人类文明进步的一边”的人间正道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;刚果（布）总统萨苏告诉习近平主席，共建“一带一路”是一项伟大的工程，为世界提供了崭新的包容发展的新模式。中国是推动世界经济增长的主要贡献者，刚方由衷钦佩中国发展取得的伟大成就。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是文明形态的焕新。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个昔日积贫积弱、百废待兴的国家，探索出了一条迥异于西方的中国式现代化道路，创造了人类文明新形态。共建“一带一路”，筑就了有形的联通之路，也重塑无形的思维方式。很多政要表达了对习近平主席战略远见的钦佩，他们将中国视为榜样，渴望借鉴中国经验。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以思想之光照亮前行之路。全球发展倡议、全球安全倡议、全球文明倡议，每一次中国之声，都在世界长久激荡。这一次也不例外。多位外国政要表示，赞赏和支持习近平主席提出的三大全球倡议，“必将为世界带来更多希望”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;20日，是这次主场外交日程安排的最后一日。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一天上午，习近平主席先后会见了斯里兰卡总统维克拉马辛哈，越南国家主席武文赏，老挝人民革命党中央总书记、国家主席通伦。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们再次谈起开幕式上习近平主席提议的“八项行动”，认为这是面向未来的务实之举。“您提出的&#39;一带一路&#39;和三大全球倡议，体现了大国大党担当，也体现了中国引领世界和平、合作与发展的感召力和积极作用。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;满载沉甸甸的收获，一架架专机腾空而起。第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛巩固了国际共识、丰富了合作成果、拓展了光明前景，也让人们再一次看到了今日中国给予世界这份公共产品的时代价值。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共建“一带一路”如瑰丽画迹，书写着人类命运共同体的时代传奇，十年、百年……序章灿烂，未来可期。人间正道，众行致远。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 22 Oct 2023 06:56:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>