<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 深入学习贯彻习近平文化思想]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/11/nw.D110000renmrb_20231011_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 11, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;All great practices require the correct guidance of scientific theories. Propaganda, ideological and cultural work is related to the future and destiny of the Party, to the long-term stability of the country, and to national cohesion and centripetal force. It must be guided by scientific theories, strengthen theoretical thinking, and summarize and apply the Party’s ideological and theoretical achievements on cultural construction in the new era. Better guide publicity, ideological and cultural work in the new era and new journey. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Recently, General Secretary Xi Jinping issued important instructions on the propaganda of ideological and cultural work. General Secretary Xi Jinping fully affirmed the historic achievements in ideological and cultural propaganda since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China from an overall and strategic perspective. The new cultural mission and the promotion of ideological and cultural work in the new era and new journey have put forward clear requirements. General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions are high-level, incisive and profound. They have a strong political, ideological and guiding nature, and point out the direction for further promoting ideological and cultural work. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;From October 7th to 8th, the National Ideological and Cultural Work Conference was held in Beijing. This is an important meeting decided by the Party Central Committee. The most important outcome of this meeting is the formal presentation and systematic exposition of Xi Jinping’s cultural thoughts, which is a milestone in the history of the development of the party’s propaganda, ideological and cultural undertakings. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Culture makes a country prosperous, and a strong culture makes a nation strong. Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core has placed ideological and cultural propaganda work in an important position in governance, made a series of major decisions and arrangements for ideological and cultural propaganda work, and promoted overall and ideological changes in the situation. Fundamental transformation. The Party&#39;s innovative theory in the new era is deeply rooted in the hearts of the people, the core socialist values ​​are widely disseminated, the creative transformation and innovative development of China&#39;s excellent traditional culture continue to advance, cultural undertakings and cultural industries are increasingly prosperous, the network ecology continues to improve, and the cultural culture of the entire Party and the people of all ethnic groups in the country continues The self-confidence has been significantly enhanced, the spirit is more high-spirited, and the historical awareness and initiative are stronger. The great history of China&#39;s development in the new era is being written with full confidence. Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the most fundamental reason why the propaganda, ideological and cultural work has achieved historic achievements is that General Secretary Xi Jinping has been at the helm and has the scientific guidance of Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Raising the flag, arranging the article, rectifying the source, staying true to the source and innovating, General Secretary Xi Jinping accurately grasped the trend of mutual stimulation of ideas and cultures around the world and the profound changes in the ideological concepts of our society, and put forward a series of new ideas and new perspectives New conclusion. Since the new era, around the propaganda, ideological and cultural work, the Party Central Committee has held intensive meetings, made comprehensive decisions and arrangements, and General Secretary Xi Jinping’s expositions have been rich, systematic, profound and profound, which are rare in the history of the Party. General Secretary Xi Jinping attended the National Propaganda and Ideological Work Conference twice, presided over meetings and delivered a speech on literary and artistic work, the party’s news and public opinion work, network security and informatization work, philosophy and social science work, ideological and political work in colleges and universities, and cultural inheritance and development. A series of important speeches, several meetings of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and meetings of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee reviewed and approved a series of plans and plans for the reform and development of publicity, ideological and cultural work, inspected various cultural inheritance and development projects in various places, and put forward a series of requirements. On multiple major international occasions, China has articulated a series of China’s positions and plans on the development of global culture and civilization, as well as exchanges and mutual learning. At the National Propaganda and Ideological Work Conference in August 2018, General Secretary Xi Jinping highly summarized our party’s regular understanding of propaganda and ideological work with the “Nine Persistences”; at the Cultural Inheritance and Development Symposium in June this year, it was clarified that cultural construction The &quot;Fourteen Emphasis&quot; on this aspect clearly put forward major innovative ideas such as upholding the party&#39;s cultural leadership, deeply understanding the &quot;two combinations&quot;, and shouldering new cultural missions, and proposed the major task of building a modern civilization of the Chinese nation; this time, General Secretary Xi Jinping The important instructions of the secretary also put forward the &quot;seven focus&quot; requirements for publicity, ideological and cultural work. General Secretary Xi Jinping’s new thoughts, new perspectives, and new judgments on cultural construction in the new era are very rich in connotation and extremely profound in discussion. They are a theoretical summary of the practical experience of party leadership in cultural construction in the new era. They enrich and develop Marxist cultural theory and constitute Xi Jinping’s The cultural chapter of the Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era formed Xi Jinping Thought on Culture. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping’s cultural thoughts not only have innovations and breakthroughs in cultural theoretical perspectives, but also have deployment requirements in the layout of cultural work. The mission statement marks that our party&#39;s understanding of the laws of socialist cultural construction with Chinese characteristics has reached a new height, that our party&#39;s historical confidence and cultural confidence have reached a new height, and has demonstrated great power in the construction of socialist culture in our country. It provides a powerful ideological weapon and scientific action guide to do a good job in publicizing ideological and cultural work in the new era and new journey and shouldering new cultural missions. Xi Jinping’s cultural thought is an ever-expanding and open ideological system that will surely be continuously enriched and developed with the deepening of practice. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Every time the party’s theoretical innovation takes a step forward, its theoretical arming must follow suit. We must conscientiously study and understand Xi Jinping&#39;s cultural thoughts, deeply grasp the great significance, rich connotation and practical requirements of Xi Jinping&#39;s cultural thoughts, persist in applying what we have learned, and achieve a thorough understanding of what we learn, think, apply, and unify knowledge, belief and action. It is necessary to continue to strengthen the study, research, and interpretation of Xi Jinping’s cultural thoughts, and consciously implement them in all aspects and the entire process of publicizing ideological and cultural work. It is necessary to thoroughly implement Xi Jinping Thought on Culture, fully implement the strategic deployment of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China on cultural construction, focus on the primary political task of arming the whole party with the party&#39;s innovative theories and educating the people, and continue to promote cultural prosperity at the new historical starting point. , build a culturally powerful country, and build the modern civilization of the Chinese nation as a new cultural mission, effectively enhance the sense of responsibility and mission to do a good job in publicizing ideological and cultural work in the new era and new journey, promote the implementation of various tasks, and contribute to the comprehensive construction of a modern socialist country and a comprehensive Promote the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation and provide strong ideological guarantee, strong spiritual power, and favorable cultural conditions. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Propaganda of ideological and cultural work is an extremely important task. In the new era and new journey, major changes in the world unseen in a century are accelerating. The great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation has entered a critical period. Strategic opportunities and risks and challenges coexist. Propaganda, ideological and cultural work is facing new situations and new tasks, and we must have a new look and new actions. Let us unite more closely around the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core, adhere to the guidance of Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, fully implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Party, thoroughly study and implement Xi Jinping Thought on Culture, and deeply understand the &quot;two The decisive significance of &quot;establishing&quot;, strengthen the &quot;four consciousnesses&quot;, strengthen the &quot;four self-confidences&quot;, achieve &quot;two safeguards&quot;, better shoulder the new cultural mission, constantly create new situations in publicity, ideological and cultural work in the new era, and provide Make new and greater contributions to the construction of a strong country and national rejuvenation. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 学思践悟创新理论  担当新的文化使命]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/11/nw.D110000renmrb_20231011_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 11, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;In the past few days, the majority of party members, cadres and the masses have deeply studied General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions on publicity and ideological and cultural work, and carefully understood the national propaganda The spirit of the Ideological and Cultural Work Conference stated that we must actively practice Xi Jinping’s cultural thoughts in our own work and strive to show a new atmosphere and new achievements in the struggle and practice of building a socialist cultural power and building a modern civilization of the Chinese nation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Understanding Xi Jinping’s Cultural Thoughts through Practice&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Xi Jinping’s Cultural Thoughts marks that our party’s understanding of the laws of socialist cultural construction with Chinese characteristics has reached a new level. The new height shows that our party&#39;s historical confidence and cultural confidence have reached a new height, which is a milestone in the history of the development of the party&#39;s propaganda, ideological and cultural undertakings.&quot; Xiao Guiqing, executive vice president of the Institute of Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, said, This important thought is a theoretical summary of the practical experience of party leadership culture construction in the new era. It enriches and develops Marxist cultural theory, embodies the combination of theory and practice, the connection between history and reality, the unity of domestic and international, and has a high degree of truth. nature, people’s nature, and practicality. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In-depth understanding of the historic achievements in publicity, ideological and cultural work since the new era, Zhang Xiong, director of the Policy and Regulations Research Office of the Propaganda Department of the Sichuan Provincial Party Committee, said that the most fundamental reason for this is that General Secretary Xi Jinping leads the way and has Xi Jinping at the helm. Scientific guidance of socialist ideology with Chinese characteristics in the new era. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Xi Jinping’s cultural thought is a scientific guide to action for carrying out work. We must study and implement it in depth, adhere to integrity and innovation, promote the high-quality development of propaganda, ideological and cultural work, promote the common prosperity of people’s spiritual life, and accelerate the construction of a new era of culture Strengthen the province and add luster to Chinese civilization with the light of Bashu culture.&quot; Zhang Xiong said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Since the new era, our country’s cyberspace atmosphere has changed, mainstream ideas and public opinions have been consolidated and strengthened, a comprehensive network management system has been basically established, and new steps have been taken in building a network power. The achievement of these achievements vividly demonstrates Xi Jinping’s culture The powerful power of ideas in the construction of socialist culture in our country.&quot; Li Fei, director of the Information Division of the Network Communication Bureau of the Central Cyberspace Administration of China, said that based on the struggle and practice of building a modern civilization of the Chinese nation, we will give full play to the advantages of network communication and empower with technological innovation. Able to innovate content, form and communication, continue to build online publicity brands, constantly create high-quality communication products, and strive to build a full-media communication system to shape a new pattern of mainstream public opinion. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After carefully studying the important instructions of General Secretary Xi Jinping and the spirit of this meeting, Zhang Xin, director of the Policy Research Division of the Theoretical Research Office of the China Federation of Literary and Art Circles, has a further understanding of Xi Jinping’s cultural thoughts. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized that &#39;the propaganda of ideological and cultural work is related to the future and destiny of the party, to the long-term stability of the country, and to national cohesion and centripetal force. It is an extremely important task.&#39; Do this work well. Literary and art workers have unshirkable responsibilities.&quot; Zhang Xin said that he will further study and thoroughly understand Xi Jinping&#39;s cultural thoughts, make the research, publicity and interpretation of this important idea more grounded, and promote the majority of literary and art workers to go deep into life, take root among the people, and create high-quality works. Excellent work, contributing literary and artistic power to building a socialist cultural power. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Deeply grasp the new situation and implement new requirements&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When talking about the understanding of the &quot;seven efforts&quot; put forward in the important instructions of General Secretary Xi Jinping, Guizhou Chen Shi, Secretary of the Shuicheng District Committee of Liupanshui City, said: &quot;The first point of the &#39;seven efforts&#39; is to strengthen the party&#39;s leadership in publicity, ideological and cultural work, which is also an important guideline for our work. We will further strengthen the party&#39;s leadership, We must implement the ideological responsibility system and accelerate the formation of a communication matrix with district-affiliated news media as the leader, government new media participation, and self-media linkage, so that the party’s innovative theories can enter thousands of households.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The autumn air is refreshing, The Yin Xu Museum, located in the northwest suburbs of Anyang City, Henan Province, is visited by an endless stream of visitors. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We will focus on ‘continuing the Chinese cultural context and promoting the creative transformation and innovative development of China’s excellent traditional culture’, and make the ancient Yin Ruins ‘alive’ with the help of digital technology and enhanced immersive experience. Promote traditional culture to continue to shine with new brilliance.&quot; said Zhao Qingrong, Secretary of the Party Branch and Executive Deputy Director of the Yinxu Museum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhou Hong, member of the Standing Committee of the Horgos Municipal Party Committee and Minister of the Propaganda Department of Xinjiang Ili Kazakh Autonomous Prefecture, was deeply touched by General Secretary Xi Jinping’s proposal to “strengthen the construction of international communication capabilities and promote exchanges and mutual learning among civilizations.” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As a ‘millennium post’ on the ancient Silk Road and an important window for my country’s opening to the west, Horgos continues to expand international communication through regular international media exchange activities such as Chinese and foreign media salons. Circle&#39;.&quot; Zhou Hong said that we will continue to innovate communication concepts and methods, build an external communication discourse system, tell the story of Horgos in the new era through multiple channels and forms, and let the world see a true, vivid, open, and united beautiful Xinjiang. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese civilization has a long history, is extensive and profound. Hu Chuansheng, director of the Archaeological Management Division of the Archeology Department of the State Administration of Cultural Heritage, said that he will continue to promote major projects such as the Chinese Civilization Discovery Project and Archaeological China, focusing on key issues such as the origin of mankind, the origin of agriculture, the origin of civilization, and the development of a unified multi-ethnic country. We should tackle key problems, protect historical culture in urban and rural construction, and inject profound and lasting cultural power into the construction of modern civilization of the Chinese nation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Continuously improve work quality and efficiency&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the banks of the Yanhe River, teachers at China&#39;s Yan&#39;an Cadre College collectively studied the important instructions and meeting spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The teaching work of the college will work hard on true learning, true understanding, true belief and true application, and deepening internalization and transformation. With the help of unique local historical and cultural resources, we will combine original readings, case teaching, and field visits to teach Xi Jinping well. The cultural chapter of the Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era further guides students to strengthen their cultural confidence and strengthen their political responsibility.&quot; said Wang Tao, director of the Party Building Teaching and Research Office of the Teaching and Research Department of China Yan&#39;an Cadre College. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After carefully studying the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions, Xinhua News Agency reporter Zhu Jichai has a clearer direction for future work: “We will grasp the correct political direction and public opinion guidance, and improve our business while strengthening the ‘four forces’ We will strive to launch more excellent news works that serve the overall interests of the country, grasp the pulse of the times, and reflect the voices of the people, so that the party’s ideas become the strongest voice of the new era, and the main theme becomes the positive energy that gathers people’s hearts.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &quot;For some time, Shaoyang City has launched a series of measures such as the &#39;Micro Lecture Hall&#39; for good people around you, to promote the construction of spiritual civilization in depth and in depth.&quot; Zhang Yingmei, deputy director of the Propaganda Department of the Shaoyang Municipal Party Committee and Director of the Municipal Civilization Office of Hunan Province, said that they will continue to reform and innovate. Use new technological means to promote the construction of spiritual civilization at the grassroots level, on the Internet, and in the hearts of the people, so that the masses can better share the achievements of spiritual civilization construction. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The General Secretary proposed to ‘continuously create a new situation in publicity, ideological and cultural work in the new era’. Publishing workers have a heavy responsibility and great potential.” Xu Hai, editor-in-chief of Jiangsu Phoenix Publishing Media Co., Ltd., said that digitization will be accelerated Construction, focusing on &quot;promoting culture&quot;, insisting on &quot;producing high-quality products&quot;, and focusing on &quot;educating new talents&quot;, create a digital publishing platform that serves national reading and smart education, launch more excellent cultural products full of the spirit of the times, and contribute to the comprehensive construction of socialist modernization It provides a strong ideological guarantee, strong spiritual power, and favorable cultural conditions for the country and comprehensively promotes the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 10)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 《共建“一带一路”：构建人类命运共同体的重大实践》白皮书发布]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/11/nw.D110000renmrb_20231011_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 11, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 10th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Chen Weiwei and Zou Duowei) introduced the joint construction of &quot; The achievements achieved by the Belt and Road Initiative in the past 10 years have further enhanced the understanding of the international community, promoted the high-quality development of the Belt and Road Initiative, and enabled the Belt and Road Initiative to benefit more countries and people. The State Council Information Office released the &quot;Joint Construction of the Belt and Road Initiative&quot; on the 10th &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot;: A major practice in building a community with a shared future for mankind&quot; white paper. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The white paper said that in March 2013, President Xi Jinping proposed the concept of building a community with a shared future for mankind; in September and October, he proposed to jointly build the &quot;Silk Road Economic Belt&quot; and the &quot;21st Century Maritime Silk Road&quot; . The joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative creatively inherits and carries forward the ancient Silk Road, the development achievements of human history and civilization, and gives it a new spirit of the times and humanistic connotation, providing a practical platform for building a community with a shared future for mankind. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The white paper points out that over the past 10 years, with the joint efforts of all parties, the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; has evolved from a Chinese initiative to international practice, from ideas to actions, from visions to reality, and from planning to layout. From the &quot;general freehand brushwork&quot; to the meticulously cultivated &quot;meticulous brushwork&quot;, it has achieved solid and profound achievements and has become a popular international public product and international cooperation platform. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The white paper said that over the past 10 years, the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; has not only brought tangible benefits to relevant countries, but also made contributions to promoting the healthy development of economic globalization, solving global development problems, and improving the global governance system. Active contributions have opened up a new path for mankind to jointly realize modernization and promoted the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind to take root. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The white paper points out that China is willing to work with all countries to unswervingly promote high-quality joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, implement the global development initiative, global security initiative, and global civilization initiative, and build a world of lasting peace, universal security, and In a world of common prosperity, openness, inclusiveness, cleanness and beauty, let the fire of peace be passed on from generation to generation, let the power of development continue, let the light of civilization shine, and jointly draw a beautiful picture of a community with a shared future for mankind! &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In addition to the preface and conclusion, the white paper is divided into five parts, namely: originating from China and belonging to the world; paving the road to common development and prosperity; promoting all-round and multi-field connectivity; and injecting world peace and development into Positive energy; promoting high-quality joint construction of the &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; for steady and long-term development. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;(See the second page for relevant reports, and the tenth to twelfth pages for the full text of the white paper)&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 李强主持召开国务院常务会议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/11/nw.D110000renmrb_20231011_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 11, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 10th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Premier Li Qiang of the State Council chaired an executive meeting of the State Council on October 10th. The &quot;Opinions on Strengthening the Dynamic Monitoring of Low-income Population and Carrying out Stratified and Classified Social Assistance Work&quot;, the &quot;Action Plan for Actively Developing Meal Assistance Services for the Elderly&quot; and the &quot;Special Action Plan for Patent Transformation and Application (2023-2025)&quot; were reviewed and adopted 》. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The meeting emphasized that social assistance is a fundamental and basic institutional arrangement in the social security system. It is necessary to thoroughly implement the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, strengthen the dynamic monitoring of low-income populations, carry out social assistance work more accurately, timely and effectively, accelerate the formation of a comprehensive, hierarchical and classified, comprehensive and efficient social assistance pattern, and provide a safety net for people&#39;s livelihood. Weave more densely and tie more firmly. It is necessary to further consolidate the main responsibilities of governments at all levels, effectively provide basic protection for people in need such as disasters, and distribute various relief funds and security funds on time and in full to ensure the basic life of people in need and ensure a safe and warm winter. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The meeting pointed out that the development of meal assistance services for the elderly is an important livelihood project and an important measure to support home and community care for the elderly and improve the well-being of the elderly. The development of meal-assisted services for the elderly should be regarded as an important part of practical work for the people, closely combined with the actual situation of various places, active, prudent, and local conditions should be developed to develop meal-assisted services for the elderly, and tilted measures should be taken to support the expansion of service supply in rural areas. All relevant departments must work closely together to form a synergy to ensure effective results. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The meeting emphasized that promoting the transformation and application of patents, fully tapping the value of patents, and vigorously developing patent-intensive industries is a strategic task to promote high-quality development. Efforts should be made to improve the quality of patent results and strengthen policy incentives, pay more attention to condensing scientific research problems from actual needs and tackling key problems, establish and improve institutional arrangements and incentive policies that are conducive to the transformation and application of patent results, and strive to open up the key to the transformation and application of patents. Blocking points, further optimizing market services, cultivating a good ecology, and accelerating the transformation of innovation results into real productivity. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Other matters were also considered at the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 深入学习贯彻习近平总书记关于巡视工作重要部署要求 以有力有效政治巡视促进国有企业高质量发展]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/11/nw.D110000renmrb_20231011_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 11, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;This newspaper, Beijing, October 10th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Meng Xiangfu) Member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Central Inspection Committee Li Xi, leader of the work leading group, attended the mobilization and deployment meeting of the 20th Central Committee’s second round of inspection work on the 10th and delivered a speech. The meeting conveyed and studied the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech when he listened to the Central Committee’s report on the first round of inspections, made arrangements for inspections of centrally managed enterprises and relevant functional departments, and emphasized the need to thoroughly study and implement the important deployment requirements of General Secretary Xi Jinping and the Party Central Committee on inspection work. , summarize and apply the experience of the first round of inspections, promote the in-depth development of political inspections with a more energetic state of mind and more scientific and pragmatic measures, urge the inspected party organizations to conscientiously perform their functions and responsibilities, and firmly support the &quot;two establishments&quot; and &quot;two establishments&quot; with practical actions. Resolutely achieve &quot;two safeguards&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Xi pointed out that since the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping and the Party Central Committee have made a series of new arrangements for inspection work from the strategic perspective of promoting the Party’s self-revolution and comprehensively and strictly governing the Party, leading the Inspection work in the new era continues to be vigorous and in-depth advancement. It is necessary to thoroughly study and implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speeches, further focus on key points, have the courage to show the sword, conduct precise supervision, and continuously improve the deterrence and pertinence of inspections. Accurately grasp the important requirements for &quot;two safeguards&quot; to be reflected in the performance of duties, conduct an in-depth search for deviations in the performance of functions and responsibilities of the inspected party organizations, and urge the inspected party organizations to shoulder their main responsibilities and implement them in action superior. Accurately grasp the important requirement that high-quality development must firmly adhere to the bottom line of safety, conduct in-depth searches for major risks and hazards, urge inspected party organizations to effectively prevent and resolve risks, and build a solid safety defense line at all levels. We must accurately grasp the important requirement of maintaining a strict tone in managing and governing the party, thoroughly identify outstanding issues in implementing the strategic deployment of comprehensive and strict party governance, and promote the in-depth development of comprehensive and strict party governance in the field of state-owned enterprises. Accurately grasp the key and important requirement of strengthening team building to grasp the &quot;top leaders&quot;, focus on strengthening the supervision of &quot;top leaders&quot;, and drive the &quot;vast majority&quot; by grasping the &quot;key minority&quot;. Accurately grasp the important requirements of being more serious in rectification in order to play the role of the inspection sword, promote the implementation of the main responsibilities and supervisory responsibilities of rectification, and ensure that inspections and rectifications achieve tangible results. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Xi emphasized that overall planning and organization and implementation should be strengthened to complete the second round of inspection tasks with high quality. We must give top priority to strengthening theoretical arming, consolidate and expand the results of thematic education, and always maintain the correct political direction of inspection work. We must adhere to the positioning of political inspection functions, strictly abide by the boundaries of responsibilities, insist on seeking truth from facts, and conduct inspections in accordance with regulations, disciplines and laws. It is necessary to adhere to the system concept, strengthen cooperation with discipline inspection and supervision agencies and organizational, auditing, finance, statistics, letters and calls and other departments, and enhance the synergy of supervision. It is necessary to conduct an in-depth analysis of the common problems and deep-seated problems that restrict the high-quality development of enterprises, and further promote the treatment of both symptoms and root causes. It is necessary to implement the requirements for education rectification, strictly enforce discipline and style, effectively strengthen the construction of the inspection team, and forge the inspection iron army with a thorough self-revolutionary spirit. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jiang Xinzhi, Vice Chairman of the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference and a member of the Central Inspection Leading Group, announced the appointment and division of tasks of the leaders of the second round of inspections of the 20th Central Committee. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 图片报道]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/11/nw.D110000renmrb_20231011_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 11, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231011/1696969750620_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/ TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Recently, the Jingxiong Bridge located on the Yongding River in Beijing completed the installation and tensioning of the suspension rods of the whole bridge, and began to dismantle the supports under the bridge and pave the bridge deck. stage, laying the foundation for the full opening of the Beijing-Xiongan Expressway (Beijing Section) within this year. The picture shows the Jingxiong Bridge under construction. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Photographed by Sun Lijun (Image China)&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - “十四五”以来新发现157处大中型矿产地（新数据 新看点）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/11/nw.D110000renmrb_20231011_7-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 11, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Our newspaper, Beijing, October 10th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Chang Qin) The reporter recently learned from the Ministry of Natural Resources: A new round of mineral prospecting breakthrough strategic actions has achieved phased results. Since the &quot;14th Five-Year Plan&quot;, 157 large and medium-sized mineral deposits have been newly discovered in various places. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In 2022, investment in oil and gas mineral exploration will reach 82.2 billion yuan, a record high, a year-on-year increase of 3.1%; investment in non-oil and gas mineral exploration will be nearly 10 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 15.6%. Since the &quot;14th Five-Year Plan&quot;, geological prospecting has achieved remarkable results. 8 newly discovered oil fields with a capacity of 100 million tons, 11 gas fields with a capacity of 100 billion cubic meters, 157 large and medium-sized mineral fields, and 112 prospecting prospecting areas have been delineated and submitted for commercial use. There are 102 exploration target areas. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Shandong gold mines, Jiangxi tungsten mines and lithium mines, Guizhou manganese mines, Gansu crystalline graphite mines, Xinjiang iron mines, Sichuan and Inner Mongolia lithium mines, and Henan coalbed methane have made significant progress in prospecting, and a new The amount of batch resources. Taking the new energy mineral lithium as an example, 1.19 million tons of new lithium oxide proven resources have been added, completing the “14th Five-Year Plan” prospecting goals ahead of schedule, laying a good foundation for accelerating domestic exploration and development of energy mineral resources and increasing reserves and production. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;It is understood that the Ministry of Natural Resources has formulated and issued a series of policies focusing on prospering the mining market and attracting business entities to invest in mineral prospecting. Natural resource authorities at all levels will further leverage the role of technology, equipment, and talents, gather the forces of all parties, and make every effort to promote a new round of strategic actions for mineral prospecting breakthroughs. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - “一带一路”，从愿景到现实（权威发布）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/11/nw.D110000renmrb_20231011_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, October 11, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;This year marks the tenth anniversary of the joint construction of the “Belt and Road” initiative. On the morning of October 10, the State Council Information Office held a press conference and released the white paper &quot;Co-building the Belt and Road Initiative: A Major Practice in Building a Community with a Shared Future for Mankind.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The white paper is guided by Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, systematically expounds the historical origins, conceptual vision, implementation path, practical achievements and world significance of the joint construction of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39;, and comprehensively introduces the joint construction&#39; The Belt and Road Initiative has produced fruitful results over the past ten years, illustrating China&#39;s determination and actions to promote high-quality development of the Belt and Road Initiative and to work with other countries to build a community with a shared future for mankind.&quot; said Chen Wenjun, Director of the Information Bureau and Spokesperson of the State Council Information Office . At the meeting, responsible comrades from relevant departments introduced and interpreted the relevant contents of the white paper. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;More than 150 countries and more than 30 international organizations have joined the Belt and Road Initiative family&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the past ten years, we have jointly built the Belt and Road Initiative. Along the way, we have always adhered to the principle of extensive consultation, joint contribution and shared benefits, upheld the concepts of openness, greenness and integrity, and aimed at high standards, sustainability and benefiting people&#39;s livelihood, and have achieved substantial and significant historic achievements.&quot; Deputy Director of the National Development and Reform Commission Cong Liang introduced. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In terms of &quot;hard connectivity&quot;. A number of landmark projects such as the China-Laos Railway, the Jakarta-Bandung High-speed Railway, the Hungary-Serbia Railway, and the Port of Piraeus have been completed and put into operation. The China-Europe freight train has opened up a new Asia-Europe land transportation channel, and the &quot;Silk Road Maritime&quot; international route network Across the world, the interconnection architecture of &quot;six corridors, six routes, multiple countries and multiple ports&quot; has basically taken shape. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As of the end of September, China-Europe trains have reached 217 cities in 25 European countries, with a total of more than 78,000 trains and more than 7.4 million TEUs of goods transported; the proportion of transported goods in the total trade between China and Europe has increased from 2016 to 2016. 1.5% to 8% in 2022. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In terms of &quot;soft connectivity&quot;. We continue to deepen cooperation with co-building countries in areas such as rules and standards. The Regional Comprehensive Economic Partnership Agreement has fully entered into force for 15 signatories. my country has signed 21 free trade agreements with 28 countries and regions, and has signed 21 free trade agreements with 65 national standardization agencies. It has signed 107 standardization cooperation agreements with international organizations and signed double taxation avoidance agreements with 112 countries and regions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In terms of &quot;heart-to-heart connection&quot;. Cooperation in the fields of education, culture, sports, tourism, archeology and other fields has been continuously deepened. It has signed agreements on mutual recognition of higher education qualifications with 45 co-building countries and regions, signed cooperation documents in the field of culture and tourism with 144 co-building countries, and established a &quot; The &quot;Silk Road&quot; government scholarship has created a number of &quot;small but beautiful&quot; cooperative brands such as &quot;Luban Workshop&quot;, &quot;Guangmingxing&quot;, and Juncao. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Trade and investment. We have actively developed mutually beneficial trade and investment cooperation with co-building countries, successfully hosted five China International Import Expos, advocated the establishment of the Asian Infrastructure Investment Bank and the Silk Road Fund, and basically formed a long-term, stable, sustainable, and risk-controllable investment and financing system. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past ten years, the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; has fully realized the transformation from concept to action, and from vision to reality, leading the construction of a new model of global interconnection, leading the creation of a new path for common prosperity and development, and leading the It has explored new options for reforming the global governance system and has become a popular international public product and international cooperation platform. “More than 150 countries and more than 30 international organizations have joined the Belt and Road Initiative to jointly build the ‘Belt and Road’ family, and the people of the jointly built countries have gained The sense of happiness and happiness are constantly increasing.&quot; Cong Liang said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;my country is the main trading partner of more than 110 countries co-building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Economic and trade cooperation is an important part of the co-building of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. Vice Minister of Commerce Guo Tingting gave a detailed introduction to the achievements of the “Belt and Road” economic and trade cooperation in the past ten years. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The volume and quality of trade cooperation increased. From 2013 to 2022, the cumulative scale of my country&#39;s trade in goods with co-founding countries reached 19.1 trillion US dollars, with an average annual growth rate of 6.4%. The growth rate was both higher than the overall growth rate of my country&#39;s foreign trade during the same period and higher than the growth rate of global trade during the same period. my country is a major trading partner of more than 110 co-building countries, and the level of trade liberalization and facilitation has been continuously improved. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two-way investment has yielded fruitful results. From 2013 to 2022, the cumulative two-way investment between my country and co-building countries has exceeded 380 billion US dollars, of which direct investment in co-building countries has exceeded 240 billion US dollars, covering multiple fields of economic and social development. Our country has also cooperated with co-building countries to build a series of economic and trade cooperation zones, with cumulative investment exceeding US$60 billion by the end of 2022. At the same time, the co-building countries have also actively invested in my country and shared my country&#39;s development opportunities. In the past ten years, the cumulative investment in China has exceeded 140 billion US dollars, and nearly 67,000 new companies have been established in China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Project construction is progressing steadily. From 2013 to 2022, my country&#39;s contracted projects in co-building countries achieved an average annual turnover of approximately US$130 billion, and built a series of landmark projects, effectively improving the host country&#39;s infrastructure conditions and significantly increasing the level of interconnection. At the same time, we have vigorously promoted green and digital development cooperation. In the first eight months of this year, the contract value of newly signed energy-saving and environmental protection projects between my country and co-building countries increased by 22% year-on-year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The &quot;Silk Road E-commerce&quot; international cooperation is an important and specific measure to implement the major initiative of jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. After more than 6 years of development, my country has signed bilateral e-commerce cooperation memorandums with 30 countries. At the same time, China-Central and Eastern Europe, China-Central Asia e-commerce cooperation dialogue mechanisms, as well as e-commerce cooperation under the SCO, BRICS and other mechanisms All have achieved real results. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the next step, we will focus on promoting the ‘One Belt, One Road’ initiative by building a new pattern of opening up to the outside world, improving cooperation in industrial and supply chains, cultivating new drivers of economic growth, and opening up new space for economic and trade development. Economic and trade cooperation has become deeper and more substantial,&quot; Guo Tingting said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;The third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum will be held in Beijing in October&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;In the past ten years, the joint construction of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39; has achieved fruitful results. , the circle of friends is getting bigger and bigger, which fully proves that the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; does not form a closed and narrow circle, transcends the old thinking of geo-game, creates a new paradigm of international cooperation, and is a &quot;development belt&quot; and &quot;happy road&quot; that truly benefits the people of all countries. .&quot; At the meeting, Li Kexin, Director of the Department of International Economic Affairs of the Ministry of Foreign Affairs, said that in the past ten years, our country, together with its partners, has established an international cooperation forum guided by the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum and supported by bilateral, trilateral and multilateral cooperation mechanisms. A composite international cooperation structure. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The summit forum plays a leading role. China successfully held two summit forums in 2017 and 2019. All parties involved conducted in-depth exchanges and reached broad consensus on the direction and key areas of cooperation in jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Bilateral cooperation mechanisms have been continuously consolidated. The &quot;Belt and Road&quot; global partnership network is expanding year by year. The &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative is effectively aligned with the development strategies of more than 30 countries and the United Nations 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development, and with the development of regional organizations such as ASEAN, the African Union, and the Eurasian Economic Union. Plan for synergies. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Multilateral cooperation platforms in various fields will be improved and upgraded. Over the past ten years, China and various parties have established more than 20 &quot;Belt and Road&quot; multilateral cooperation platforms in the fields of energy, taxation, finance, humanities, green development and other fields, and simultaneously promoted policy communication and practical cooperation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Kexin introduced that China will hold the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum in Beijing in October this year. Representatives from more than 130 countries and more than 30 international organizations have confirmed their participation. Activities during the summit forum include an opening ceremony, three high-level forums on connectivity, green development, and digital economy, and six special forums on unimpeded trade, people-to-people connectivity, think tank exchanges, clean Silk Road, local cooperation, and maritime cooperation. At the same time, There will also be an Entrepreneurs Conference. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China is willing to work with all parties to take the opportunity of hosting the third Belt and Road International Cooperation Summit Forum to promote high-quality joint construction of the Belt and Road to continuously achieve new results and promote the common development of all countries. Prosperity and promote the building of a community with a shared future for mankind and make greater contributions.&quot; Li Kexin said. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 为形成陆海联动、东西互济的开放格局贡献力量（共建“一带一路”·权威访谈）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/11/nw.D110000renmrb_20231011_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月11日星期三&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;陕西省副省长徐明非近日接受新华社记者专访时表示，共建“一带一路”倡议提出十年来，陕西始终牢记习近平总书记对陕西开放发展作出的重要指示，深度融入共建“一带一路”大格局，坚持高位部署、统筹推进，坚持发挥优势、彰显特色，打造国内大循环的重要支点、国内国际双循环的战略链接，助力陆海内外联动、东西双向互济的开放格局加快形成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;打造高端平台&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;服务国家开放大局&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年9月，在西安举行的2023欧亚经济论坛上，51个国家和地区的政商学界人士为更好地服务共建“一带一路”展开交流，持续放大中国—中亚峰会效应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十年来，陕西积极承接重大任务，有力服务国家开放大局。徐明非表示，陕西与哈萨克斯坦、吉尔吉斯斯坦、乌兹别克斯坦等国元首家乡建立友好省州关系，在元首“家乡外交”带动下，“一带一路”重要节点作用凸显。成功举行中国—中亚峰会、“中国+中亚五国”外长第二次、第四次会晤等主场外交活动，以及中国—中亚民间友好论坛、亚洲文化遗产保护联盟大会等重大外事活动，为建设中国—中亚命运共同体贡献了陕西力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们以高能级平台为&#39;助推器&#39;，稳步扩大制度型开放，在经贸、人文等方面与共建&#39;一带一路&#39;国家和地区开展创新实践。”徐明非说，中国—中亚峰会17项涉陕成果正有序推进，陕西自贸试验区36项典型经验在全国复制推广，上海合作组织农业技术交流培训示范基地与60多个国家和地区开展了现代农业合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;徐明非表示，十年来，丝绸之路国际博览会、欧亚经济论坛、杨凌农高会等在陕举行的展会、论坛影响力不断扩大。目前，陕西综保区达到7个，各类开放平台叠加聚集效应不断释放，为陕西在扩大对内对外开放中强动力、增活力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 立足自身优势&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;实现互利共赢&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;9月28日，满载着165辆汽车的X8489次中欧班列从西安出发驶往莫斯科，标志着中欧班列（西安）自2013年开行首列以来，已开行突破20000列。陕西立足区位优势，以高水平通道建设为“先手棋”，效率高、成本低、服务优的亚欧陆海贸易大通道正加快形成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“目前，中欧班列（西安）常态化开行17条国际线路，通达45个国家和地区，开行21条&#39;+西欧&#39;线路，开行量占全国总量超20%。&#39;空中丝绸之路&#39;织线成网，在全国率先实现中亚&#39;五国六城&#39;通航全覆盖。”徐明非说，陕西加快外向型产业集聚发展，完善海外仓、境外进出口商品仓储加工配送中心等布局，外贸盘子不断做大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2013年至2022年，陕西与共建“一带一路”国家和地区进出口额年均增长18.4%，并在2022年首次突破千亿元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陕西积极嵌入全球产业链供应链，打造国际产能合作中心。多家龙头企业正加快海外布局，一批标志性工程统筹推进。其中，陕汽重型卡车远销110多个国家和地区，隆基绿能马来西亚光伏组件生产项目在当地创造近4000个就业岗位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至2022年底，陕西省306家境外企业累计实现对外投资68.8亿美元，在共建“一带一路”国家和地区投资18.2亿美元，占总额的26.5%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“下一步，我们将继续引导有实力的企业&#39;走出去&#39;，开拓国际市场，建好境内外国际合作园区，形成海外产业聚集，拓展国际产能合作领域，深度参与国际产业链供应链合作，增强供应链韧性。”徐明非说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 增进友好交往&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;提升人民福祉&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们发挥人文优势，注重讲好&#39;一带一路&#39;上的陕西故事。”徐明非表示，十年来，陕西不断推进民心相通，举办丝绸之路国际艺术节、世界文化旅游大会等活动，“国风·秦韵”陕西文化周、非遗精品展等一批文化交流项目在海外引起强烈反响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为科教大省，陕西强化共建“一带一路”智力人才支撑力度，在科技教育中心打造上拓点扩面。依托各类科技创新主体，陕西深度参与“一带一路”科技创新行动计划，着力推进科技人文交流、共建联合实验室、科技园区合作，持续推进高校特色联盟发展，先后成立了丝绸之路大学联盟、丝绸之路农业教育科技创新联盟、“一带一路”文化遗产国际合作联盟等，在推进“一带一路”教育共同体建设中发挥重要作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;徐明非介绍，陕西大力培养语言通、专业精的本土化、国际化复合型人才，省内高校的国际学生中来自共建“一带一路”国家和地区的人数占比逐年提高，2022年达71%，“已成为中亚国家和地区留学生首选目的地之一”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;徐明非说，陕西将更加主动融入和服务构建新发展格局，更加深度融入共建“一带一路”大格局，在中医药、联合考古等领域谋划一批造福当地百姓的新项目，在农业等领域国际合作竞争中培育新优势，为实现高水平对外开放作出新贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（新华社西安10月10日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;记者刘书云、郑昕、孙正好）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 学思践悟创新理论  担当新的文化使命]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/11/nw.D110000renmrb_20231011_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月11日星期三&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;连日来，广大党员干部群众深入学习习近平总书记对宣传思想文化工作的重要指示，认真领会全国宣传思想文化工作会议精神，表示要在本职工作中积极践行习近平文化思想，努力在建设社会主义文化强国、建设中华民族现代文明的奋斗和实践中展现新气象新作为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;在实践中学深悟透习近平文化思想&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“习近平文化思想标志着我们党对中国特色社会主义文化建设规律的认识达到了新高度，表明我们党的历史自信、文化自信达到了新高度，在党的宣传思想文化事业发展史上具有里程碑意义。”清华大学习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想研究院常务副院长肖贵清表示，这一重要思想是新时代党领导文化建设实践经验的理论总结，丰富和发展了马克思主义文化理论，体现了理论和实践的结合、历史与现实的贯通、国内与国际的统一，具有高度的真理性、人民性、实践性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;深入领会新时代以来宣传思想文化工作取得的历史性成就，四川省委宣传部政策法规研究室主任张雄表示，这最根本就在于有习近平总书记领航掌舵，有习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想科学指引。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“习近平文化思想是开展工作的科学行动指南。我们要深入学习贯彻，坚持守正创新，推动宣传思想文化工作高质量发展，促进人民精神生活共同富裕，加快建设新时代文化强省，以巴蜀文化之光为中华文明添彩。”张雄说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“新时代以来，我国网络空间气象一新，主流思想舆论巩固壮大，网络综合治理体系基本建成，网络强国建设迈出新步伐。这些成就的取得，生动彰显了习近平文化思想在我国社会主义文化建设中的强大伟力。”中央网信办网络传播局新闻处处长李斐表示，将立足建设中华民族现代文明的奋斗和实践，充分发挥网络传播优势，以技术创新赋能内容创新、形式创新、传播创新，持续打造网宣品牌，不断创作传播精品，努力以全媒体传播体系建设，塑造主流舆论新格局。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;认真学习了习近平总书记重要指示和这次会议精神，中国文联理论研究室政策研究处处长张鑫对习近平文化思想有了进一步理解。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“习近平总书记强调&#39;宣传思想文化工作事关党的前途命运，事关国家长治久安，事关民族凝聚力和向心力，是一项极端重要的工作&#39;，做好这项工作，文艺工作者责无旁贷。”张鑫表示，将进一步学深悟透习近平文化思想，把这一重要思想的研究宣传阐释工作做得更接地气，推动广大文艺工作者深入生活、扎根人民，创作精品佳作，为建设社会主义文化强国贡献文艺力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 深刻把握新形势落实新要求&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在谈到对习近平总书记重要指示中提出的“七个着力”的理解时，贵州省六盘水市水城区委书记陈石说：“&#39;七个着力&#39;的第一点就是着力加强党对宣传思想文化工作的领导，这也是我们开展工作的重要遵循。我们将进一步加强党的领导，落实好意识形态责任制，加快形成以区属新闻媒体为龙头、政务新媒体参与、自媒体联动的传播矩阵，让党的创新理论走进千家万户。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;秋高气爽，位于河南省安阳市西北郊的殷墟博物馆游客络绎不绝。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们将聚焦&#39;着力赓续中华文脉、推动中华优秀传统文化创造性转化和创新性发展&#39;，借助数字化技术手段、增强沉浸式体验等让古老殷墟&#39;活起来&#39;，推动传统文化持续焕发新光彩。”殷墟博物馆党总支书记、常务副馆长赵清荣说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新疆伊犁哈萨克自治州霍尔果斯市委常委、宣传部部长周虹对习近平总书记提出的“着力加强国际传播能力建设、促进文明交流互鉴”感触颇深。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“作为古丝绸之路上的&#39;千年驿站&#39;、我国向西开放的重要窗口，霍尔果斯通过常态化开展中外媒体沙龙等国际媒体交流活动，不断扩大国际传播&#39;朋友圈&#39;。”周虹说，将继续创新传播理念和方式、构建对外传播话语体系，多渠道多形式讲好新时代霍尔果斯故事，让世界看见一个真实、生动、开放、团结的美丽新疆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中华文明源远流长、博大精深。国家文物局考古司考古管理处处长胡传耸表示，将持续推进中华文明探源工程、考古中国等重大项目，聚焦人类起源、农业起源、文明起源、统一多民族国家发展等关键问题联合攻关，做好城乡建设中的历史文化保护，为建设中华民族现代文明注入深厚持久的文化力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 不断提高工作质量效能&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;延河之畔，中国延安干部学院的教师们集体学习了习近平总书记重要指示和会议精神。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“学院教学工作将在真学真懂真信真用、深化内化转化上下功夫，借助当地独特历史文化资源，将原著导读、案例教学、实地走访相结合，讲好习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想的文化篇，进一步引导学员坚定文化自信，强化政治担当。”中国延安干部学院教学科研部党建教研室主任王涛说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;认真学习了习近平总书记的重要指示精神，新华社记者朱基钗对今后的工作方向更加明晰：“我们将把握正确政治方向和舆论导向，在增强&#39;四力&#39;中提升业务本领，努力推出更多服务国家大局、把握时代脉搏、反映人民心声的新闻佳作，让党的主张成为新时代的最强音，让主旋律成为聚人心的正能量。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一段时间以来，邵阳市推出身边好人&#39;微讲堂&#39;等一系列举措，推动精神文明建设走深走实。”湖南省邵阳市委宣传部副部长、市文明办主任张映梅说，将不断改革创新，运用新技术手段推动精神文明建设进基层、上网络、入人心，让群众更好共享精神文明建设成果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“总书记提出&#39;不断开创新时代宣传思想文化工作新局面&#39;，出版工作者重任在肩，大有可为。”江苏凤凰出版传媒股份有限公司总编辑徐海表示，将加快数字化建设，聚焦“兴文化”、坚持“出精品”、着力“育新人”，打造服务于全民阅读与智慧教育的数字出版平台，推出更多富有时代精神的优秀文化产品，为全面建设社会主义现代化国家、全面推进中华民族伟大复兴提供坚强思想保证、强大精神力量、有利文化条件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（新华社北京10月10日电）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 全国新能源汽车保有量达1821万辆]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/11/nw.D110000renmrb_20231011_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月11日星期三&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报北京10月10日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者张天培）记者从公安部获悉：截至2023年9月底，全国机动车保有量达4.3亿辆，其中汽车3.3亿辆，新能源汽车1821万辆；机动车驾驶人5.2亿人，其中汽车驾驶人4.8亿人。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;据介绍，前三季度新注册登记机动车2601万辆，其中新注册登记汽车1817万辆，同比增长4.4%，一季度、二季度、三季度新注册登记汽车分别为588万辆、587万辆、642万辆。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;截至9月底，全国新能源汽车保有量达1821万辆，占汽车保有量的5.5%。其中，纯电动汽车保有量1401万辆，占新能源汽车总量的76.9%。一至三季度，全国新注册登记新能源汽车519.8万辆，同比增长40%，占汽车新注册登记量的28.6%，其中，一季度、二季度、三季度新注册登记新能源汽车分别为144万辆、170.9万辆、204.9万辆。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;据了解，前三季度二手车市场保持活跃。一至三季度，各地公安交管部门共办理机动车转让登记业务2505万笔，其中汽车转让登记业务2331万笔，占93.1%。近年来，公安部会同商务部等部门推进实施便利二手车异地交易登记改革措施，更好促进了二手车流通，今年一至三季度，公安交管部门办理二手小客车异地交易登记业务380.5万笔。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;截至9月底，全国有90个城市的汽车保有量超过100万辆，同比增加8个城市。其中，43个城市汽车保有量超过200万辆，25个城市超过300万辆。北京、重庆、成都汽车保有量超过600万辆，上海、苏州汽车保有量超过500万辆，天津、杭州、郑州、武汉、西安、深圳、东莞汽车保有量超过400万辆。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 11 Oct 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>