<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平向2023年世界互联网大会乌镇峰会开幕式发表视频致辞]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/09/nw.D110000renmrb_20231109_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 9, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/09/01/rmrb2023110901p43_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the morning of November 8, President Xi Jinping delivered a video speech to the opening ceremony of the 2023 World Internet Conference Wuzhen Summit. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Li Xueren&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;■In 2015, I was at the second World At the opening ceremony of the Internet Conference, the &quot;Four Principles&quot; and &quot;Five Points&quot; for global Internet development and governance were proposed, and the establishment of a community with a shared future in cyberspace was advocated. This concept has been widely recognized and responded positively by the international community. The world today is intertwined with chaos, and the changes that have occurred over the past century are accelerating. How to solve the development deficit, resolve the security dilemma, and strengthen mutual learning among civilizations are issues of the times that we all face. The Internet has increasingly become a new driving force for development, a new territory for maintaining security, and a new platform for mutual learning among civilizations. Building a community with a shared future in cyberspace is not only an inevitable choice to answer the issues of the times, but also the common voice of the international community. We must deepen exchanges and pragmatic cooperation, and jointly promote the construction of a community with a shared future in cyberspace to a new stage&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■We advocate development priority and build a more inclusive and prosperous cyberspace. Deepen international exchanges and cooperation in the digital field and accelerate the transformation of scientific and technological achievements. Accelerate the popularization of information services, narrow the digital divide, protect and improve people&#39;s livelihood in the development of the Internet, and allow more countries and people to share the fruits of Internet development&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■ We advocate sharing weal and woe and build a more peaceful and secure cyberspace. Respect network sovereignty and respect the Internet development paths and governance models of each country. We must abide by international rules in cyberspace and refrain from pursuing cyber hegemony. We will not engage in cyberspace camp confrontation or arms race. Deepen pragmatic cooperation on network security, effectively combat illegal and criminal activities on the Internet, and strengthen data security and personal information protection. Properly respond to rule conflicts, social risks, and ethical challenges brought about by technological development. China is willing to work with all parties to implement the Global Artificial Intelligence Governance Initiative and promote the safe development of artificial intelligence&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■ We advocate mutual learning among civilizations and build a more equal and inclusive cyberspace. Strengthen online exchanges and dialogues to promote mutual understanding and mutual understanding among people of all countries, promote tolerance and symbiosis of different civilizations, and better promote the common values ​​of all mankind. Strengthen the construction of Internet civilization, promote the production and dissemination of high-quality Internet cultural products, fully demonstrate the outstanding achievements of human civilization, actively promote the inheritance and development of civilization, and jointly build an online spiritual home&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■The trend of the information revolution era is advancing vigorously, and cyberspace carries the It expresses mankind’s infinite longing for a better future. Let us join hands to build a community with a shared future in cyberspace, let the Internet better benefit people all over the world, and jointly create a better future for mankind&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 8 On the morning of November 8, President Xi Jinping delivered a video speech to the opening ceremony of the Wuzhen Summit of the 2023 World Internet Conference. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that in 2015, at the opening ceremony of the Second World Internet Conference, I proposed the &quot;Four Principles&quot; and &quot;Five Points&quot; for global Internet development governance, advocating the construction of a community with a shared future in cyberspace, This concept has been widely recognized and responded positively by the international community. The world today is intertwined with chaos, and the changes that have occurred over the past century are accelerating. How to solve the development deficit, resolve the security dilemma, and strengthen mutual learning among civilizations are issues of the times that we all face. The Internet has increasingly become a new driving force for development, a new territory for maintaining security, and a new platform for mutual learning among civilizations. Building a community with a shared future in cyberspace is not only an inevitable choice to answer the issues of the times, but also the common voice of the international community. We must deepen exchanges and pragmatic cooperation and jointly promote the construction of a community with a shared future in cyberspace to a new stage. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;We advocate giving priority to development and building a more inclusive and prosperous cyberspace. Deepen international exchanges and cooperation in the digital field and accelerate the transformation of scientific and technological achievements. Accelerate the popularization of information services, narrow the digital divide, protect and improve people&#39;s livelihood in the development of the Internet, and allow more countries and people to share the fruits of Internet development. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;We advocate sharing weal and woe and building a more peaceful and secure cyberspace. Respect network sovereignty and respect the Internet development paths and governance models of each country. We must abide by international rules in cyberspace and refrain from pursuing cyber hegemony. We will not engage in cyberspace camp confrontation or arms race. Deepen pragmatic cooperation on network security, effectively combat illegal and criminal activities on the Internet, and strengthen data security and personal information protection. Properly respond to rule conflicts, social risks, and ethical challenges brought about by technological development. China is willing to work with all parties to implement the Global Artificial Intelligence Governance Initiative and promote the safe development of artificial intelligence. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;We advocate mutual learning among civilizations and build a more equal and inclusive cyberspace. Strengthen online exchanges and dialogues to promote mutual understanding and mutual understanding among people of all countries, promote tolerance and symbiosis of different civilizations, and better promote the common values ​​of all mankind. Strengthen the construction of Internet civilization, promote the production and dissemination of high-quality Internet cultural products, fully demonstrate the outstanding achievements of human civilization, actively promote the inheritance and development of civilization, and jointly build an online spiritual home. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping finally emphasized that the information revolution era is moving forward vigorously, and cyberspace carries mankind’s infinite longing for a better future. Let us join hands to build a community with a shared future in cyberspace, let the Internet better benefit people all over the world, and jointly create a better future for mankind! &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The 2023 World Internet Conference Wuzhen Summit will be held in Wuzhen, Zhejiang from November 8th to 10th. The theme is &quot;Building an inclusive, universally beneficial, and resilient digital world-Working together to build a community with a shared future in cyberspace.&quot; &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:56:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 携手构建网络空间命运共同体]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/09/nw.D110000renmrb_20231109_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 9, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;On November 8, President Xi Jinping delivered a video speech to the opening ceremony of the Wuzhen Summit of the 2023 World Internet Conference. President Xi Jinping emphasized that the information revolution era is moving forward vigorously, and cyberspace carries mankind’s infinite longing for a better future. Let us join hands to build a community with a shared future in cyberspace, let the Internet better benefit people all over the world, and jointly create a better future for mankind! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Participating guests and people from all walks of life said that President Xi Jinping’s video speech fully reflected his profound understanding of the development laws of human society in the information age, built consensus and pooled strength. All parties should strengthen dialogue and exchanges and deepen pragmatic cooperation. , work together to build a community with a shared future in cyberspace. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Wuzhen Summit of the World Internet Conference is the largest and highest-level Internet conference held in China. It is also an unprecedented summit meeting in the world&#39;s Internet field. Political dignitaries and Internet elites from all over the world gathered together to discuss cooperation plans and jointly promote the construction of a community with a shared future in cyberspace to a new stage. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The concept of building a community with a shared future in cyberspace has been widely recognized and responded positively by the international community&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping pointed out that in 2015, I spoke at the Second World Internet Conference At the opening ceremony, the &quot;Four Principles&quot; and &quot;Five Points&quot; for global Internet development and governance were proposed, and the establishment of a community with a shared future in cyberspace was advocated. This concept has been widely recognized and responded positively by the international community. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In recent years, in international exchanges and cooperation, we have deeply felt that the concept of building a community with a shared future in cyberspace has been widely recognized by the international community.” said Xu Yamin, the relevant person in charge of the Tomorrow City Research Institute of the Global Smart City Conference , as an international exchange and cooperation platform for more than 800 cities in more than 140 countries around the world, the Global Smart City Conference leverages the development of Internet technology to allow governments, enterprises, academia, etc. to better share and communicate and help build future cities. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Rafael Evangelista, a member of the board of directors of the Brazilian Internet Steering Committee, said that the concept of building a community with a shared future in cyberspace has been widely recognized. The Internet is shared by all mankind, so the development of the Internet must revolve around the concept of &quot;commonness&quot;. Only in this way can everyone build a common network society and work together to solve Internet-related problems. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The concept of building a community with a shared future in cyberspace has evolved from concept documents to action initiatives to practical cases, and the ideological consensus has gradually turned into concrete actions. In Tongxiang and Wuzhen, through the holding of annual summits, we It has witnessed the proposal and deepening of the concept of building a community with a shared future in cyberspace, and it continues to be deeply rooted in the hearts of the people.&quot; Secretary of the Tongxiang Municipal Party Committee of Zhejiang Province lobbied at the meeting, and Tongxiang will work harder to build an Internet communication and collaboration platform and strive to continue to write the next wonderful chapter of the Wuzhen Summit. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, Internet platform companies from various countries have also continued to strengthen cooperation, promote development, and lead innovation. &quot;The concept of building a community with a shared future in cyberspace has pointed out the direction for the development of Internet companies. Through international exchanges and collisions of technology and ideas, various sources of innovation have fully flowed.&quot; Guo Kaitian, senior vice president of Tencent Group, said that this year, under the guidance of the State Administration of Cultural Heritage, Dunhuang Research The &quot;Digital Scripture Cave&quot;, a participatory museum jointly created by the Academy and Tencent, was officially launched, and the &quot;Digital Scripture Cave (International Version)&quot; was released at this summit. Chinese Internet companies strive to make useful explorations for exchanges and mutual learning among civilizations and help build a community with a shared future in cyberspace. Zhihu founder Zhou Yuan said that he strongly felt at the Wuzhen Summit that the industry strongly agrees with the concept of building a community with a shared future in cyberspace and hopes to continue to strengthen exchanges and cooperation and continue to drive development and progress through innovation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;It is not only an inevitable choice to answer the issues of the times, but also the common voice of the international community&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping pointed out that the world today is intertwined with chaos and the changes that have occurred over the past century are accelerating. How to Solving the development deficit, resolving the security dilemma, and strengthening mutual learning among civilizations are issues of our times that we all face. The Internet has increasingly become a new driving force for development, a new territory for maintaining security, and a new platform for mutual learning among civilizations. Building a community with a shared future in cyberspace is not only an inevitable choice to answer the issues of the times, but also the common voice of the international community. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Chairman Xi Jinping&#39;s important statement on building a community with a shared future in cyberspace is &#39;the inevitable choice to answer the issues of the times&#39; is very important.&quot; Wang Shuangyi, a researcher at the Institute of Automation, Chinese Academy of Sciences, said that while cyberspace has brought new developments to mankind, , also brought new topics and new challenges. Today, the digital divide between countries and regions continues to widen, and the Internet field has exposed problems such as uneven development, imperfect rules, and unreasonable order. Answering the relevant issues of cyberspace construction and creating a safe, stable and prosperous cyberspace is not only in line with the common interests of the international community, but also the common responsibility of the international community. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jiang Zhonghui, deputy general manager of China Broadcasting (Shaoxing) Cable Information Co., Ltd., said that the Internet has broken through the physical limitations between people and countries. As an Internet industry practitioner, he will Start from yourself and promote the building of a community with a shared future in cyberspace. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fang Fang, Vice President of North China Electric Power University, said: &quot;In today&#39;s world, the Internet has increasingly become a new driving force for development, a new territory for maintaining security, and a new platform for mutual learning among civilizations. Today, represented by artificial intelligence, The development of information technology is in full swing, with great prospects and great potential. We must keep up with the trend of the times, answer the issues of the times, continue to realize the safe and efficient use of technology, and better promote the construction of a community with a shared future in cyberspace.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Japan Shigeyuki Ohara, Speaker of the Komagane City Council in Nagano Prefecture, said that he strongly agrees with the concept of building a community with a shared future in cyberspace. Facing the new situation and new requirements of today&#39;s era, countries need to strengthen consultation and cooperation around Internet development and governance so that the Internet can better benefit mankind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Currently, building a community with a shared future in cyberspace has become an inevitable choice to answer the issues of the times.” Cheng Haibo, an associate researcher at the Shenyang Institute of Automation, Chinese Academy of Sciences, said, “As scientific researchers, we must strengthen original innovation and deepen international cooperation. , promote the achievements of China’s industrial Internet development to more countries, and use practical actions to help build a community with a shared future in cyberspace.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Jointly promote the construction of a community with a shared future in cyberspace to a new stage&lt;/strong>;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping pointed out that we must deepen exchanges and pragmatic cooperation and jointly promote the construction of a community with a shared future in cyberspace to a new stage. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &quot;The important statement of &#39;jointly promoting the construction of a community with a shared future in cyberspace to a new stage&#39; is full of wisdom and impressive.&quot; said Zafar Mahmoud, Chairman of Pakistan&#39;s &quot;Understanding China&quot; Forum , &quot;Currently, the field of information technology is changing with each passing day. The Internet is constantly updated and iterated, and the issues we need to pay attention to and think about are also constantly updated. Under new technologies and new situations, how can the development of the Internet better benefit mankind instead of having negative effects and better promote Building a community with a shared future in cyberspace is an issue that requires special consideration. The theme of this year&#39;s World Internet Conference, &#39;Building an inclusive, universally beneficial, and resilient digital world - Join hands to build a community with a shared future in cyberspace&#39;, reflects the pursuit of the new stage.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xue Feng, head of the IIOE Operations Center of the UNESCO Innovation Center for Higher Education, said: &quot;President Xi Jinping pointed out that &#39;it is necessary to deepen exchanges and pragmatic cooperation and jointly promote the construction of a community with a shared future in cyberspace to a new stage.&#39; We will Adhering to the principle of extensive consultation, joint contribution and shared benefits, we will join hands with all parties to promote the digital transformation of higher education and jointly build a community with a shared future in cyberspace.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Chairman Xi Jinping&#39;s video speech is an enrichment of the concept of building a community with a shared future in cyberspace. and development.&quot; Zhang Wenxian, member of the Party Committee of the China Law Society and director of the Academic Committee, said that the call to &quot;jointly promote the construction of a community with a shared future in cyberspace to a new stage&quot; has pointed out new goals and directions for the development of the world&#39;s Internet industry and the construction of a community with a shared future in cyberspace. , it is necessary to further strengthen learning and conduct new explorations in Internet governance. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Our reporters Jin Xin, Gu Chun, Liu Junguo, Liu Shiyao, Ma Yuan, Cao Xuemeng, Li Chenyang, Deng Jianyang, Cui Yan)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:56:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 共同推动构建网络空间命运共同体迈向新阶段]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/09/nw.D110000renmrb_20231109_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 9, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;The Internet is the common home of mankind. No matter how innovative and developed digital technology is, no matter how the international environment changes, everyone shares weal and woe and has a connected destiny in cyberspace. On November 8, President Xi Jinping delivered a video speech to the opening ceremony of the Wuzhen Summit of the 2023 World Internet Conference, emphasizing that &quot;we must deepen exchanges and pragmatic cooperation, and jointly promote the construction of a community with a shared future in cyberspace to a new stage&quot;, advocating development priority and sharing weal and woe. , mutual learning among civilizations, and put forward three propositions to build a cyberspace that is more universally beneficial, prosperous, peaceful, secure, equal, and inclusive, and inject strong positive energy into the joint efforts of all countries to build a community with a shared future in cyberspace. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Today&#39;s world is intertwined with chaos, and the changes that have occurred over the past century are accelerating. How to solve the development deficit, resolve the security dilemma, and strengthen mutual learning among civilizations are issues of the times that we all face. Under this situation, China has not stayed alone, but has strengthened cooperation with other countries around the world to jointly find solutions. President Xi Jinping proposed the Belt and Road Initiative, the Global Development Initiative, the Global Security Initiative, and the Global Civilization Initiative. He hopes to work with all countries in the world to achieve economic development, improve people&#39;s livelihood, achieve mutual benefit and win-win results, and let unity replace division, cooperation instead of confrontation, Tolerance replaces exclusivity and we work together to build a world that lasts for lasting peace, universal security, common prosperity, is open and inclusive, clean and beautiful. Practice tells us that we must firmly practice true multilateralism, promote the joint construction of higher-quality and higher-level new developments in the Belt and Road Initiative, promote the implementation of global development initiatives, global security initiatives, and global civilization initiatives, and promote the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind. Only in this way can we cope with various global challenges and jointly create a better future for mankind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Internet has increasingly become a new driving force for development, a new territory for maintaining security, and a new platform for mutual learning among civilizations. Building a community with a shared future in cyberspace is not only an inevitable choice to answer the issues of the times, but also the common voice of the international community. In 2015, President Xi Jinping proposed the &quot;Four Principles&quot; and &quot;Five Points&quot; for global Internet development governance at the opening ceremony of the Second World Internet Conference, advocating the construction of a community with a shared future in cyberspace. This concept has been widely recognized and recognized by the international community. response actively. China&#39;s international cooperation in cyberspace in the new era, under the vision of building a community with a shared future in cyberspace, continues to make new achievements, achieve new breakthroughs, and show a new atmosphere. Practice has fully proved that promoting the construction of a community with a shared future in cyberspace will provide ample digital impetus for building a community with a shared future for mankind, build a solid security barrier, and build a broader consensus on cooperation. On the way forward, China will always adhere to the concept of building a community with a shared future in cyberspace and work with the international community to build a cyberspace that is more universally beneficial, prosperous, peaceful, secure, equal and inclusive. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The development of the Internet requires everyone&#39;s participation, and the results of development should be shared by everyone. As the new generation of information and communication technology accelerates integration and innovation, digitalization, networking, and intelligence are accelerating penetration and integration in various economic and social fields, profoundly changing people&#39;s production methods and lifestyles. At the same time, the uneven development levels of different countries and regions in Internet popularization, infrastructure construction, technological innovation and creation, digital economic development, digital literacy and skills, etc., affect and restrict the information construction and digitalization of countries around the world, especially developing countries. transformation. President Xi Jinping pointed out: &quot;We advocate development first and build a more inclusive and prosperous cyberspace.&quot; Only by deepening international exchanges and cooperation in the digital field, accelerating the transformation of scientific and technological achievements, accelerating the popularization of information services, narrowing the digital divide, and ensuring and improving the Internet development Only by improving people&#39;s livelihood can more countries and people share the fruits of Internet development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Security is the prerequisite for development. A safe, stable and prosperous cyberspace is of great significance to all countries in the world. We must deeply realize that network security is a global challenge and no country can stay out of it. Maintaining network security is the common responsibility of the international community. At the same time, the principle of sovereign equality established in the United Nations Charter is the basic norm of contemporary international relations and also applies to cyberspace. President Xi Jinping pointed out: &quot;We advocate sharing weal and woe and build a more peaceful and secure cyberspace.&quot; Only by respecting cyber sovereignty, abiding by international rules in cyberspace, deepening pragmatic cooperation on cyber security, effectively cracking down on cyber crimes, and strengthening data security and personal information protection , Only in this way can we properly deal with the conflict of rules, social risks and ethical challenges brought about by the development of science and technology, and better maintain the security of cyberspace. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Civilizations become colorful through exchanges and develop through mutual learning. The Internet is an important carrier for spreading excellent human culture and promoting positive energy. Creating an online cultural exchange and sharing platform to promote exchanges and mutual learning is conducive to jointly promoting the prosperity and development of online culture, enriching people&#39;s spiritual world, and promoting the progress of human civilization. President Xi Jinping pointed out: &quot;We advocate mutual learning among civilizations and build a more equal and inclusive cyberspace.&quot; Only by strengthening online exchanges and dialogues, promoting mutual understanding and mutual understanding among people of all countries, and promoting tolerance and symbiosis of different civilizations can we better promote the common values ​​of all mankind. Only by strengthening the construction of Internet civilization, promoting the production and dissemination of high-quality Internet cultural products, fully displaying the outstanding achievements of human civilization, and actively promoting the inheritance and development of civilization can we jointly build an online spiritual home. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The era of information revolution is moving forward vigorously, and cyberspace carries mankind’s infinite longing for a better future. On the way forward, by following the general trend of Internet development, promoting interconnection, sharing and co-governance of cyberspace, and working together to build a community with a shared future in cyberspace, we will surely make the Internet more prosperous, cleaner, and safer, and better benefit people around the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:56:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 韩正出席第六届创新经济论坛并访问新加坡]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/09/nw.D110000renmrb_20231109_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 9, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/09/01/rmrb2023110901p34_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;November 8, National Vice Chairman Han Zheng attended the opening ceremony of the 6th Innovation Economy Forum held in Singapore and delivered a keynote speech. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Gao Jie&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Xinhua News Agency, Singapore, November 8th&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;(Reporters Jiang Guopeng and Cai Shuya) From November 7th to 8th, Vice President Han Zheng attended the 6th Innovation Economic Forum held in Singapore and was invited to visit Singapore. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Han Zheng delivered a keynote speech at the opening ceremony of the forum. Han Zheng said that in the face of changes in the world, the times, and history, President Xi Jinping put forward the major concept of building a community with a shared future for mankind, proposed global development initiatives, global security initiatives, and global civilization initiatives, and promoted the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; to a high level. The new stage of quality development contributes China’s solutions to meet the common challenges of all mankind and build a better world. China is willing to work with other countries in the world to seize the development opportunities of the times, jointly respond to risks and challenges, and jointly create a better future for mankind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Han Zheng put forward three initiatives. First, we insist on promoting cooperation through openness. China will unswervingly promote high-level opening up to the outside world, is willing to provide more market opportunities and investment opportunities, and share the dividends of China&#39;s institutional opening up with companies from all over the world. The second is to persist in seeking motivation through innovation. China will strengthen the sharing of innovation results with other countries, jointly address the challenges of climate change, and inject new momentum into world economic growth. The third is to persist in promoting development through peace. China is willing to work with other countries to safeguard world peace and security, seek development and prosperity, and promote the building of a community with a shared future for mankind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Han Zheng pointed out that some recent important high-level contacts between China and the United States have increased the international community&#39;s positive expectations for the improvement of Sino-US relations in the future. China has always viewed and handled Sino-US relations in accordance with the three principles of mutual respect, peaceful coexistence, and win-win cooperation proposed by President Xi Jinping. We are willing to strengthen communication and dialogue with the United States at all levels, promote mutually beneficial cooperation, properly manage differences, and work together to respond to global challenges. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Han Zheng also met with Bloomberg, founder of the Innovation Economy Forum and founder of the Bloomberg Group, and met collectively with guests and representatives attending the forum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During his visit to New Zealand, Han Zheng met respectively with Singaporean President Tharman Shanmugaratnam, Prime Minister Lee Hsien Loong, Deputy Prime Minister Heng Swee Keat, and State Counselor and Coordinating Minister for National Security Teo Chee Hean. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When meeting with Tharman Shanmugaratnam, Han Zheng conveyed the cordial greetings from President Xi Jinping, saying that China and New Zealand are close neighbors and important cooperative partners, and are a model of friendly exchanges between countries. With the joint efforts of both sides, the cooperation between the two countries has demonstrated strong resilience and vitality. It is believed that more and better results will be achieved in the future. The world today is facing many global risks and challenges, and no country can be immune to it. All countries need to adhere to true multilateralism, build consensus, and work together. China will inject more certainty into the world with its own stability and bring more new opportunities to the world with its own new development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tharman Shanmugaratnam asked Han Zheng to convey his sincere greetings to President Xi Jinping, saying that standing at a new historical starting point, the leaders of the two countries have upgraded the bilateral relationship into an all-round, high-quality forward-looking partnership, providing a solid foundation for the two countries. The development of bilateral relations has pointed the way forward. New Zealand is willing to deepen practical cooperation with China in various fields to better benefit the two peoples. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When meeting with Lee Hsien Loong, Han Zheng said that President Xi Jinping and Mr. Prime Minister upgraded China-New Zealand relations to a comprehensive, high-quality forward-looking partnership in March this year, which is a milestone in the process of bilateral relations. This year marks the 100th anniversary of the birth of Mr. Lee Kuan Yew. Singapore uses Eastern values ​​​​and international perspective to promote the modernization process and find a development path that is consistent with its national conditions. China is willing to work with New Zealand to jointly build the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; with high quality, promote the upgrading of cooperation projects between the two countries, intensify personnel exchanges and people-to-people exchanges between the two countries, make full use of bilateral cooperation mechanisms, and position the new position of bilateral relations to We will make new contributions to regional prosperity and stability. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lee Hsien Loong said that New Zealand and China enjoy profound traditional friendship. New Zealand is willing to deepen the docking of development strategies with China, successfully hold a new round of bilateral cooperation mechanism meetings between New Zealand and China, and promote the all-round and high-quality forward-looking partnership between New Zealand and China to a new level. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:56:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 更好支撑和服务中国式现代化（学思想 强党性 重实践 建新功）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/09/nw.D110000renmrb_20231109_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 9, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;When General Secretary Xi Jinping presided over a symposium on further promoting the high-quality development of the Yangtze River Economic Belt, he emphasized: “Pursue long-term trends and implement A long-term strategy and a long-lasting foundation will further promote the high-quality development of the Yangtze River Economic Belt and better support and serve Chinese-style modernization.&quot; &quot;We must take thematic education as an opportunity to educate and guide cadres to establish and practice a correct view of political performance, improve the promotion of Skills for high-quality development.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the launch of the second batch of the theme education on studying and implementing Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, the provinces and cities along the Yangtze River Economic Belt have conscientiously studied and implemented the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech and persisted in implementing the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech. Thematic education is combined with the important task of promoting the high-quality development of the Yangtze River Economic Belt, educating and guiding cadres to establish and practice a correct view of political performance, and gathering strong force to further promote the high-quality development of the Yangtze River Economic Belt. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Learn to take responsibility and plant a green background for high-quality development&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unswervingly insist on joint efforts in large-scale protection and do not engage in large-scale development. It is necessary to strengthen responsibility, insist on laying the foundation for long-term benefits, and solidly promote the ecological and environmental protection and restoration of the Yangtze River. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the rain and the sky clears up, the scenery on the river in Zhongxian County, Chongqing, located in the center of the Three Gorges Reservoir Area, is particularly pleasant. &quot;Now there are much fewer floating objects on the river. In October this year, the reservoir area was once again impounded to an altitude of 175 meters. You can enjoy the beautiful scenery of the flat lake after work.&quot; Zhou Kangming, a cleaning worker, witnessed the ecological changes in the reservoir area. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Focusing on restoring the ecology and improving the environment, Zhong County has implemented projects such as filling gaps and improving the quality of landscaping in the county, and greening and beautifying &quot;slopes and cliffs&quot;. It has also implemented systematic management of the ecological environment in the countryside. Both sides of the Yangtze River have been planted with citrus and bamboo shoots. The bamboo-based &quot;ecological corridor&quot; increased the county&#39;s forest coverage rate by 12 percentage points. In conjunction with thematic education, the local area focuses on the difficulties and blockages in industrial upgrading, and establishes mechanisms such as &quot;seven-chain collaboration&quot; to grasp the industry and &quot;walking through publicity and interpretation&quot; to serve the private economy, to accelerate green development. At the same time, we will accelerate the construction of the Yangtze River National Cultural Park (Chongqing Section) and promote the in-depth integrated development of culture and tourism. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;How to make green waters and green mountains produce ecological, economic and social benefits? Provinces and cities along the Yangtze River take the theme education as an opportunity to consciously use the party&#39;s innovative theory to explore the path of ecological value transformation and plant a green foundation for high-quality development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Dongshan Village, Wuning County, Jiujiang City, Jiangxi Province, most of the villagers were engaged in fish farming and fishing. After a total fishing ban was implemented in the waters of the West Sea of ​​Lushan Mountain, Dongshan Village built a lakeside ecological village and built an ecological industrial park. The conversion rate of ecological value products in the village&#39;s collective economy has reached 75.7%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the launch of thematic education, Wuning County has carried out on-the-ground investigation and research, built a &quot;whole-process&quot; closed-loop implementation chain of problem-solving, problem-solving, and problem-solving, and explored a new model of &quot;forest chief + grassroots forestry&quot; joint management and co-governance; Give full play to the role of a central platform for the value transformation of ecological products; actively promote forestry carbon neutrality and forestry carbon sink measurement and monitoring pilots, and develop a carbon sink economy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Learn work skills and implement the new development concept completely, accurately and comprehensively&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The key is to persist in protecting during development and developing in protection. Think and use methods to make enemies. In the theme education, the provinces and cities along the Yangtze River draw wisdom and power from the Party&#39;s innovative theory, improve work skills, correctly grasp the relationship between breaking old kinetic energy and cultivating new kinetic energy, completely, accurately and comprehensively implement the new development concept, so as to better support and serve China. Make new contributions to modernization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Huangshi City, Hubei Province, a resource-based city that thrived on mining, is transforming into an ecological garden city by transforming and upgrading traditional industries, cultivating and strengthening alternative industries, and developing high-tech industries. In the theme education, Huangshi City focused on the key and difficult issues in the high-quality development of the Yangtze River Economic Belt, insisted on learning, comparing, inspecting, and rectifying while guiding party organizations at all levels in the city to consciously shoulder their responsibilities and coordinately promote carbon reduction, pollution reduction, In order to expand green and grow, the green transformation and upgrading of industries have been regarded as a top priority. We have continued to increase investment and implemented industrial technological transformation projects. The competitiveness of a number of key enterprises has been significantly improved. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;How to transform the scientific research and talent advantages of the Yangtze River Economic Belt into development advantages? The provinces and cities along the Yangtze River insist on innovation-led development, actively open up new areas and new tracks for development, create new drivers of development and new advantages, and demonstrate their responsibility in serving the process of Chinese-style modernization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It really helped us solve our urgent need!” said Wang Zhu, general manager of Jiangsu Leibo Microelectronics Equipment Co., Ltd. This high-tech enterprise located in the Pioneer Park of Jiangyin High-tech Zone in Jiangsu Province has experienced increasingly tight production space as its products continue to be iteratively upgraded. During the theme education, the party organization of the Pioneer Park learned about the difficulties of the company during the investigation and solved the problems immediately. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jiangyin City focuses on the development of the Yangtze River Economic Belt and other fields in thematic education, and determines 37 research topics. Party members and cadres carry out the &quot;three-step process of entering enterprises and factories, entering towns (streets) and villages (communities), and entering households&quot;. The &quot;Enter Three Entries&quot; visit will promote the solution of development difficulties and blockages. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Learn political ability and do a good job in the &quot;game of chess&quot; for regional coordinated development.&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As a river basin economy, how does the Yangtze River Economic Belt position its own development? In the overall situation of coordinated development, the performance concept and political ability of the majority of cadres are tested. In thematic education, provinces and cities along the Yangtze River focus on enhancing regional transportation interconnectivity, policy unity, rule consistency, and execution synergy, and work hard to promote coordinated regional development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The construction site of Shanghai Songjiang Hub is in full swing, with more than 3,000 workers full of enthusiasm. As an important fulcrum of the G60 Science and Technology Innovation Corridor in the Yangtze River Delta, Songjiang Hub will have direct access to more than 80% of the major cities in the Yangtze River Delta. It will also rely on China-Europe freight trains and China-Laos freight trains to jointly build the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and help Shanghai achieve high-quality development. New results. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shanghai Songjiang District insists on combining thematic education with the implementation of the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee and the work arrangements of the Municipal Party Committee, firmly grasps the major opportunities of the G60 Science and Technology Innovation Corridor in the Yangtze River Delta, and closely adheres to the &quot;real&quot; orientation and Use the &quot;connected&quot; method, implement the &quot;strict&quot; requirements, start from solving specific problems that affect reform, development and stability, and effectively transform learning results into entrepreneurial skills and creative execution capabilities. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Regional efforts should be coordinated to share development results. In the theme education, the provinces and cities along the Yangtze River insist on promoting learning to do, further improve the inter-provincial consultation and cooperation mechanism, steadily promote the construction of ecological community and interest community, and strive to do a good job in the &quot;chess game&quot; of regional coordinated development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Now, protecting the Chishui River has become the consensus of the people along the river.” Chang Lu, a 74-year-old party member in Yinchang Village, Zhenxiong County, Zhaotong City, Yunnan, has been patrolling the river voluntarily for more than 30 years, and does so every week Take a walk around the river in the village. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chishui River is a first-class tributary in the upper reaches of the Yangtze River, flowing through the three provinces of Yunnan, Guizhou and Sichuan. During the theme education, Zhaotong City held research symposiums and mass meetings, collected 832 opinions and suggestions, and determined 40 key tasks in 9 aspects, including the &quot;river chief system&quot; and &quot;two pollution&quot; management, to form an overall idea and specific ideas for large-scale protection and management. Countermeasures and effective measures. Zhaotong City has also joined forces with Bijie City in Guizhou and Luzhou City in Sichuan to jointly promote the construction of ecological civilization in the Chishui River Basin and improve mechanisms for cross-provincial and municipal consultation, ecological co-governance, whole-region co-construction, and development sharing. Currently, joint efforts have been launched at the junction of the three provinces of Sichuan, Yunnan, and Guizhou. Law enforcement inspection 4 times. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Adhering to learning to build souls, learning to increase wisdom, learning to rectify the style, and learning to promote cadres, party members and cadres in the provinces and cities along the Yangtze River further improve their ability to promote high-quality development, overcome difficulties, and work hard to start a business. The spirit is even more exciting, and the enthusiasm for learning and work radiated by thematic education is being transformed into an inexhaustible driving force to promote the high-quality development of the Yangtze River Economic Belt and better support and serve Chinese-style modernization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Our reporters Cao Lingjuan, Zhu Lei, Yang Wenming, Yao Xueqing, Fan Haotian and Wang Xinyue participated in the reporting)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:56:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 新疆扎实推进高质量发展（高质量发展调研行）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/09/nw.D110000renmrb_20231109_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 9, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;In August this year, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized when listening to the work report of the Party Committee and Government of the Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region and the Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps, To build a new development pattern, promote high-quality development, and promote Chinese-style modernization, Xinjiang is facing new opportunities and must make new achievements. Based on resource endowment, location advantages and industrial foundation, we must vigorously promote scientific and technological innovation, cultivate and expand characteristic advantageous industries, actively develop emerging industries, accelerate the construction of a modern industrial system that reflects Xinjiang&#39;s characteristics and advantages, and push Xinjiang onto the track of high-quality development. The whole country works together to comprehensively build a modern socialist country. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Keeping in mind General Secretary Xi Jinping’s earnest instructions, the cadres and masses of Xinjiang have seized new opportunities, demonstrated new achievements, and solidly promoted high-quality development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Cultivation and expansion of characteristic advantageous industries and active development of emerging industries&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On September 1, the 16-megawatt offshore wind turbine unit of Fujian Pingtan Offshore Wind Farm was The daily power generation reached 384,100 kilowatt hours, setting a new record for global wind power generation in a single day. This wind turbine is produced by Goldwind Technology Co., Ltd., a Xinjiang wind power company. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“新疆充足的自然资源，是我们创新创造的扎实土壤。”金风科技股份有限公司党委副书记房忠说，“截至今年6月底，公司拥有国内外专利申请逾6700项，专利申请数量每年保持高速增长。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“新疆能源资源丰富，得天独厚的资源禀赋为发展特色优势产业提供坚实基础。”新疆维吾尔自治区党委政研室副主任张世俊说，依托优势资源禀赋，新疆不断加大科技创新力度，建设能源、高端能源化工、高端装备制造、新能源等产业集群，加快构建体现新疆特色和优势的现代化产业体系。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;依托科技创新，新疆把资源优势转化为经济优势，把优势产业打造成现代产业，培育壮大特色优势产业。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在伊犁哈萨克自治州，新天煤化工有限责任公司把煤制成天然气，收入是之前的数倍；在哈密市，众友浦汇科技有限公司将煤制成甲醇，再将甲醇制成甲基丙烯酸甲酯，甲基丙烯酸甲酯可用于生产有机玻璃、工业塑料、电子器件等工业产品，产业链条不断延长。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在位于喀什经济开发区的九疆新能源科技有限公司车间里，员工们正有条不紊地进行锂电池的制片、卷绕、注液等作业。 2022年以来，喀什经济开发区引进落地锂电企业28家，项目计划总投资105.78亿元，达产后可实现年产值130多亿元。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;塔里木油田建起一座座大型光伏电站，截至今年9月累计生产绿电突破1亿千瓦时；中国石油独山子石化分公司利用原油、天然气生产乙烯新材料，畅销市场；乌鲁木齐石化公司生产出硫含量低于0.5%的低硫石油焦，应用于新能源电池制造……新疆大力发展新能源、新材料等战略性新兴产业。今年前三季度，新疆工业投资同比增长30.6%，其中风力光伏发电项目投资同比增长1.6倍。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;强化科技引领，为农业现代化注入动力&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新疆的戈壁荒漠中，经常能看到一根根黑色的皮管藏在沙土里。得益于滴灌技术应用，皮管延伸到的地方，就是绿色生长的地方。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新疆强化科技引领，为农业现代化注入动力。新疆的滴灌技术不断发展进步，以此为基础的干播湿出、膜下滴灌、水肥一体化等现代农业技术走在全国前列，诞生了一批知名的农业机械企业、育种制种企业和农产品深加工企业。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;位于昌吉市的九圣禾种业股份有限公司是农业产业化国家重点龙头企业，利用“种质资源整合”和“公司+村集体经济组织+基地+农户”模式，带动新疆农户小麦、玉米、棉花种植制种达20多万亩。 “我们生产的良种已销往17个省份。”九圣禾控股集团有限公司董事长舍亚辉说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至2022年底，新疆农业高效节水应用面积近6300万亩，其中精准水肥调控示范面积120万亩以上，粮食作物良种覆盖率达98%以上，全区农作物综合机械化水平达86.74%，小麦、玉米、棉花等主要农作物实现耕种收全程机械化。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在喀什地区疏勒县蔬乐现代高效农业示范园的日光温室大棚里，技术人员指导农民用现代设备采摘保存水果；不远处的直播间里，主播正在线销售刚刚采摘的新品种西瓜……“我们种的西瓜供不应求。”疏勒县郭牌西瓜种植培训基地运营部主管于尧尧说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;疏勒县引进山东水发集团、山东郭牌西瓜、江苏德利尔等15家龙头企业，建设喀什现代蔬菜产业示范园、蔬乐现代高效农业示范园、疏勒县智慧农业产业园，建成智能温室大棚8000平方米、日光温室大棚1000余座，带动5000余人就业增收。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新疆各地努力做大做强一批领军型农产品加工龙头企业，不断提升产业带动力和市场竞争力。近年来着力建设的薄皮核桃、库尔勒香梨、新疆葡萄、伊犁马、新疆棉花、新疆褐牛等6个农业优势特色产业集群，目前全产业链产值均已突破100亿元。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;发挥区位优势，开放之路越走越宽&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;喀什综合保税区里，一派繁忙景象。跨境电商进出口商品展示交易中心内，综合运营平台实时显示着的跨境电商贸易路线，从喀什延伸到世界各地。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新疆打好口岸贸易这张牌，据乌鲁木齐海关统计，今年前三季度外贸进出口总值达2528.4亿元，同比增长47.3%。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌鲁木齐国际陆港区里，机车穿梭，装卸忙碌，一列列中欧（中亚）班列在这里完成换装后出发，2天可抵达哈萨克斯坦，8天可抵达俄罗斯，16天可抵达荷兰。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“陆港区是中欧班列西通道距离中西亚和欧洲最近的物流枢纽。”乌鲁木齐国际陆港有限责任公司副总经理卢山介绍，陆港区班列累计发运7000余列，运载货物包含200多个种类；开行线路由最初的4条增至21条，通达亚欧19个国家、26个城市。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;口岸兴旺，贸易发达，也带动了新疆新产业、新业态、新服务模式的发展。新疆明确以积极服务和融入新发展格局为目标，在巩固口岸、边境贸易等传统优势的同时，发力培育外贸新业态、贸易产业融合发展等新优势。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新疆霍尔果斯公路口岸出境货运通道上，不同类型、产地的国产汽车整齐排列。这些车在办妥手续后，将出口至哈萨克斯坦。为更好服务整车企业出口需求，霍尔果斯海关开辟出口专用通道，提供本地报关、一体化申报、直通转关等多种出境通关方案。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新疆持续完善“西引东来”“东联西出”，在产业链、供应链、物流链领域与中亚及欧洲各国不断深化合作，开放之路越走越宽。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（本报记者韩立群、白阳、张义钊参与采写）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:56:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 二〇二三金融街论坛年会在京开幕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/09/nw.D110000renmrb_20231109_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月09日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报北京11月8日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者王昊男）以“更好的中国，更好的世界——加强金融开放合作，促进经济共享共赢”为主题的2023金融街论坛年会8日在京开幕。围绕年会主题，与会嘉宾深入交流、凝聚共识。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;北京市委书记尹力表示，将深入贯彻落实中央金融工作会议精神，全力服务好国家金融管理工作，不断增强服务金融发展的功能；全面提升金融服务质效，更好满足社会多元化金融需求；积极深化金融改革开放，着力提升金融高质量发展能级；牢牢守住金融安全底线，持续推进金融治理体系和治理能力现代化，加快建设具有首都特点的现代金融体系，营造更加开放有序的金融发展环境，为促进金融高质量发展贡献力量。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;中国人民银行行长、国家外汇局局长潘功胜表示，货币政策将更加注重跨周期和逆周期调节，平衡好短期与长期、稳增长与防风险、内部均衡与外部均衡的关系，为稳定物价、促进经济增长、扩大就业、维护国际收支平衡营造良好的货币金融环境。在推动金融业高水平双向开放方面，要稳慎扎实推进人民币国际化，务实推进国际金融合作，积极参与国际经济金融治理。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;国家金融监督管理总局局长李云泽表示，中国经济基本面好、潜力足、回旋余地大，为金融业持续健康发展奠定了坚实基础。金融开放是我国金融业改革发展的重要动力。将加快完善准入前国民待遇加负面清单管理模式，进一步放宽外资机构市场准入要求，持续增强金融制度和政策的透明度、稳定性和可预期性，努力营造审慎经营和公平竞争的制度环境。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;中国证监会主席易会满表示，加强监管、防范风险是实现高质量发展的重要保障。下一步将认真落实中央金融工作会议部署，深刻认识资本市场监管的政治性、人民性，全面强化机构监管、行为监管、功能监管、穿透式监管、持续监管，不断提升监管适应性、针对性，守牢风险底线，维护资本市场平稳运行，提振投资者信心，走好中国特色现代资本市场发展之路。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;新华通讯社社长傅华表示，在加快建设金融强国的历史进程中，金融要为经济社会发展提供高质量服务，媒体也应当发挥积极作用。新华社将深入贯彻落实中央金融工作会议精神，继续用好自身独特优势，为学习贯彻习近平经济思想提供权威解读，为推动金融高质量发展凝聚强大信心，为深化金融供给侧结构性改革加强智力支持，为推进金融高水平开放搭建合作桥梁。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;国际清算银行总经理阿古斯丁·卡斯滕斯在视频演讲中表示，作为世界第二大经济体，中国多年来为全球经济增长提供了动力，也为全球和地区金融业作出贡献。期待与中国和其他成员国的央行紧密合作，共同维护全球金融稳定。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;本届金融街论坛年会由北京市人民政府、中国人民银行、金融监管总局、中国证监会、新华社、国家外汇局共同主办。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:56:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 规范实施政府和社会资本合作新机制]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/09/nw.D110000renmrb_20231109_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月09日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报北京11月8日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者刘志强）记者从国家发展改革委获悉：国务院办公厅近日转发国家发展改革委、财政部《关于规范实施政府和社会资本合作新机制的指导意见》。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;指导意见提出，规范实施政府和社会资本合作新机制，充分发挥市场机制作用，拓宽民间投资空间。坚决遏制新增地方政府隐性债务，提高基础设施和公用事业项目建设运营水平，确保规范发展、阳光运行。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;指导意见明确，聚焦使用者付费项目，全部采取特许经营模式。合理把握重点领域，优先选择民营企业参与，明确管理责任分工，稳妥推进新机制实施。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;在规范推进建设实施方面，指导意见提出，严格审核特许经营方案，公平选择特许经营者，规范签订特许经营协议，严格履行投资管理程序，做好项目建设实施管理。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;在加强运营监管方面，指导意见明确，定期开展项目运营评价，惩戒违法违规和失信行为。规范开展特许经营协议变更和项目移交等工作，建立常态化信息披露机制。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;此外，指导意见还明确了支持民营企业参与的特许经营新建（含改扩建）项目清单（2023年版）。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:56:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 奋力开拓乡村振兴新局面（权威访谈）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/09/nw.D110000renmrb_20231109_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月09日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;今年是全面贯彻落实党的二十大精神的开局之年，是加快建设农业强国的起步之年。在以习近平同志为核心的党中央坚强领导下，国民经济持续恢复、总体回升向好，高质量发展扎实推进，社会大局保持稳定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新时代新征程，稳住农业基本盘、守好“三农”基础是应变局、开新局的“压舱石”。今年以来，粮食生产有望再获丰收，全面推进乡村振兴落地见效，加快建设农业强国步伐稳健。记者就当前农业农村经济形势等有关问题采访了农业农村部党组书记、部长唐仁健。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;强化粮食安全保障，夯实稳产增产基础&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：粮食安全是“国之大者”。今年以来，我国局部地区出现台风、干旱、洪涝、冰雪等极端天气事件，如何实现抗灾夺丰收？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;唐仁健：粮食和重要农产品稳定安全供给，是保持经济社会大局稳定、应对各种风险挑战的底气所在。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年，粮食生产先后遭遇黄淮罕见“烂场雨”、华北东北局地严重洪涝、西北局部干旱、东北局地冰雪等灾害，很多人担心粮食会不会减产。目前看，秋粮收获已进入扫尾阶段，全年粮食有望再夺丰收、继续增产。今年夏粮略减了25.5亿斤，仍是第二高产年，早稻增产了4.3亿斤。全年粮食产量的大头在秋粮，综合专家田间测产和多个部门单位预测研判，今年秋粮仍将增产。全年综合算大账，增减相抵，粮食将继续保持在1.3万亿斤以上。同时，肉蛋奶和蔬菜水果、水产品等供应充足。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我们这么大一个国家，可以说自然灾害年年都有，抗灾夺丰收几乎是每年农业工作的主题之一。今年，河南、黑龙江、河北等局部地区农业受灾的确较重，但从全国来看，灾情总体上比上年和常年要轻。此外，今年各主产区降水普遍较多，土壤墒情好，雨热同期同至，尤其对近10亿亩灌溉条件不足的旱地粮食生产十分有利。总的看，面上的增产有效弥补了点上损失。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;把牢粮食安全主动权，离不开重农抓粮政策支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年，国家继续提高早籼稻和小麦最低收购价，增加产粮大县奖励资金，出台了支持大豆生产等政策组合拳，一系列真金白银的政策有效调动了农民种粮积极性。各地压紧压实粮食安全党政同责，千方百计稳定粮食种植面积，夯实了丰收基础。农情调度显示，今年秋粮面积增加了700多万亩，特别是高产作物玉米增加1300多万亩，为夺取粮食丰收创造了条件。中央财政安排37亿元农业防灾救灾资金，在秋粮生产关键时期还专门安排24亿元用于“一喷多促”，促进作物壮苗稳长，对于秋粮稳产增产发挥了重要作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大面积单产提升，有效对冲了灾害影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;年初，我们启动了粮油等主要作物大面积单产提升行动，针对大田产量与试验示范田产量的差距，从耕种管收、地种肥药全领域全环节查找短板弱项，拿出良田、良种、良法、良制、良机“五良”集成组装的综合性解决方案。今年，重点在100个大豆、200个玉米主产县整建制推进大面积提单产，主推了玉米大豆密植技术，效果显著。专家测算，300个重点县单产提升对粮食增产的贡献率达到73%以上。面上单产的提升有效对冲了洪涝、干旱、冰雪等灾害对粮食生产的影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;巩固拓展脱贫攻坚成果，有序推进宜居宜业和美乡村建设&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：“三农”向好，全局主动。目前看，今年粮食生产有望再获丰收，乡村振兴其他各项重点工作推进如何？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;唐仁健：今年以来，农业农村部全力抓好以乡村振兴为重心的“三农”各项工作，农业农村发展呈现稳中向好态势，为推动经济持续回升向好、加快构建新发展格局、着力推动高质量发展提供了有力支撑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;脱贫攻坚成果进一步巩固拓展，全面推进乡村振兴的底线任务牢牢扛在肩上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年以来，各地进一步健全完善防止返贫监测帮扶机制，从发现返贫风险到识别认定再到实施帮扶，一般不超过1个月，确保早发现早干预、应纳尽纳、应帮尽帮，63.5%的监测对象已消除返贫致贫风险，其余均落实了帮扶措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，突出抓好产业就业帮扶，推动衔接补助资金用于产业发展超过60%，脱贫劳动力务工规模达到3297万人，超额完成3000万人的年度任务。去年脱贫人口人均纯收入同比增长14.3%，预计今年将继续保持较快增长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;宜居宜业和美乡村建设有序推进，逐步使农村基本具备现代生活条件。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年农业农村部会同有关部门认真总结推广浙江“千万工程”经验，各地深入学习运用，扎实推进乡村振兴持续走深走实。目前，全国农村卫生厕所普及率超过73%，90%以上的行政村常态化开展生活垃圾收运处理，农村公共基础设施持续改善。50%左右的行政村推广运用清单制、积分制，有效规范村级组织运行，减轻了基层负担，提升了乡村治理效能。持续推进乡村产业发展，前三季度农副食品加工业增加值继续增长，产品网络零售额保持两位数增长，带动农民收入实际增长7.3%，比城镇居民收入增速快2.6个百分点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;加快实现高水平农业科技自立自强，为农业高质量发展提供强劲动能&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：今年在加快实现高水平农业科技自立自强方面重点开展了哪些工作？有什么进展和成效？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;唐仁健：建设农业强国，利器在科技。近年来，我国农业科技创新能力稳步提升，农业科技进步贡献率达到62.4%，为农业高质量发展提供了强劲动能。今年以来，我们持续用好种业振兴行动、农业关键核心技术攻关、生物育种重大项目这三大抓手，在底盘技术、核心种源、关键农机装备等领域持续发力，加快补上短板弱项。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一是持续推进种业创新攻关。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;种子是农业的“芯片”，目前国产种子基本能够满足国内需求，但在一些品种和领域，与国际先进水平差距还比较大。把当家品种牢牢攥在自己手里，我们瞄准保障粮食和重要农产品稳定安全供给的战略需要，扎实推进种业振兴行动，取得了一批突破性成果。我们自主培育出3个白羽肉鸡新品种，打破了此前完全依赖进口的局面，实现“从0到1”的突破，今年市场占有率已达到20%，还首次出口国外。自主培育的12个南美白对虾新品种，市场占有率达到35%。今年还育成了短生育期油菜“中油早1号”，生育期只需要约169天，有助于南方地区实施“稻稻油”轮作、利用冬闲田种植油菜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;二是加快农机装备补短板。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前，我国农业发展已进入机械化主导阶段，农机制造和使用规模居世界第一，但一些领域短板也比较突出。东北地区长期使用的都是国外品牌大马力农机，南方6亿多亩丘陵区耕地也一直缺少适用的小型机具。聚焦“一大一小”问题，我们会同工业和信息化部启动了农机装备补短板行动，组织开展协同攻关，目前一批重要标志性机具研制取得突破。在“一大”方面，国产320、240马力的无级变速拖拉机已经实现量产和产业化应用。在“一小”方面，多款拖拉机完成样机试制，能够适应15度以下坡度作业，可以解决南方山地“无机可用”的问题。油菜移栽机、再生稻收获机、大豆玉米带状复合种植专用播种机等产业发展急需机械也陆续应用于生产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三是加强底盘技术研发攻关。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;底盘技术是农业现代化绕不开的关键所在，是“要不来、买不来、讨不来”的。加快这方面布局攻关，目前部分领域已取得突破进展。比如基因编辑工具方面，开发出了我们自己的基因编辑“剪刀”，为种业振兴提供了技术支撑。围绕耕地地力提升、盐碱地整治、农业节水等领域，我们正在布局开展关键核心技术攻关，力争尽早取得突破。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;到年底还有不到两个月，各项工作时间紧、任务重。我们将继续加大工作力度，强化措施落实，坚决完成党中央、国务院确定的年度目标任务，奋力开拓乡村振兴新局面，为推动经济持续回升向好提供有力支撑。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:56:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 共同推动构建网络空间命运共同体迈向新阶段]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/09/nw.D110000renmrb_20231109_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月09日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;互联网是人类共同的家园。无论数字技术如何创新发展，无论国际环境如何风云变幻，每个人都在网络空间休戚与共、命运相连。11月8日，习近平主席向2023年世界互联网大会乌镇峰会开幕式发表视频致辞，强调“我们要深化交流、务实合作，共同推动构建网络空间命运共同体迈向新阶段”，倡导发展优先、安危与共、文明互鉴，提出构建更加普惠繁荣、和平安全、平等包容的网络空间的三点主张，为各国携手构建网络空间命运共同体注入强大正能量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当今世界变乱交织，百年变局加速演进，如何解决发展赤字、破解安全困境、加强文明互鉴，是我们共同面临的时代课题。在此形势下，中国没有独善其身，而是同世界各国加强合作，共同探寻解决之道。习近平主席提出共建“一带一路”倡议、全球发展倡议、全球安全倡议、全球文明倡议，就是希望和世界各国一道，实现经济发展，改善民生，互利共赢，让团结代替分裂、合作代替对抗、包容代替排他，共同建设持久和平、普遍安全、共同繁荣、开放包容、清洁美丽的世界。实践告诉我们，坚定践行真正的多边主义，推动共建“一带一路”更高质量、更高水平的新发展，推动落实全球发展倡议、全球安全倡议、全球文明倡议，推动构建人类命运共同体，才能应对各种全球性挑战，共同创造人类更加美好的未来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;互联网日益成为推动发展的新动能、维护安全的新疆域、文明互鉴的新平台，构建网络空间命运共同体既是回答时代课题的必然选择，也是国际社会的共同呼声。2015年，习近平主席在第二届世界互联网大会开幕式上提出了全球互联网发展治理的“四项原则”、“五点主张”，倡导构建网络空间命运共同体，这一理念得到国际社会广泛认同和积极响应。新时代的中国网络空间国际合作，在构建网络空间命运共同体的愿景下，不断取得新成绩、实现新突破、展现新气象。实践充分证明，推动构建网络空间命运共同体，将为构建人类命运共同体提供充沛的数字化动力，构筑坚实的安全屏障，凝聚更广泛的合作共识。前进道路上，中国将始终秉持构建网络空间命运共同体理念，同国际社会一道，共同构建更加普惠繁荣、和平安全、平等包容的网络空间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;互联网发展需要大家共同参与，发展成果应由大家共同分享。随着新一代信息通信技术加速融合创新，数字化、网络化、智能化在经济社会各领域加速渗透融合，深刻改变人们的生产方式和生活方式。同时，不同国家和地区在互联网普及、基础设施建设、技术创新创造、数字经济发展、数字素养与技能等方面的发展水平不平衡，影响和限制世界各国特别是发展中国家的信息化建设和数字化转型。习近平主席指出：“我们倡导发展优先，构建更加普惠繁荣的网络空间。”只有深化数字领域国际交流合作，加速科技成果转化，加快信息化服务普及，缩小数字鸿沟，在互联网发展中保障和改善民生，才能让更多国家和人民共享互联网发展成果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安全是发展的前提，一个安全稳定繁荣的网络空间，对世界各国都具有重大意义。必须深刻认识到，网络安全是全球性挑战，没有哪个国家能够置身事外，维护网络安全是国际社会的共同责任。同时，《联合国宪章》确立的主权平等原则是当代国际关系的基本准则，同样适用于网络空间。习近平主席指出：“我们倡导安危与共，构建更加和平安全的网络空间。”只有尊重网络主权，遵守网络空间国际规则，深化网络安全务实合作，有力打击网络违法犯罪行为，加强数据安全和个人信息保护，才能妥善应对科技发展带来的规则冲突、社会风险、伦理挑战，更好维护网络空间安全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文明因交流而多彩，因互鉴而发展。互联网是传播人类优秀文化、弘扬正能量的重要载体。打造网上文化交流共享平台，促进交流互鉴，有利于共同推动网络文化繁荣发展，丰富人们精神世界，促进人类文明进步。习近平主席指出：“我们倡导文明互鉴，构建更加平等包容的网络空间。”只有加强网上交流对话，促进各国人民相知相亲，推动不同文明包容共生，才能更好弘扬全人类共同价值。只有加强网络文明建设，促进优质网络文化产品生产传播，充分展示人类优秀文明成果，积极推动文明传承发展，才能共同建设网上精神家园。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;信息革命时代潮流浩荡前行，网络空间承载着人类对美好未来的无限憧憬。前进道路上，顺应互联网发展大势，推动网络空间互联互通、共享共治，携手构建网络空间命运共同体，就一定能让互联网更繁荣、更干净、更安全，更好造福世界各国人民。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:56:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 韩正出席第六届创新经济论坛并访问新加坡]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/09/nw.D110000renmrb_20231109_5-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月09日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/09/01/rmrb2023110901p34_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;11月8日，国家副主席韩正出席在新加坡举行的第六届创新经济论坛开幕式并发表主旨演讲。&lt;BR/>;新华社记者高洁摄&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;新华社新加坡11月8日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者蒋国鹏、蔡蜀亚）11月7日至8日，国家副主席韩正出席在新加坡举行的第六届创新经济论坛，并应邀访问新加坡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩正在论坛开幕式上发表主旨演讲。韩正表示，面对世界之变、时代之变、历史之变，习近平主席提出构建人类命运共同体的重大理念，提出全球发展倡议、全球安全倡议、全球文明倡议，推动共建“一带一路”进入高质量发展的新阶段，为应对全人类共同挑战、构建更加美好的世界贡献了中国方案。中国愿与世界各国一道，把握时代发展机遇，携手应对风险挑战，共同开创人类更加美好的未来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩正提出三点倡议。一是坚持以开放促合作。中国将坚定不移地推进高水平对外开放，愿提供更多市场机遇、投资机遇，与各国企业共享中国制度型开放红利。二是坚持以创新谋动力。中国将与各国加强创新成果共享，共同应对气候变化挑战，为世界经济增长注入新动能。三是坚持以和平促发展。中国愿同各国一道，共同维护世界和平与安全，共谋发展与繁荣，推动构建人类命运共同体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩正指出，最近中美之间开展的一些重要高层接触，提升了国际社会对未来中美关系改善的正面预期。中方始终按照习近平主席提出的相互尊重、和平共处、合作共赢三原则看待和处理中美关系。我们愿与美方加强各层次的沟通、对话，推进互利合作，妥善管控分歧，合力应对全球性挑战。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩正还会见了创新经济论坛创始人、美国彭博集团创始人布隆伯格，集体会见了出席论坛的嘉宾代表。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;访新期间，韩正分别会见新加坡总统尚达曼、总理李显龙、副总理王瑞杰、国务资政兼国家安全统筹部长张志贤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会见尚达曼时，韩正转达了习近平主席的亲切问候，表示中新互为近邻和重要合作伙伴，是国与国友好交往的典范。在双方共同努力下，两国合作展现强大韧性和蓬勃活力，相信未来将取得更多更好成果。当今世界面临诸多全球性风险和挑战，任何一个国家都不可能独善其身，需要各国坚持真正的多边主义，凝聚共识，携手合作。中国将以自身稳定性为世界注入更多确定性，以自身新发展为世界带来更多新机遇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;尚达曼请韩正转达对习近平主席的诚挚问候，表示站在新的历史起点上，两国领导人把双边关系提升为全方位高质量的前瞻性伙伴关系，为两国关系发展指明了前进方向。新方愿同中方深化各领域务实合作，更好造福两国人民。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会见李显龙时，韩正表示，习近平主席同总理先生今年3月将中新关系提升为全方位高质量的前瞻性伙伴关系，在两国关系进程中具有里程碑意义。今年是李光耀先生诞辰100周年，新加坡运用东方价值观和国际视野推进现代化进程，走出一条符合本国国情的发展之路。中方愿同新方一道，高质量共建“一带一路”，推动两国合作项目提质升级，密切两国人员往来和人文交流，用好用足双边合作机制，将两国关系新定位落到实处，为地区繁荣稳定作出新贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李显龙表示，新中传统友谊深厚。新方愿同中方深化发展战略对接，开好新一轮新中双边合作机制会议，推动新中全方位高质量的前瞻性伙伴关系迈上新台阶。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 09 Nov 2023 05:56:08 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>