<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 中国残疾人联合会第八次全国代表大会在京开幕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20230919_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, September 19, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-09/19/01/rmrb2023091901p26_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;September 18, China The Eighth National Congress of the Disabled Persons&#39; Federation opened in the Great Hall of the People in Beijing. This is Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, President of the State, and Chairman of the Central Military Commission, paying tribute to the participants on the rostrum. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Li Xueren&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center &quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-09/19/01/rmrb2023091901p25_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On September 18, the Eighth National Congress of the China Disabled Persons&#39; Federation opened at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing. Xi Jinping, Li Qiang, Zhao Leji, Wang Huning, Cai Qi, Ding Xuexiang and others took their seats on the rostrum to congratulate the convening of the conference. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Pang Xinglei&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, September 18th&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;(Reporter Li Changyu) The Eighth National Congress of the China Disabled Persons’ Federation opened on the morning of the 18th at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing. Xi Jinping, Li Qiang, Zhao Leji, Wang Huning, Cai Qi and other party and state leaders attended the meeting to congratulate. Ding Xuexiang delivered a speech on behalf of the Party Central Committee and the State Council. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The auditorium of the Great Hall of the People is brightly lit and the atmosphere is solemn and warm. The emblem of the &quot;Eighth National Congress of the China Disabled Persons&#39; Federation&quot; hangs above the rostrum. The emblem of the China Disabled Persons&#39; Federation in the middle of the background is particularly eye-catching, with 10 red flags lined up on both sides. A giant banner hangs on the terrace on the second floor: &quot;Guided by Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, fully implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Party, and unite and lead the disabled to create a happier and better life in the process of Chinese modernization!&quot; . More than 600 representatives from all over the country attended the conference, shouldering the great trust of approximately 85 million people with disabilities. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;At 10 a.m., Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, President of the State, and Chairman of the Central Military Commission, entered the venue, and the audience burst into warm applause. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The conference opened with the majestic national anthem of the People&#39;s Republic of China. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;On behalf of the Party Central Committee and the State Council, Ding Xuexiang delivered a speech entitled &quot;Working Together to Create a Happier and Better Life for Disabled Persons in the Process of Chinese Modernization&quot;, expressing warm congratulations on the convening of the conference and congratulating all disabled people across the country. We extend cordial greetings to people, relatives and friends of persons with disabilities, and workers with disabilities, and express our heartfelt thanks to people from all walks of life who care about and support the cause of persons with disabilities. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Ding Xuexiang said in his speech that under the strong leadership of the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping at the core, my country&#39;s cause of disabled people has created a new situation of vigorous development in the ten years of the new era, and has achieved &quot;building a moderately prosperous society in all respects&quot; as scheduled. society, there must be no less disabled people”. The vast number of disabled people keep their dreams as companions and keep pace with the times. They turn their beautiful dreams into reality with tenacious struggle and vividly interpret the great national spirit of constant self-improvement and the spirit of the times with practical actions. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Ding Xuexiang emphasized that the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China put forward clear requirements for improving the social security system and care service system for disabled people and promoting the all-round development of the cause of disabled people. We must adhere to the guidance of Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, fully implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important expositions and important instructions on the development of the cause of persons with disabilities, firmly grasp the value orientation of equality, integration, and sharing, and firmly grasp the We will advance the historical mission of modernizing the cause of persons with disabilities, firmly grasp the goal and task of promoting common prosperity for persons with disabilities, and promote the all-round development of causes for persons with disabilities. Party committees and governments at all levels should further improve the leadership system for the cause of persons with disabilities. Government committees on disabled persons at all levels should strengthen overall planning and coordination, relevant departments and units should cooperate closely, and Disabled Persons&#39; Federations at all levels should conscientiously perform their duties. Disabled persons should continue to promote self-esteem, self-confidence, and self-improvement. , spirit of self-reliance, and jointly create a happier and better life for people with disabilities in the process of Chinese modernization. (See the second page for the full text of the speech)&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Huang Xiaowei, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and First Secretary of the Secretariat of the All-China Women’s Federation, represented the All-China Federation of Trade Unions, the Central Committee of the Communist Youth League of China, the All-China Women’s Federation, and China The Federation of Literary and Art Circles, the Chinese Writers Association, the China Association for Science and Technology, the All-China Federation of Returned Overseas Chinese, and the All-China Taiwan Compatriots Association sent congratulatory messages to the conference. The congratulatory message pointed out that all mass organizations should continue to carry forward their fine traditions, give full play to their respective advantages, lead the people they are associated with to be more confident and more motivated to follow the party on the broad road of building a strong country and national rejuvenation, and jointly write the story of the party in the new era. A new chapter in group work. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;On behalf of the seventh presidium of the China Disabled Persons&#39; Federation, Zhang Haidi, Chairman of the China Disabled Persons&#39; Federation, made a speech to the conference titled &quot;Working hard to promote the comprehensive development of the cause of persons with disabilities under the guidance of Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era&quot; work report. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Some members of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee, members of the Secretariat of the CPC Central Committee, and relevant leading comrades of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, the State Council, the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference, and the Central Military Commission attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Relevant departments of the central and state agencies, various people&#39;s organizations, relevant military units and responsible comrades in Beijing, leaders of the Central Committee of Democratic Parties and the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce, and representatives of the Eighth National Congress of the China Disabled Persons&#39; Federation attended the opening meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 05:56:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 建好建强国家重要商品粮生产基地（打好夺取秋粮丰收这场硬仗）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20230919_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, September 19, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Opening words&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Food security is &quot;the most important thing in a country&quot;. In September this year, General Secretary Xi Jinping chaired a symposium on promoting the comprehensive revitalization of Northeast China in the new era and emphasized that “guaranteing national food security must always be given top priority.” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All localities and departments conscientiously implement the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, implement various measures, and go all out to achieve a bumper autumn harvest. Starting from today, this newspaper will open a column on &quot;Winning the Tough Battle for Autumn Grain Harvest&quot; to report on the vivid practice of cadres and masses in major grain-producing areas who have kept their instructions in mind, worked hard to keep their jobs firmly in their hands, and tried every means to increase yields. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The ears of rice are big and the grains are full. It’s heavy to hold a handful in your hand.” Liu Chun, head of the Northeast Paddy Modern Agricultural Machinery Professional Cooperative in Fujin City, Heilongjiang Province He said that this year’s seedlings were planted early and transplanted scientifically and densely. “Behind the bumper harvest is the credit of science and technology!”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“8,000 acres of rice were planted this year. Except for a small area affected by floods, most of them are growing basically. Normal.&quot; Wang Jinkui, chairman of the Baina Rice Planting Professional Cooperative in Youguo Village, Wuchang City, said that the total rice output should not be different. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized that &quot;Heilongjiang must serve as the &#39;ballast stone&#39; for national food security&quot; and &quot;build an important commodity grain production base for a strong country.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We resolutely shoulder the responsibility and mission of being the &#39;ballast stone&#39; of national food security.&quot; The relevant person in charge of the Heilongjiang Provincial Department of Agriculture and Rural Affairs said that in response to the early floods, the whole province was working on disaster relief and disaster relief. In order to increase the yield per unit area, according to the latest agricultural situation analysis, the province&#39;s grain production is expected to achieve &quot;twenty consecutive harvests&quot; this year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Walking on the land of Longjiang, the black soil is full of busy figures, and the fields are pregnant with the hope of a good harvest. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Multiple measures have been taken and field management has been meticulous to minimize production losses in disaster-stricken farmland&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fertile black soil and excellent ecology have made Wuchang Rice famous far and wide. In early August, affected by continuous heavy rainfall, flooding occurred in some areas of Wuchang City, Heilongjiang Province, posing challenges to autumn grain production. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Recently, the reporter walked into Wuchang. Under the autumn sunshine, the rice in the continuous rice fields was growing gratifyingly and the grains were full. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Our cooperative has planted 20,000 acres of rice. This year, the land affected by the disaster is mainly the land on both sides of the river. The water area is about 2,000 acres.&quot; Huang, technician of Wangjiatun Modern Agriculture and Agricultural Machinery Professional Cooperative in Dujia Town, Wuchang City Changming said that after the flood occurred, the cooperative immediately rushed to drain the stagnant water, sprayed foliar fertilizers in time, and improved ventilation conditions in the fields. &quot;Currently, it appears that rice fields that have been flooded with water will have reduced yields to varying degrees, but rice fields with higher terrain or better drainage will be relatively less affected.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;From a city-wide perspective, we are doing our best to drain the stagnant water in the fields. At the same time, technical guidance services were quickly carried out in categories, and multiple drones were deployed to spray plant protection agents on the affected fields to speed up the rice filling.&quot; Wang Shouxin, director of the Wuchang Municipal Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau, said that the damaged rice seedling greenhouses, germination workshops and other types of All agricultural production facilities will be repaired before the end of October, which will not delay agricultural production next year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shangzhi City also benefited from the early start and the promotion and application of high-yield and efficient technologies. At present, most of the city&#39;s crops are growing close to normal, and the growth of soybeans is better than normal. Wei Jinsheng, deputy director of the Shangzhi Municipal Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau, said that the city has established six post-disaster self-rescue technical guidance groups for agricultural production to provide point-to-point technical guidance in various towns and villages; on the basis of the early drainage of waterlogging and loose soil moisture, the city has accelerated the construction and repair of village roads and farmland culverts. and other infrastructure to ensure long-term production capacity. Currently, the city has completed maintenance work on 14,000 tractors and more than 2,400 harvesters. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Will floods affect the province’s grain output? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The disaster-stricken areas are mainly concentrated in 11 counties (cities, districts) in Harbin and Mudanjiang.” Guo Jiayong, deputy director of the Planting Industry Management Office of the Heilongjiang Provincial Department of Agriculture and Rural Affairs, said that from the perspective of the province as a whole, It can be seen that the affected area is 5.5198 million acres, accounting for only 2.36% of the province&#39;s actual crop sowing area, and the impact on the total grain output is lower than normal. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Up to now, the drainage of disaster-stricken farmland in Heilongjiang Province has basically been completed, and 18.4888 million acres of foliar fertilizers have been sprayed. Multiple measures have been taken to ensure stable production in lightly affected areas and reduce production in severely affected areas. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Look, the rice ears are growing so strong, it’s another good harvest year.” In the rice fields of Yucheng Modern Agricultural Machinery Professional Cooperative in Huachuan County, Yang Zhongsheng, director of the County Agricultural Technology Extension Center, uploaded according to the intelligent monitoring equipment Analysis of field data gave Li Yucheng, chairman of the cooperative, a clear idea. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In early August, Huachuan County also experienced continuous rain. The county immediately launched agricultural production to fight disasters and self-rescue. Agriculture and rural areas, meteorology, emergency management and other departments stepped up consultations and judgments to guide farmers to implement defensive measures in advance. The County Agricultural Technology Extension Center collaborated with scientific research institutes to establish an expert-involved technical guidance group, which went deep into the fields of nine towns and villages in the county to provide guidance on disaster prevention, disaster reduction, and disaster resistance to achieve a bumper harvest. &quot;With the guidance of professional and technical personnel and careful and scientific field management, the harvest should not be lost.&quot; Li Yucheng said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xu Jinyou, director of the Huachuan County Agricultural and Rural Affairs Bureau, said, &quot;Due to adequate preparation and careful management, agricultural production in the county is recovering in an orderly manner, and the overall growth of crops is good.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Heilongjiang The provincial autumn grain harvest is in sight. Ding Ran, deputy director of the Agricultural Machinery Department of the Provincial Department of Agriculture and Rural Affairs, said that the province has made preparations for the early stage of mechanized production of autumn harvest machinery and personnel in advance, and has reserved 203,000 harvesting machinery to ensure adequate supply of machinery and equipment, standardized operator operation, and adequate service guarantees. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Increase the yield per unit area in a large area, make up for the deficit with abundance, and lay a solid foundation for stabilizing and increasing grain production&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Enter Shanshu Village, Liming Town, Zhaodong City. The corn stalks are thick and thick. Not long ago, a multi-spraying operation was carried out here to promote navigation. &quot;Spraying foliar fertilizers and plant growth regulators at this stage will help promote the synthesis and accumulation of organic matter, promote early maturity and increase grain weight.&quot; Han Zhiqiang, director of the Zhaodong Agricultural Technology Extension Center, said that the city has completed all spraying tasks. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Qixing Farm Co., Ltd., the Sanjiang Branch of the Beidahuang Group, in more than 10 days, a large area of ​​​​rice will be harvested. This year, the farm has integrated and promoted the application of 22 agricultural innovative technologies such as standardized grid field transformation, variable side depth fertilization, and wide and narrow row rice transplanting to carry out precise management and protection. &quot;We use satellite remote sensing technology to detect the growth of ground crops. Different color layers represent different situations, and we conduct precise judgment and management to ensure high yields and harvests all year round.&quot; said Qin Yuqiu, a grower in the company&#39;s first management area. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In interviews, farmers in unaffected areas of Heilongjiang Province said that the growth of staple food crops such as rice, corn, and soybeans this year is better than in previous years, and the yield per mu is expected to increase. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Where does the confidence for the harvest come from? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Guo Jiayong listed several sets of data - as of August 30, the average accumulated temperature in Heilongjiang Province was higher than the same period in previous years; the average precipitation was 487.8 mm, 19.6% more than the same period in previous years; the average temperature was 18.5 degrees Celsius, 0.2 degrees Celsius higher than previous years. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Although there are local meteorological disasters such as low temperature and lack of sunshine and typhoons and floods, comprehensive analysis of indicators such as temperature, moisture, and accumulated temperature shows that the overall meteorological conditions are conducive to agricultural production, and most indicators are better than normal.&quot; Guo Jiayong He said that this year, Heilongjiang Province adjusted and optimized the planting structure, and the new grain planting area reached 4.5691 million acres, laying a solid foundation for a bumper harvest. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Especially this year, our country has launched a new round of operations to increase grain production capacity by 100 billion kilograms, and increasing the yield per unit area of ​​major grain crops has become a key word for agricultural production. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Dongsheng Village, Wuliming Town, Zhaodong City, the number of corn plants per acre has increased from about 3,700 to 5,500, and slender drip irrigation belts pass through the ridges. Shan Yuheng, chairman of the Xinboli Agricultural Machinery Professional Cooperative, picked a corn and broke it open to take a closer look. &quot;The core is fine, the kernels are deep, not blind and pointed, and it can grow for another 20 days or so!&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhao Ma Mingzhe, deputy director of the Dongshi Municipal Bureau of Agriculture and Rural Affairs, said that on the basis of dense crop planting, this year the city has successively built field water transmission and distribution pipe networks and other supporting facilities in the 200,000-acre project area to achieve precise fertilizer and water control throughout the growth period. Once completed, it is expected to promote The average corn yield per mu in the project area increased by 200 to 300 kilograms. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shan Yuheng said that the more than 2,000 acres of land transferred by the cooperative use high-quality density-resistant varieties, and integrate water and fertilizer drip irrigation on demand through sensors. &quot;Compared with ordinary planting methods, one acre of land can increase yield by at least 20%.&quot; His target output per acre this year is 2,500 kilograms. &quot;Judging from the current plant type and ear shape, there is basically no problem.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Technology helps increase unit production. This year, Heilongjiang Province will implement a plan to increase grain production by tens of millions of tons, promote corn and soybean large-ridge close-planting cultivation technology, and carry out pilot projects to improve unit yields in four counties (cities and districts) including Tailai County and Zhaodong City, striving to have the main technology promoted throughout the province in place. The rate has remained above 95%, and 140 agricultural science and technology demonstration bases have been established to build a solid &quot;ballast stone&quot; for food security. &quot;Insist on focusing on multiple factors, set up a good harvest framework in all aspects, and strive to achieve new breakthroughs in yields of major food crops.&quot; said Jiang Yiquan, chief agronomist of the Heilongjiang Provincial Department of Agriculture and Rural Affairs. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Consolidate the foundation of food security in an all-round way and steadily improve the comprehensive grain production capacity&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are 258 million acres of cultivated land, and 103 million acres of high-standard farmland have been built. Black soil arable land accounts for more than half of the country&#39;s total area... With fertile fields and thick soil, Heilongjiang, a large granary, not only has excellent endowments, but its comprehensive grain production capacity continues to improve. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Build a large granary and continue to protect and improve the quality of black soil farmland. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The key is to adhere to systematic policy implementation and establish a scientific and technological support system.” The relevant person in charge of the Heilongjiang Provincial Department of Agriculture and Rural Affairs said that in recent years, the province and scientific research institutes have carried out in-depth cooperation in the “Black Soil Granary” scientific and technological battle, focusing on Carry out scientific and technological research to improve the fertility of black soil and build a fertile cultivated layer, and create black soil protection and utilization technologies that are useful and popular. At the same time, a seven-level field director responsibility system from province to household has been established to accelerate the formation of a full-field, all-factor, and full-coverage black soil farmland protection situation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To build a large granary, you must firmly hold the best seeds in your own hands. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strengthen research in the seed industry and carry out trials and demonstrations of new technologies. In the field of Yuxin Modern Agricultural Machinery Professional Cooperative in Bei&#39;an City, demonstration planting of Longda No. 5, Dengke No. 4, Nongken 3092 and other varieties was carried out. &quot;Conduct multiple varieties trials in one field to see which variety performs best in the field.&quot; Chairman Wang Fugui said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“To improve the yield level of grain and oil crops, the focus is on preserving good seeds, breeding new varieties, and promoting superior varieties.” Liu Xiaobing, deputy director of the Seed Industry Management Division of the Heilongjiang Provincial Department of Agriculture and Rural Affairs, said that the province’s rice and soybean seeds The self-sufficiency rate has reached 100%, and the contribution of crop seeds to increased grain production has reached 45%. The next step is to accelerate the construction of a germplasm resource improvement and breeding platform and improve the level of basic research in the seed industry. Guide scientific research institutions and seed companies to strengthen cooperation, tap high-quality germplasm resources, cultivate excellent new varieties, and accelerate the improvement of variety yields and resistance levels. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Build a large granary and accelerate the integration of new technologies and models for grain production. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This year, Yuxin Modern Agricultural Machinery Professional Cooperative also undertakes a new experimental task-selecting and promoting compound microbial fertilizer and inoculants. In the test field, the soybeans are in the seeding stage. It can be seen at a glance that the soybeans treated with microbial fertilizers and inoculants are significantly stronger. Wang Fugui said that this new technology can increase soybean production by more than 8% on average. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This test provides strong support for promoting the efficient implementation and transformation of soybean yield improvement actions.” Yang Wei, deputy director of the Heilongjiang Provincial Agricultural Technology Extension Station, said that the province will carry out rhizobia inoculation, different leaf Experimental demonstrations such as diversified fertilization technology of surface fertilizer combinations and soybean control and lodging resistance and high-yield technology have been implemented to increase soybean yields through one county, one policy and integrated high-tech models. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Build large granaries and strengthen disaster prevention and reduction capabilities in grain production. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to reports, Heilongjiang Province took the lead in establishing an online monitoring and early warning system for crop disease and pest epidemics covering the entire province’s agricultural areas, with 6,000 rural disease and pest epidemic monitoring outlets. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Shengping Village, Wuliming Town, Zhaodong City, Shao Chunyu, chairman of the Yuyan Corn Planting Professional Cooperative, is both a new technology demonstration household and a village-level plant protection officer. During the field management period, he used the &quot;Pocket Plant Protection&quot; APP on his mobile phone to carry out monitoring information standardization surveys on the surrounding 40,000 acres of cultivated land. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In recent years, people have paid more and more attention to the prevention and control of pests and diseases. For example, we need to coat the seeds with two layers before sowing, and actively cooperate with the unified prevention and control. The corn borer that often appeared in the past has rarely appeared in recent years. It happened.&quot; Shao Chunyu said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“By adopting the government-purchased service method, each monitoring point hires a village-level plant protection officer to extend the monitoring tentacles to the ends of the countryside to achieve early detection and early response.” Heilongjiang Provincial Phytosanitary and Plant Protection Station Deputy webmaster Lu Tao introduced. As of September 18, the province has collected a total of 15.879 million pieces of monitoring data and 3.322 million pictures this year, providing scientific basis for monitoring and early warning of major disease and insect pest epidemics in the province. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Our reporters Cui Jia, Zhu Jun, Yu Jingxian, Qu Xinming, Zhu Dawei)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 05:56:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 蔡奇参加2023年全国科普日主场活动]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20230919_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, September 19, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, September 18th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Cai Qi, Member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Secretary of the Central Secretariat on the 18th In the afternoon, I came to Beijing Shougang Park to participate in the main event of National Science Popularization Day. Cai Qi pointed out that it is necessary to thoroughly study and implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions on popularizing science and building scientific literacy, continue to do a good job in science popularization, improve the scientific literacy of the whole people, inspire confidence in scientific and technological innovation, and achieve high-level scientific and technological self-reliance and promote Chinese-style make new and greater contributions to modernization. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cai Qi visited the exhibition areas of &quot;Leading the Helm and Creating Glory&quot;, &quot;Confidence and Self-reliance to Build a Strong Country&quot; and &quot;Science and Technology Benefiting the People&#39;s Livelihood&quot; to learn about the development achievements of science popularization, and inspected deep space exploration, manned spaceflight, petrochemical industry, Special exhibitions such as rural revitalization, and cordial exchanges with scientific and technological workers. He pointed out that General Secretary Xi Jinping attaches great importance to scientific and technological innovation and science popularization, and has made a series of important instructions and expositions on science popularization and scientific quality building, leading the science popularization cause to achieve historic achievements. Science and technology associations at all levels, all sectors of society, and science and technology workers must focus on the &quot;big players in the country&quot;, take the initiative to take on their responsibilities, and effectively play the important and fundamental role of science popularization in achieving innovative development. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In the &quot;Science Popularization Carnival&quot; and &quot;Science Education Addition&quot; exhibition area, Cai Qi learned in detail about the new development of the artificial intelligence industry, watched the innovative exploration of schools and society in science education, and listened to the &quot;Middle School Student Talents&quot; Plan&quot; has been implemented for ten years to serve the country&#39;s basic research talent cultivation work practice and introduce the scientific and technological innovation achievements of Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei youth. He interacted cordially with the educators and teenagers present, encouraging teenagers to have scientific dreams, establish innovative aspirations, and strive to achieve high standards as soon as possible. Science and technology contribute to self-reliance and self-reliance. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Li Shulei, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and director of the Propaganda Department of the CPC Central Committee, attended the event. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The National Science Popularization Day is an important science popularization activity that implements the &quot;Science and Technology Popularization Law of the People&#39;s Republic of China&quot;, mobilizes scientific and technological workers and all aspects of society to widely participate in science popularization, and is directly oriented to the public and serves the public. . Since 2004, it has been held for 20 consecutive sessions, and a total of more than 400,000 key science popularization activities have been held. The 2023 National Science Popularization Day event has the theme of &quot;improving the scientific literacy of the people and promoting self-reliance and self-reliance in science and technology&quot; and will provide the public across the country with a series of colorful and diverse science popularization services. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 05:56:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 李希对古巴进行正式友好访问]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20230919_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, September 19, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20230919/1695067653793_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;September 16th to 18th, in Cuba The Communist Party of China invited Li Xi, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Secretary of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection, to pay an official goodwill visit to Cuba. This is September 16, local time. Li Xi met with First Secretary of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of Cuba and President of Cuba Díaz-Canel in Havana. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Ding Haitao&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Xinhua News Agency, Havana, September 18th&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;(Reporters Sun Yi, Lin Zhaohui) At the invitation of the Communist Party of Cuba, Li Xi, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Secretary of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection, paid an official goodwill visit to Cuba from September 16 to 18. He met with the First Secretary of the Central Committee of the Cuban Communist Party and President Díaz-Canel held talks with Morales, member of the Political Bureau of the Central Committee of the Cuban Communist Party and Secretary of the Central Organization, and visited General Raul Castro, the leader of the Cuban revolution. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When meeting with Díaz-Canel, Li Xi conveyed the cordial greetings from General Secretary Xi Jinping and congratulated Cuba on the complete success of the &quot;G77 and China&quot; Havana Summit. Li Xi said that after the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping met with you twice, pointing out the direction for the development of relations between the two parties and countries between China and Cuba. China is willing to work with Cuba to implement the important consensus reached by the top leaders of the two parties and two countries, carry out in-depth exchanges of experience in party and state governance and practical cooperation in various fields, continue to support each other on issues involving each other&#39;s core interests, and promote the construction of their respective parties and the development of socialist causes. . China is willing to work with Cuba to promote the implementation of global development initiatives, global security initiatives, and global civilization initiatives, and promote the building of a community with a shared future for mankind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Díaz-Canel asked Li Xi to convey his sincere greetings to General Secretary Xi Jinping, and warmly welcomed Li Xi to attend the summit as President Xi Jinping’s special representative and lead the CCP delegation to visit Cuba, expressing that China firmly cooperates with the &quot;global The countries of the &quot;South&quot; stand together and effectively safeguard the common interests of developing countries. Cuba thanks China for its assistance to Cuba&#39;s economic and social development and is willing to maintain close friendly exchanges with the Communist Party of China and promote practical cooperation. Cuba thanks China for its firm support for the Cuban people’s just struggle against unilateral blockade and sanctions, and its firm support for the major global initiatives proposed by General Secretary Xi Jinping. I wish the third “Belt and Road” International Cooperation Summit Forum a complete success. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When meeting with Morales, the two sides agreed to strengthen political mutual trust and strategic coordination, deepen practical cooperation in various fields, strengthen exchanges and mutual learning in state governance, and exchange and cooperation in party management and anti-corruption experience. The two sides also witnessed the signing of a memorandum of understanding on cooperation between the State Supervisory Commission of China and the General Accounting Office of Cuba. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When visiting Raul Castro, Li Xi conveyed the cordial greetings and best wishes from General Secretary Xi Jinping, saying that the traditional friendship between China and Cuba was personally forged and carefully cultivated by the older generation leaders of the two countries. Comrade Raul is a close friend of the Chinese party and people and has made historic contributions to the development of relations between the two parties and the two countries. Facing the complex and ever-changing international situation, China is willing to join hands with Cuba to build a China-Cuba community with a shared future. Raul asked Li Xi to convey his cordial greetings to General Secretary Xi Jinping and fondly recall his experience in interacting with Chinese comrades. Raúl said that Cuba is happy and inspired by the great achievements made in the cause of socialism with Chinese characteristics and is willing to learn from China&#39;s development experience. Raul also visited the Fidel Castro Center with Li Xi. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During his visit to Cuba, Li Xi introduced the CPC’s comprehensive and strict governance of the party and anti-corruption work under the strong leadership of General Secretary Xi Jinping and the Party Central Committee, pointing out the revolutionary significance of comprehensive and strict governance of the party in the new era. Forging, China has successfully embarked on a path of anti-corruption relying on the advantages of its system and the rule of law. The Communist Party of China has become stronger and more powerful, and has won the heartfelt support of the people. Cuba spoke highly of the remarkable achievements made by the Communist Party of China in party building and anti-corruption, and expressed its willingness to deepen experience exchanges with China in the fields of party management and discipline inspection and supervision. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Xi also laid a wreath at the Jose Martí Memorial and visited the Jose Martí Memorial Hall and the Frank Pais Agricultural Credit Union. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 05:56:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 加快产业转型升级  推动高质量发展（高质量发展调研行）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20230919_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, September 19, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Huatuo Road, Simiao Road, Shizhen Road... In Daxing, Beijing, roads named after famous doctors crisscross and interweave. An industrial park with an output value of 100 billion yuan - Zhongguancun Science and Technology Park Daxing Biopharmaceutical Industrial Base will be launched. Today, the base is moving towards building a “Chinese Medicine Valley” with international influence. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;0.01 mm! It&#39;s as thin as a cicada&#39;s wing, but it can withstand temperatures of thousands of degrees Celsius. The extreme ultra-thin optical glass developed by Hebei Qinhuangdao Xingjian Special Glass Co., Ltd. is widely used in the aerospace field and provides &quot;armor&quot; for the Shenzhou series spacecraft. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;No materials used in making clothes? Shandong Weihai Dishang Group is one of the largest clothing export companies in the country. Here, designing and making a sample garment does not require fabric procurement or actual sewing. It takes a few minutes to find suitable resources in the database, use 3D technology to perform virtual sewing, and a finished garment is ready. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The driverless bus moves forward steadily. The vehicle automatically accelerates, decelerates, changes lanes, turns, and makes a U-turn, and automatically stops when encountering red lights or obstacles. In the &quot;China Car Valley&quot; in Hubei Wuhan Economic and Technological Development Zone, &quot;smart cars&quot; cooperate with &quot;smart roads&quot;, and science fiction scenes become a reality...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;High-quality development is the primary task of building a modern socialist country in an all-round way . General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized that “we must unremittingly promote high-quality development, accelerate the transformation of economic development methods, accelerate industrial transformation and upgrading, accelerate the conversion of old and new driving forces, and promote economic development to achieve reasonable growth in quantity and steady improvement in quality.”&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;Walking around Beijing, Hebei, Shandong and Hubei, one can feel the unremitting efforts of “economic structure optimization” everywhere. All regions use transformation to tap potential, optimize to increase momentum, and upgrade to add vitality, achieve both quantity and quality improvements, and promote high-quality development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Be good at what you do and promote industrial transformation and upgrading&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Reduced development” has been a key word in Beijing’s development in recent years. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out that alleviating Beijing’s non-capital functions is the “narrow tip” of Beijing’s urban planning and construction. Implementing the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions, Beijing has worked hard to transform its driving force, innovate models, and improve its level, giving full play to its advantages in science and technology and talents, and striving to create a new highland for development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, Beijing has released the country&#39;s first list of new industries prohibited and restricted with the goal of curing &quot;big city diseases&quot;. It has withdrawn a total of about 3,000 general manufacturing and polluting companies, decentralizing and upgrading regional professional markets. and nearly 1,000 logistics centers. Using the space vacated by demolition and demolition, Beijing has left about 9,000 hectares of green space and built and upgraded more than 7,700 convenient service outlets. The decentralization has also brought about the optimization of the industrial structure, with the proportion of newly established business entities such as technology, commerce, culture, and information increasing from 40.7% in 2013 to 65.6% in 2022. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hebei and Shandong are both traditional industrial provinces. In recent years, the two provinces have focused on eliminating backward and excess production capacity, cultivating new economic growth points, and accelerating high-quality development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tangshan, Hebei was built because of coal and prospered because of steel. While eliminating backward production capacity, Tangshan is making every effort to build three pillars: new industry, large ports, and high technology, and accelerate the construction of a modern industrial system supported by high-quality steel, high-end equipment manufacturing, robots, new energy, new materials and other industries, and strive to promote The transformation and development of the old industrial city. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The changes in Tangshan are the epitome of Hebei&#39;s efforts to transform its energy structure that favors coal and its industrial structure that favors coal. At present, Hebei has exceeded the state&#39;s overcapacity reduction tasks in the six major industries of steel, coal, cement, flat glass, coke, and thermal power. On the other hand, Hebei has accelerated the planning and construction of a clean, efficient, and diversified support new energy system. In 2022, Hebei&#39;s total installed wind power and photovoltaic capacity will reach 66.52 million kilowatts, and newly installed pumped storage capacity will be 2.1 million kilowatts, gradually forming a new energy pattern with complementary multi-energy sources. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Six years ago, after the last batch of molten iron was produced, Jinan Iron and Steel Co., Ltd., which had been established for 59 years, suspended all steel production lines in Jinan, Shandong Province, becoming the first 10-million-ton city in the country to completely shut down its main steel industry. Steel companies. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Remove overcapacity, rather than “remove enterprises”. Over the past six years, Jinan Iron and Steel has actively explored a new development model of &quot;industry-city integration and cross-border integration&quot; to achieve Phoenix Nirvana. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;In 2021, Jigang&#39;s operating income will be 44.7 billion yuan, returning to the top 500 national enterprises; in 2022, it will achieve operating income of 46.6 billion yuan.&quot; Bo Tao, Secretary of the Party Committee and Chairman of Jigang Group Co., Ltd., said, Jinan Iron and Steel Group will focus on new generation information technology, intelligent manufacturing, modern services and other industrial fields to accelerate the realization of high-quality development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Hubei Xingfa Group Yichang New Materials Industrial Park, a round copper landmark on the riverside is engraved with a string of extraordinary numbers such as &quot;2018.4.24&quot;. From that day on, a major transformation began. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dismantle 32 chemical production units along the river, with a total asset value of nearly 1.4 billion yuan; block the sewage outlets and invest 1.2 billion yuan to build sewage treatment devices; a total investment of nearly 6 billion yuan to comprehensively promote the green transformation and upgrading of enterprises ... Over the past five years, Xingfa Group, a long-established chemical enterprise, has continuously improved the “green content” and “gold content” of corporate development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Transformation generates new momentum for development. Chen Xiaoqing, assistant general manager of Xingfa Group, said that the price of high-tech chemical products developed by the group can reach 5,000 yuan per gram, and the products have changed from &quot;sold by ton&quot; to &quot;sold by gram,&quot; achieving a win-win situation for economic growth and environmental improvement. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized at the symposium on promoting the development of the Yangtze River Economic Belt that “at present and for a long time to come, the restoration of the ecological environment of the Yangtze River must be placed in an overwhelming position, and joint efforts should be made to protect the Yangtze River and not to engage in large-scale Development.&quot; Changing methods, adjusting structure, and increasing momentum, Hubei has found a convergence between development and protection. In the first half of this year, Hubei&#39;s GDP reached 2,625.922 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 5.6%, showing a steady start, continued recovery, and steady improvement. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By &quot;breaking&quot; new space and &quot;establishing&quot; new advantages, the industrial structure of Beijing, Hebei, Shandong and Hubei is being optimized and the quality of development is improving. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Reform and innovation to realize the conversion of old and new driving forces&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shandong is a comprehensive experimental zone approved by the state for the conversion of old and new driving forces. Walking into the starting area for the conversion of old and new kinetic energy in Jinan, there is a busy construction scene. Not long ago, 33 key projects with a total investment of over 40 billion yuan were started here, covering advanced manufacturing, strategic emerging industries and other fields. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen Ying, general manager of Jinan Green Dynamic Hydrogen Energy Technology Co., Ltd., which was put into operation last year, told reporters: &quot;We chose the starting area because of its rich hydrogen energy application scenarios and the streamlined and efficient management to create a Good business environment.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May this year, the &quot;Implementation Plan for Deepening the Innovation and Improvement of Business Environment in Shandong Province&quot; was released. This is the fourth consecutive action to optimize the business environment released by Shandong since 2020. plan. &quot;We have proposed 170 specific reform measures in 20 areas to comprehensively build a more attractive and competitive business environment.&quot; said Zhang Chengjie, full-time deputy director of the Reform Office of the Shandong Provincial Party Committee. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The continuously optimized business environment is the &quot;dividing factor&quot; that removes obstacles to the development of business entities. With its two original biological drugs, Tatacept and Vidicitomab, Rongchang Biotech has reached the world&#39;s leading level in the field of antibody drug research and development. Looking back on the arduous journey of &quot;ten years of hard work&quot;, Chairman Wang Weidong said that on the road to innovation, he has always felt the government&#39;s sincerity in solving difficulties for operating entities. The continuous increase in the policy of super deduction of R&amp;D expenses demonstrates the country’s clear direction of encouraging and supporting scientific and technological innovation, and is a real support for innovative drug R&amp;D companies to ease financial pressure and increase R&amp;D efforts. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking at Yantai&#39;s high-end manufacturing industry, thanks to the excellent business environment and solid foundation, the biopharmaceutical industry represented by Rongchang Biotech is showing an exciting new scene: achievements in cutting-edge fields Several breakthroughs have been made, the industrial innovation ecology has been gradually optimized, and new space for development has been further opened. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The conversion of old and new driving forces has allowed Shandong’s economic structure to continue to be optimized and new advantages to be continuously strengthened. In the first half of this year, Shandong&#39;s province&#39;s GDP was 4,412.5 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 6.2%, and high-tech manufacturing investment increased by 27.7%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记指出，“以科技创新开辟发展新领域新赛道、塑造发展新动能新优势，是大势所趋，也是高质量发展的迫切要求，必须依靠创新特别是科技创新实现动力变革和动能转换。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在京津冀国家技术创新中心，一个个超级“种子”正在培育。据介绍，目前中心实施的前瞻性科创项目已达208项，其中约10%为世界首创或领先，139项已实现成果转化；培育硬科技企业105家，其中上市企业9家。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为全国科技创新中心，近年来，北京市研发经费投入强度保持在6%左右，位居国际创新城市前列，培育形成新一代信息技术产业和科技服务业两个万亿级产业集群，成为京津冀协同发展的创新引擎。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年上半年，北京大兴经济开发区“招大引强”迎来新突破。大兴经开区新增注册企业1089家，注册资金千万元及以上的298家，其中亿元企业14家；数字经济和科学技术服务类企业占比约60%。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;创新发展是爬坡过坎的关键。只有坚定不移深化改革，破除阻碍发展的体制机制障碍，加大对战略性新兴产业的扶持力度，才能发挥出创新驱动的“乘数效应”，推动高质量发展。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;位于石家庄鹿泉开发区的河北远东通信系统工程有限公司，近期投产了一条“高稳定度恒温晶体振荡器生产线”。该生产线是河北战略性新兴产业发展专项资金扶持项目，实现了高稳定度恒温晶振产品批量生产。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“恒温晶振是高端时频器件，广泛应用在5G移动通信、卫星导航等领域。”公司工程师张文平介绍，目前公司高端恒温晶振年产量超200万只，年出货量全球领先。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以新发展理念为引领，河北大力扶持以新一代信息技术、生物医药、空天技术为代表的战略性新兴产业，开辟发展新领域，塑造发展新动能。今年上半年，河北实现地区生产总值20778.9亿元，同比增长6.1%，第二、三产业成为全省经济增长的主要支撑。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;武汉东湖新技术开发区被誉为“中国光谷”，是国内最大的激光产业基地。 2022年6月，习近平总书记在湖北考察时指出，“湖北武汉东湖新技术开发区在光电子信息产业领域独树一帜。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三维五轴激光切割机，代表目前全球激光数控机床最高技术水平，是汽车制造的重要装备。近年来，华工科技等龙头企业开展协同创新，促成三维五轴数控系统、激光器和切割头“三大件”彻底摆脱进口依赖。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;协同创新突破一系列关键技术，为中国制造注入强劲动力。湖北乘势做强“光车联动”，擎起两大万亿产业集群，再次印证科技创新在发展中的“乘数因子”地位。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“光谷”向东，武汉拥抱鄂州、黄石、黄冈，共织“光芯屏端网”创新产业链，光纤光缆产量全球第一，光电器件、中小尺寸显示面板产量全国第一；“车谷”向西，武汉牵手襄阳、十堰、随州，同筑全国汽车发展高地，商用车和专用车产量均位居全国第一。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在高质量发展这场大考中，新旧动能转换是必答题。知重负重，知责担责，扛着使命奔跑，地方发展的热土上正奏响着创新创造的激昂旋律。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 行稳致远，更好惠及全体人民&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人民幸福安康是推动高质量发展的最终目的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记强调，“以推动高质量发展为主题，必须坚定不移贯彻新发展理念，以深化供给侧结构性改革为主线，坚持质量第一、效益优先，切实转变发展方式，推动质量变革、效率变革、动力变革，使发展成果更好惠及全体人民，不断实现人民对美好生活的向往。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;带动经济发展实现量质齐升，推动人民群众获得感、幸福感、安全感不断增强，是各地完整、准确、全面贯彻新发展理念的生动体现。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从2014年开始，石家庄市民王汝春每天在固定时间、地点拍摄城市同一片天空。 3000多张照片组成的“天空日记”里，从“雾霾锁城”到看见天际线，再到晴空万里成为常态，石家庄蓝天数量越来越多。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人不负青山，青山定不负人。 2022年，河北省PM2.5平均浓度36.8微克/立方米，为2013年有监测记录以来历史最好水平；今年上半年，全省空气优良比例为81.9%，同比提高3.9个百分点。全省森林覆盖率由2015年的31%提高到2022年的35.6%；全省地表水国考断面优良比例达到84.4%，Ⅴ类及以下断面首次清零。绿色发展，让广大人民群众共享蓝天、绿地、秀水。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;绿水青山就是金山银山。走进湖北宣恩县万寨乡伍家台村，漫山的茶园笼罩着薄雾，空气中弥漫着淡淡的茶香。 “伍家台有着2000多年的种茶历史，曾经老百姓守着&#39;绿叶子&#39;，过着紧日子，不少村民撂荒茶园外出务工，有的甚至准备毁掉茶园改种其他作物。”伍家台村党支部书记郑时兵回忆。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，伍家台村深度挖掘茶园自然观光、贡茶非遗技艺展演等，深化茶旅融合，让茶区变景区、采摘变体验，累计接待游客超300万人次，实现旅游综合收入6亿元。曾经籍籍无名的小山村，连续两届上榜“全国文明村”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以花为媒，以花兴城。山东菏泽着力推动牡丹“链”上生长，积极发展新技术、新产品、新业态，实现了从“一朵花”到“整个牡丹产业链”的“美丽蝶变”。 2022年，菏泽牡丹产业产值突破100亿元，带动10多万人就业，牡丹已成为菏泽开启乡村振兴的一把“金钥匙”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高品质生活离不开高品质产品。不久前，2023中国国际消费电子博览会在青岛开幕，海尔智家展区人潮涌动。透过现场展示的海尔三翼鸟全屋智慧全场景方案，人们不仅体验到了一系列高端科技产品，更感受到了定制化“智慧家”的便捷、温馨，发现了生活的新可能。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高品质生活更需要高品质服务。北运河畔，一座约128万平方米的“地下城”初现轮廓。这是正在建设的北京城市副中心站综合交通枢纽工程，预计2025年投入使用。据介绍，未来这里不只是京津冀交通换乘的枢纽，还将成为首都北京新门户、副中心活力商圈。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京城市副中心党工委委员、管委会副主任胡九龙说，“副中心的规划建设，始终坚持以人民为中心的发展思想，所有城市功能都是为了更好满足人民对美好生活的向往。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如今在北京，人们能体会到身边切切实实的变化——城市空间布局和经济结构优化提升，空气质量持续改善，居民生活环境更加优美……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;风劲好扬帆，奋进正当时。以习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想为指引，锚定高质量发展航向，中国经济航船一定能够乘风破浪、行稳致远，不断增进民生福祉、提高人民生活品质。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（本报记者张志锋、侯琳良、王昊男、潘俊强、史自强、范昊天、王洲、马原参与采写）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 05:56:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 我国成为世界最大船东国（新数据 新看点）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20230919_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月19日星期二&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报北京9月18日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者韩鑫）记者从北外滩国际航运论坛新闻发布会上获悉：目前，我国已与100多个国家和地区建立了航线联系，服务网络不断完善，海运连接度全球领先。我国船东拥有的船队规模达到2.492亿总吨，从总吨上成为世界最大船东国。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;作为综合交通运输体系的重要组成部分，航运业是服务经济社会发展和国家重大战略、助力实现中国式现代化的重要支撑。当前，全国水路货运量、货物周转量在综合交通运输体系中占比分别达到16.9%和53.5%。海运承担了我国约95%的对外贸易运输量，在保障粮食、能源资源等重点物资运输和国际国内物流供应链安全稳定畅通中发挥了重要作用。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;看港口货运量，我国港口货物吞吐量和集装箱吞吐量连续多年位居世界第一，全球货物和集装箱吞吐量排名前十的港口中，我国分别占8席和7席。2022年全国港口货物吞吐量达156.85亿吨，集装箱吞吐量2.96亿标箱。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;看内河货运量，我国内河货运量连续多年稳居世界第一，内河通航里程世界第一，长江干线连续多年成为全球内河运输最繁忙、运量最大的黄金水道。2022年我国内河运输完成货运量44.02亿吨、货物周转量1.9万亿吨公里，支撑服务保障区域经济发展能力显著增强。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;看智慧化发展，我国已建成自动化集装箱码头16座，在建10余座，已建和在建规模均居世界首位。目前，全国电子航道图发布里程超过5700公里，长江水系电子航道图干支联通持续推进，航道运行监测、梯级船闸联合调度、服务区功能提升等数字化、智能化转型发展加快。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 05:56:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 在中国式现代化进程中共同创造残疾人更加幸福美好的生活]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20230919_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月19日星期二&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;各位代表，同志们：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国残疾人联合会第八次全国代表大会今天隆重开幕了。我受习近平总书记委托，代表党中央和国务院，向大会召开表示热烈祝贺！向全国广大残疾人、残疾人亲友、残疾人工作者致以亲切问候！向关心支持残疾人事业的社会各界人士表示衷心感谢！&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;党的十八大以来，中国特色社会主义进入新时代。以习近平同志为核心的党中央团结带领全国各族人民完成脱贫攻坚、全面建成小康社会的历史任务，实现第一个百年奋斗目标，党和国家事业取得历史性成就、发生历史性变革，推动我国迈上全面建设社会主义现代化国家新征程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在党中央坚强领导下，新时代十年我国残疾人事业开创了蓬勃发展的新局面，广大残疾人生活全面改善，获得感、幸福感、安全感显著增强，如期实现“全面建成小康社会，残疾人一个也不能少”的目标。我们坚持精准扶贫、尽锐出战，在脱贫攻坚中把残疾人作为“群体攻坚的重点”，710多万农村贫困残疾人实现整体脱贫，彻底改变了千百年来残疾人与贫困相伴相随的不幸命运。我们强化兜底保障、全面覆盖，在实施普惠保障的基础上，建立了困难残疾人生活补贴、重度残疾人护理补贴、残疾儿童康复救助等专项保障制度，惠及2000多万残疾人。我们注重统筹规划、兼顾特性，着力解决残疾人急难愁盼问题，不断满足残疾人康复、教育、就业、文化生活等需求，显著提升残疾人健康、教育水平和生活质量。我们倡导平等参与、融合发展，成功举办北京2022年冬残奥会，实施无障碍环境建设法，开展形式多样的扶残助残文明实践活动，不断汇聚向上向善的积极力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些成绩的取得，充分体现了中国共产党领导和中国特色社会主义制度的巨大优势，充分体现了我国综合国力和人权保障事业的显著进步，得到了国际社会的普遍赞誉！&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些成绩的取得，根本在于有以习近平同志为核心的党中央坚强领导，有习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想的科学指引。新时代以来，习近平总书记对残疾人事业发展作出一系列重要论述和重要指示批示，为残疾人事业发展指明了前进方向、提供了根本遵循。习近平总书记对残疾人这一特殊困难群体始终牵挂在心、念兹在兹，多次亲切看望慰问残疾人，为残疾人自强拼搏的奋斗精神点赞，激励广大残疾人勇敢迎接生活挑战、努力实现人生梦想，给广大残疾人极大的温暖和鼓舞。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国残疾人联合会第七次全国代表大会以来，各级残联组织认真学习贯彻习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想，深入贯彻落实党中央和国务院决策部署，紧紧围绕党和国家工作大局，助力打赢贫困残疾人脱贫攻坚战，着力提升残疾人保障和发展水平，切实维护残疾人合法权益，积极开展国际交流合作，扎实推进党的建设和自身改革，团结引领广大残疾人听党话、感党恩、跟党走，政治性、先进性、群众性不断增强，“代表、服务、管理”职能有效发挥。广大残疾人工作者密切联系、热忱服务，努力为残疾人排忧解难，给残疾人带来更多希望。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;广大残疾人以梦想为伴、与时代同行，用顽强奋斗把一个个美好梦想变成现实，在逆境向前中绽放自己的光彩，以实际行动生动诠释了自强不息的伟大民族精神和时代精神！&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;党的二十大描绘了以中国式现代化全面推进强国建设、民族复兴的宏伟蓝图，对完善残疾人社会保障制度和关爱服务体系、促进残疾人事业全面发展提出了明确要求。在中国式现代化进程中促进残疾人事业全面发展，不断创造残疾人更加幸福美好的生活，是新时代新征程中国特色残疾人事业的鲜明主题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;促进残疾人事业全面发展，必须坚持以习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想为指导。习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想是党和国家必须长期坚持的指导思想。新征程上，我们要认真学习贯彻这一重要思想，深刻领悟“两个确立”的决定性意义，坚决做到“两个维护”，始终坚持党对残疾人事业的领导，全面贯彻落实习近平总书记对残疾人事业发展作出的重要论述和重要指示批示精神，以新思想引领残疾人事业新发展，以新发展满足残疾人生活新期待。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;促进残疾人事业全面发展，必须牢牢把握平等、融合、共享的价值导向。残疾人是社会大家庭的平等成员，是坚持和发展中国特色社会主义的一支重要力量，有志向、有能力为强国建设、民族复兴作出贡献。残疾人也是一个特殊困难群体，需要格外关心、格外关注。要坚持人民至上，大力弘扬人道主义精神，帮助残疾人创造更多发展条件，提供人生出彩机会，更好保障残疾人平等权利，实现残疾人共享经济社会发展成果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;促进残疾人事业全面发展，必须牢牢把握推进残疾人事业现代化的历史使命。残疾人事业是中国特色社会主义事业的重要组成部分，全面建设社会主义现代化国家，残疾人事业也要现代化，14亿多人口整体迈向现代化，残疾人不能掉队。要统筹把握中国式现代化进程中残疾人事业发展的新目标新任务新要求，不断加强残疾人社会保障和公共服务，使残疾人跟上现代化前进步伐。立足中国国情，学习借鉴国际先进经验，贡献更多残疾人事务治理的中国方案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;促进残疾人事业全面发展，必须牢牢把握推进残疾人共同富裕的目标任务。中国式现代化是全体人民共同富裕的现代化，推进全体人民共同富裕，残疾人是特别需要关注的群体。要完整准确全面贯彻新发展理念，推动残疾人事业高质量发展，积极拓展残疾人家庭就业增收渠道，加快健全兜底性、基础性残疾人社会福利制度，着力提高残疾人康复、教育、文化体育、托养照护、无障碍等服务质量，不断提高残疾人生活品质。着力巩固拓展残疾人脱贫攻坚成果，推动农村残疾人事业与乡村振兴有效衔接。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;让广大残疾人过上幸福美好的生活，是我们党全心全意为人民服务宗旨的重要体现，是我国社会主义制度的必然要求。各级党委和政府要进一步健全党委领导、政府负责的残疾人事业领导体制，各级政府残工委要发挥牵头作用，加强统筹协调，推动解决残疾人事业发展中的重大问题。有关部门要各负其责、密切配合，切实执行和落实好助残优惠政策，共同做好残疾人工作。工会、共青团、妇联等人民团体要发挥各自优势，多为残疾职工、残疾青年、残疾妇女、残疾儿童做雪中送炭的事。各类基层组织要落实好各项残疾人工作，提升为残疾人服务的水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;残疾人事业是需要全社会共同努力、合力推进的光荣事业。要继承发扬中华民族扶弱济困、守望相助的优良传统，积极践行社会主义核心价值观，把平等对待作为最好的关爱，把促进自立作为最好的扶助，消除有形无形的障碍和歧视，营造全社会理解、尊重、关心、帮助残疾人的浓厚氛围和良好环境。要凝聚社会各方力量，培育助残社会组织，发展残疾人公益慈善事业，广泛开展志愿助残服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;残联组织是党和政府联系残疾人的桥梁纽带。要把加强党的全面领导贯穿残联各项工作全过程，坚持不懈用习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想凝心铸魂，深刻领悟“两个确立”的决定性意义，增强“四个意识”、坚定“四个自信”、做到“两个维护”。牢记初心使命，心系“国之大者”，认真履行“代表、服务、管理”职能，把实现好、维护好、发展好广大残疾人的根本利益作为残疾人工作的出发点和落脚点，不断提升残疾人组织综合服务能力，解决好残疾人急难愁盼问题，坚决同侵害残疾人合法权益的现象做斗争，把党和政府的温暖及时传递给残疾人，做残疾人的知心人、贴心人。要持之以恒推进全面从严治党，深化残联改革，打造高素质残疾人工作者队伍，把残联组织建设得更接地气、更有能力、更具活力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新时代是奋斗者的时代，新征程是追梦者的远征。希望广大残疾人继续发扬自尊、自信、自强、自立精神，乐观向上、拼搏有为，在强国建设、民族复兴的伟大进程中尽展聪明才智、实现人生梦想，同全国人民一道共创更加幸福美好的生活。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;各位代表、同志们，让我们更加紧密地团结在以习近平同志为核心的党中央周围，为全面推进强国建设、民族复兴伟业而共同奋斗！&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（新华社北京9月18日电）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 05:56:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - “天宫课堂”第四课即将开课]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20230919_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月19日星期二&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报北京9月18日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者刘诗瑶）记者从中国载人航天工程办公室获悉：“天宫课堂”第四课定于9月21日15时45分开课，神舟十六号航天员景海鹏、朱杨柱、桂海潮将面向全国青少年进行太空科普授课。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;据介绍，本次太空授课活动继续采取天地互动方式进行。3名航天员将在轨展示介绍中国空间站梦天实验舱工作生活场景，演示球形火焰实验、奇妙“乒乓球”实验、动量守恒实验以及“又见陀螺”实验，并与地面课堂进行互动交流。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;空间站作为国家太空实验室，承担着重要的科普教育职能。空间站任务以来，神舟十三号、神舟十四号乘组先后3次面向广大青少年开展“天宫课堂”太空授课活动，社会反响热烈，为我国科普教育工作作出重要贡献。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;神舟十六号航天员诚邀广大青少年在地面同步尝试开展相关实验，从天地实验差异中感知宇宙奥秘、体验探索乐趣。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 05:56:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 加快产业转型升级  推动高质量发展（高质量发展调研行）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20230919_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月19日星期二&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;华佗路、思邈路、时珍路……北京大兴，以名医命名的道路纵横交错，交织出一个千亿元级产值规模的产业园——中关村科技园区大兴生物医药产业基地。如今，该基地正向建设具有国际影响力的“中国药谷”迈进。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;0.01毫米！薄如蝉翼，却耐得住上千摄氏度高温。河北秦皇岛星箭特种玻璃有限公司研制的极限超薄光学玻璃，被广泛应用在航空航天领域，为神舟系列飞船穿上“铠甲”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;制衣不用料？山东威海迪尚集团，全国最大的服装出口企业之一。在这里，设计制作一件样衣无需面料采购、实际缝制。花几分钟，在数据库中找到合适的资源，用3D技术进行虚拟缝制，一件成衣就打样完成。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无人驾驶巴士稳稳前行，车辆自动加速、减速、变道、转弯、掉头，遇到红灯或障碍物会自动停车。在湖北武汉经开区“中国车谷”，“聪明的车”配合“智慧的路”，科幻场景成为现实……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高质量发展是全面建设社会主义现代化国家的首要任务。习近平总书记强调，“要坚持不懈推动高质量发展，加快转变经济发展方式，加快产业转型升级，加快新旧动能转换，推动经济发展实现量的合理增长和质的稳步提升。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;行走在京冀鲁鄂，时时处处感受到“经济结构优化”的不懈努力。各地以转型挖潜力、优化增动力、升级添活力，实现量质齐升，推动高质量发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 善作善成，推动产业转型升级&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“减量发展”，是近年来北京发展的一个关键词。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记指出，疏解北京非首都功能是北京城市规划建设的“牛鼻子”。落实习近平总书记重要指示精神，北京在转变动力、创新模式、提升水平上下功夫，发挥科技和人才优势，努力打造发展新高地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，北京发布全国首个以治理“大城市病”为目标的新增产业禁限目录，累计退出一般制造和污染企业约3000家，疏解和升级区域性专业市场和物流中心近1000个。利用拆违腾退空间，北京留白增绿约9000公顷，建设提升便民服务网点7700余个。疏解更带来了产业结构的优化，科技、商务、文化、信息等新设经营主体占比由2013年的40.7%上升至2022年的65.6%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;河北、山东，都是传统工业大省。近年来，两省着力淘汰落后和过剩产能，培育新的经济增长点，跑出高质量发展的加速度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;河北唐山因煤而建、因钢而兴。唐山在淘汰落后产能的同时，全力打造新工业、大港口、高科技三大支柱，加快构建以精品钢铁、高端装备制造、机器人、新能源、新材料等产业为支撑的现代化产业体系，奋力推动工业老城转型发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;唐山之变，正是河北着力转变偏煤的能源结构、偏重的产业结构的缩影。目前，河北已超额完成国家下达的钢铁、煤炭、水泥、平板玻璃、焦炭、火电六大行业去产能任务；另一方面，加快规划建设清洁高效、多元支撑的新型能源体系。2022年，河北风电光伏总装机量达6652万千瓦，新增抽水蓄能装机210万千瓦，逐步形成多能互补的能源新格局。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;6年前，出完最后一炉铁水，建厂59年的济钢在山东济南的钢铁生产线全线停产，成为全国首家全面关停钢铁主业的千万吨级城市钢企。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去产能，而不是“去企业”。6年来，济钢积极探索“产城融合、跨界融合”的发展新模式，实现凤凰涅槃。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“2021年，济钢营业收入447亿元，重返全国企业500强；2022年实现营业收入466亿元。”济钢集团有限公司党委书记、董事长薄涛表示，济钢集团将聚焦新一代信息技术、智能制造、现代服务等产业领域，加速实现高质量发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;湖北兴发集团宜昌新材料产业园，江边一块铜铸的圆形地标上镌刻着“2018.4.24”这样一串意义非凡的数字。从那天起，一场重大转型开始了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拆除沿江化工生产装置32套，总资产价值近14亿元；封堵排污口，投资12亿元建污水处理装置；总投入近60亿元，全面推动企业绿色转型升级……5年来，老牌化工企业兴发集团不断提升企业发展的“含绿量”和“含金量”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;转型催生发展新动能。兴发集团总经理助理陈晓清表示，目前集团开发的高科技化工产品每克价格可达5000元，产品从“论吨卖”变成了“论克卖”，经济增长和环境改善实现双赢。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记在推动长江经济带发展座谈会上强调，“当前和今后相当长一个时期，要把修复长江生态环境摆在压倒性位置，共抓大保护，不搞大开发。”转方式、调结构、增动能，在发展和保护之间，湖北找到契合点。今年上半年，湖北实现生产总值26259.22亿元，同比增长5.6%，呈现平稳开局、持续恢复、稳健向好态势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“破”出新空间，“立”出新优势，京冀鲁鄂四地的产业结构在优化、发展质量在提高。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 改革创新，实现新旧动能转换&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;山东是国家批复的新旧动能转换综合试验区。走进济南新旧动能转换起步区，一派繁忙建设景象。前不久，总投资超400亿元的33个重点项目在这里集中开工，覆盖先进制造业、战略性新兴产业等多个领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年投产的济南绿动氢能科技有限公司总经理陈颖告诉记者：“我们选择落地起步区，看中的就是这里丰富的氢能应用场景，以及精简高效管理营造的良好营商环境。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年5月，《山东省深化营商环境创新提升行动实施方案》发布，这是山东自2020年以来连续发布的第四个优化营商环境行动方案。“我们在20个领域提出170条具体改革措施，全面建设更具吸引力、竞争力的营商环境。”山东省委改革办专职副主任张成杰说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;持续优化的营商环境，是扫除经营主体发展障碍的“除法因子”。凭借泰它西普、维迪西妥单抗两款原创性生物药物，荣昌生物在抗体药物研发领域达到世界领先水平。回顾“十年磨一药”的艰辛历程，董事长王威东表示，创新之路上一直感受到政府为经营主体解决困难的真心实意。研发费用加计扣除政策的不断加码，彰显了国家鼓励、支持科技创新的鲜明导向，对创新药物研发企业缓解资金压力、加大研发力度是一个实实在在的支撑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;放眼烟台高端制造业，得益于优良的营商环境、雄厚的基础底蕴，以荣昌生物为代表的生物医药产业正展露出令人充满期待的新景象：前沿领域取得若干突破，产业创新生态逐步优化，发展新空间进一步被打开。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新旧动能转换，让山东经济结构持续优化，新优势不断塑强。今年上半年，山东全省生产总值44125亿元，同比增长6.2%，高技术制造业投资增长27.7%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记指出，“以科技创新开辟发展新领域新赛道、塑造发展新动能新优势，是大势所趋，也是高质量发展的迫切要求，必须依靠创新特别是科技创新实现动力变革和动能转换。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在京津冀国家技术创新中心，一个个超级“种子”正在培育。据介绍，目前中心实施的前瞻性科创项目已达208项，其中约10%为世界首创或领先，139项已实现成果转化；培育硬科技企业105家，其中上市企业9家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为全国科技创新中心，近年来，北京市研发经费投入强度保持在6%左右，位居国际创新城市前列，培育形成新一代信息技术产业和科技服务业两个万亿级产业集群，成为京津冀协同发展的创新引擎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年上半年，北京大兴经济开发区“招大引强”迎来新突破。大兴经开区新增注册企业1089家，注册资金千万元及以上的298家，其中亿元企业14家；数字经济和科学技术服务类企业占比约60%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;创新发展是爬坡过坎的关键。只有坚定不移深化改革，破除阻碍发展的体制机制障碍，加大对战略性新兴产业的扶持力度，才能发挥出创新驱动的“乘数效应”，推动高质量发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;位于石家庄鹿泉开发区的河北远东通信系统工程有限公司，近期投产了一条“高稳定度恒温晶体振荡器生产线”。该生产线是河北战略性新兴产业发展专项资金扶持项目，实现了高稳定度恒温晶振产品批量生产。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“恒温晶振是高端时频器件，广泛应用在5G移动通信、卫星导航等领域。”公司工程师张文平介绍，目前公司高端恒温晶振年产量超200万只，年出货量全球领先。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以新发展理念为引领，河北大力扶持以新一代信息技术、生物医药、空天技术为代表的战略性新兴产业，开辟发展新领域，塑造发展新动能。今年上半年，河北实现地区生产总值20778.9亿元，同比增长6.1%，第二、三产业成为全省经济增长的主要支撑。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;武汉东湖新技术开发区被誉为“中国光谷”，是国内最大的激光产业基地。2022年6月，习近平总书记在湖北考察时指出，“湖北武汉东湖新技术开发区在光电子信息产业领域独树一帜。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;三维五轴激光切割机，代表目前全球激光数控机床最高技术水平，是汽车制造的重要装备。近年来，华工科技等龙头企业开展协同创新，促成三维五轴数控系统、激光器和切割头“三大件”彻底摆脱进口依赖。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;协同创新突破一系列关键技术，为中国制造注入强劲动力。湖北乘势做强“光车联动”，擎起两大万亿产业集群，再次印证科技创新在发展中的“乘数因子”地位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“光谷”向东，武汉拥抱鄂州、黄石、黄冈，共织“光芯屏端网”创新产业链，光纤光缆产量全球第一，光电器件、中小尺寸显示面板产量全国第一；“车谷”向西，武汉牵手襄阳、十堰、随州，同筑全国汽车发展高地，商用车和专用车产量均位居全国第一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在高质量发展这场大考中，新旧动能转换是必答题。知重负重，知责担责，扛着使命奔跑，地方发展的热土上正奏响着创新创造的激昂旋律。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 行稳致远，更好惠及全体人民&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人民幸福安康是推动高质量发展的最终目的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记强调，“以推动高质量发展为主题，必须坚定不移贯彻新发展理念，以深化供给侧结构性改革为主线，坚持质量第一、效益优先，切实转变发展方式，推动质量变革、效率变革、动力变革，使发展成果更好惠及全体人民，不断实现人民对美好生活的向往。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;带动经济发展实现量质齐升，推动人民群众获得感、幸福感、安全感不断增强，是各地完整、准确、全面贯彻新发展理念的生动体现。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从2014年开始，石家庄市民王汝春每天在固定时间、地点拍摄城市同一片天空。3000多张照片组成的“天空日记”里，从“雾霾锁城”到看见天际线，再到晴空万里成为常态，石家庄蓝天数量越来越多。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人不负青山，青山定不负人。2022年，河北省PM2.5平均浓度36.8微克/立方米，为2013年有监测记录以来历史最好水平；今年上半年，全省空气优良比例为81.9%，同比提高3.9个百分点。全省森林覆盖率由2015年的31%提高到2022年的35.6%；全省地表水国考断面优良比例达到84.4%，Ⅴ类及以下断面首次清零。绿色发展，让广大人民群众共享蓝天、绿地、秀水。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;绿水青山就是金山银山。走进湖北宣恩县万寨乡伍家台村，漫山的茶园笼罩着薄雾，空气中弥漫着淡淡的茶香。“伍家台有着2000多年的种茶历史，曾经老百姓守着&#39;绿叶子&#39;，过着紧日子，不少村民撂荒茶园外出务工，有的甚至准备毁掉茶园改种其他作物。”伍家台村党支部书记郑时兵回忆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，伍家台村深度挖掘茶园自然观光、贡茶非遗技艺展演等，深化茶旅融合，让茶区变景区、采摘变体验，累计接待游客超300万人次，实现旅游综合收入6亿元。曾经籍籍无名的小山村，连续两届上榜“全国文明村”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以花为媒，以花兴城。山东菏泽着力推动牡丹“链”上生长，积极发展新技术、新产品、新业态，实现了从“一朵花”到“整个牡丹产业链”的“美丽蝶变”。2022年，菏泽牡丹产业产值突破100亿元，带动10多万人就业，牡丹已成为菏泽开启乡村振兴的一把“金钥匙”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高品质生活离不开高品质产品。不久前，2023中国国际消费电子博览会在青岛开幕，海尔智家展区人潮涌动。透过现场展示的海尔三翼鸟全屋智慧全场景方案，人们不仅体验到了一系列高端科技产品，更感受到了定制化“智慧家”的便捷、温馨，发现了生活的新可能。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;高品质生活更需要高品质服务。北运河畔，一座约128万平方米的“地下城”初现轮廓。这是正在建设的北京城市副中心站综合交通枢纽工程，预计2025年投入使用。据介绍，未来这里不只是京津冀交通换乘的枢纽，还将成为首都北京新门户、副中心活力商圈。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;北京城市副中心党工委委员、管委会副主任胡九龙说，“副中心的规划建设，始终坚持以人民为中心的发展思想，所有城市功能都是为了更好满足人民对美好生活的向往。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如今在北京，人们能体会到身边切切实实的变化——城市空间布局和经济结构优化提升，空气质量持续改善，居民生活环境更加优美……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;风劲好扬帆，奋进正当时。以习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想为指引，锚定高质量发展航向，中国经济航船一定能够乘风破浪、行稳致远，不断增进民生福祉、提高人民生活品质。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（本报记者张志锋、侯琳良、王昊男、潘俊强、史自强、范昊天、王洲、马原参与采写）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 05:56:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 李希对古巴进行正式友好访问]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20230919_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月19日星期二&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20230919/1695067653793_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;9月16日至18日，应古巴共产党邀请，中共中央政治局常委、中央纪委书记李希对古巴进行正式友好访问。这是当地时间9月16日，李希在哈瓦那会见古共中央第一书记、古巴国家主席迪亚斯—卡内尔。&lt;BR/>;新华社记者丁海涛摄&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;新华社哈瓦那9月18日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者孙奕、林朝晖）应古巴共产党邀请，中共中央政治局常委、中央纪委书记李希9月16日至18日对古巴进行正式友好访问，在哈瓦那会见古共中央第一书记、国家主席迪亚斯—卡内尔，同古共中央政治局委员、中央组织书记莫拉莱斯举行会谈，看望古巴革命领导人劳尔·卡斯特罗大将。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会见迪亚斯—卡内尔时，李希转达习近平总书记的亲切问候，祝贺古方举办“77国集团和中国”哈瓦那峰会取得圆满成功。李希表示，中共二十大后，习近平总书记同你两次会晤，为中古两党两国关系发展指明方向。中方愿同古方落实好两党两国最高领导人重要共识，深入开展治党治国经验交流和各领域务实合作，继续在涉及彼此核心利益问题上相互支持，推动各自党的建设和社会主义事业发展。中方愿同古方推动全球发展倡议、全球安全倡议、全球文明倡议落地落实，推动构建人类命运共同体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;迪亚斯—卡内尔请李希转达对习近平总书记的诚挚问候，热烈欢迎李希作为习近平主席特别代表出席峰会并率中共代表团访古，表示中国坚定同“全球南方”国家站在一起，有力维护了发展中国家共同利益。古方感谢中方对古经济社会发展提供帮助，愿同中国共产党密切友好往来，推进务实合作。古方感谢中方坚定支持古巴人民反对单边封锁制裁的正义斗争，坚定支持习近平总书记提出的重大全球倡议。预祝第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛圆满成功。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同莫拉莱斯会谈时，双方同意加强政治互信和战略协作，深化各领域务实合作，加强治国理政交流互鉴和管党治党、反腐败经验交流与合作。双方还共同见证了中国国家监委和古巴总审计署签署合作谅解备忘录。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;看望劳尔·卡斯特罗时，李希转达了习近平总书记的亲切问候和良好祝愿，表示中古传统友谊是两国老一辈领导人亲手缔结并精心培育的。劳尔同志是中国党和人民的亲密朋友，为两党两国关系发展作出了历史性贡献。面对复杂多变的国际形势，中方愿同古方携手共建中古命运共同体。劳尔请李希转达对习近平总书记的亲切问候，深情回忆与中国同志交往经历。劳尔表示，古方为中国特色社会主义事业取得巨大成就感到高兴和鼓舞，愿借鉴中国发展经验。劳尔还和李希一同参观了菲德尔·卡斯特罗中心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;访古期间，李希介绍了在习近平总书记和党中央坚强领导下，中国共产党全面从严治党和反腐败工作情况，指出经过新时代全面从严治党的革命性锻造，中国成功走出了一条依靠制度优势、法治优势反腐败之路，中国共产党更加坚强有力，赢得了人民群众衷心拥护。古方高度评价中国共产党在党建、反腐败等方面取得显著成效，表示愿同中方深化管党治党、纪检监察领域经验交流。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李希还向何塞·马蒂纪念碑敬献花圈，参观了何塞·马蒂纪念馆和弗兰克·派斯农业信用合作社。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 05:56:08 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 图片报道]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20230919_5-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月19日星期二&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20230919/1695067946289_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;9月17日，湖北省宜昌市“一江两岸”污水厂网新建、改扩建项目大公桥调蓄池正在施工。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;近年来，宜昌等长江沿岸城市加紧水环境综合整治工程建设，通过城镇污水治理、岸线生态修复、兴建“公园式”污水处理厂、城市智慧管网管控、补齐雨水污水管网短板等措施，全链条推进城市水环境治理。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;新华社记者&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;肖艺九摄&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 19 Sep 2023 05:56:08 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>