<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 时时放心不下的牵挂]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/12/nw.D110000renmrb_20231112_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Sunday, November 12, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;This uneasy concern has always been lingering in the mind of General Secretary Xi Jinping. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the end of July and early August this year, extreme rainfall occurred in North China, Huanghuai and other places, causing floods and geological disasters, causing heavy casualties in Beijing, Hebei and other places. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping pays close attention to the flood situation, attaches great importance to flood prevention and relief work, and has issued important instructions on many occasions, demanding that all efforts be made to ensure the safety of people&#39;s lives and property. &quot;During that time, I paid attention to the disaster every day and guided the relief work. I was always thinking about the disaster-stricken areas and the affected people.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On September 7, General Secretary Xi Jinping, who was inspecting Heilongjiang, came to Longwangmiao Village, Laojieji Township, Shangzhi City, Harbin, which was severely affected by the disaster, visited and expressed condolences to the victims and learned about the progress of post-disaster recovery and reconstruction. Talking about North China from the Northeast, the General Secretary said: &quot;I am concerned about the disaster-stricken places. I will also visit those places in the future.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On November 10, as winter entered the north, General Secretary Xi Jinping made a special trip He came to Beijing, Mentougou District, Hebei Province, and Zhuozhou City, Baoding, which were hit hard by the disaster, to visit and express condolences to the victims, and to inspect and guide post-disaster recovery and reconstruction work. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In one day, by bus and train, the journey spanned Beijing and Hebei, covering rural areas, communities, schools, municipal facilities, water conservancy projects, visiting residents, meeting teachers and students, visiting shops, and entering farmers&#39; households. , enter the wheat fields, go up the embankment, brave the severe cold, and return in the dark night. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Walking along, hearing and seeing, I feel at ease and relieved that the recovery and reconstruction work is proceeding as planned.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We must continue to restore and rebuild after the disaster. Implement the work one by one, and continue to work hard to push people&#39;s lives in a better direction, so that the people will live a better life in the future!&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&quot;I have always been thinking about the disaster area. &quot;People&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shuiyuzui Village in Miaofengshan Town is located in the mountainous area in the west of Beijing, with the Yongding River winding through the north of the village. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the morning of the 10th, General Secretary Xi Jinping drove through Shuiyuzui Bridge and got off at the entrance of the village. The photos on the display board on the shore record the scene when the floods were raging this summer and the peak of the flood passed through. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The place where we are standing now was flooded. The water overflowed the bridge deck of Shuiyuzui Bridge.” The local responsible comrade told the general secretary that due to the timely transfer, no one in the village was injured. There were casualties, but 87% of the houses were damaged. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;How is the recovery going?&quot; asked the general secretary. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“All the damaged houses have been repaired.” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Along the village road, the general secretary walked to inspect the appearance of the village. The roads are clean and the houses are in good repair. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Villager Li Meng&#39;s house is right on the roadside, and a sign hangs on the wall at the door: &quot;The submerged water depth is 2.6 meters.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Walking into Li Meng’s house, General Secretary Xi Jinping inspected it carefully. The walls have been painted, and there are no traces of flooding. The doors, windows, furniture, and electrical appliances on the first floor have also been newly replaced. The sun shines through the glass into the two-story building, making it bright. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Meng told the General Secretary that the flood flooded the first floor and the whole house was filled with mud. After the disaster, the government provided subsidies and the family worked together to restore and repair the house. It has now been tidied up. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The Communist Party is a party that serves the people. Now that our country&#39;s economic strength has increased, we must do more for the people. I wish you a happier life.&quot; said the general secretary. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Just after the beginning of winter, the lowest temperature in the land of Yanzhao was already below zero degrees Celsius. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of the 10th, General Secretary Xi Jinping came to Yongji Xiuyuan Community, Shuangta Street, Zhuozhou, which was severely affected by the disaster, and first inspected the thermal station here. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Learning that the community had started heating half a month in advance on November 1, the General Secretary was very happy: &quot;This is what should be done, you have done a good job!&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping The general secretary then visited the home of Dong Caiying, a resident of the community. Her family lives on the first floor. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As soon as I entered the house, I felt the warmth. After looking at the thermometer and touching the radiator, the General Secretary smiled and said: &quot;The temperature has reached the standard.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pointing to the water stains on the white wall, Dong Caiying told the General Secretary that there was also a storm at home at that time. Furniture, appliances and some clothes and bedding were flooded. Now, with the help of party members and cadres, the house has been cleaned and repaired, and it will be warm for the winter. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I am very gratified to see that you have turned the corner and that after the disaster, life can continue as usual, but also improve a little bit.” said the general secretary. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wanquanzhuang Village, Diaowo Town, Zhuozhou City is located in the Langouwa flood storage and detention area. During this year’s flood season, all 311 households in the village were affected, and many houses were washed down or seriously damaged. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When General Secretary Xi Jinping came to the village on the afternoon of the 10th, he saw a scene of construction in full swing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The newly built house of villager Fu Jun’s family is about to be topped out. He enthusiastically welcomed the General Secretary into his future new home and introduced the internal structure of the house in detail: &quot;These are the four bedrooms in Chaoyang, this is the kitchen, and the bathroom is over there...&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fu Jun told the General Secretary , after the house was hit by the disaster, I quickly received the farm house insurance claim, and there were subsidies for steel bars, sand, cement and other building materials. The government also provided guarantees and contacted the construction team, and I made up my mind to rebuild as soon as possible. &quot;The party&#39;s policies are good. We must catch up with this good era, otherwise we will not be able to build it.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When leaving the village, the villagers gathered on both sides of the village road. There were white-haired old people and children. Applause warmly and greet the General Secretary loudly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The general secretary and fellow villagers said: &quot;I have always been thinking about the people in the disaster area. Today, I came here to take a look, and I feel at ease. The policies of the Party Central Committee have been translated into practical measures in various places. It works.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After hearing the general secretary&#39;s words, everyone applauded again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The general secretary continued: &quot;I see hope from everyone&#39;s expressions. Our life after the disaster will be better than before. I hope that the villagers will be self-reliant, work hard, and use their hard-working hands to speed up recovery and reconstruction.&quot; , promote rural revitalization.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&quot;After major floods, we must build and improve&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On August 17 this year, during the flood prevention and relief As the struggle achieved major phased results, General Secretary Xi Jinping presided over a meeting of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and proposed that we should carefully investigate and summarize, work hard to make up for shortcomings and strengths and weaknesses, and further enhance our country&#39;s disaster prevention, reduction, and relief capabilities. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With this thought in mind, General Secretary Xi Jinping’s first stop during this inspection came to the Sanjiadian water diversion hub located at the exit of the Guanting Gorge of the Yongding River. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Through this control project, the Yongding River flows from the undulating mountainous area into the main urban area of ​​Beijing, which is a vast plain. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing suffered extremely heavy rainfall this summer, and the Yongding River also experienced a rare flood peak. The responsible comrade of the Beijing Municipal Water Affairs Bureau said that at that time, the maximum water storage level of the regulating pool of the Sanjiadian Water Diversion Hub had exceeded 110 meters, the floodwaters had overflowed ashore, and the barrage had opened its largest flood discharge since it was built. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the floods this summer, Beijing City, in its post-disaster recovery and reconstruction work, based on root causes, focused on strengthening the construction of the flood control engineering system, and formulated relevant master plans, ranging from river dredging and repair, dam hazard removal and reinforcement, layout and construction Reservoirs, etc., are committed to achieving the goal of “basic recovery in one year, comprehensive improvement in three years, and long-term high-quality development”. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping said that after a disaster, we must sum up experience and draw inferences from one example so that we can have more complete plans and better measures in disaster prevention, reduction, and relief. Our current national and economic strength has also increased, and we must use stronger power to solve this problem. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the floods occurred, the cadres and the masses in North China seized the &quot;window period&quot; and carried out self-rescue in agricultural production. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While inspecting Zhuozhou, General Secretary Xi Jinping got off the bus and walked along the field ridge into a farmland in Diaowo Town. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the field, the winter wheat that was just sown last month has sprouted, green and growing happily. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The moisture content is good.” The general secretary praised. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the vegetable field on the side, cabbages were full and green. The general secretary leaned over and touched the heart of the cabbage: &quot;It has grown solid.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The village cadre introduced that the local Chinese cabbage is quite famous and is sold to Beijing, Tianjin and other surrounding areas. After the flood receded, the village organized everyone to rush to plant more than 1,000 acres of &quot;frost-fall radish and winter-beginning cabbage.&quot; Some cabbage has already begun to be harvested, and the sales and prices are very good. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The general secretary warned: &quot;The recovery of agricultural production after the disaster is not only directly related to the income of every household, but also related to the national food security. The party&#39;s good policy is to make the people happy. It is necessary to organize and arrange agricultural production this winter and next spring. Try to have a good harvest next year.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the fields, there is hope for a good harvest. The streets are filled with vitality. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the entrance of Yongji Xiuyuan Community, the General Secretary walked into a pharmacy and a supermarket. &quot;Where was the water flooded at that time? How much damage was done to the goods? What are the subsidy policies?&quot; He asked very carefully. &lt; /p>;&lt;p>;In the Baigou River management project in the east of Zhuozhou City, machinery roars, and hundreds of workers are carrying out construction such as dam reinforcement. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping walked onto the embankment and listened to the layout of major water conservancy projects for post-disaster reconstruction. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The responsible comrade of the National Development and Reform Commission unfolded a planning map to introduce in detail the next step of strengthening water conservancy project construction in North China. The three-year plan involves the reinforcement and upgrading of river dams, the removal of dangerous reservoirs, the construction of flood storage and detention areas, and urban drainage projects, etc., and will systematically improve the flood prevention and disaster resistance capabilities of North China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“After major floods, we must carry out extensive construction and improvement, and greatly improve the level of water conservancy facilities and flood control facilities. Chinese-style modernization also includes water conservancy modernization and emergency management modernization.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Standing on the embankment, looking at the wide river, the General Secretary had profound thoughts: &quot;Recently, the central government decided to issue an additional 1 trillion yuan of national debt, making great efforts and spending a lot of money to support post-disaster recovery and reconstruction and projects that enhance disaster prevention, reduction and relief capabilities. Construction. I believe that through construction, our country&#39;s disaster prevention, reduction and relief capabilities, especially in the northern region, will be greatly improved.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Vigorously promote the spirit of flood fighting and disaster relief&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;The touching stories of flood fighting and disaster relief have turned into the most convincing real-life &quot;teaching materials&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During this disaster, due to its high terrain, the Miaofengshan National School became a &quot;safe island&quot; for nearby disaster-stricken villagers to resettle, for rescue workers to rest, and for the transfer of emergency and disaster relief materials and equipment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Children who experienced severe floods during the summer vacation used clay works they made today to thank the most lovable people in their hearts. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the classroom on the first floor of the teaching building, a class of fifth-grade students held a theme class meeting under the leadership of their head teacher. The four characters &quot;gratitude&quot; and &quot;determination&quot; are written on the blackboard. The theme of the class meeting is &quot;Stories of Flood Fighting and Disaster Relief Around Me.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping also joined in and listened carefully. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A girl stood up: &quot;My work is Uncle Rescue. At that time, the place where my grandpa stored his things was flooded. Uncle Rescue came to help quickly, and they were all soaked. &quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Another girl also picked up her work: &quot;I think uncles from the People&#39;s Liberation Army are the cutest people. They go out early and come back late, fall asleep covered in mud and water, and fall asleep again before dawn the next day. It was very hard to go out.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Holding a clay work of an angel in white, a boy told the scene he saw at the resettlement site: &quot;One day, a grandma had a heart attack, and several doctors I quickly got the instruments to check my grandma, asked her about her previous physical condition, and treated her as soon as possible. I want to study hard, become a doctor when I grow up, and help more people get rid of their illnesses.&quot;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;Looking at these sensible children, the general secretary’s eyes were full of warmth:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The children have personally experienced this disaster, which has a significant impact on their lives. You have experienced this through the things you have encountered around you. When you meet the People’s Liberation Army, volunteers, village cadres, etc., you will see that in times of crisis, our party’s organizations and party members and cadres at all levels will be on the front line for the people.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; On the school playground, General Secretary Xi Jinping cordially expressed condolences to the martyrs Liu Jie and Xiong Li’s spouse and children who sacrificed their lives in the line of duty during the flood fighting and disaster relief operations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The General Secretary held their hands tightly and said with concern: &quot;Take good care of your family, arrange your life well, and train your children well.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping exhorted : &quot;We must always remember the martyrs who sacrificed their lives in flood fighting and disaster relief, publicize their heroic deeds, and care for their families. We must vigorously promote the spirit of flood fighting and disaster relief and carry it forward in all aspects of work.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;Spirit is sublimated in struggle; strength is condensed in hardship. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the last stop of this inspection, on the embankment of Baigou River, &quot;camouflage green&quot;, &quot;flame blue&quot; and &quot;rescue red&quot; were lined up neatly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping cordially visited and expressed condolences to the water conservancy project construction personnel, representatives of the People&#39;s Liberation Army and Armed Police Force, militia reservists, fire rescue teams and other representatives who had participated in Zhuozhou flood fighting and rescue. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When one side is in trouble, all parties provide support, which fully demonstrates the strong political advantages of our party and country.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Facing the “soldiers” with high morale, General Secretary Xi Jinping’s words Full of power: &quot;You are the mainstay. The teams led by the Communist Party of China are all teams that serve the people. When the sea is flowing, heroes show their true colors! The people thank you, the party and the government thank you! I hope comrades will continue to work hard and make new achievements. !&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 再接再厉抓好灾后恢复重建]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/12/nw.D110000renmrb_20231112_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Sunday, November 12, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;On November 10, General Secretary Xi Jinping inspected the post-disaster recovery and reconstruction work in Beijing and Hebei and delivered an important speech, inspiring and Gathering strength and arousing enthusiastic response among the cadres and the masses. Everyone said that they must thoroughly study and understand the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech, conscientiously implement the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, and make persistent efforts to restore and rebuild after the disaster to ensure that the people live and work in peace and contentment and have a warm winter. We must always adhere to the people-centered approach, adhere to the system concept, adhere to truth-seeking and pragmatism, scientific planning, and rational layout, seize the opportunity to make up for shortcomings and strengths and weaknesses, accelerate the improvement of flood control engineering systems and emergency management systems, and continuously improve disaster prevention, reduction, and relief capabilities. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Ensuring that the affected people can survive the winter safely and warmly&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out that ensuring that the affected people can survive the winter safely and warmly is a hard task. Winters are long in the north, and winters in the mountains are especially cold. Heating work must be carried out in detail and implemented in every household. For disaster-stricken households that have completed house repairs, reinforcements or reconstruction and are eligible for occupancy, we should provide guidance and help them implement winter heating. For the disaster-stricken households whose houses have not yet been rebuilt, measures such as staying with relatives and friends, renting houses, and government resettlement should be used to ensure that they have a warm winter. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Learning and understanding the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech has strengthened our confidence and determination to do a good job in post-disaster recovery and reconstruction.” Yang Haijun, Secretary of the Party Branch of Wanquanzhuang Village, Diaowo Town, Zhuozhou City, Baoding, Hebei Province, introduced that the whole village The construction of 172 houses that need to be repaired has been completed, and the villagers have all moved into their homes; the 139 houses that need to be demolished and rebuilt have been resettled by visiting relatives, renting houses, etc.; various subsidies should be fully disbursed, and the disaster-stricken people will be able to Move into a new house. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since October, Mentougou District in Beijing has carried out the &quot;Monthly Operation to Ensure a Warmth and Warmth Winter for the People&quot;. More than 4,000 disaster-stricken houses have been cleaned and repaired, and more than half of the houses included in the reconstruction have started. Before the Spring Festival, All construction will begin. &quot;All 62 households&#39; damaged gas heating furnaces have been replaced, and more than 70 households with damaged wall facades have also completed repairs to their insulation layers. Next, village cadres will be arranged to conduct household surveys, check for leaks and fill in the gaps as soon as possible. Solve the problem and ensure that every household is safe and warm during the winter.&quot; said Hu Fengcai, Party branch secretary of Shuiyuzui Village, Miaofengshan Town, Mentougou District. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“To implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech, we must further do all the work in detail, organize professionals to provide in-depth on-site guidance, and accelerate housing reconstruction.” Wei Hongmei, Secretary of the Hailin Municipal Party Committee in Mudanjiang, Heilongjiang, introduced, At present, more than 11,000 disaster-stricken people in the city have all evacuated from 45 resettlement sites and returned to repaired and reinforced homes, settled in new houses, or stayed with relatives and friends, or rented houses to ensure a safe and warm winter. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Comprehensively improve disaster prevention, reduction and relief capabilities&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out that we must adhere to the people-centered approach, focus on the long-term, scientific planning, and combine recovery and reconstruction with Promote high-quality development, promote the construction of resilient cities, promote rural revitalization, and promote the construction of ecological civilization, and take targeted measures to comprehensively improve disaster prevention, reduction, and relief capabilities. In particular, it is necessary to improve the urban and rural grassroots emergency management organization system and enhance the grassroots disaster prevention and avoidance, self-rescue and mutual rescue capabilities. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech has further pointed out the direction for us to strengthen the construction of key water conservancy projects and ensure the safety of flood control in the capital.” Liu Hongwei, chief planner of the Beijing Municipal Water Affairs Bureau, said that outstanding problems and weak links will be targeted , in accordance with the principle of &quot;upper storage, middle dredging, lower drainage, and effective flood control&quot;, starting from building a solid &quot;upper storage&quot; barrier, smoothing the &quot;middle dredging&quot; and &quot;lower drainage&quot; channels, expanding the flood &quot;detention&quot; space, and strengthening the mountain torrent Five aspects, including channel management and improvement of defense technology, will make up for shortcomings, build a safety line of defense against floods, and improve urban operation support capabilities. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Junwu, director of the Tianjin Municipal Emergency Management Bureau, said that to implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech, Tianjin should continue to prepare and drill grassroots emergency plans while focusing on strengthening townships (streets), villages (communities) ) Construction of disaster prevention and reduction infrastructure and emergency material reserve stations, &quot;We will increase efforts to popularize knowledge on natural disaster prevention and avoidance and emergency self-rescue, build a disaster risk management model with government leadership, social participation, and multi-party collaboration, and comprehensively improve disaster prevention and reduction Disaster relief capabilities.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In early August, a number of water conservancy project facilities in 16 counties (cities, districts) in Harbin City, Heilongjiang Province were damaged to varying degrees by floods, and emergency repair work has been completed. &quot;To implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s important speech, we must focus on strengthening the Mopanshan Reservoir flood control facility improvement project to resist excessive floods and the construction of the Ash River flood control and regulation project to further enhance disaster prevention and reduction capabilities.&quot; said Liu Zhicheng, director of the Harbin Municipal Water Affairs Bureau. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei water system is connected, and flood prevention and fighting are a game of chess. &quot;General Secretary Xi Jinping requested in-depth research and promotion of the construction of a flood control engineering system in the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region. This points the way for us to strengthen the system concept.&quot; Wang Hongbin, deputy chief engineer of Hebei Water Conservancy and Hydropower Survey and Design Institute Group Co., Ltd. said, &quot;Targeting the shortcomings and weaknesses , we must focus on improving the flood control system and pattern of the river basin, scientifically arrange the construction of reservoirs, rivers, embankments, flood storage and detention areas and other functions, build a flood control security system with appropriate standards, controllable risks, safe and reliable, and overall improve the flood prevention and disaster reduction capabilities of the river basin. ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The construction of the Baigou River control project is being actively promoted. The total length of the Zhuozhou section of the project is about 25.76 kilometers. The earthwork filling task has been completed and the embankment construction will be completed by the end of the year. After the Zhuozhou section project is completed, it will Effectively improve the flood control capabilities in the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region.&quot; Li Jiang, first-level chief staff member of Zhuozhou Water Conservancy Bureau, said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Organize and arrange agricultural production this winter and next spring&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out that agricultural production is an important aspect of post-disaster recovery and reconstruction, and is not only directly related to the income of every household , and also related to national food security. We must continue to repair disaster-damaged farmland and agricultural facilities, increase the supply of agricultural materials, strengthen agricultural technology guidance, organize and arrange agricultural production this winter and next spring, and strive for a good harvest next year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For agricultural production this winter and next spring, Beijing’s Fangshan District started early and prepared early, focusing on ensuring the supply of agricultural materials, and promptly distributed 5,900 tons of chemical fertilizers, 9.6 tons of pesticides, etc. to 325 villages and more than 13,000 households. Disaster relief agricultural supplies. &quot;The district&#39;s special team for ensuring the supply of agricultural materials coordinates the transportation and storage of agricultural materials by production enterprises, supply and marketing systems, and agricultural materials distribution companies to ensure that the supply of agricultural materials is uninterrupted and not out of stock, making it convenient for farmers to purchase nearby at any time.&quot; Fangshan District Agriculture and Rural Affairs Zhang Shan, deputy director of the bureau, said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Diaowo Town, Zhuozhou City, more than 4,000 acres of cabbage planted after the disaster have matured, and villagers are busy harvesting. &quot;The General Secretary walked into the farmland to inspect the growth of winter wheat and Chinese cabbage, and urged the organization to arrange agricultural production this winter and next spring. This made us deeply inspired and more motivated.&quot; Zhang Dazhong, secretary of the Diaowo Town Party Committee, said that we must make arrangements for the ongoing in-depth development We should closely integrate the theme education with post-disaster recovery and reconstruction, vigorously promote the spirit of flood fighting and disaster relief, give full play to the fighting fortress role of grassroots party organizations and the vanguard and exemplary role of party members and cadres, consolidate the advantages of party branches in leading professional cooperatives, and build high-standard farmland and promote agricultural insurance. We will continue to make efforts to fully cover and strengthen the industrial chain, and use the results of restoration and reconstruction and people&#39;s satisfaction to test the effectiveness of thematic education. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“To implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech, we must further enhance our sense of mission and responsibility for agricultural production this winter and next spring.” Shulan City is one of the main grain-producing areas in Jilin Province. Shi Wanchun, deputy director of the Technology Extension Center, has just finished an agricultural technology guidance in the village. &quot;After the disaster, we went deep into the fields to carry out agricultural technology guidance, tried our best to reduce agricultural losses, and guided farmers to restore black soil by returning straw to the fields and applying more organic fertilizers.&quot; Fertility. Next, it is necessary to strengthen agricultural technology training and guidance in seriously affected towns and villages, and strive for a good harvest next year.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Agricultural production in Wuchang City, Heilongjiang is accelerating its recovery, and damaged rice seedlings have been repaired so far. There are more than 3,300 greenhouses. &quot;It is expected that by the end of this year, production facilities such as greenhouses and field roads will be repaired to ensure that next year&#39;s spring plowing production will not be affected.&quot; Wang Shouxin, director of the Wuchang City Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau, said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Strive to build a better homeland&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When General Secretary Xi Jinping left Shuiyuzui Village, Miaofengshan Town, Mentougou District, Beijing, the local people gave him a warm farewell. The general secretary told everyone that I have always been thinking about the people in the disaster area. The Communist Party is a party that serves the people. It always puts the people at the top of its heart and will go all out whether it is emergency rescue or disaster relief or post-disaster recovery and reconstruction. I hope that the villagers will strengthen their confidence and work hard to build a better home. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Municipal Bureau of Agriculture and Rural Affairs sprayed foliar fertilizers and pesticides from airplanes for us for free, and we received 3,000 yuan in compensation the next day after the damage to the extinct land was determined. Good policies are delivered to our doorsteps, and we We have to rely on our own efforts and work harder!&quot; After the flood receded, Li Dan, a villager in Longwangmiao Village, Shangzhi City, Heilongjiang Province, immediately went to the fields to remove silt and drain water and carry out self-rescue. After the autumn harvest, before it was too cold, she hurriedly closed the greenhouse again. Screening the seedbed soil in preparation for planting and raising seedlings next year, &quot;We must use our hard-working hands to build a home and make the days more prosperous.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;To implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s important speech, we must grasp We will implement various policies and measures in detail and find ways to help the affected people, enterprises and merchants tide over the difficulties.&quot; Lu Peng, director of the Commerce Bureau of Fangshan District, Beijing, said that for the disaster-stricken small, medium and micro enterprises and individual industrial and commercial households, Fangshan District has introduced relief subsidies and consumer vouchers and other policy measures to increase enthusiasm for resuming work and production. At present, Fangshan District is working hard to promote the post-disaster recovery and reconstruction of rural commercial outlets, fill the gaps in basic convenience services in remote areas, and promote the construction of the &quot;Village Purchase&quot; project. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Gezi Zhang Restaurant on Songlin Road in Fangshan District has now returned to its former glory. &quot;The General Secretary is concerned about the business recovery of merchants after the disaster, and requires party committees and governments at all levels to take multiple measures to help us tide over the difficulties. This makes us deeply moved and inspired.&quot; Zhang Ke, general manager of Gezi Zhang Restaurant, said with emotion, &quot; When the floods rushed into the store, we suffered heavy losses. Thanks to the district’s timely dispatch of special personnel to serve us, they helped us restore water and electricity, etc., and also provided preferential policies for enterprises.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Keeping in mind the general secretary’s instructions, We must organize and coordinate grassroots organizations, party members and cadres, neighbors, professional forces and volunteers from all walks of life to work together to speed up recovery and reconstruction and build a beautiful home.&quot; Yao Guibin, secretary of the Party Working Committee of Shuangta Street, Zhuozhou City, said that it is necessary to fill in the vacancies by checking and filling them. Strengthen the renovation of old residential areas, implement measures such as the renovation of water supply and drainage pipelines, waterproof renovation of residential building facades, and add public green spaces to continuously enhance the people&#39;s sense of gain, happiness, and security. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“To implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech, we require pragmatism, scientific planning, and rational layout, use funds where possible, and promote high-quality post-disaster recovery and reconstruction projects and improve disaster prevention, reduction, and relief capabilities. Construction.&quot; Yu Huafeng, Secretary of the Mentougou District Party Committee, said that the district is carrying out the construction of new disaster prevention facilities, and must build various projects into popular projects, high-quality projects, and clean projects to build a better home. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Our reporters Wang Haonan, Wu Shaomin, Zhu Dawei, Pan Junqiang, Li Jiading, Zhang Tengyang, Shi Ziqiang, Zheng Zhiwen, Guo Xiaolong)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt; div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 坚定信心，努力把家园建设得更加美好]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/12/nw.D110000renmrb_20231112_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Sunday, November 12, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;On November 10, General Secretary Xi Jinping came to Mentougou, Beijing, which suffered severe floods and geological disasters at the end of July and early August this year. , Baoding, Hebei and other places to visit and express condolences to the victims, understand the post-disaster recovery and reconstruction situation on the spot, and inspect and guide the post-disaster recovery and reconstruction work. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out during the inspection, &quot;I hope that the villagers will strengthen their confidence and work hard to build a better home.&quot; The deep concern and ardent entrustment made the disaster-stricken people feel warm and inspired . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When the General Secretary came to our home, we felt warm in our hearts.” Li Meng, a villager in Shuiyuzui Village, Miaofengshan Town, Mentougou, Beijing, told reporters, “The damage to the house, repair expenses, heating, etc., The general secretary asked very carefully. The party and government&#39;s support policies are real. Now the supply of water, electricity, gas, etc. in our village has been restored, and the heating has kept up. It is not a problem to survive the winter safely and warmly.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;Wang Yao, Secretary of the Party Committee of Miaofengshan Town, took reporters to visit and introduced that the roads in the village are smooth and clean, and the damaged houses that have been reinforced and repaired have been repainted. &quot;We must thoroughly implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s important speech, closely integrate restoration and reconstruction with the promotion of high-quality development, the construction of resilient cities, the revitalization of rural areas, and the construction of ecological civilization, and strive to build a better homeland.&quot; Wang Yao said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I walked into the Miaofengshan National School, which was used as a temporary disaster shelter and a place for flood prevention and relief personnel during this year’s flood season, I saw that the playground was wide and clean, and the classroom windows were bright and clean. Sun Yiliang, a student in Class 1 of the fifth grade, showed reporters the clay works made with the theme of flood relief: medical staff who rescued the injured, rescuers who rushed to danger, and rescue helicopters... &quot;We must learn to be grateful as Grandpa Xi taught us. , Set up ambitions to be builders and successors of the socialist cause.&quot; Sun Yiliang said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the beginning of winter, the lowest outdoor temperature in Zhuozhou City, Baoding, Hebei Province dropped below zero degrees Celsius, and 29 residential buildings in Yongji Xiuyuan Community, Shuangta Street, have all been heated. Resident Dong Caiying took reporters to visit her home&#39;s storage room: meat, eggs, milk, vegetables and fruits, etc. are all available. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When the General Secretary came to my home to visit and express condolences, he asked in detail about flood levels, emergency accommodation, furniture and appliance updates, heating, related subsidies, etc. We thank the General Secretary from the bottom of our hearts, and thank the party and the government for their support of us. Dong Caiying said that not long after the disaster occurred, the community organized and sent emergency supplies, and now water, electricity and heating supplies are guaranteed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the Furong Xingsheng convenience supermarket at the entrance of Yongji Xiuyuan Community, the owner Liu Hongchang is busy unloading the goods, and the shelves are full of various products. &quot;After the disaster, the relevant departments immediately learned from us about the damage to our operations and helped us apply for subsidized loans in accordance with the policy. This time the General Secretary came to our supermarket to inquire in detail about the business recovery situation and asked party committees and governments at all levels to We are taking multiple measures to help the affected people, enterprises and merchants tide over the difficulties.&quot; Liu Hongchang said, &quot;This makes us more motivated and we must work hard to build a good home.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Located in Langouwa flood storage and detention In Wanquanzhuang Village, Diaowo Town, Zhuozhou City, all 311 households in the village were affected by the flood during this year&#39;s flood season. When the reporter visited the village on November 11, the roads in the village had been renovated and many houses on the roadside had been repaired and reinforced. Walking into the home of villager Yang Peiran, the sun shines into the living room through the floor-to-ceiling windows, making the house warm and bright. &quot;The General Secretary was thinking about us disaster-stricken people. After coming to my house, he didn&#39;t even bother to sit down. He asked about my family&#39;s family income, repair expenses, production recovery, etc.&quot; Yang Peiran said, &quot;When I said that my family has used natural gas and pavement, The general secretary smiled happily after using the floor heating.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Diaowo Town Party Committee Secretary Zhang Dazhong said that of the 311 affected households in Wanquanzhuang Village, 172 houses that need repair have been repaired, and the houses need to be demolished and rebuilt. 139 households have been resettled by visiting relatives, renting houses, etc. “After listening to the General Secretary’s important speech on the spot, our next key work is more clear. We must further care and help the reconstruction households, take practical and effective measures to prevent people from returning to poverty due to disasters, and ensure that all Villagers are safe and warm through the winter.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Agricultural production is an important aspect of post-disaster recovery and reconstruction. To the west of Wanquanzhuang Village, in a farmland of Dongfeng Village, winter wheat and Chinese cabbage are growing well. Wang Sen, secretary of the Dongfeng Village Party branch, said, “Keeping in mind the general secretary’s instructions, we must continue to do a good job in supplying agricultural materials and guiding agricultural technology, and organize and arrange agricultural production this winter and next spring.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing The water systems of Tianjin and Hebei are connected, and flood prevention and fighting are a chess game. Baigou River is a backbone flood channel in the Daqing River Basin. On November 11, hundreds of construction workers were carrying out the embankment reinforcement work of the Baigou River Management Project (Zhuozhou Section), and more than 10 excavators were dredging the river at full power. &quot;After the Zhuozhou section project is completed, the flood control standards of dykes and dams will be further improved, and the overall flood control capacity of the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region will be improved.&quot; Li Jiang, first-level chief staff member of the Zhuozhou Municipal Water Conservancy Bureau, said, &quot;We must adhere to pragmatism, scientific planning, and rational layout. Use the project funds wisely and build the project into a popular project, a high-quality project, and a clean project.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;We are confident that we can build our homeland into a better place.&quot; Cai Weihua, Secretary of the Zhuozhou Municipal Party Committee, said, &quot;We want to Conscientiously implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech, closely integrate the ongoing thematic education with post-disaster recovery and reconstruction, regard doing practical things for the people as an important part of thematic education, and use the results of recovery and reconstruction and people’s satisfaction to test the effectiveness of thematic education Results.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Do practical things for the people and enhance their sense of gain. “Some time ago, thanks to the township organization that drained the farmland water in the village and deployed machinery, seeds, fertilizers, etc., we successfully completed the winter wheat sowing.” Li Shutian, a villager in Dongfeng Village, said, “Keeping in mind the general secretary’s instructions, I will not miss the farming season. Produce and strive for a good harvest next year!&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under the sun, the winter wheat sown not long ago has grown to a height of more than ten centimeters. The wind blows, and the hope of a good harvest surges in the green wheat fields. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 韩正访问马来西亚]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/12/nw.D110000renmrb_20231112_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Sunday, November 12, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/12/01/rmrb2023111201p27_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;November 9 to 11 On the same day, Vice President Han Zheng was invited to visit Malaysia. This is November 9. Han is meeting with Malaysian Prime Minister Anwar in Putrajaya. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Gao Jie&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Xinhua News Agency, George Town, Malaysia, November 11 &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Zhang Chongfang, Jiang Guopeng) From November 9th to 11th, Vice President Han Zheng was invited to visit Malaysia and met with Malaysian Supreme Head of State Abdullah Abdullah and Prime Minister Anwar in Kuala Lumpur and Putrajaya respectively. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When meeting with Abdullah, Han Zheng first conveyed President Xi Jinping’s cordial greetings to Supreme Head of State Abdullah, saying that China and Malaysia are friendly neighbors facing each other across the sea, and the friendship between the two countries has a long history. Next year the two countries will celebrate the 50th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations. China is willing to work with Malaysia to promote the further development of bilateral relations, to jointly build the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; with high quality under the guidance of jointly building a community with a shared future for China and Malaysia, to jointly promote the implementation of their respective national development plans, and to continuously Enrich and enrich the connotation of the comprehensive strategic partnership between the two countries. China has always adhered to the concept of extensive consultation, joint contribution and shared benefits, deepened cooperation with neighboring countries, and is willing to strengthen practical cooperation in various fields with ASEAN countries, including Malaysia, to promote sustained prosperity and stable development in the region. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Abdallah asked Han Zheng to convey his sincere greetings to President Xi Jinping, congratulated China on the great achievements of the &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; initiative, thanked China&#39;s strong economic radiation for driving the development of ASEAN countries, and expressed his willingness to further enhance the level of bilateral cooperation. better benefit the people of both countries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会见安瓦尔时，韩正表示，中马世代友好，两国友谊历久弥新。今年是中马全面战略伙伴关系建立10周年，习近平主席同总理先生就共建中马命运共同体达成重要共识，为新时期双边关系发展擘画了蓝图，具有重要里程碑意义。中马是国与国友好交往的典范，中方视马来西亚为值得信赖的朋友和重要战略伙伴，始终支持马方选择符合自身国情的发展道路，愿与马方在涉及彼此核心利益问题上坚定相互支持。中方愿同马方一道，高质量共建“一带一路”，鼓励两国各层级各地方密切交流往来，扩大经贸、文化、旅游、教育、科技等领域合作，不断增进人民之间的友好感情，为两国全面战略伙伴关系赋予新内涵、注入新动力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安瓦尔表示，马中关系具有特殊性、战略性。马方坚定支持习近平主席提出的构建人类命运共同体理念和全球发展倡议、全球安全倡议、全球文明倡议，愿同中方一道积极推动共建“一带一路”。马方对双边关系未来充满期待，欢迎中国企业到马投资兴业，实现共同发展。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;韩正还会见了马来西亚副总理扎希德，就推动双边务实合作进行深入交流，表示习近平主席宣布高质量共建“一带一路”八项行动，将有力助推“一带一路”合作和两国高质量发展。双方同意进一步密切高层交往，深化战略沟通。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10日，韩正赴槟城州访问，会见槟城州首席部长曹观友，表示欢迎槟城州继续加强同中国各省市的交流合作，发挥地方特点，实现优势互补，将中马命运共同体建设落到实处。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;访马期间，韩正考察了吉利宝腾合资公司丹戎马林工厂、益纳利美昌有限公司，参观了阅书报社孙中山纪念馆、侨生博物馆。 &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 全国秋粮收获已过九成半（新数据 新看点）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/12/nw.D110000renmrb_20231112_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月12日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/12/01/rmrb2023111201p22_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;数据来源：农业农村部&lt;BR/>;制图：汪哲平&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报北京11月11日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者郁静娴）农业农村部最新农情调度显示：伴随玉米大豆及中稻收获进入尾声、南方晚稻收获加速推进，全国秋粮收获进度达96.2%，基本实现丰收到手。今年以来，我国粮食生产克服局部地区洪涝干旱等灾害影响，全年粮食产量有望再创新高。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;种植面积增加，产能基础不断夯实。今年秋粮面积连续第四年增加，预计达13.1亿亩，比上年增加700多万亩。其中，高产作物玉米面积预计增加1300多万亩，大豆面积连续2年稳定在1.5亿亩以上。大豆玉米带状复合种植面积达到2000万亩，比去年增加500万亩左右。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;大面积单产提升落地见效。今年我国重点在200个玉米大县、100个大豆大县整建制推进单产提升，耕种管收、地种药肥全环节综合施策，重点推广玉米大豆增密、精准肥水调控和中后期“一喷多促”关键措施。初步测算，300个重点县单产提升对粮食丰收的贡献率达到了73%。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;目前，各地秋冬种正有序推进。截至11月10日，全国冬小麦完成意向播种面积过九成。其中，西北地区播种基本结束，黄淮海地区九成半，长江中下游和华南地区过七成半，西南地区过六成。全国冬油菜完成意向播种面积过九成半，其中长江中下游地区播种基本结束，西南地区过九成。各地积极推广良种良法，持续提高播种质量。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 着力打造现代金融机构和市场体系]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/12/nw.D110000renmrb_20231112_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月12日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;中央金融工作会议提出，要着力打造现代金融机构和市场体系，疏通资金进入实体经济的渠道。如何落实落细相关措施，贯彻落实会议部署要求？相关部门负责人和专家从更好发挥金融市场功能、提升金融机构服务质效、强化市场规则等方面进行了解读。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;优化融资结构，更好发挥资本市场枢纽功能&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：中央金融工作会议提出，优化融资结构，更好发挥资本市场枢纽功能。如何理解资本市场的枢纽功能？下一步怎样发力健全这一功能，服务高质量发展？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国证监会市场监管一部主任张望军：中央金融工作会议提出更好发挥资本市场枢纽功能。“枢纽功能”这一提法表明资本市场在金融运行中具有牵一发而动全身的重要作用，体现出党中央对资本市场的高度重视，也在新形势下赋予了资本市场新的重任和使命。未来中国证监会将坚持走中国特色金融发展之路，加快建设安全、规范、透明、开放、有活力、有韧性的资本市场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;优化融资结构，要围绕提高直接融资比重，健全多层次资本市场体系，完善资本市场投融资功能。要聚焦支持高水平科技自立自强关键目标，推动股票、债券、期货市场协调发展。还要发展多元化股权融资，支持上海、深圳证券交易所建设世界一流交易所，高质量建设北京证券交易所，引导私募股权创投基金投早投小投科技。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，要推动股票发行注册制改革走深走实。从2018年至今，以信息披露为核心的注册制改革，由试点到全面落地，经历了逐步深化的过程。未来，中国证监会还将持续完善发行、上市、交易、并购重组、退市等相关基础制度，推动资本市场基础制度更加完善、更加定型，增强中国特色现代资本市场的竞争力和普惠性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：投资银行和投资机构是资本市场的参与主体，是更好发挥资本市场功能的重要力量，怎样培育一流投资银行和投资机构？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国民生银行首席经济学家温彬：培育一流投资银行和投资机构是更好发挥资本市场枢纽功能、推动股票发行注册制走深走实的内在要求。培育一流投资银行要求投资银行在业务体系、综合服务能力、国际化水平和风险管理等方面进一步提升，以提高注册制下企业上市质量，发挥服务实体经济、服务居民财富管理的功能作用。培育一流投资机构是活跃资本市场、优化估值水平的重要方式，要在扩大全国社保、基本养老保险、年金等基金投资范围，支持机构投资者参与上市公司治理，便利专业机构投资运作等方面为培育机构投资者提供良好环境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：债券市场是重要的直接融资方式，怎样进一步促进债券市场高质量发展？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国证监会债券部主任周小舟：债券市场是多层次资本市场的重要组成部分。中国证监会高度重视加强债券市场建设，以深化债券注册制改革为牵引，完善债券市场基础制度，激发债券市场活力，持续提升债券市场服务实体经济和国家战略的重要功能。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;下一步，中国证监会将主要从四方面促进债券市场高质量发展：进一步健全债券市场发行、交易和管理制度，健全公开透明、规范有序、廉洁高效的债券审核注册体系，加强债市投资端改革，壮大债券做市商队伍，扩大债券市场对外开放；全面加强债券市场监管，持续健全债券市场防假打假制度机制，保护债券投资者合法权益；坚持底线思维，全力做好房地产、城投等重点领域债券违约风险防控，维护债券市场平稳运行；牢牢把握服务实体经济的根本宗旨，推动股权融资和公司（企业）债券、ABS（资产支持证券）、REITs（不动产投资信托基金）协同发展，大力支持科技创新、绿色发展等国家重大战略，全力做好科技金融、绿色金融、普惠金融、养老金融、数字金融五篇大文章，以债券市场的高质量发展助力建设金融强国。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;完善机构定位，提升服务实体经济质效&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：不同类型金融机构的定位和优势不同，如何支持国有大型金融机构、中小金融机构发挥各自优势，提升服务实体经济水平？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;温彬：国有大型金融机构是服务实体经济的主力军和维护金融稳定的压舱石，要支持国有大型金融机构做优做强，充分发挥国有金融机构资源配置、估值定价、风险管理、保荐承销等能力，保持资本和信贷持续增长，提升直接融资占比，加大制造业中长期资金投入，切实满足市场融资需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，中小金融机构应定位于“立足当地开展特色化经营”。在监管方面，须严格控制股东资质审查，推进中小金融机构分类监管；在经营方面，要鼓励中小金融机构依托区域发展特色和中小微企业融资需求，聚焦重点客群，开展特色化、精细化、差异化经营。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：政策性金融依托国家信用支持，在服务高质量发展上发挥了重要作用，未来应该怎样进一步强化政策性金融机构职能定位？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家开发银行首席业务官刘培勇：对国家开发银行来说，要聚焦主责主业，进一步支持国家重大战略、重点领域和薄弱环节发展，积极服务基础设施建设、高水平科技自立自强和先进制造业发展等领域，支持加快保障性住房等“三大工程”建设。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：如何发挥保险业的经济减震器和社会稳定器功能？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;温彬：随着中国保险市场规模不断壮大，保险业作为经济减震器和社会稳定器的作用愈发凸显。要鼓励保险机构持续探索优化保险产品和服务，继续丰富在人身健康、财富管理等领域的产品供给，积极参与个人养老金市场发展；同时拓展服务范围，为重大科技创新、关键民生项目等提供有效保障。此外，要引导保险资金长期稳健投资，推动保险资金在稳定资本市场、支持实体经济和服务国家重大战略等方面发挥更大作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;强化市场规则，打造规则统一、监管协同的金融市场&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：如何通过强化市场规则、加强市场监管来促进长期资本形成？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张望军：围绕“促进长期资本形成”，中国证监会将持续加强部门协同，出台资本市场投资端改革行动方案，优化资本市场投资生态，营造有利于中长期资金入市的政策环境。推动打通堵点，提高各类中长期资金参与资本市场的积极性和稳定性，推动社保基金、基本养老保险基金、年金基金、保险资金等中长期资金与资本市场整体保持良性互动。持续丰富资本市场产品工具，提升投资交易便利性，营造“愿意来、留得住、能发展”的市场环境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，对资本市场来说，强化市场监管是促进长期资本入市的重要保障。未来，中国证监会将提升资本市场监管适应性，牢牢守住风险底线。规范发行和交易行为，及时评估优化股份减持、融资融券、再融资等机制安排，加强一二级市场逆周期调节，统筹优化上市公司回购、股东增持等制度，全面加强资本市场监管，加大资本市场防假打假力度，强化穿透监管，为投资者提供真实透明的上市公司。有力有序化解债券违约、私募基金等重点领域风险，防范风险跨区域、跨市场、跨境传递共振，牢牢守住不发生系统性风险的底线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：中央金融工作会议提出，拓宽银行资本金补充渠道，做好产融风险隔离。如何落实好这一要求？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上海金融与发展实验室主任曾刚：中小银行确实存在资本补充渠道有限的问题，需要进一步拓展资本补充渠道。在内源融资方面，要引导中小金融机构通过差异化、特色化经营来提高经营业绩，以提升利润来补充资本金；在外源融资方面，对符合条件的中小银行，可以适度扩大其融资渠道，特别是发债、上市等市场化融资渠道，创造更好的资本补充环境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;产融风险隔离方面，应完善和加强金控集团监管，将金融控股公司纳入金融监管，推动产融风险有效隔离。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 推动构建房地产发展新模式（权威访谈）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/12/nw.D110000renmrb_20231112_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月12日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;7月24日召开的中央政治局会议提出，“适应我国房地产市场供求关系发生重大变化的新形势，适时调整优化房地产政策”“要加大保障性住房建设和供给，积极推动城中村改造和&#39;平急两用&#39;公共基础设施建设”。近日举行的中央金融工作会议强调，“加快保障性住房等&#39;三大工程&#39;建设，构建房地产发展新模式”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如何看待当前房地产市场形势？如何理解房地产发展新模式？如何加快保障性住房等“三大工程”建设？本报记者采访了住房城乡建设部党组书记、部长倪虹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;b>;今年房地产市场“前高、中低、后稳”，保交楼工作扎实推进&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：今年以来，一系列房地产调整优化措施接连出台。如何看待当前房地产市场形势，下一步将怎样促进市场平稳健康发展？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;倪虹：研判市场重要的是尊重规律、看大势。7月24日召开的中央政治局会议提出“适应我国房地产市场供求关系发生重大变化的新形势”，这是立足我国经济社会发展阶段和房地产自身发展规律作出的重大判断。要认识当前房地产市场形势，首先要把握住这个重大变化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从供给看，整体上，“有没有”的问题基本得到解决，但结构性不足问题仍然存在。从需求看，人民群众对住房品质有了更高要求，希望住上更好的房子、获得更好的服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年的房地产市场，总的看是“前高、中低、后稳”，“认房不认贷”“降低首付比例和利率”等政策措施起到了积极效果。1至10月份，一手房成交量虽然下降，但二手房成交量是上升的，一、二手房合起来，同比是正增长的。此外，保交楼工作正在扎实推进，1至10月份，带动全国房屋竣工面积同比增长近20%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;针对房地产市场形势，党中央、国务院作出了一系列重要部署，包括构建房地产发展新模式，实施保障性住房等“三大工程”，一视同仁满足不同所有制房地产企业合理融资需求等。我们将会同有关部门，指导地方认认真真落实好这些重大部署，努力满足人民群众的住房需求，促进房地产市场平稳健康和高质量发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时也要看到，房地产是不动产，房地产市场的特殊性，在于它是以城市为单元的市场，具有明显的区域特征，不同城市的交易量和价格有很大差异。常言道，“十家锅灶九不同”。关于房地产调控，我们强调要因城施策、精准施策、一城一策，就是这个道理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;b>;房地产发展新模式下，拼的是高质量、新科技、好服务&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：对于构建房地产发展新模式，社会比较关注。如何理解新模式的意义和内涵？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;倪虹：构建房地产发展新模式，是破解房地产发展难题、促进房地产市场平稳健康发展的治本之策。房地产市场已经从主要解决“有没有”转向主要解决“好不好”的阶段，过去追求速度和数量的发展模式，已不适应高质量发展的新要求，亟须构建新的发展模式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在理念上，要始终坚持房子是用来住的、不是用来炒的定位，以满足刚性和改善性住房需求为重点，努力让人民群众住上好房子。好房子好在哪儿？就是要绿色、低碳、智能、安全，让群众住得健康、用得便捷，成本低又放心安心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在体制机制上，一方面，建立“人、房、地、钱”要素联动的新机制，从要素资源科学配置入手，以人定房，以房定地，以房定钱，防止市场大起大落。另一方面，建立房屋从开发建设到维护使用的全生命周期管理机制，包括优化开发方式、融资方式、销售方式，建立房屋体检、房屋养老金、房屋保险等制度。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在抓落实上，要实施好规划建设保障性住房、城中村改造和“平急两用”公共基础设施建设“三大工程”；落实中央金融工作会议精神，一视同仁满足不同所有制房地产企业合理融资需求，促进金融与房地产良性循环。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新模式下，房地产企业要有清醒的认识：现在要拼的是高质量、新科技、好服务，谁能为群众建设好房子，谁能为群众提供好服务，谁就会有市场、谁就会有发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;规划建设保障性住房，实现政府保障基本需求、市场满足多层次住房需求&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：加快保障性住房等“三大工程”建设，将着重抓好哪些工作？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;倪虹：加快“三大工程”建设是党中央作出的重大战略部署，是根据房地产市场新形势推出的重要举措。目前，有关工作已经启动。其基本要求包括以下内容：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;规划建设保障性住房，是完善住房制度和供应体系、重构市场和保障关系的重大改革。这次改革的重点是拓展配售型保障性住房的新路子，最终是实现政府保障基本需求、市场满足多层次住房需求，建立租购并举的住房制度。这就要求城市党委、政府担负起主体责任，解决好群众尤其是新市民、青年人的住房问题，让他们放开手脚为美好生活去奋斗。青年人有希望，城市才能有未来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;城中村改造，是解决群众急难愁盼问题的重大民生工程，重点是消除安全风险隐患，改善居住环境，促进产业转型升级，推动城市高质量发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“平急两用”公共基础设施建设，是统筹发展与安全、提高城市韧性的重大举措，关键是“平时用得着、急时用得上”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当前，我国房地产市场正处在转型期，虽然遇到了一些困难，但未来持续发展仍然有坚实支撑。中央各项决策部署的持续落实，房地产发展新模式的逐步建立，将推动房地产转型升级、实现高质量发展，让人民群众住上更好的房子。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 精心描绘乡村振兴新图景]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/12/nw.D110000renmrb_20231112_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月12日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;峰峦叠嶂，阳光正好，湖南省花垣县双龙镇，记者再访十八洞村，恰逢蜂农收蜜时。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;养蜂大户龙先兰割下一块块金灿灿的蜂巢，放入洗净的圆桶。“村里生态好，去年蜂蜜就卖了40多万元，这是大山里的希望蜜、自豪蜜、幸福蜜！”龙先兰说，他不仅自己养蜂脱了贫，还带动本村和周边的100多名村民一起增收，“日子一年一个新台阶，芝麻开花节节高！”&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;乡村振兴新征程上，一个脱贫户的好日子，折射着一个村庄的好前景。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;2013年11月3日，习近平总书记在十八洞村考察时，首次提出精准扶贫的重要思想。一个大国消除绝对贫困的伟大实践，在这个大山深处、久困于穷的村庄，留下了最为鲜明的时代印记。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;精准扶贫首倡地，如何走好乡村振兴新征程？&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;新任驻村第一书记龙科，带着思考走进十八洞村：“跟前任工作队和村两委反复商量，发现答案还是在总书记的嘱托里，&#39;从实际出发，因地制宜，把种什么、养什么、从哪里增收想明白&#39;。”&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;多年前种下的千亩猕猴桃，今年销售额超过了400万元，成了为村里增收的“金果果”。特色种植，还有没有新路子？&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;花垣县农业农村局专家现场调研，认为这里“气候、地形、土壤，都适合种油茶。”村里引进油茶企业，县里建起生产加工基地。“公司+合作社+企业”，产加销贯通。眼下，计划年产5万吨的油茶生产线即将落户，据测算，将带动十八洞村及周边数万户农户参与油茶种植。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;如何延长产业链，把更多增值收益留在农村？琢磨好“土特产”文章，思路更开阔。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;多年前成立的苗绣合作社，让苗家绝活走出大山，但仍需创新，进一步打开销路。去年，从事苗绣设计制作的陈国桃，带着团队和市场资源走进十八洞村，一年多时间里，便推出了50多样新品，苗绣合作社年销售额增长了10倍。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;发展特色产业，最大的优势还是文旅。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;4个寨子组成的十八洞村，游客一度只往梨子寨跑，顶多留下吃顿农家饭。让寨与寨手牵手、共富裕，就要“一盘棋”谋划，一寨一特色。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;前不久正式运营的十八洞村田园综合体，集教育培训、文化旅游、餐饮住宿和现代农业为一体，建在当戎寨；蜡染非遗体验馆和古法酿酒体验中心，主打“民俗牌”，布局竹子寨；村里唯一的大型文化广场，落子飞虫寨，10月底刚完工，便迎来了一场苗家长龙宴……&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;梨子寨参观，当戎寨培训，竹子寨体验，飞虫寨欢歌。10年间，十八洞村村民人均年收入从2013年的1668元增至去年的23505元。村党支部书记施金通介绍，今年村集体收入有望突破500万元。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;跳出十八洞村看均衡，还有更大范围的“一盘棋”。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;十八洞村连同周边7个村，地相邻、人相亲、资源禀赋相近。十八洞村带头，资源共享、产业共谋、组织联建，一体打造“十八洞片区”。“以点带片、以片带面，让群众的日子越过越红火。”花垣县委主要负责同志说。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;年轻人返乡，新动作接连不断。网络直播、短视频推介……苗寨涌动新活力。村民们继续撸起袖子加油干，“饮水思源，自立自强”的宣示不仅写在村规民约里，也闪现在点滴变化间。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;践行精准扶贫重要思想，跑好乡村振兴接力赛。湖南省着力处理好“稳”和“进”、“输血”和“造血”、重点攻坚和整体推进、政府扶持和群众自主等关系，巩固拓展脱贫攻坚成果与乡村振兴有效衔接。据统计，2022年，湖南省脱贫户人均纯收入达到15499元，增长14.4%；脱贫县农村居民可支配收入达到14714元，增长8.7%。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 时时放心不下的牵挂]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/12/nw.D110000renmrb_20231112_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月12日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;这份时时放心不下的牵挂，一直萦绕在习近平总书记的心头。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年7月底8月初，华北、黄淮等地出现极端降雨，引发洪涝和地质灾害，造成北京、河北等地重大人员伤亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记密切关注汛情，高度重视防汛抗洪救灾工作，多次作出重要指示批示，要求全力保障人民群众生命财产安全。“那段时间，我每天都关注着灾情，指导着救灾工作，心里一直惦念着受灾地区和受灾群众。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;9月7日，正在黑龙江考察的习近平总书记，来到受灾较重的哈尔滨尚志市老街基乡龙王庙村，看望慰问受灾群众，了解灾后恢复重建进展。从东北谈到华北，总书记说：“我牵挂着受灾的地方。那些地方我之后也会去看。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;11月10日，北方入冬之际，习近平总书记专程来到北京、河北受灾较重的门头沟区、保定涿州市，看望慰问受灾群众，检查指导灾后恢复重建工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一天时间，乘汽车、换火车，行程横跨京冀两地，足迹覆盖农村、社区、学校、市政设施、水利工程，访居民、见师生、看商铺，入农户、进麦田、上大堤，冒着严寒而往，沐着夜色而归。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一路走下来，听到了看到了，我心里感到踏实，也是欣慰的，恢复重建工作都在按照计划进行。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“要继续把灾后恢复重建工作一件一件落实好，继续为推动人民生活向着更好的方向前进而努力，让老百姓今后的日子过得更好！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“我心里一直惦念着灾区的人民群众”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;妙峰山镇水峪嘴村位于北京西部山区，永定河从村北蜿蜒而过。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10日上午，习近平总书记乘车通过水峪嘴桥，在村口下车。岸边展板上的照片，记载了今夏洪水肆虐、洪峰过境时的景象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们现在所站的地方，当时已被洪水淹没。大水漫过水峪嘴桥的桥面。”当地负责同志告诉总书记，因转移及时，全村群众无一伤亡，但87%的房屋受损。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“恢复得怎么样？”总书记问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“受损房屋已经全部修完了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沿着村道，总书记步行察看村容村貌。道路整洁，房屋修葺一新。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;村民李盟的房子就在路边，门口墙上悬挂着一个标识牌：“淹没水深2.6米”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;走进李盟家，习近平总书记仔细察看。墙壁经过粉刷，已经看不出水淹的痕迹，一楼门窗和家具、电器也是新换的。阳光透过玻璃洒进两层小楼，亮堂堂的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李盟告诉总书记，当时洪水把一楼淹了，满屋都是淤泥。受灾后，政府给了补贴，一家人齐心协力恢复修缮，目前已经收拾一新。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“共产党是为人民服务的党。现在我们国家经济实力增强了，更要为人民多做事情。祝你们生活越过越幸福。”总书记说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;立冬刚过，燕赵大地，最低气温已在零摄氏度以下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10日下午，习近平总书记来到涿州受灾较严重的双塔街道永济秀园小区，首先察看了这里的热力站。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;得知小区已于11月1日提前半个月开始供暖，总书记十分高兴：“这是应该做的，你们做得很好！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记随后来到小区居民董彩英家看望。她家住在一楼。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一进屋，就感到了暖意。看了看温度计，又摸了摸暖气片，总书记笑着说：“这温度达标了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;指着白墙上的水迹，董彩英告诉总书记，当时家里也进了水，家具家电和一些衣服被褥被淹了。如今在党员干部帮助下，房子已完成清理修缮，温暖过冬没问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“看到你们转危为安，大灾之后生活可以照旧，而且还能提高一点，我感到很欣慰。”总书记说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;涿州市刁窝镇万全庄村位于兰沟洼蓄滞洪区，今年汛期全村311户全部受灾，不少房子被冲倒或严重受损。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10日下午，习近平总书记来到村子时，看到的是一片热火朝天的施工景象。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;村民付俊家新建的房子即将封顶。他热情地把总书记迎进未来的新居，详细介绍房屋内部结构：“这是朝阳的4间卧室，这是厨房，那边是卫生间……”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;付俊告诉总书记，房子受灾后，很快就收到了农房保险理赔款，钢筋、沙子、水泥等建材都有补贴优惠，政府还给担保联系了施工队，自己就下定决心尽快重建了。“党的政策好，赶上这个好时代，要不然就盖不起来了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;离开村子时，村民们聚拢到村道两旁，有白发老人，也有小孩子，纷纷热烈鼓掌、高声向总书记问好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总书记同乡亲们说：“我心里一直惦念着灾区的人民群众。今天，来这里看了看，心里踏实了，党中央的政策在各地转化为实际的举措，还是管用的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;听了总书记的话，大家又鼓起掌来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总书记接着说：“我从大家的表情看到了希望。我们灾后的生活比以前还会更好。希望乡亲们自力更生、艰苦奋斗，用自己的勤劳双手，加快恢复重建、推进乡村振兴。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“大涝大灾之后，务必大建大治”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年8月17日，就在防汛抗洪救灾斗争取得重大阶段性成果之际，习近平总书记主持召开中央政治局常委会会议，提出要认真排查总结，抓紧补短板、强弱项，进一步提升我国防灾减灾救灾能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;带着这样的思考，习近平总书记此次考察首站来到位于永定河官厅山峡出口处的三家店引水枢纽。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;通过这一控制性工程，永定河从山峦起伏的山区，奔流入一马平川的北京主城区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年夏天北京遭遇极端强降雨，永定河也迎来罕见洪峰。北京市水务局负责同志介绍，当时三家店引水枢纽调节池的最高蓄水位已经超过110米，洪水已经满溢上岸，拦河闸开启了建成以来最大泄洪流量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今夏洪水过后，北京市在灾后恢复重建工作中，立足治本之策，着力加强防洪工程体系建设，制定了有关总体规划，从河道疏浚修复、堤坝除险加固、布局建设水库等，致力于实现“一年基本恢复、三年全面提升、长远高质量发展”的目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记表示，经过一次灾害，就要总结经验，举一反三，使我们在防灾减灾救灾方面，有更完备的预案和更好的措施。我们现在的国力和经济实力也上来了，要用更强的力量来解决这个问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;汛情发生之后，华北地区广大干部群众抢抓“窗口期”，开展了农业生产自救。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在涿州考察时，习近平总书记中途下车，沿着田埂，走进刁窝镇的一片农田。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;田里，上个月刚播种的冬小麦已经出苗，一片葱绿，长势喜人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“墒情不错。”总书记赞道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一旁的菜地里，一棵棵白菜饱满青翠，总书记俯身摸了摸菜心：“已经长实了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;村干部介绍，当地的大白菜比较有名，销售到了北京、天津等周边地区。洪水退后，村里组织大家一共抢种了1000多亩，“霜降萝卜、立冬白菜”，有的白菜已经开始收了，销路和价格都很好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总书记叮嘱：“灾后农业生产恢复不仅直接关系家家户户的收入，也关系国家粮食安全。党的政策好就是要让老百姓高兴。要组织安排好今冬明春的农业生产，争取明年有个好收成。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;田地里，孕育着丰收的希望。街面上，升腾起勃勃生机。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在永济秀园小区门口，总书记先后走进一家药店和一家超市。“当时水淹到哪了？货品损失了多少？有什么补助政策？”问得十分仔细。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;得知政府给予贷款贴息，帮助两家商铺重新走上正轨、8月底恢复营业，总书记十分高兴，勉励道：“祝你们接下来经营得比以前还要好！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;涿州城东的白沟河治理工程，机械轰鸣，上百名工作人员正进行堤坝加固等施工。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记走上大堤，现场听取灾后重建重大水利工程的谋篇布局。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家发展改革委负责同志展开一幅规划图，详细介绍下一步华北地区加强水利工程建设的设想。为期3年的规划，涉及江河堤坝加固提升、病险水库除险、蓄滞洪区建设、城市排涝工程等，将系统提升华北地区防洪抗灾能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“大涝大灾之后，务必大建大治，大幅度提高水利设施、防汛设施水平。中国式现代化，也包括水利现代化、应急管理现代化。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;站在大堤上，望着宽阔的河道，总书记思虑深远：“最近中央决定增发1万亿元国债，下大功夫，花大本钱，用于支持灾后恢复重建和提升防灾减灾救灾能力的项目建设。相信通过建设，我们国家特别是北方地区的防灾减灾救灾能力会有一个大的提高。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“大力弘扬抗洪救灾精神”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;抗洪救灾中的感人故事，化作了最有说服力的现实“教材”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次灾情期间，妙峰山民族学校因地势较高，成为附近受灾村民安置、救援人员休整、抢险救灾物资设备中转的“安全岛”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;暑假经历了特大洪灾的孩子们，今天用他们亲手制作的黏土作品，感谢他们心中最可爱的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;教学楼一层的教室里，五年级一班学生在班主任老师带领下召开主题班会。黑板上写着“感恩”“立志”四个大字，班会的主题是“我身边的抗洪救灾故事”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记也加入进来，认真倾听。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一名女生站了起来：“我的作品是救援叔叔。当时我姥爷存放东西的地方被水淹了，救援叔叔很快就赶来帮忙，他们浑身都湿透了。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一名女生也拿起自己的作品：“我觉得解放军叔叔是最可爱的人。他们早出晚归，满身泥水倒头就睡，第二天天还没亮就又出去了，特别辛苦。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;手举白衣天使的黏土作品，一名男生讲述了自己在安置点看到的场景：“有一天，一位奶奶突发心脏病，几位医生赶紧取来仪器给奶奶做检查，还询问奶奶之前的身体状况，第一时间给奶奶治病。我要好好学习，长大后做一名医生，帮助更多的人摆脱病痛。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;看着这些懂事的孩子，总书记目光里充满温暖：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这次灾害，孩子们亲身经历，对一生都有重大影响。你们通过自己身边遇到的事，遇到的解放军、志愿者、村干部等等，就会看到，危难之际，我们党的各级组织和党员干部，都会为人民冲在第一线。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;学校操场上，习近平总书记亲切慰问了这次抗洪抢险救灾因公牺牲的烈士刘捷、熊丽的爱人和孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总书记紧紧握住他们的手，关切地说：“把家庭照顾好，把生活安排好，把孩子培养好。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记叮嘱道：“我们要永远怀念在抗洪抢险救灾中牺牲的烈士，宣扬他们的英勇事迹，关心照顾好他们的家人。要大力弘扬抗洪救灾精神，并将其发扬光大到各个方面工作中。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;精神，在斗争中升华；力量，在磨砺中凝聚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此次考察最后一站，白沟河畔的大堤上，“迷彩绿”“火焰蓝”“救援红”整齐列队。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记亲切看望慰问水利工程建设人员、曾经参加涿州抗洪救援的解放军和武警部队官兵、民兵预备役人员、消防救援队伍等方面的代表。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一方有难、八方支援，充分展现了我们党和国家的强大政治优势。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;面对士气高昂的“战士们”，习近平总书记的话语充满力量：“你们是中流砥柱。中国共产党领导的队伍，都是为人民服务的队伍。沧海横流，方显英雄本色！人民群众感谢你们，党和政府感谢你们！希望同志们继续努力，再立新功！”&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 明年1月1日起建立煤电容量电价机制]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/12/nw.D110000renmrb_20231112_5-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月12日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报北京11月11日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者刘志强）近日，为加快构建新型电力系统，更好保障电力安全稳定供应，推动新能源加快发展和能源绿色低碳转型，国家发展改革委、国家能源局联合印发《关于建立煤电容量电价机制的通知》，决定自2024年1月1日起建立煤电容量电价机制，对煤电实行两部制电价政策。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;通知提出，为适应煤电向基础保障性和系统调节性电源并重转型的新形势，决定将现行煤电单一制电价调整为两部制电价。其中，电量电价通过市场化方式形成，容量电价水平根据煤电转型进度等实际情况逐步调整，充分体现煤电对电力系统的支撑调节价值，更好保障电力系统安全运行。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;通知明确，对合规在运的公用煤电机组实行煤电容量电价政策，容量电价按照回收煤电机组一定比例固定成本的方式确定。其中，用于计算容量电价的煤电机组固定成本实行全国统一标准，为每年每千瓦330元；2024年至2025年，多数地方通过容量电价回收固定成本的比例为30%左右，部分煤电功能转型较快的地方适当高一些；2026年起，各地通过容量电价回收固定成本的比例提升至不低于50%。煤电容量电费纳入系统运行费用，每月由工商业用户按当月用电量比例分摊。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[03版要闻 - 推动中美关系重回健康稳定发展轨道]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/12/nw.D110000renmrb_20231112_1-03.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月12日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;应美国总统拜登邀请，国家主席习近平将于11月14日至17日赴美国旧金山举行中美元首会晤，同时应邀出席亚太经合组织第三十次领导人非正式会议。两国元首将就事关中美关系的战略性、全局性、方向性问题，以及事关世界和平与发展的重大问题深入沟通。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中美两国元首时隔一年后再次举行面对面会晤，国际社会高度关注。接受本报记者采访的各界人士表示，期待中美元首会晤能推动中美关系重回健康稳定发展轨道，为变乱交织的世界注入更多稳定性和正能量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“为加强彼此乃至国际间的团结协作提供重要机遇”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近一段时间，在双方共同努力下，中美关系出现了止跌企稳势头。国际社会期待中美两国在元首外交引领下持续推进互利合作，为推动世界经济复苏、政治解决国际和地区热点问题及应对全球性挑战注入新动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;耶鲁大学法学院蔡中曾中国中心高级研究员董云裳表示，美中两个大国领导人面对面沟通极为重要。国际社会期待美中提出各自关切，更加了解对方，避免陷入不必要的危机和冲突。“用&#39;竞争&#39;一词描述美中两国关系是不准确的，世界期待两国共同努力，为人类创造更加光明的美好未来。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“国际社会高度期待美中元首会晤，它有助于推动两国在不同领域积极合作。”美国北卡罗来纳大学教堂山分校教授克劳斯·拉瑞斯表示，美国和中国作为世界上主要大国，应该加强沟通交流，两国元首会晤值得称赞，“这是朝着发展建设性关系迈出的重要一步”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;约旦侯赛因·本·塔拉勒大学教授哈桑·达贾表示，去年11月，习近平主席同拜登总统在印度尼西亚巴厘岛举行会晤，达成一系列重要共识，为中美关系指明了方向。即将在美国旧金山举行的中美元首会晤意义重大，双方不仅将讨论事关中美关系的战略性、全局性、方向性问题，也将讨论事关世界和平与发展的重大问题，“这为加强彼此乃至国际间的团结协作提供重要机遇”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;泰国正大管理学院中国—东盟研究中心主任汤之敏表示，中美元首会晤将向世界发出一个信号，就是中美领导人将致力于将两国关系置于更加稳定和建设性的轨道上，两国能够管控分歧，避免和防止由于误解误判或激烈竞争演变成对抗甚至冲突。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国国际问题研究院美国研究所副所长苏晓晖说，国际社会高度关注中美元首会晤。本次会晤将对稳定中美大国关系，使之重回正轨产生积极作用。国际社会期待中美关系重回健康稳定发展轨道，期待两国能够在一系列重大问题上进行合作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“为稳定和改善两国关系注入新动力”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中美关系是世界上最重要的双边关系。中美两国如何相处，决定人类的前途和命运。正如习近平主席所说：“我们有一千条理由把中美关系搞好，没有一条理由把中美关系搞坏。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;复旦大学国际问题研究院院长吴心伯表示，即将举行的中美元首会晤对外释放了双方加强沟通交流和分歧管控的积极信号，增强了各方对中美关系止跌企稳的积极预期。最近一段时间，中美双方密集举行一系列民间交往活动，活跃了中美关系的社会氛围，为发出客观理性声音创造了平台，对于推动中美关系健康稳定发展具有积极意义。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“美中元首面对面会晤使得双方有机会将各自的问题和诉求传递给对方，实现双边关系的逐步改善。”克劳斯·拉瑞斯表示，对美中两国而言，落实元首会晤共识至关重要。例如，美中之间增加航班将促进学者、学生、游客等人员来往。只有两国人民多走动、多交流，才能增进对彼此国家文化、历史、经济等各方面的了解，这对两国关系的长远发展大有裨益。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;墨西哥国立自治大学国际关系中心研究员伊格纳西奥·马丁内斯表示，中美是世界上两个重要大国，中美元首会晤“将为稳定和改善两国关系注入新动力”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;智利天主教大学孔子学院智方院长何塞·路易斯·帕拉表示，中美两国元首会晤将有利于双方更好地交换看法，促进双方在全球经济疫后复苏、应对气候变化、解决地区热点问题等领域的合作。“期待通过此次中美元首会晤，两国关系及各领域合作能够取得更多建设性成果。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新加坡南洋理工大学拉惹勒南国际问题研究院副教授李明江表示，一个稳定的中美关系，对全球的和平与发展都具有重要意义。中美关系在最近这段时间有一些积极变化，处理两国关系，相互尊重、和平共处、合作共赢三原则是非常重要的。希望双方本着这些原则，进一步增强合作、推动两国关系稳定发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“有利于维护世界和平稳定和可持续发展”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中美两国是全球前两大经济体，经济总量超过世界1/3、人口总数占世界近1/4、双边贸易额约占世界1/5，双方利益交融十分紧密。双方加强沟通和合作，有助于推动世界增加稳定性和确定性，有助于推动世界和平与发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吴心伯认为，此次中美元首会晤将为双方聚焦共同利益创造机遇，有助于双方寻找经济发展的利益结合点，也有助于双方在涉及世界和平稳定的热点问题上加强沟通协调。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哈桑·达贾表示，中美关系是当今全球最重要的双边关系，双方寻求在利益交融的领域开展合作，同时有必要妥善管控分歧，合力应对全球性挑战，“双方保持建设性的沟通以及对话，有利于维护世界和平稳定和可持续发展”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“作为两个世界大国，中国和美国对世界和平、稳定与发展负有重要责任，也能够发挥关键作用。”阿联酋趋势研究与咨询中心高级研究员纳吉拉·阿扎鲁尼表示，元首外交在中美关系发展中发挥着不可替代的引领作用，“期待此次中美元首会晤能够推动中美关系进一步止跌企稳，为应对全球性挑战、促进全球发展繁荣注入更多正能量。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;汤之敏表示，中美元首巴厘岛会晤为中美关系指明了前进方向，也在国际上推动形成了中美关系趋稳向好的积极预期。东盟国家乐见稳定的中美关系，国际社会普遍期待本次中美元首会晤能够促进两国管控分歧和风险，恢复沟通和对话，引领世界和平和发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德国波恩大学全球研究中心主任辜学武表示：“这次中美元首会晤的重要意义在于，它将给世界增加更多的稳定性和确定性。中美两个世界大国能排除干扰，在尊重彼此核心关切、充分沟通交流的基础上寻求最大公约数，是一个极好的消息。期待双方在有关重大双边和全球性事务上达成共识，为世界注入更多正能量。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（本报北京、旧金山、阿布扎比、柏林、里约热内卢、墨西哥城、曼谷11月11日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;记者吴乐珺、张梦旭、胡泽曦、张朋辉、陈尚文、张博岚、杨一、管克江、刘仲华、宋亦然、彭敏、任皓宇、张矜若）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>