<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 《习近平关于基层治理论述摘编》出版发行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/23/nw.D110000renmrb_20231023_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Monday, October 23, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 22nd The book &quot;Excerpts of Essays on Grassroots Governance&quot; was recently published by the Central Literature Publishing House and distributed nationwide. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;If the grassroots are strong, the country will be strong, and if the grassroots are safe, the world will be safe. Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core has stood at the height of consolidating the Party&#39;s ruling foundation and safeguarding the security of national power, upholding and strengthening the Party&#39;s leadership of grassroots governance, and taking serving the people and benefiting the people as its starting point and goal. We must adhere to systemic governance, governance according to law, comprehensive governance, and source governance, strengthen the governance capacity of grassroots governments, build an urban and rural grassroots governance pattern of co-construction, co-governance, and sharing, stimulate grassroots vitality, enhance community capabilities, and form a stable and stable society for the people. Good order situation. Comrade Xi Jinping has published a series of important expositions on grassroots governance, with lofty intentions, rich connotations and profound thoughts. It is necessary to continuously improve the urban and rural grassroots governance system that combines autonomy, rule of law and morality under the leadership of party organizations, and to modernize the grassroots governance system and governance capabilities. , it is of great significance to build a social governance community in which everyone is responsible, everyone fulfills his responsibilities, and everyone enjoys it. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;&quot;Excerpts of Discussions&quot; is divided into 7 topics, with a total of 216 paragraphs of discussion, extracted from Comrade Xi Jinping&#39;s reports, speeches, explanations, congratulatory letters, replies, and instructions from November 15, 2012 to September 21, 2023. and 130 important documents. Some of these discussions are published publicly for the first time. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 总书记关心关爱“半边天”的故事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/23/nw.D110000renmrb_20231023_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Monday, October 23, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;In General Secretary Xi Jinping’s heart, women are the founders of human civilization and the promoters of social progress. Women’s cause has always been the party’s and an important part of the people&#39;s cause. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Chinese Dream is the dream of the Chinese nation and the dream of all women in China.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the new journey, every woman is the protagonist and has the opportunity to make a difference in life. .&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Development cannot be separated from women, and development must benefit all people, including women.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Emotionally encouraged again and again , to inspire the aspirations of women; each heart-warming measure unites the power of women. In the new era and the new journey, the majority of women will keep in mind General Secretary Xi Jinping’s instructions and strive to be builders of great causes, advocates of civilized trends, and strivers who dare to pursue dreams. They will brave the wind and waves, strive to be the first, and contribute magnificently to the construction of a strong country and national rejuvenation. The power of women. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Respect the status of women——&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“Women can hold up half the sky”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Women can hold up half the sky” Half the sky. How heroic these words are!&quot; On October 31, 2013, during a collective conversation with the new leadership team of the All-China Women&#39;s Federation, General Secretary Xi Jinping specifically recalled the &quot;eldest sisters&quot; who have made outstanding contributions in the history of the party. &quot; They: Soong Ching Ling, He Xiangning, Cai Chang, Deng Yingchao, Kang Keqing... He praised them as &quot;all models of a generation, and all heroines born in the torrent of the times.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Men and women ride side by side, like the sun in the east. Women are an important force in promoting social development and progress. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping profoundly pointed out: &quot;The pursuit of equality between men and women is a great cause. Throughout history, without the liberation and progress of women, there will be no liberation and progress of mankind.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It has always been General Secretary Xi Jinping not only respects the status of women and pays attention to protecting women&#39;s rights, but also practices it and uses actions to support and encourage every woman to pursue their dreams, make contributions, and write their own beautiful life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Every year on International Women’s Day, there is a spring promise. General Secretary Xi Jinping always sends holiday greetings to women, sending warm care and words of encouragement. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Applause for &quot;her&quot; moments of glory, and provide stronger support and protection for &quot;their&quot; work and life. Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping has delivered important speeches and issued important instructions on many occasions, advocating for safeguarding women&#39;s legitimate rights and interests and promoting the development of women&#39;s causes in our country -&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;We must ensure that Women&#39;s rights and interests have been systematically incorporated into laws and regulations, elevated to the will of the country, and internalized into social behavioral norms.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Increase attention, care, and support, severely crack down on illegal and criminal acts that infringe on women&#39;s rights, and protect women in accordance with the law. rights.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Pay more attention to the most ordinary women, especially women in need, pay special attention to poor women, disabled women, left-behind women and other needy women, do good deeds, solve problems, Do practical things.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Actively create conditions and build platforms for women to participate in economic and social development, protect the legitimate rights and interests of women and children, and strive to make respect for women and care for children a common practice throughout society.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;…………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Women’s Federation is the bridge and link between the party and the government and the women. In two collective talks with the new leadership team of the All-China Women&#39;s Federation, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized adhering to the basic national policy of gender equality and giving full play to the great role of my country&#39;s women, and put forward meticulous requirements for the work of the Women&#39;s Federation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out: &quot;Use your own eyes to see the most real situation, use your own ears to listen to the most real voices, and help the majority of women solve their problems.&quot; &quot;We must regard contacting and serving women as the lifeline of our work and become a A family member that a woman can trust, rely on, and cannot live without.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Adhere to the basic national policy of equality between men and women and protect the legitimate rights and interests of women and children. Rights and interests&quot; was written into the party&#39;s third historical resolution, enriching new connotations for the development of the party and the country&#39;s undertakings;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Formulating and implementing a series of laws and policies to promote gender equality and the all-round development of women, the country&#39;s &quot;Thirteenth Five-Year Plan&quot; The 14th Five-Year Plan outline has dedicated chapters to promote the development of women and children, and continuously improve and improve the legal system for the protection of women&#39;s rights and interests;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Convened the first mass work meeting of the Central Party Committee in the history of the Party to Women&#39;s work has been included in the overall layout of the party committee&#39;s work, and the reform of the Women&#39;s Federation has been regarded as an important task for comprehensively deepening the reform; Equal rights in all fields of politics, economy, culture, society and family life have been better realized. Respecting and caring for women has gradually become the will of the country, civic literacy and social fashion, inspiring every &quot;she&quot; to move forward bravely. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Every year at the National Two Sessions, female representatives and committee members performing their duties for the people are a beautiful sight; whenever there are major state affairs, the power of Chinese women has never been absent. At the critical moment of the fight against the epidemic, on the front lines of poverty alleviation and rural revitalization, at the forefront of scientific research, at the highest palace of national political discussions, on the big stage of grassroots governance, and in the small harbor of family construction...the heroines of the Chinese story have written This wonderful chapter fully demonstrates the self-esteem, self-confidence, self-reliance and self-improvement of women in the new era. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking across the country, hundreds of millions of women use their own development to mark the height of social civilization. In today&#39;s China, women not only have a more equal social status, but also have a broader space for development. Our country&#39;s women&#39;s cause has made historic achievements -&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The average life expectancy of women in our country has exceeded 80 years, which is longer than that of women in the world. The average level is 4 years higher;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The gender gap has basically been eliminated in the compulsory education stage, and the proportion of female students among undergraduate, junior college and postgraduate students in higher education exceeds that of male students;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The proportion of female employed personnel exceeds 40%, women account for about 1/3 of new businesses such as e-commerce and live broadcasting, and female scientific and technological workers account for 45.8%;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The proportions of female representatives to the 14th National People’s Congress and female members of the National Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference are respectively 26.54% and 22.4%, both record highs; women account for about 1/3 of enterprise employee directors, employee supervisors, and employee representative congresses; women account for 28.1% of the members of the new village committee, an increase of 7.1 compared with the previous one percentage points; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;44.16 million rural women have been lifted out of absolute poverty; the number of women participating in various social insurances has increased significantly; illegal crimes against women and children have been severely cracked down; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;“China has established a legal system that comprehensively protects women’s rights and interests, including more than 100 laws and regulations. It has been listed by the World Health Organization as one of the 10 countries with high performance in maternal and child health. It has basically eliminated the gender gap in compulsory education, and has Women account for more than 40% of social workers, and more than half of entrepreneurs in the Internet field are women.&quot; On October 1, 2020, at the high-level meeting of the United Nations General Assembly to commemorate the 25th anniversary of the World Conference on Women in Beijing, General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s words were sonorous and resonant. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The solemn promise that &quot;we must make unremitting efforts to open up a broad path for the development of women&#39;s careers&quot; is becoming a reality step by step. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Like struggling women - &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&quot;Every woman has the opportunity to excel in life and realize her dreams&quot;&lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;You are a heroine and a representative of women who hold up half the sky. Now you have become the &#39;image ambassador&#39; of Chinese women!&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the 2013 National Two Sessions, General Secretary Xi Jinping After attending the plenary meeting of the People&#39;s Liberation Army delegation at the first session of the 12th National People&#39;s Congress, they had a cordial exchange with Liu Yang, China&#39;s first female astronaut in space. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The new era is an era of strivers, and the advancement of women is the most beautiful scenery. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the process of the Chinese people’s pursuit of a better life, every woman has the opportunity to excel in life and realize her dreams.” General Secretary Xi Jinping’s firm and powerful words inspire every struggling woman. New era women. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In October 2015, Tu Youyou won the Nobel Prize in Physiology or Medicine. In his New Year&#39;s message in 2016, General Secretary Xi Jinping specifically mentioned Tu Youyou and praised that &quot;as long as you persist, dreams can always be realized.&quot; In September 2019, General Secretary Xi Jinping awarded Tu Youyou the &quot;Medal of the Republic.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In September 2019, on the occasion of the 70th anniversary of the founding of the People&#39;s Republic of China, the Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team defended the World Cup with a complete victory. General Secretary Xi Jinping specially invited representatives of the Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team members and coaches to attend a reception celebrating the 70th anniversary of the founding of the People&#39;s Republic of China, and cordially met with representatives of the women&#39;s volleyball team before the meeting. The general secretary praised the Chinese women&#39;s volleyball team and its spirit: &quot;The spirit of the women&#39;s volleyball team represents the spirit of an era and shouts out the strongest voice of the era in fighting for the rise of China.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;As long as I still have breath, I will Stand on the podium, give your all, give everything, and have no regrets even if you die nine times.&quot; On June 29, 2021, the &quot;July 1 Medal&quot; award ceremony was held to celebrate the 100th anniversary of the founding of the Communist Party of China, the Party Committee of Huaping Girls&#39; High School, Lijiang, Yunnan Province Zhang Guimei, branch secretary, principal and director of Huaping County Children&#39;s Welfare Institute, spoke from the bottom of her heart. General Secretary Xi Jinping looked at her with warm and kind eyes. Previously, at the National Poverty Alleviation Summary and Commendation Conference, the General Secretary bent down and solemnly awarded a medal to Zhang Guimei, who was sitting in a wheelchair. &quot;Dedicate yourself to education to alleviate poverty and ignite the hope of girls in Dashan.&quot; When delivering an important speech, the General Secretary especially praised her advanced deeds. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Everyone is amazing. As long as you work hard and diligently, you can achieve extraordinary results in ordinary positions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping often encourages women to seize opportunities, strive for excellence, and achieve excellence in life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On April 24, 2016, General Secretary Xi Jinping visited Dawan Village, Jinzhai County, Lu&#39;an City, Anhui Province, located in the hinterland of the Dabie Mountains, and held a symposium in the courtyard of Chen Zeshen, a poor household. At the meeting, Yu Jing, then captain of the poverty alleviation work team, made a solemn promise to the General Secretary: &quot;If no household in Dawan Village is lifted out of poverty, I will not resign.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Find out the advantages and characteristics, develop the tea industry, and Strengthen the planting and breeding industry, and develop the tourism industry... Under the leadership of &quot;Iron Lady&quot; Yu Jing, Dawan Village, a well-known poor mountain village, has embarked on the fast track of rural revitalization and development that combines red and green, tea and tourism, and has successfully achieved &quot;Counterattack&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I will continue to lead the people of Dawan Village to strive and work hard on the road of rural revitalization!” Yu Jing said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On October 1, 2020, at the high-level meeting of the United Nations General Assembly commemorating the 25th anniversary of the World Conference on Women in Beijing, General Secretary Xi Jinping delivered an important speech via video, telling the story of a young Chinese nurse born in the 2000s. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“At the most critical moment in China’s fight against the COVID-19 epidemic, two-thirds of the more than 40,000 medical staff from all over China rushing to aid Hubei were women. A young nurse from Guangdong Province also Under 20 years old. The reporter asked her, are you still a child and still need help from others? She replied, if I put on protective clothing, I will no longer be a child. This conversation moved the whole of China!&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This The nurse is named Liu Jiayi. She is the youngest member of the Guangdong Provincial Medical Team to Aid Hubei. She is also the epitome of Chinese women fighting on all fronts during the fight against the epidemic. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is thousands of Chinese women like this, wearing white clothes and holding armor, going against the trend of the times, interpreting the benevolence of doctors with courage and hard work, and winning the world with their responsibility and dedication.” President Xi Jinping The secretary expressed deep praise for the vast number of female medical staff, disease control personnel, scientific and technological personnel, community workers, volunteers, etc. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One by one, &quot;she&quot; writes extraordinary achievements in all walks of life with the pride and struggle of women. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This year’s National People’s Congress, Zhuo Changli, a representative of the National People’s Congress and the leader of the “Sunshine Sister” team in Jinan, Shandong Province, stood out among the representatives in orange-red work clothes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhuo Changli once had mixed feelings about this piece of workwear that has been with him for decades: &quot;In the past, the society always thought that domestic workers were &#39;nannies&#39; and inferior. But now I feel this The value and sense of honor of the profession.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In November 2013, at the Jinan Comprehensive Service Center for Migrant Workers, General Secretary Xi Jinping, who came for an inspection, had a cordial meeting with the staff of the window unit and the migrant workers who came to handle matters. During the conversation, Zhuo Changli was among them. At that time, Zhuo Changli, who was starting his own business for the second time, led his sisters to engage in the housekeeping industry. &quot;The General Secretary said that &#39;domestic service has great potential,&#39; which made my heart warm up all of a sudden.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the National Two Sessions in 2018, Zhuo Changli, as a representative of the National People&#39;s Congress, once again reported &quot;Sunshine&quot; to the General Secretary in person. The development of &quot;Big Sister&quot;. On that day, she specially put on her work clothes, &quot;The General Secretary said that the housekeeping industry is like the name &#39;Sister Sunshine&#39;, it is a sunrise industry, and he encouraged us to do this mutually beneficial and win-win work well and turn it into a love project. ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The General Secretary’s encouragement made Zhuo Changli more determined in his choice to do housekeeping service as a career. Nowadays, &quot;Sister Sunshine&quot; has spread from Jinan to the whole country, and the number of domestic helpers has grown to more than 70,000 people, more than three times the size in 2013. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We must unite the power of women, pool their wisdom, respect and care for women, and guide women to actively participate in the great practice of the new era and new journey, so as to comprehensively build a modern socialist country and comprehensively promote the greatness of the Chinese nation. Make new and greater contributions to China&#39;s rejuvenation.&quot; On March 6 this year, at the joint meeting of the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference, General Secretary Xi Jinping said earnestly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Winning gold and silver in sports arenas, traveling in space to build a galaxy of dreams, preaching and teaching from a three-foot podium, spreading hope in rural fields, and climbing to new heights in scientific research... Today, on the vast social stage, &quot;her power&quot; &quot;Growing toward the sun, the sonorous roses bloomed to their fullest. &quot;They&quot; continued to strive for self-improvement in innovation, pioneering in creation, and worked hard in entrepreneurship, showing the unique style of women in the new era. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Focus on family education and family tradition - &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“Strive to make thousands of families the key to national development, national progress and social harmony. &quot;Important basic point&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The foundation of the world lies in the country, and the foundation of the country lies at home.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Chinese nation has valued family since ancient times. A harmonious family means a stable society, a happy family means a peaceful society, and a civilized family means a civilized society. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping attaches great importance to family construction, pays attention to the family, pays attention to family education, pays attention to family tradition, fully affirms the role of women in the construction of family virtues, and emphasizes &quot;to give full play to the unique role of women and promote the implementation of socialist core values ​​​​in the family root&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The thread is in the hands of a loving mother, and the clothes are on the body of a wanderer. There is a tight seam before leaving, and I am afraid that I will return late. Whoever speaks an inch of grass will be rewarded with three rays of spring.&quot; On the eve of the Spring Festival in 2015, General Secretary Xi Jinping said at the Spring Festival At the group visit, poet Meng Jiao&#39;s famous poem &quot;The Wandering Son&quot; was quoted, revealing a deep family complex. The General Secretary emphasized that no matter how much the times change, no matter how much the life pattern changes, we must pay attention to family construction, family, family education, and family tradition. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A family is the smallest country, and a country is composed of thousands of families. During the revolutionary war years, mothers taught their children to fight in Japan, and their wives sent their husbands to the battlefield. During the period of socialist construction, they prioritized the family before the small family, and left the small family for everyone. These all reflected the upward pursuit of the family and the noble feelings of family and country. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When I was a child, my mother told stories about serving the country with loyalty and tattooing my mother-in-law, which made the General Secretary unforgettable. &quot;I said, it hurt to tattoo the words on it! My mother said, it hurt, but she remembered it in her heart. I have remembered the words &#39;Serve the Country with Loyalty&#39; from that time until now. It is also what I have pursued throughout my life. Goal.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On December 12, 2016, the atmosphere was warm in the front hall of the conference building of Jingxi Hotel. General Secretary Xi Jinping met with representatives of the first national civilized family here and praised their deeds as &quot;warming people&#39;s hearts. They have interpreted civilization, spread positive energy, and set an example for the whole society.&quot; I praised them emotionally, &quot;They are all good!&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;We must pay attention to the construction of family civilization and strive to make millions Ten thousand families have become an important starting point for national development, national progress, and social harmony, and a place where people&#39;s dreams can set sail.&quot; The general secretary&#39;s important speech spread throughout the country. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Family education involves many aspects, but the most important thing is moral education, which is the education of how to behave. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On September 26, 2013, when meeting with the winners of the 4th National Moral Model and Nomination Award, General Secretary Xi Jinping turned his attention to an old man sitting on the left side of the first row. The general secretary said affectionately: &quot;I just saw this old lady. She is Gong Quanzhen, the wife of our veteran general Gan Zuchang. She is over 90 years old this year. I was deeply moved after seeing her.&quot;&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;In 1957, Gong Quanzhen gave up urban life and followed her husband back to her hometown. With her meager wages, she built water conservancy projects, power stations, and school buildings for her hometown to help the poor. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping said: &quot;More than half a century has passed, Comrade Gong Quanzhen has always maintained the spirit of hard work and was elected as a national moral model. I am very pleased to attend our meeting today. I would like to express my sincere gratitude to Comrade Gong Quanzhen I pay my highest respect.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized that we must carry forward this spirit of hard work, not only for our generation, but also for our next generation, and to pass it on from generation to generation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core has attached great importance to the construction of family civilization and promoted the high-quality development of family education and family tradition in the new era——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Ten The Fourth Five-Year Plan outline has a special section on &quot;strengthening family construction&quot; for the first time; the Civil Code establishes the principle provisions that &quot;families should establish good family traditions, promote family virtues, and pay attention to the construction of family civilization&quot;; seven departments issued &quot;On Further Strengthening Family Education and Family Traditions&quot; Implementation Opinions on the Construction of Family Civilization&quot;, and the Central Civilization Commission issued the &quot;Opinions on Deepening the Construction of Family Civilization&quot;; 31 provinces, autonomous regions and municipalities have established multi-departmental coordination working mechanisms for family work, and 24 provinces, autonomous regions and municipalities have established special funds for family work. Party and government-led The family work mechanism is gradually improved...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hold various family tradition story sharing meetings, jointly carry out clean family tradition themed activities, continue to promote the pilot work of changing customs, and deepen the creation of green families... Women&#39;s federation organizations at all levels vigorously implement The &quot;Every Family Happiness and Health Project&quot; has carried out regular and widespread activities to find the &quot;most beautiful family&quot; and promoted the formation of a new trend of socialist family civilization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At present, 14.84 million &quot;most beautiful families&quot; have emerged across the country. Family relationships in the new era of equality, harmony, and civilization have been generally established, and core socialist values ​​have taken root in the majority of families. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Family is the first school in life, and parents are their children’s first teachers. General Secretary Xi Jinping encouraged everyone: &quot;Teach children the &#39;first lesson in life&#39; and help them buckle the first button of life.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On November 2, 2018, General Secretary Xi Jinping spoke with the All-China Women&#39;s Federation Members of the new leadership team pointed out in a collective conversation: &quot;In the report of the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, I proposed the strategic task of cultivating new people of the era who will take on the responsibility of national rejuvenation. The Women&#39;s Federation must focus on this major issue and find the right moral principles in family work. It is an entry point for cultivating people and helping children to button the first button of life.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March 2014, General Secretary Xi Jinping met Jiao Yulu’s five children when he revisited Lankao. The second daughter Jiao Shouyun said to the General Secretary: &quot;We must inherit our father&#39;s spirit and maintain the family tradition of tutoring.&quot; After hearing this, the General Secretary nodded and said: &quot;Good family tradition, good family tradition.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Family tradition and tutoring are the most precious wealth of a family, and family civilization is the cornerstone of social civilization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Always maintain a pure heart and have a strong sense of family and country, which will provide you with inexhaustible motivation for struggle and lofty goals for progress. The progress of each family will definitely add up to the progress of the country; the value created by each family will definitely bring together the great power of national rejuvenation. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 巾帼之花绽放新时代]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/23/nw.D110000renmrb_20231023_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Monday, October 23, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Youth blooms in the sunshine; women show the style of the times. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core has, based on the overall development of the party and the country&#39;s undertakings, cared for the all-round development of women, planned and deployed to promote women&#39;s work, and inspired hundreds of millions of women to realize the goals of the Chinese nation. On the new journey of national rejuvenation, we must hold our heads high and strive to pursue our dreams. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;“Women’s cause has always been an important part of the cause of the Party and the people”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;February 25, 2021, Great Hall of the People in Beijing. The National Poverty Alleviation Summary and Commendation Conference was grandly held here. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the podium, General Secretary Xi Jinping leaned over and solemnly awarded the medal to Zhang Guimei, who was sitting in a wheelchair. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Take care of yourself!” the general secretary said with concern. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite suffering from illness, Zhang Guimei, the principal of Huaping Girls&#39; Senior High School in Lijiang, Yunnan, has used her hands to support more than 2,000 mountainous girls to study in the past 10 years. The General Secretary praised her deeds: &quot;Dedicated to education and poverty alleviation, igniting hope for girls in the mountains.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than four months later, she used her plastered hands to &quot;hold&quot; the &quot;July 1st Medal&quot;, which represents the party&#39;s highest honor. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the name of the country, we pay tribute to the heroes. On the journey of Chinese-style modernization, the dazzling light of women&#39;s role models shines; in the history of the Republic, the outstanding achievements of &quot;Half the Sky&quot; are engraved! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Our party has led the people in the glorious journey of unremitting struggle. Every victory has the active participation and outstanding contribution of women.” General Secretary Xi Jinping’s words are profound and meaningful. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For more than 100 years, in various historical periods of revolution, construction, and reform, the Communist Party of China has always insisted on writing the realization of women&#39;s liberation and development and the realization of equality between men and women on its struggle banner, and has always regarded the majority of women as An important force that promotes the development of the cause of the party and the people, it has always placed women&#39;s work in an important position, opened up a path for the development of socialist women with Chinese characteristics, and led the majority of women to write a wonderful chapter of sharing the fate of the motherland and struggling with the people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Women can hold up half the sky. How heroic this sentence is!” In the mind of General Secretary Xi Jinping, women are not inferior to men, and the power of women is limitless. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On March 8, 1990, Xi Jinping, then Secretary of the Ningde Prefectural Committee, published an article in the Mindong Newspaper entitled &quot;Women are a great force in promoting social development - for the &quot;March 8th&quot; International Working Women The article &quot;Working with Section&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The article writes, &quot;History and reality tell us that women, who account for more than half of the population, are a great force promoting the development of the entire society. The victory of each of our undertakings includes the hard work of women.&quot; . Between the lines, there is praise and encouragement for fellow women. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Happy holidays! You are all in good spirits today.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On March 8, 2013, during the National Two Sessions, General Secretary Xi Jinping cordially visited the Jiangsu delegation when participating in the deliberation The female representatives said to everyone: &quot;Female representatives are the best among women. I hope you will give full play to your leading role.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the spring of March, women usher in their own festival. Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping’s sincere holiday blessings have arrived as scheduled every year at this time. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping is very concerned about the development of women’s causes. Based on the present and focusing on the future, the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core has made a series of groundbreaking, overall, and long-term major decisions and arrangements:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Adhere to the basic national policy of equality between men and women and protect the legitimate rights and interests of women and children.&quot; &quot;Written into the reports of the 18th, 19th and 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Pay attention to the construction of family education and family tradition, and protect the rights and interests of women and children&quot; was written into the third historical resolution of the Party;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;The Fourth Plenary Session of the 19th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China clearly stated that &quot;uphold and improve the institutional mechanisms for promoting equality between men and women and the all-round development of women&quot;;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;October 2013 On March 31, General Secretary Xi Jinping held a collective conversation with the new leadership team of the All-China Women&#39;s Federation, pointing out the way forward for the development of women&#39;s causes in the new era - &quot;Achieve the goals and tasks put forward by the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, and achieve The great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation is the overall work of the party and the country, and is also the theme of the contemporary Chinese women&#39;s movement.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the new era and new journey, the development of women&#39;s cause has been given a new era connotation, and hundreds of millions of women shoulder the greater responsibility of the times. important mission. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At 23:57 on November 1, 2018, as the 41st Beidou navigation satellite successfully launched into space, thunderous applause erupted in the command hall. Colleagues gave Zhang Runhong a thumbs up and praised her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The sonorous command for the satellite launch was given by 36-year-old Zhang Runhong. This is the first time in China&#39;s aerospace history that a woman has served as the &quot;01&quot; commander. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the eve of the Spring Festival that year, General Secretary Xi Jinping came to a base of the army stationed in Sichuan to visit and express condolences to the officers and soldiers. Zhang Runhong, who was in the team, reported his ambitions to the General Secretary:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Report Chairman, I also have a goal, which is to become the first female commander of &#39;01&#39; in our country.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Commander &#39;01&#39; can undertake such a heavy scientific research task. This is also a symbol of the cause of women in our country. , I also hope you can achieve your goal as soon as possible.&quot; The general secretary happily encouraged Zhang Runhong. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Heroes strive to realize their dreams, and the development of women&#39;s careers in the new era shows a new look. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“We must make unremitting efforts to open up a broad path for the development of women’s causes”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On April 19, 2007, Comrade Xi Jinping served as Secretary of the Shanghai Municipal Party Committee for less than One month later, I made a special trip to the Shanghai Women&#39;s Federation for investigation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As soon as he entered the conference room, he shook hands with each of us.” Recalling the scene that year, Zhang Lili, then secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Shanghai Women’s Federation, could not conceal her excitement. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Women hold up half of the sky. If we do half of this well, it will affect the overall situation and the whole.” Comrade Xi Jinping’s exhortation made Zhang Lili and other comrades present feel the great responsibility. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The care is consistent and the feelings are deep and long-lasting. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping has profoundly pointed out: “Doing a good job in the party’s women’s work is related to uniting and cohesion of the vast number of women who account for half of our country’s population, and is related to providing strong support for the development of the cause of the party and the people. Strength is related to consolidating the class foundation and mass foundation of the party&#39;s governance.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From ensuring women’s basic medical and health services to enhancing women’s ability to participate in political and economic activities; from developing vocational education and lifelong education for women to carrying out international development cooperation in the field of women; from formulating the Outline for the Development of Chinese Women (2021-2030)&quot;, to the revision of the Law on the Protection of Women&#39;s Rights and Interests... The Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core has always attached great importance to the comprehensive development of women, leading the majority of women to release their creative vitality and realize the value of life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Housekeeping services have great potential” - General Secretary Xi Jinping’s words during an inspection at the Jinan Comprehensive Service Center for Migrant Workers in November 2013 strengthened the determination of Zhuo Changli, a housekeeping practitioner: “ The general secretary’s encouragement made my heart warm up all of a sudden!”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Care turns into motivation, and hope inspires action. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Today, the &quot;Sunshine Sister&quot; housekeeping service company founded by Zhuo Changli has spread from Jinan to the whole country, and its team of housekeeping attendants has grown to more than 70,000 people. Zhuo Changli and his sisters also changed their destiny and realized their value in the process of serving the society. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the process of the Chinese people’s pursuit of a better life, every woman has the opportunity to excel in life and realize her dreams.” Listening to women’s voices and respecting women’s wishes, General Secretary Xi Jinping’s affectionate entrustment, gives The confidence and strength of women to move forward and pursue their dreams. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping attaches special importance to the training of female cadres. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“That meeting was really good. Comrade Xi Jinping’s care became the motivation for us to walk a good life.” Thirty years have passed, and retired female cadre Zhu Hua is always grateful. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 1993, the Fuzhou Women&#39;s Federation held a symposium for female cadres and invited Xi Jinping, then Secretary of the Fuzhou Municipal Party Committee, to attend and provide guidance. Comrade Xi Jinping stated at the meeting that women&#39;s participation in politics is a sign of social civilization, women&#39;s liberation and the superiority of the socialist system. Accelerating the training of women cadres is a need to speed up reform, opening up and economic construction, and is also an important part of our party&#39;s organizational work. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The more than 20 female cadres who attended the meeting were greatly encouraged. Through their own efforts, they have successively stepped into important positions and played a backbone role. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The status of women is one of the important indicators to measure the level of civilization in a society. We must understand the characteristics of women cadres and care for them. We hope that women cadres can establish the spirit of self-esteem, self-confidence, self-reliance, and self-improvement, and boldly commence to work&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a collective conversation with members of the new leadership team of the All-China Women&#39;s Federation, she emphasized &quot;care for their growth and create a broad stage for more female talents to stand out&quot;; at the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, she emphasized &quot;paying attention to the training of female cadres&quot; selection work, giving full play to the important role of female cadres”... Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping has encouraged and supported women to participate in economic and social development practices and contribute to the construction of a strong country and national rejuvenation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Old aunt, you are here too.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the eve of the 2016 Lunar New Year, General Secretary Xi Jinping, who was inspecting Jinggangshan, came to the Bajiaolou Shende Bookstore and recognized him as soon as he entered the door. Gong Quanzhen. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than two years ago, when meeting with the winners of the 4th National Moral Model and Nomination Award, General Secretary Xi Jinping specially introduced to the participants: This old senior is Gong Quanzhen, the wife of veteran general Gan Zuchang. She is over 90 years old, and I was deeply moved after seeing her. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I had this text when I was a primary school student. The content is about generals becoming farmers. We are deeply affected.” General Secretary Xi Jinping said that half a century later, Mr. Gong still carries forward this spirit. This spirit of hard work should not only be passed down by our generation, but also carried forward by the next generation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A family is the smallest country, and a country is composed of thousands of families. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Women should play a greater role in society and a key role in the family.” General Secretary Xi Jinping attaches great importance to the unique role of women in promoting the family virtues of the Chinese nation and establishing good family traditions. , to promote the harmony of small families to jointly build the harmony of the large society. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the tide of the times moves forward, how can the Women’s Federation continue to be a good “parental family” for hundreds of millions of women? How to keep women&#39;s work fresh and full of vitality? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In July 2015, General Secretary Xi Jinping presided over the first mass working meeting of the Central Party Committee in the history of the party, which kicked off the Women&#39;s Federation&#39;s deepening reform. One year later, the &quot;All-China Women&#39;s Federation Reform Plan&quot; was issued, and a series of major measures were taken to continuously enhance the political, progressive, and mass nature of the Women&#39;s Federation organization, allowing &quot;family members&quot; to speak up, defend their rights, and serve women when they need it. Do more practical and good things for women. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The &quot;Women Lecture&quot; has reached more than 1.5 billion people online and offline, and a large number of advanced models, including more than 4,000 national March 8th red flag bearers, convey the power of role models; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1.08 million women&#39;s groups, 900,000 &quot;women&#39;s homes&quot; and &quot;women&#39;s micro-homes&quot; are spread throughout urban and rural communities; nearly 7 million executive members of women&#39;s federations at all levels are active at the grassroots level and serve women;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Official cadres regularly go to the grassroots and visit households Pair up to solve practical difficulties for women; the Online Women’s Federation has been upgraded and developed to create a 24-hour “online home” for women; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We want Make unremitting efforts to open up a broad path for the development of women&#39;s causes&quot; - a solemn commitment made by the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping at the core, is constantly turning into a beautiful reality. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;“Every woman is a writer of the times and a striver to pursue dreams”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The COVID-19 epidemic struck suddenly. Liu Jiayi, a female nurse born in the 2000s of the Guangdong Provincial Medical Aid Team to Hubei, plunged into Wuhan during the &quot;storm&quot;. She said: &quot;When I put on protective clothing, I am no longer a child.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This sentence moved China and the world. On October 1, 2020, General Secretary Xi Jinping told the world the story of this female nurse at the high-level meeting of the United Nations General Assembly commemorating the 25th anniversary of the World Conference on Women in Beijing -&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;It is the story of thousands of这样的中国女性，白衣执甲，逆行而上，以勇气和辛劳诠释了医者仁心，用担当和奉献换来了山河无恙。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国有大事，中国女性从未缺席。在抗击新冠疫情的紧急关头，在脱贫攻坚和乡村振兴的火热一线，在科研攻关的前沿阵地……广大妇女无私无畏、甘于奉献，谱写了壮丽的巾帼华章。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;做伟大事业的建设者，为国为民、发光发亮——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021年7月21日，在西藏林芝市嘎拉村便民服务中心，习近平总书记见到了90后女村官黄海芬。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;得知这位潮汕女孩大学毕业后放弃白领工作，到雪域高原安了家，习近平总书记勉励她：“从沿海到高原，这里需要人啊，你在这边好好干。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谆谆嘱托，如春风拂过心田。黄海芬无悔选择，决意将青春挥洒在党和人民最需要的地方。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2020年9月11日，在科学家座谈会上，长期从事古遗传学研究的80后女科学家付巧妹向总书记坦言：“经常有人问，&#39;你的研究有什么用&#39;。我曾在实验室很难维持的时候，也想过要不要去做热门研究……”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总书记听了以后深有感触地说：“对冷门怎么看？按一般概念，一些冷门的东西没有用。这种认识可能把一个领域的事业耽搁了。做科研事业的评估，要有长远的眼光、世界的眼光、科学的眼光。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;铭记总书记的鼓励，付巧妹甘坐“冷板凳”，带领团队继续在古基因组研究领域潜心钻研。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;个人“小我”融入党和国家“大我”，广大妇女自立自强、锐意进取，为国家各项事业发展贡献智慧和力量。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;做文明风尚的倡导者，赓续传统、弘扬美德——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021年6月29日上午，北京人民大会堂，党中央首次颁授“七一勋章”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“王兰花，你又来了啊，光荣地又来了。”看到前一年赴宁夏考察时见过的这位老人走上台，习近平总书记亲切打招呼。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;70多岁的王兰花是宁夏吴忠市金花园社区志愿者带头人，在社区里被称为“活雷锋”。她说，遇到困难的时候，常会想起总书记说过的“社会主义是干出来的”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从只有7个人的“王兰花热心小组”到超9.5万人的志愿者队伍，年逾古稀的王兰花领着一群热心大妈，走上了越来越宽广的“爱心大道”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“兰花芬芳”，行胜于言。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;清晨，贵州省黔西市化屋村一派忙碌景象。非遗工坊里，绣娘们飞针走线，正赶制一批苗绣服饰订单。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021年2月3日，习近平总书记来到化屋村。非遗传承人彭艺向总书记讲述了自己回乡创业发展苗绣技艺的经历。总书记肯定道：“苗绣既是传统的也是时尚的，你们一针一线绣出来，何其精彩！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;牢记总书记“一定要把苗绣发扬光大”的勉励，彭艺不仅为当地妇女学习苗绣技艺提供平台，也积极探索苗绣的创新发展，让古老苗绣焕发新的活力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;黎锦、藤编、加牙藏毯……在地方考察调研中，总书记同许多女性非遗传承人有过交流。殷殷期许，激励广大妇女以自信姿态将中华优秀传统文化代代相传。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;做敢于追梦的奋斗者，顽强拼搏、奋发进取——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2019年女排世界杯9月14日至29日在日本举行，中国女排不畏强手、敢打敢拼，以十一连胜的骄人成绩夺得冠军，成功卫冕。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在庆祝新中国70周年华诞之际，习近平总书记专门邀请刚刚夺冠的中国女排队员参加国庆招待会，并在会前亲切会见了女排代表。总书记称赞道：“你们在赛场上展现了祖国至上、团结协作、顽强拼搏、永不言败的精神面貌。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023年10月7日，杭州亚运会，中国女排再创佳绩，以六战全胜第九次摘得亚运金牌。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谆谆话语、殷殷嘱托，激励女排姑娘们叱咤赛场，鼓舞亿万妇女昂扬奋进，以最美的姿态逐梦复兴征途。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2012年，刘洋踏上飞天征程，中国女性首次徜徉浩瀚宇宙。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你可是巾帼英雄啊，也是妇女能顶半边天的代表，现在还成了中国妇女的&#39;形象大使&#39;！”2013年全国两会期间，习近平总书记亲切称赞刘洋。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们幸运地赶上了国家发展的好时代，我们一定会将祖国的荣誉写满太空！”刘洋坚定地说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十年如一日，刘洋全力投入备战训练。 2022年，她随神舟十四号载人飞船再叩苍穹。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;海阔凭鱼跃，天高任鸟飞。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“新征程上，每一位妇女都是时代的书写人、追梦的奋斗者。要凝聚巾帼之力、汇集巾帼之智，尊重和关爱妇女，引导广大妇女积极投身新时代新征程的伟大实践，为全面建设社会主义现代化国家、全面推进中华民族伟大复兴作出新的更大贡献。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在以习近平同志为核心的党中央坚强领导下，广大妇女心怀伟大时代赋予的美好梦想，以巾帼不让须眉的豪情和实干，在新征程广阔天地建功立业、续写荣光。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（新华社北京10月22日电）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 推动共建“一带一路”进入高质量发展的新阶段]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/23/nw.D110000renmrb_20231023_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月23日星期一&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;“我们追求的不是中国独善其身的现代化，而是期待同广大发展中国家在内的各国一道，共同实现现代化。”习近平主席在第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛开幕式上发表主旨演讲，强调“中方愿同各方深化&#39;一带一路&#39;合作伙伴关系，推动共建&#39;一带一路&#39;进入高质量发展的新阶段，为实现世界各国的现代化作出不懈努力”，郑重宣布了中国支持高质量共建“一带一路”的八项行动，为“一带一路”明确了新方向，开辟了新愿景，注入了新动力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今天的中国，正在以中国式现代化全面推进强国建设、民族复兴伟业。中国式现代化既造福中国人民、又促进世界共同发展，是我们强国建设、民族复兴的康庄大道，也是中国谋求人类进步、世界大同的必由之路。中国始终把自身命运同各国人民的命运紧紧联系在一起，努力以中国式现代化新成就为世界发展提供新机遇，为人类对现代化道路的探索提供新助力，为人类社会现代化理论和实践创新作出新贡献。共建“一带一路”既是中国扩大开放的重大举措，旨在以更高水平开放促进更高质量发展，与世界分享中国发展机遇；也是破解全球发展难题的中国方案，旨在推动各国共同走向现代化，推进更有活力、更加包容、更可持续的经济全球化进程，让发展成果更多更公平地惠及各国人民。 10年来，共建“一带一路”不仅给相关国家带来实实在在的利益，也为推进经济全球化健康发展、破解全球发展难题和完善全球治理体系作出积极贡献，开辟了人类共同实现现代化的新路径，是各国共同走向现代化之路，也是人类通向美好未来的希望之路。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;构建“一带一路”立体互联互通网络；支持建设开放型世界经济；开展务实合作；促进绿色发展；推动科技创新；支持民间交往；建设廉洁之路；完善“一带一路”国际合作机制。习近平主席宣布中国支持高质量共建“一带一路”的这八项行动，是推动共建“一带一路”进入高质量发展的新阶段、推动实现世界各国的现代化的务实举措，得到各方积极响应和支持。这次高峰论坛形成的最重要共识，就是开启高质量共建“一带一路”新阶段。大家都支持进一步深化互联互通，建设高质量、可持续、有韧性的基础设施，不断提升基础设施软联通水平，构建开放型世界经济。大家都主张加快建设“数字丝绸之路”，促进人工智能健康有序安全发展。大家都认为应深耕“绿色丝绸之路”，合力应对气候变化挑战，加强生物多样性保护，建立绿色发展投融资伙伴关系，为绿色发展赋能。大家都期待全面推进务实合作，促进贸易和投资自由化便利化，优化营商环境，发展蓝色经济，建设廉洁丝路，深化地方交流，开展丰富多彩的人文交流活动。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;推动共建“一带一路”进入高质量发展的新阶段，这对引领新形势下国际合作和全球发展具有重要意义。这将是亚欧大陆立体联通的新阶段，我们提出从五个方面支持构建亚欧大陆立体互联互通网络，包括加强以中欧班列为基础的铁路互联互通，开辟以公路直达运输为支撑的亚欧大陆物流新通道，建设跨里海国际运输走廊，推进“丝路海运”和陆海新通道以及建设中欧空中丝绸之路。这将是绿色丝绸之路引领的新阶段，我们将与各方在绿色基建、绿色能源、绿色交通等领域深化合作，加大对“一带一路”绿色发展国际联盟的支持，落实“一带一路”绿色投资原则，让绿色发展成为“一带一路”的鲜明旗帜。这将是数字丝绸之路赋能的新阶段，我们将与各方共同营造开放、公平、非歧视的数字经济发展环境，推动数字技术和实体经济深度融合，缩小数字鸿沟。这将是中国同各国携手实现世界现代化的新阶段，我们将通过共建“一带一路”促进中国经济和世界经济更深融合发展，坚定致力于建设开放型世界经济，共同实现和平发展、互利合作、共同繁荣的现代化，推动落实习近平主席提出的全球发展倡议、全球安全倡议、全球文明倡议，构建人类命运共同体。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为长周期、跨国界、系统性的世界工程、世纪工程，共建“一带一路”的第一个10年只是序章。习近平主席指出：“共建&#39;一带一路&#39;走过了第一个蓬勃十年，正值风华正茂，务当昂扬奋进，奔向下一个金色十年！”这次高峰论坛，巩固了共建“一带一路”的国际共识，丰富了共建“一带一路”的合作成果，拓展了共建“一带一路”的光明前景，是共建“一带一路”历史进程中又一个重要里程碑。站在新的起点上，各方坚守初心、牢记使命、携手同行，深化“一带一路”国际合作，迎接共建“一带一路”更高质量、更高水平的新发展，一定能推动实现世界各国的现代化，建设一个开放包容、互联互通、共同发展的世界，共同推动构建人类命运共同体，共同开创人类更加美好的未来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 十四届全国人大常委会第六次会议举行联组会议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/23/nw.D110000renmrb_20231023_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月23日星期一&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;本报北京10月22日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者黄庆畅）十四届全国人大常委会第六次会议22日上午在北京人民大会堂举行联组会议，审议国务院关于打击生态环境和资源保护领域犯罪工作情况、最高人民法院关于人民法院环境资源审判工作情况、最高人民检察院关于人民检察院生态环境和资源保护检察工作情况的报告并开展专题询问。赵乐际委员长出席会议。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李鸿忠副委员长主持会议并讲话。国务委员、公安部部长王小洪，最高人民法院院长张军，最高人民检察院检察长应勇，国务院有关部门负责同志到会听取意见、回答询问。全国人大常委会委员吴杰明、高友东、吕忠梅、张轩、鲜铁可和吴艳刚、邹宁等与会同志提出询问。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李鸿忠指出，党的十八大以来，在习近平生态文明思想指引下，我国生态文明建设发生了历史性、转折性、全局性变化，取得举世瞩目的成就。今后五年是美丽中国建设的重要时期。要深入贯彻落实习近平生态文明思想、习近平法治思想和党中央决策部署，立足人大职能定位，持续推动生态环境和资源保护领域法治建设。要做好生态环境领域法典编纂和立法修法工作，构建科学严密、系统完善的生态环境保护法律制度体系；推动其他国家机关和地方健全完善配套法规和标准，保证生态环保法律落实落细；加强对生态环保法律实施和相关工作的监督，推动“一府两院”提高执法司法工作水平；让绿水青山就是金山银山理念深入人心，凝聚共同建设美丽中国的强大力量。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王小洪表示，国务院及各有关部门将深入学习贯彻习近平生态文明思想和习近平法治思想，从依法严打、源头治理、改革攻坚三个方面进一步加大力度，切实提高打击防范环境资源犯罪工作水平，努力以高标准执法落实高水平保护、支撑高质量发展。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;张军表示，人民法院将切实把习近平生态文明思想和习近平法治思想转化为更高水平的司法实践，积极回应人民群众日益增长的美好生活需要，以环境资源审判工作现代化更好服务中国式现代化，把“人与自然和谐共生”理念落实到具体审判工作中。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;应勇表示，检察机关将坚持以习近平生态文明思想、习近平法治思想为指引，全面协调充分履行刑事、民事、行政、公益诉讼检察职能，深化一体履职、综合履职、能动履职，高质效办好每一个环境资源案件，推动生态文明建设取得新成效。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全国人大常委会副委员长王东明、肖捷、郑建邦、丁仲礼、郝明金、蔡达峰、何维、彭清华、张庆伟、洛桑江村、雪克来提·扎克尔，秘书长刘奇出席会议。 &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 扎实开展第二批主题教育  确保取得实实在在的成效]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/23/nw.D110000renmrb_20231023_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月23日星期一&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;新华社西安10月22日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;中共中央政治局常委、中央书记处书记蔡奇21日至22日在陕西宁陕县调研。他强调，要深入贯彻落实习近平总书记重要讲话和重要指示批示精神，深刻领悟“两个确立”的决定性意义，坚决做到“两个维护”，加强分类指导，注重上下联动，扎实开展第二批主题教育，确保取得实实在在的成效。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蔡奇来到筒车湾镇胶州小区、海棠园村，了解基层主题教育和党组织建设情况，走进村民家中看望。他指出，第二批主题教育在群众身边开展，越到基层越要突出一个“实”字。要广泛听取群众意见，把解决群众的操心事烦心事揪心事作为着力点，落实落细惠民政策和为民服务，让群众有获得感。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在城关镇机关，蔡奇一一翻阅问题清单、检视整改等资料，并与乡镇干部交流。他表示，检视整改要一项一项查摆，一个一个研究解决，查到症结上、落到关键处。要坚持党建引领，提升基层治理效能，注重为基层减负。在宁陕县委主题教育办，蔡奇强调，理论学习、调查研究、检视整改等重点措施要贯通起来，针对不同层级、不同领域、不同对象特点分门别类组织好，推动主题教育走深走实。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蔡奇在座谈交流时指出，县一级处在承上启下的关键环节，是发展经济、保障民生、维护稳定的重要基础。第二批主题教育，县一级是个重点，要结合实际抓好各项重点措施落地见效。理论学习要入心见行，带着问题学，不断取得新收获。县处级以上领导干部要认真读原著学原文悟原理，学深悟透弄懂做实；县直部门和街道乡镇要结合班子和队伍建设开展主题教育；基层党组织和普通党员学习内容要突出重点，通俗易懂。领导干部要带头讲好党课。要把“四下基层”作为重要抓手，调查研究直奔问题去，注重“小切口”，实打实拿出具体对策，推动从解决“一件事”向办好“一类事”延伸。检视整改要真查实改，抓住群众反映强烈而长期没有解决的问题、推动高质量发展需要集中破解的问题、干部思想作风方面的突出问题，注重以检促改、举一反三，务求实效。要做好定点帮扶工作，巩固脱贫攻坚成果，助力宁陕县立足生态资源禀赋，走高质量绿色发展之路。各级党委（党组）要压实压紧领导责任，加强指导督导，力戒形式主义。要加强主题教育宣传引导，形成良好氛围。要把主题教育与当前重点工作任务结合起来，做到两手抓、两促进。 &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 杭州第四届亚洲残疾人运动会隆重开幕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/23/nw.D110000renmrb_20231023_7-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月23日星期一&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;新华社杭州10月22日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者齐中熙、夏亮）相聚钱塘江畔，奏响逐梦乐章。杭州第四届亚洲残疾人运动会22日晚在杭州隆重开幕。国务院副总理丁薛祥出席开幕式并宣布本届亚洲残疾人运动会开幕。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;杭州奥体中心体育场灯火璀璨，流光溢彩，宛如一朵美丽的“大莲花”。现场4万多名观众欢声笑语，共同分享这一难忘时刻。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;践行“阳光、和谐、自强、共享”办赛理念的本届亚残运会，是中国继北京冬残奥会后举办的又一个国际残疾人体育盛会，也是按照“两个亚运同样精彩”精神举办的一次亚洲体育盛会。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;19时30分许，在欢快激昂的乐曲声中，丁薛祥同亚残奥委员会主席马吉德·拉什德、国际残奥委会主席帕森斯步入主席台，向观众挥手致意。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在两名佩戴人工耳蜗的听障儿童与健全儿童一同深情唱响《我的祖国》音乐声中，数十名听障儿童护送国旗走入会场，将国旗准确地递到仪仗队员手中。随着嘹亮的国歌声响起，全场起立，场地中的手语老师带着残疾人演员深情地用手语与大家合“唱”国歌。五星红旗冉冉升起，迎风飘扬。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;开场短片《盛情满杭城》吸引了全场目光。杭州，以亚残运会的名义，再次向全亚洲发出诚挚的邀请。随后文艺表演《心相约》拉开帷幕。一位视障小女孩静立场中，在静谧的夜色中，用童稚之声开始讲述桂花开时贵客盈门的喜悦。网幕上呈现杭州标志性景致，22组金桂花团不断变化，在空中形成巨大的“金桂花冠”。道具车台绕场一周后，在场地中间夹道列队，金桂少女手持金桂花环准备欢迎运动员入场。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;19时45分，伴着轻快的乐曲《我们的亚细亚》，运动员入场式开始。本届杭州亚残运会共有来自44个国家（地区）的代表团、3100多名残疾人运动员参加。未来6天里，他们将参加22个大项、564个小项的比赛。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;东道主中国体育代表团最后入场，全场掌声欢呼声此起彼伏。中国代表团共723人，其中参赛运动员439人，他们将参加全部22个大项的角逐。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;杭州第四届亚洲残疾人运动会组委会主席、浙江省省长王浩，杭州第四届亚洲残疾人运动会组委会主席、中国残疾人联合会主席程凯，亚残奥委员会主席马吉德·拉什德先后致辞。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;20时55分，国务院副总理丁薛祥宣布：杭州第四届亚洲残疾人运动会开幕！ “数字焰火”绚烂绽放，全场响起热烈的掌声。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文艺节目《勇向前》以“金石篆刻”的艺术化表现诠释残疾运动员“精诚所至，金石为开”的拼搏精神。短片中，金石篆刻的手法与现场残疾人运动员“刀锋战士”的肢体动作相结合开启表演。健全舞者与轮椅舞者完美共舞。地屏周围出现22个数智印章玉石，石刻质感的杭州第四届亚洲残疾人运动会运动图标依次呈现。运用特效虚拟技术，一棵“金桂花树”昂然挺立，象征着残疾运动员超越自我、坚韧生长的力量。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;8名中国残奥会冠军手持亚残奥委员会会旗入场。在亚残奥委员会会歌声中，亚残奥委员会会旗缓缓升起，和鲜艳的五星红旗一道，在会场上空高高飘扬。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国运动员余钦权、蒋裕燕，中国裁判员陈然、夏昕分别代表参赛运动员、裁判员宣誓。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在激情的手鼓声中，文艺表演《梦闪耀》呈现在观众面前。百名手持金桂花环的演员加油呐喊，看台上“千家万户”的门窗点亮。沸腾之声稍歇，由听障儿童组成的童声合唱团，唱响一曲温暖的天籁之声。歌声中，肢残舞者与健全舞者默契携手、精彩共舞。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;21时14分，主火炬点燃仪式开始。采集自广州亚运会亚残运会博物馆内圣火台的亚残运会圣火，自19日在杭州市“三江两岸”依次传递，最终抵达杭州奥体中心体育场。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;体育场内，周国华、郑雄鹰、侯斌、杜剑平、王海涛等5名火炬手接力前行，受到全场观众的热烈欢迎。最后一棒火炬手徐佳玲来到火炬塔下。她用智能仿生手臂高擎火炬，虚拟的良渚玉鸟向火而来。万众瞩目中，主火炬被点燃，玉鸟再次飞旋，化作杭州亚残运会吉祥物“飞飞”，体育场内一片欢腾。随即，全场共同唱起本届亚残运会歌曲《我的深情为你守候》。网幕影像中出现百余名残疾人与健全人的灿烂笑脸，传递出深情的祝福。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谌贻琴出席开幕式。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚残奥委员会官员等出席开幕式。 &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 在新时代新征程上书写巾帼荣光（社论）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/23/nw.D110000renmrb_20231023_8-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月23日星期一&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;今天，中国妇女第十三次全国代表大会在京隆重开幕。这对于动员引领亿万中国妇女积极投身新时代新征程的伟大实践，为全面建设社会主义现代化国家、全面推进中华民族伟大复兴而团结奋斗，具有重大意义。我们对大会的召开表示热烈祝贺！ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;妇女事业始终是党和人民事业的重要组成部分。党的十八大以来，以习近平同志为核心的党中央从党和国家事业发展全局出发，高度重视和积极推进妇女工作，加强党对妇女工作的领导，坚持中国特色社会主义妇女发展道路，部署妇联改革任务，发挥妇女在各个方面的积极作用，推动我国妇女事业取得历史性成就。我国广大妇女与时代同发展，与祖国共奋进，积极投身新时代中国特色社会主义事业，以巾帼不让须眉的豪情和努力，奋勇争先、顽强拼搏，起到了重要作用，展现了新时代女性风采。实践充分证明，广大妇女不愧是人类物质文明和精神文明的创造者，不愧是推动社会发展进步的重要力量，不愧是撑起中国特色社会主义伟大事业的半边天。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;妇联组织是党联系妇女群众的桥梁纽带，是党开展妇女工作的得力助手，是妇女群众信赖的温暖之家。新时代以来，习近平总书记围绕妇女儿童和妇联工作发表了一系列重要论述，进一步深化了我们党对妇女儿童事业发展的规律性认识，为新时代新征程发展妇女事业、做好妇女工作提供了根本遵循和行动指南。中国妇女第十二次全国代表大会以来，各级妇联组织坚持以习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想为指导，深入贯彻习近平总书记关于妇女儿童和妇联工作的重要论述，强化引领服务联系，勇于改革创新，把广大妇女紧紧凝聚在党的周围，妇联工作开创了新局面，为推动我国妇女事业发展、夯实党执政的群众基础作出新贡献。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;党的二十大擘画了全面建设社会主义现代化国家、以中国式现代化全面推进中华民族伟大复兴的宏伟蓝图。习近平总书记强调，“推进强国建设、民族复兴伟业，妇女是重要力量”“实现党和国家发展的宏伟蓝图，需要包括妇女在内的全体中华儿女共同奋斗”。新征程上，牢牢把握当代中国妇女运动的时代主题，做伟大事业的建设者、做文明风尚的倡导者、做敢于追梦的奋斗者，最大限度调动妇女积极性、主动性、创造性，凝聚巾帼之力、汇集巾帼之智，广大妇女一定能够为实现中华民族伟大复兴的中国梦作出新的更大贡献。做好党的妇女工作关系团结凝聚占我国人口半数的妇女，关系为党和人民事业发展提供强大力量。切实承担引领广大妇女听党话、跟党走的政治责任，牢牢把握当好桥梁纽带和得力助手的工作定位，把联系和服务广大妇女作为工作生命线，激发广大妇女的历史责任感和主人翁精神，推动妇女事业高质量发展，各级妇联组织一定能最广泛地为党的事业团结凝聚妇女力量。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国梦是中华民族的梦，也是中国全体妇女的梦。”新征程上，每一位妇女都是时代的书写人、追梦的奋斗者。让我们更加紧密地团结在以习近平同志为核心的党中央周围，全面贯彻习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想，把妇女半边天作用充分发挥出来，形成同心共圆中国梦的强大合力，在强国建设、民族复兴的新征程上书写巾帼荣光、创造新的奇迹。 &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 巾帼英姿展风采  书写时代新华章]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/23/nw.D110000renmrb_20231023_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月23日星期一&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;“中国梦是中华民族的梦，也是中国全体妇女的梦。新征程上，每一位妇女都是时代的书写人、追梦的奋斗者。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“妇女能顶半边天。这句话说得何等豪迈啊！做好党的妇女工作，关系到团结凝聚占我国人口半数的广大妇女，关系到为党和人民事业发展提供强大力量，关系到巩固党执政的阶级基础和群众基础，使命光荣、责任重大。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;妇女事业始终是党和人民事业的重要组成部分。党的十八大以来，以习近平同志为核心的党中央从党和国家事业发展全局出发，高度重视和积极推进妇女工作，加强党对妇女工作的领导，坚持中国特色社会主义妇女发展道路，部署妇联改革任务，发挥妇女在各个方面的积极作用，推动我国妇女事业取得历史性成就。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;站在新的历史起点，中国妇女事业开启壮阔新征程。各级妇联组织锐意进取、开拓创新，妇女工作蓬勃开展，妇联改革全力推进。亿万妇女奋勇争先、建功立业，在强国建设、民族复兴新征程上贡献巾帼力量。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 把思想政治引领贯穿妇女工作始终&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;实现中华民族伟大复兴是当代中国妇女运动的时代主题。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“坚持党的领导，是做好党的妇女工作的根本保证。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“各级妇联组织要承担引领广大妇女听党话、跟党走的政治责任，激发广大妇女的历史责任感和主人翁精神，为推动我国妇女事业发展作出新贡献。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“要把思想政治引领贯穿于妇联开展的各种活动，引导妇女擦亮眼睛、明辨是非，增强中国特色社会主义道路自信、理论自信、制度自信、文化自信，自觉捍卫中国共产党领导和我国社会主义制度，自觉为中国特色社会主义共同理想而奋斗。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;党的十八大以来，习近平总书记关于妇女儿童和妇联工作的重要论述，为新时代中国妇女事业发展指明了前进方向。各级妇联牢记嘱托、扛起责任，把思想政治引领贯穿于妇联开展的各种活动，引导妇女深入学习贯彻习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想，坚定不移朝着正确方向和理想目标持续奋进。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“人逢喜事精神爽，欢声笑语聚一堂，打起快板跳起舞，二十大的赞歌唱……”在广西桂林市恭城瑶族自治县西岭镇西岭村，巾帼宣讲员的一段说唱音乐快板《党的二十大精神来领航》，让在场群众听得津津有味。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;西岭村的这一幕，是各地妇联开展“巾帼大宣讲”的一个缩影。让身边人讲身边事，以小故事讲大道理，打通全面联系服务妇女群众的“最后一公里”，把党的创新理论讲到妇女群众心里。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;妇女在哪里，妇女思想政治引领工作就做到哪里。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在学习贯彻习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想主题教育、党史学习教育、“四史”宣传教育等期间，各级妇联聚焦目标任务、注重实际成效，因地制宜面向妇女开展“巾帼大学习”“巾帼大宣讲”，有力推动党的创新理论“飞入寻常百姓家”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——精心策划主题活动，妇女思想政治引领接地气。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我想用自己成长的故事，带动更多妇女姐妹学习文化、传播文化，实现自我成长。”宁夏吴忠市红寺堡区农民作家马慧娟在一条短视频中款款讲述。马慧娟在干农活之余用手机写作，发起成立了“泥土书香”读书社，带动和鼓励农村妇女学习文化知识，用书香凝聚乡村振兴的精神力量。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022年7月，全国妇联部署开展“我奋斗·家国美”短视频征集展示活动，组织广大妇女和家庭通过短视频讲好奋斗故事、家庭故事、美好生活故事，得到各界广泛参与。围绕庆祝新中国成立70周年、庆祝中国共产党成立100周年、党的二十大胜利召开等重大节点，各级妇联线上线下联动开展“巾帼心向党”系列群众性主题宣传教育活动，产生广泛影响。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——发挥榜样作用，思想政治引领有人气。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“航天领域的技术攻关、研发生产很艰苦，能坚守在航天领域的女性都相当不容易，她们在团队中不可或缺。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“蛟龙探海，雪龙破冰。我立志投身科考事业，探索海洋奥秘，助力建设海洋强国。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“每一架飞机都有上百万个铆钉，保障飞机的质量和安全，我愿意做这样的铆钉。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年6月，多位全国三八红旗手走进西安交通大学，结合自身成长经历讲述奋斗故事，拉开“巾帼榜样走进陕西高校思政课”的序幕。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，全国妇联充分发挥全国三八红旗手等先进妇女典型的榜样引领作用，广泛开展宣讲进校园、进机关、进企业、进社区等活动，打造“巾帼大宣讲”思想政治引领活动品牌，激发广大妇女的历史责任感和主人翁精神，受到广泛认可。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——线上线下同频共振，巩固联系服务妇女群众的网上桥梁纽带。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们要更好地通过作品书写新时代，让读者看到女性的自信自立自强。”在“争做巾帼好网民”主题活动启动仪式上，重庆市网络作家协会妇联主席韩路荣表示，现在要做的就是多下基层，多了解身边的女性奋斗者、建设者。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，重庆市网络作家协会妇联进一步加大对活跃在网络空间中优秀女性的联系，满足了新领域、新群体、新行业女性寻找“娘家人”的现实需要，带领女作家走向更广阔的舞台。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文化、生活、健康、科普等领域的女性网络创作者活跃在云端，巾帼好网民不断涌现，引导广大妇女坚定不移听党话、矢志不渝跟党走。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;团结带领广大妇女做伟大事业的建设者、文明风尚的倡导者、敢于追梦的奋斗者&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“妇联组织要帮助妇女点燃梦想、追寻梦想、共筑梦想，为妇女释放创造活力、实现自我价值搭建平台，促进妇女权益更有保障、人生更加出彩、生活更加幸福。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“希望广大妇女做伟大事业的建设者、做文明风尚的倡导者、做敢于追梦的奋斗者，在全面建设社会主义现代化国家新征程上，为实现中华民族伟大复兴的中国梦作出新的更大贡献。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记关于妇女儿童和妇联工作的重要论述，为新时代新征程上推动妇女事业高质量发展提供了根本遵循，广大妇女群众的获得感、幸福感与日俱增，自信追求人生出彩的底气越来越足。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——着眼长远，务实有效规划目标。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“坚持男女平等基本国策，保障妇女儿童合法权益”写入党的十八大、十九大、二十大报告；“注重家庭家教家风建设，保障妇女儿童权益”写入党的第三个历史决议。党的二十大首次将“加强家庭家教家风建设”写入党代会报告。 “十三五”和“十四五”规划纲要均列章节对促进妇女儿童发展作出部署，“十四五”规划纲要首设“加强家庭建设”专节，国务院连续颁布实施4个周期的中国妇女发展纲要。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——积极参与法律法规制定修订，进一步保障妇女权益。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;妇联组织积极参与民法典、妇女权益保障法等法律政策的制定修订，推进反家庭暴力法、家庭教育促进法贯彻实施，建立完善集矛盾排查、纠纷调解、法律帮助、关爱服务于一体的综合维权服务模式。法规政策性别平等评估机制已覆盖31个省区市，进一步推动男女平等价值理念落实到法规政策的制定、实施和监督各环节。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——推进巾帼建功系列活动，激发干事创业热情。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;走进浙江省杭州市萧山区所前镇金山村“巾帼共富工坊”，室内摆满了具有亚运元素的珠绣文创作品，萧山珠绣非遗传承人、工坊负责人王丽华正手把手地教学员珠绣技艺。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2018年，王丽华创办了萧山丽华花边珠绣研究所。在此基础上，在区镇两级妇联指导下，成立了以王丽华为带头人的“巾帼共富工坊”，带动周边村庄200多名妇女就业，人均年增收8000余元。萧山区妇联大力挖掘乡村振兴女带头人、女巧手等“领头雁”，带动更多优秀女性就业创业。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“巾帼脱贫行动”“乡村振兴巾帼行动”“科技创新巾帼行动”……妇联组织广泛开展富有女性特色的巾帼建功立业活动，助力新时代女性在更加广阔的天地实现人生价值。将科技力量注入农田的“种米姑娘”陈雨佳；把“小红薯”做成“大产业”的女企业家黄晓艳；打造社区“十分钟生活服务圈”的居委会主任刘娟……在乡村振兴第一线、经济发展大浪潮、基层治理小单元，广大妇女踔厉奋发，创造了骄人成绩。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——关爱服务惠及更多妇女，自我发展能力不断提升。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;江西省赣州市于都县女孩庄雨轩平静的生活，被父亲突发的心脏疾病打破。父亲的医药费、她和哥哥读书的费用……家庭生活的重担压在庄雨轩母亲一人身上。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就在生活的乌云笼罩这个小家庭时，“春蕾计划”如一缕阳光照进了庄雨轩的生活。在老师的帮助下，庄雨轩经审核后幸运地成为一名“春蕾女童”，从高二开始，她每年都会收到“春蕾计划”助学款，缓解了拮据的生活状况。去年8月，庄雨轩如愿考上北京大学，“&#39;春蕾计划&#39;将激励我继续在追梦的路上奋力拼搏。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;庄雨轩的故事是“春蕾计划”的一个缩影。由全国妇联所属中国儿童少年基金会发起的“春蕾计划”已累计为409万人次女童提供助学帮扶。不仅仅是“春蕾计划”，农村妇女“两癌”免费检查、“母亲健康快车”、“母亲邮包”、“母亲水窖”等项目，让更多妇女的身心健康状况得到极大改善，自我发展能力不断提升。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——促进家家幸福安康，推动形成社会主义家庭文明新风尚。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“最美家庭”的先进事迹，展现着“最美”的风采，传递着“最美”的能量。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2000年，为响应国家号召，原本在湖北省襄阳市南漳县农业部门工作的何文国下海创业，与妻子陈盛芬共同开办南漳县“放心种子大厅”。 20多年来，他们始终将保障农民的利益放在首位，用自己的专业知识为农民做好售后技术服务。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从西南三线建设，到铁路大提速，再到高铁时代……中国中铁六局北京公司京唐铁路燕郊站枢纽站前工程项目部党支部书记李国胜一家三代筑路人，将青春和热血投注在祖国发展大动脉上，全心全意践行铁路人的使命。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;家是最小国，国是千万家。妇联组织大力实施“家家幸福安康工程”，加强家庭文明建设，深入开展家庭教育指导服务，常态化开展寻找“最美家庭”、五好家庭评选等活动，累计评选1484万户“最美家庭”、558万户五好家庭，引导广大妇女带动家庭成员建设好家庭、涵养好家教、培育好家风，促进社会主义核心价值观在家庭生根。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——巧运匠心，传承弘扬中华优秀传统文化。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这些陶俑发现于泾阳大堡子墓地，较为完整地再现了西汉的乐舞场景，为研究西汉早期的音乐、舞蹈等文化生活提供了丰富的研究材料。”提起考古发掘，陕西省考古研究院29岁的女子考古队队长朱瑛培如数家珍，“这是我们加班加点修复、再现的一组文物，每次看到它们，我的内心就会涌出一股强烈的自豪感和成就感。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在全国妇女爱国主义教育基地眉山三苏祠博物馆，前来旅游研学者络绎不绝。 “传承和传播好三苏文化，让三苏祠更好地折射出中华优秀传统文化的光辉。”徐丽是三苏祠最早的一批讲解员之一。苏洵发奋攻读、苏母勤劳持家……她与同事通过一个个生动的故事，以“润物细无声”的讲解方式浸润广大妇女和家庭。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着我国经济社会快速发展、文化自信不断增强，越来越多的女性成为传承弘扬中华优秀传统文化的生力军，她们用热爱和坚守向人们展现中华文化的强大魅力，努力奏响弘扬中华优秀传统文化的时代乐章。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;在深化妇联改革和建设中巩固桥梁纽带&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“推动妇女事业发展，做好妇联工作，必须有改革创新精神。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“要以更实的举措推进妇联改革，深化基层妇联组织改革，转变机关干部工作作风，提高服务能力，加大攻坚克难力度，确保改革在基层落地。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“把联系和服务广大妇女作为工作生命线，切实改进工作作风，创新工作方法，深入基层做好工作，不断促进妇女发展，真正把妇联建设成为可信赖依靠的&#39;妇女之家&#39;。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;党的十八大以来，习近平总书记立足新时代的历史方位，高瞻远瞩，总揽全局，深邃思考，就妇女事业、妇联工作、妇联改革作出一系列重要指示。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2015年7月，党中央首次召开中央党的群团工作会议。习近平总书记强调，工会、共青团、妇联等群团组织要切实保持和增强党的群团工作和群团组织的政治性、先进性、群众性，开创新形势下党的群团工作新局面。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;党中央有号召，妇联有行动。 2016年，随着《全国妇联改革方案》正式印发，妇联深化改革蹄疾步稳。全国妇联出台《“十四五”时期妇联事业发展规划》《“十四五”时期深化妇联系统改革方案》等制度文件，全国县级以上妇联印发改革配套文件、规定、制度等，组织建设制度体系更加系统完备。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一场从上至下、由浅入深的组织重塑、机制重建、方法重构、资源重组，在各级妇联渐次推进。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在有&#39;妇联主席+执委+代表&#39;组成团队，为姐妹们&#39;零距离&#39;服务。”山东省莱阳市柏林庄街道北小平村妇联主席李福玲欣喜地说，村（社区）妇代会改建妇联后，一批品行好、能力强、热心肠的优秀妇女加入妇联队伍，服务妇女的底气更足。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从“有形覆盖”到“有效覆盖”，通过“会改联”和乡镇妇联区域化建设，108万个妇女小组、90万个“妇女之家”“妇女微家”遍布城乡社区，一个“上面千条线、下面一张网、身边一个家”的妇联基层组织新格局已初步构建。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这个包款式简单大方，可以单肩背也可以斜挎……”走进河北省保定市白沟新城电商微家，一名女主播正在直播销售女士背包。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，白沟新城妇工委结合当地箱包特色产业，实施“电商·妇女微家”行动，通过“产业+直播+创业”模式，开展乡村振兴巾帼电商直播培训，累计免费培训1.4万余名农村妇女，其中1300多人成为专业主播。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;妇女在哪里，妇联组织和妇联工作就要延伸到哪里。在社区广场、商务楼宇、电商平台，灵活多样的妇女组织如雨后春笋般涌现，立体化、多层面的组织体系把广大妇女凝聚起来，让妇女随时随地、实实在在感受到妇联组织的关心。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;测血压、问诊、超声检查……广东省广州市番禺区罗家村义诊点人头攒动，番禺区妇联执委、番禺区中心医院超声科主任陈毓菁正忙着为妇女看病。作为番禺区家庭教育讲师团成员，工作之余，陈毓菁还定期开展关爱妇女健康主题的医学讲座，为妇女群众提供家庭教育指导。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;番禺区妇联依托综治网格，把家庭教育讲师、基层妇联干部、执委网格志愿者放在格上，整合区内资源，组建家庭教育讲师团，依托区、镇（街）、村（社区）三级妇女儿童之家，推动讲师团下沉基层进入村居，为网格居民提供家庭教育指导服务。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如今，全国各级妇联组织开展“执委走访”“我为妇女群众办实事”等活动，探索建立“执委工作站”、执委与网格员交叉任职等模式，近700万名妇联执委活跃在基层一线、服务在群众身边。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“新征程上，每一位妇女都是主角，都享有人生出彩的机会。广大妇女要积极投身新时代的伟大实践，拼搏进取，担当奉献，展现&#39;半边天&#39;风采，为全面建设社会主义现代化国家、实现中华民族伟大复兴的中国梦作出新的更大的贡献。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在以习近平同志为核心的党中央坚强领导下，在习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想特别是习近平总书记关于妇女儿童和妇联工作的重要论述的科学指引下，广大妇女正以巾帼不让须眉的豪情，凝聚巾帼之力、汇集巾帼之智，向着强国建设、民族复兴的宏伟目标踔厉奋发、勇毅前行！ &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 总书记关心关爱“半边天”的故事]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/23/nw.D110000renmrb_20231023_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月23日星期一&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;习近平总书记心中，妇女是人类文明的开创者、社会进步的推动者，妇女事业始终是党和人民事业的重要组成部分。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国梦是中华民族的梦，也是中国全体妇女的梦。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“新征程上，每一位妇女都是主角，都享有人生出彩的机会。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“发展离不开妇女，发展要惠及包括妇女在内的全体人民。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一次次深情鼓励，激扬巾帼之志；一项项暖心举措，凝聚巾帼之力。新时代新征程，广大妇女牢记习近平总书记的嘱托，争做伟大事业的建设者、文明风尚的倡导者、敢于追梦的奋斗者，乘风破浪、奋勇争先，为强国建设、民族复兴贡献磅礴的巾帼力量。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;尊重女性地位——&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“妇女能顶半边天”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“妇女能顶半边天。这句话说得何等豪迈啊！”2013年10月31日，在同全国妇联新一届领导班子集体谈话时，习近平总书记特意回顾了在党的历史上作出过杰出贡献的“老大姐”们：宋庆龄、何香凝、蔡畅、邓颖超、康克清……称赞她们“都是一代楷模，都是在时代洪流中产生的巾帼英雄”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;男女并驾，如日方东。妇女是推动社会发展和进步的重要力量。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记深刻指出：“追求男女平等的事业是伟大的。纵观历史，没有妇女解放和进步，就没有人类解放和进步。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一直以来，习近平总书记不但尊重女性地位、注重保障女性权益，而且身体力行，用行动支持和鼓励每一位女性追逐梦想、建功立业，书写自己的美丽人生。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;每年“三八”国际妇女节，都有一个春天的约定，习近平总书记总要向广大妇女致以节日的问候，送去温暖的关怀、激励的话语。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为“她”的高光时刻喝彩，也为“她们”的工作和生活提供更有力支持和保障。党的十八大以来，习近平总书记在多个场合发表重要讲话、作出重要指示，为维护妇女合法权益、推动我国妇女事业发展鼓与呼——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们要把保障妇女权益系统纳入法律法规，上升为国家意志，内化为社会行为规范。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“加大重视、关心、支持力度，严厉打击侵害妇女权益的违法犯罪行为，依法维护妇女权益。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“把更多注意力放在最普通的妇女特别是困难妇女身上，格外关心贫困妇女、残疾妇女、留守妇女等困难妇女，为她们做好事、解难事、办实事。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“积极为妇女参与经济社会发展创造条件、搭建平台，保障妇女、儿童合法权益，努力让尊重妇女、关爱儿童在全社会蔚然成风。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;妇联组织是党和政府联系妇女群众的桥梁和纽带。在两次同全国妇联新一届领导班子集体谈话时，习近平总书记都着重强调坚持男女平等基本国策，充分发挥我国妇女伟大作用，对妇联工作提出的要求细致入微。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记指出：“用自己的眼睛看最真实的情况，用自己的耳朵听最真实的声音，帮助广大妇女排忧解难”“要把联系和服务妇女作为工作生命线，成为妇女信得过、靠得住、离不开的娘家人”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;将“坚持男女平等基本国策，保障妇女儿童合法权益”连续写入党的十八大、十九大、二十大报告，把“注重家庭家教家风建设，保障妇女儿童权益”写入党的第三个历史决议，丰富了党和国家事业发展新内涵；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;制定实施一系列促进男女平等和妇女全面发展的法律政策，国家“十三五”“十四五”规划纲要均对促进妇女儿童发展进行专章部署，不断健全完善妇女权益保障法治体系；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;召开党的历史上第一次中央党的群团工作会议，把妇女工作纳入党委工作总体布局，把妇联改革作为全面深化改革的重要任务；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新时代的中国妇女事业阔步前行，我国妇女在政治、经济、文化、社会和家庭生活各领域的平等权利得到更好实现，尊重和关爱妇女逐步成为国家意志、公民素养和社会风尚，鼓舞着一个个“她”勇毅前行。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;每年全国两会，女代表、女委员为民履职的身姿，都是一道亮丽的风景线；每当国有大事，中国女性力量从未缺席。在抗击疫情紧急关头，在脱贫攻坚、乡村振兴一线，在科研攻关前沿，在国家议政建言的最高殿堂，在基层治理的大舞台，在家庭建设的小港湾……中国故事的女主角们书写了精彩的篇章，充分展现出新时代妇女自尊、自信、自立、自强的精神风貌。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;放眼神州大地，亿万女性用自身的发展，标注着社会文明所抵达的高度。今天的中国，女性不仅拥有更加平等的社会地位，也拥有更加辽阔的发展空间，我国妇女事业取得历史性成就——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我国妇女人均预期寿命已超80岁，比世界女性平均水平高4岁；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;义务教育阶段性别差距基本消除，高等教育本专科、研究生在校生中女生占比均超过男生；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;女性就业人员占比超过四成，电商、直播等新业态中妇女约占1/3，女科技工作者占45.8%；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第十四届全国人大女代表和全国政协女委员占比分别为26.54%和22.4%，均创历史新高；企业职工董事、职工监事、职工代表大会中，女性占1/3左右；新一届村委会班子成员中女性占28.1%，比上届提高7.1个百分点；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;4416万农村妇女摆脱绝对贫困；参加各类社会保险的妇女大幅增加；侵害妇女儿童违法犯罪行为受到严厉打击；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国建立了包括100多部法律法规在内的全面保障妇女权益法律体系，被世界卫生组织列为妇幼健康高绩效的10个国家之一，基本消除义务教育性别差距，全社会就业人员女性占比超过四成，互联网领域创业者中女性更是超过一半。”2020年10月1日，联合国大会纪念北京世界妇女大会25周年高级别会议，习近平总书记话语铿锵，掷地有声。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们要不懈努力，为妇女事业发展开辟广阔道路”的庄严承诺，正一步步变为现实。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; 点赞奋斗女性——&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“每一位妇女都有人生出彩和梦想成真的机会”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“你可是巾帼英雄啊，也是妇女能顶半边天的代表，现在还成了中国妇女的&#39;形象大使&#39;！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2013年全国两会，习近平总书记在出席十二届全国人大一次会议解放军代表团全体会议后，与中国首位进入太空的女航天员刘洋亲切交流。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新时代是奋斗者的时代，巾帼奋进是最美的风景线。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在中国人民追求美好生活的过程中，每一位妇女都有人生出彩和梦想成真的机会。”习近平总书记坚定有力的话语，鼓舞着每一位奋斗着的新时代女性。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2015年10月，屠呦呦获得诺贝尔生理学或医学奖。在2016年的新年贺词中，习近平总书记专门提到了屠呦呦，并称赞“只要坚持，梦想总是可以实现的”；2019年9月，总书记向屠呦呦颁授了“共和国勋章”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2019年9月，新中国成立70周年之际，中国女排在世界杯比赛中以全胜战绩卫冕。习近平总书记专门邀请中国女排队员、教练员代表，参加庆祝中华人民共和国成立70周年招待会，并在会前亲切会见女排代表。总书记盛赞中国女排和女排精神：“女排精神代表着一个时代的精神，喊出了为中华崛起而拼搏的时代最强音。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“只要还有一口气，我就要站在讲台上，倾尽全力、奉献所有，九死亦无悔。”2021年6月29日，庆祝中国共产党成立100周年“七一勋章”颁授仪式现场，云南省丽江华坪女子高级中学党支部书记、校长，华坪县儿童福利院院长张桂梅的感言发自肺腑。习近平总书记望着她，目光温暖而亲切。此前，在全国脱贫攻坚总结表彰大会上，总书记弯下腰，为坐在轮椅上的张桂梅郑重颁授奖章。 “献身教育扶贫、点燃大山女孩希望”，在发表重要讲话时，总书记特别为她的先进事迹点赞。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;…………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;每个人都了不起。只要踏实劳动、勤勉劳动，在平凡岗位上也能干出不平凡的业绩。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记时常勉励广大妇女抓住机遇，奋勇争先，实现人生出彩。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2016年4月24日，习近平总书记来到地处大别山腹地的安徽省六安市金寨县大湾村考察，并在贫困户陈泽申家小院举行了一场座谈会，时任扶贫工作队队长余静向总书记郑重承诺：“大湾村一户不脱贫，我坚决不撤岗。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;找准优势特色，做大茶产业、做强种养业、做旺旅游业……在“铁娘子”余静的带领下，大湾村这个远近闻名的穷山村，走上红绿结合、茶旅融合的乡村振兴发展快道，成功实现“逆袭”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我要继续带领大湾村人在乡村振兴路上奋斗、实干！”余静说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2020年10月1日，在联合国大会纪念北京世界妇女大会25周年高级别会议上，习近平总书记通过视频发表重要讲话，深情讲述了一名00后中国小护士的故事。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在中国抗击新冠肺炎疫情最紧要的时刻，来自中国全国各地驰援湖北的4万多名医护人员中，三分之二是女性。有一位来自广东省的小护士还不满20岁。记者问她，你还是一个孩子，还需要别人帮助。她回答说，穿上防护服，我就不是孩子了。这段对话感动了整个中国！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这名小护士叫刘家怡，是广东省援鄂医疗队中年龄最小的队员，也是抗击疫情期间在各战线奋战的中国女性的缩影。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“正是成千上万这样的中国女性，白衣执甲，逆行而上，以勇气和辛劳诠释了医者仁心，用担当和奉献换来了山河无恙。”习近平总书记为广大女性医务人员、疾控人员、科技人员、社区工作者、志愿者等深情点赞。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个个的“她”，以巾帼不让须眉的豪情和奋斗，在各行各业书写着不平凡的成就。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年全国两会，全国人大代表、山东济南“阳光大姐”团队负责人卓长立身着橘红色工服，在代表中格外醒目。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对于这件陪伴了自己数十年的工装，卓长立曾有复杂感情：“以前，社会上总认为家政人员就是&#39;保姆&#39;，低人一等。但现在我感受到了这份职业的价值和荣誉感。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2013年11月，在济南市外来务工人员综合服务中心，前来考察的习近平总书记同窗口单位工作人员和前来办事的农民工亲切交谈，卓长立便在其中。那时，二次创业的卓长立带领姐妹们一起从事家政行业。 “总书记说&#39;家政服务大有可为&#39;，让我的心一下子就热乎起来。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2018年全国两会期间，卓长立作为全国人大代表，再次向总书记当面汇报“阳光大姐”发展情况。那天，她特意穿上了自己的工服，“总书记说家政业像&#39;阳光大姐&#39;这个名字一样，是朝阳产业，鼓励我们把这个互利共赢的工作做实做好，办成爱心工程。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总书记的鼓励，让卓长立更加坚定自己的选择——把家政服务当成事业来干。如今，“阳光大姐”已从济南走向全国，家政服务员队伍发展到7万多人，规模是2013年的3倍多。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“要凝聚巾帼之力，汇集巾帼之智，尊重和关爱妇女，引导广大妇女积极投身新时代新征程的伟大实践，为全面建设社会主义现代化国家、全面推进中华民族伟大复兴作出新的更大的贡献。”今年3月6日，在全国政协联组会上，习近平总书记语重心长地说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;体育赛场摘金夺银，太空出差筑梦星河，三尺讲台传道授业，乡土田野播撒希望，科研一线勇攀高峰……如今，广阔的社会舞台上，“她力量”向阳生长，铿锵玫瑰尽情绽放，“她们”在创新中自强不息、在创造中开拓进取、在创业中艰苦奋斗，展现出新时代女性的别样风采。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;注重家庭家教家风——&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“努力使千千万万个家庭成为国家发展、民族进步、社会和谐的重要基点”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“天下之本在国，国之本在家”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中华民族自古以来就重视家庭。家庭和睦则社会安定，家庭幸福则社会祥和，家庭文明则社会文明。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记重视家庭建设，注重家庭、注重家教、注重家风，充分肯定妇女在家庭美德建设中的作用，强调“发挥妇女独特作用，推动社会主义核心价值观在家庭落地生根”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“慈母手中线，游子身上衣。临行密密缝，意恐迟迟归。谁言寸草心，报得三春晖。”2015年春节前夕，习近平总书记在春节团拜会上引用诗人孟郊的名篇《游子吟》，流露出深厚的家庭情结。总书记强调，不论时代发生多大变化，不论生活格局发生多大变化，我们都要重视家庭建设，注重家庭、注重家教、注重家风。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;家是最小国，国是千万家。革命战争年代母亲教儿打东洋、妻子送郎上战场，社会主义建设时期先大家后小家、为大家舍小家，都体现着向上的家庭追求，体现着高尚的家国情怀。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;小时候母亲讲精忠报国、岳母刺字的故事，让总书记难以忘怀。 “我说，把字刺上去，多疼啊！我母亲说，是疼，但心里铭记住了。&#39;精忠报国&#39;四个字，我从那个时候一直记到现在，它也是我一生追求的目标。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2016年12月12日，京西宾馆会议楼前厅气氛热烈，习近平总书记在这里会见第一届全国文明家庭代表，盛赞他们的事迹“温暖了人心，诠释了文明，传播了正能量，为全社会树立了榜样”，充满感情地点赞他们“都是好样的！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们要重视家庭文明建设，努力使千千万万个家庭成为国家发展、民族进步、社会和谐的重要基点，成为人们梦想启航的地方。”总书记的重要讲话，传遍大江南北。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;家庭教育涉及很多方面，但最重要的是品德教育，是如何做人的教育。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2013年9月26日，在会见第四届全国道德模范及提名奖获得者时，习近平总书记把目光转向坐在第一排左边的一位老人。总书记饱含深情地说：“我刚才看到这位老前辈，她就是我们的老将军甘祖昌的夫人龚全珍，她今年90多岁了，我看到她以后心里一阵阵的感动。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1957年，龚全珍放弃城市生活，跟随丈夫回乡，靠微薄工资为家乡修水利、建电站、盖校舍，扶贫济困。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记说：“半个多世纪过去了，龚全珍同志始终保持艰苦奋斗精神，并当选了全国道德模范，出席我们今天的会议，我感到很欣慰。我向龚全珍同志致以崇高的敬意。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记强调，我们要弘扬这种艰苦奋斗精神，不仅我们这代人要传承，我们的下一代也要弘扬，要一代一代传承下去。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;党的十八大以来，以习近平同志为核心的党中央高度重视家庭文明建设，推动新时代家庭家教家风建设高质量发展——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“十四五”规划纲要首设“加强家庭建设”专节；民法典确立“家庭应当树立优良家风，弘扬家庭美德，重视家庭文明建设”原则性规定；七部门印发《关于进一步加强家庭家教家风建设的实施意见》，中央文明委印发《关于深化家庭文明建设的意见》；31个省区市建立家庭工作多部门协调工作机制，24个省区市设立了家庭工作专项经费，党政主导的家庭工作机制逐步健全……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;举办形式多样的家风故事分享会，联合开展清廉家风主题活动，持续推进移风易俗试点工作，深化绿色家庭创建……各级妇联组织大力实施“家家幸福安康工程”，常态化广覆盖开展寻找“最美家庭”活动，推动形成社会主义家庭文明新风尚。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前，全国涌现出1484万户“最美家庭”，平等和睦文明的新时代家庭关系普遍建立，社会主义核心价值观在广大家庭落地生根。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;家庭是人生的第一所学校，家长是孩子的第一任老师。习近平总书记勉励大家：“要给孩子讲好&#39;人生第一课&#39;，帮助扣好人生第一粒扣子。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2018年11月2日，习近平总书记在同全国妇联新一届领导班子成员集体谈话时指出：“我在党的十九大报告中提出了培养担当民族复兴大任的时代新人的战略任务，妇联要围绕这个重大课题，在家庭工作中找准立德树人的切入点，帮助孩子扣好人生的第一粒扣子。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2014年3月，习近平总书记重访兰考时见到了焦裕禄的5个子女。二女儿焦守云对总书记说：“我们一定传承好父亲的精神，保持家教家风。”总书记听后，一边点头一边说：“好家风，好家风。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;家风家教是一个家庭最宝贵的财富，家庭文明是社会文明的基石。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;永葆赤子之心，厚植家国情怀，奋斗就有了不竭的动力，前进就有了远大的目标。每个家庭前进的脚步，就一定叠加成国家的进步；每个家庭创造的价值，就一定汇聚起民族复兴的伟力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[03版要闻 - 深化互联互通  促进共同发展]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/23/nw.D110000renmrb_20231023_1-03.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月23日星期一&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;“10年来，我们致力于构建以经济走廊为引领，以大通道和信息高速公路为骨架，以铁路、公路、机场、港口、管网为依托，涵盖陆、海、天、网的全球互联互通网络，有效促进了各国商品、资金、技术、人员的大流通，推动绵亘千年的古丝绸之路在新时代焕发新活力。”在第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛开幕式上，习近平主席宣布中国支持高质量共建“一带一路”的八项行动，其中第一项就是构建“一带一路”立体互联互通网络。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;借鉴古丝绸之路，以互联互通为主线，共建“一带一路”把共建国家紧密联系在一起，致力于合作共赢、共同发展，让发展成果由各国人民共享，得到国际社会的广泛支持和响应。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“在促进互联互通方面成效卓著”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“&#39;一带一路&#39;和互联互通是相融相近、相辅相成的。如果将&#39;一带一路&#39;比喻为亚洲腾飞的两只翅膀，那么互联互通就是两只翅膀的血脉经络。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;实践证明，共建“一带一路”提升了全球互联互通水平，推动了国际投资贸易繁荣发展，为变乱交织的国际局势注入了更多确定性。10年来，共建“一带一路”以“六廊六路多国多港”为基本架构，加快推进多层次、复合型基础设施网络建设，基本形成“陆海天网”四位一体的互联互通格局，为促进经贸和产能合作、加强文化交流和人员往来奠定了坚实基础。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;正如联合国秘书长古特雷斯所说，没有基础设施就没有发展。广大发展中国家目前仍有数十亿人缺乏基础设施，这是本届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛以及共建“一带一路”倡议的重要性所在。在共建“一带一路”倡议推动下，各国在基础设施领域获得更多机遇，加速落实可持续发展目标。“这为数十亿民众以及我们共享的地球带来希望和进步”，古特雷斯说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;基础设施的联通，有效降低了共建国家参与国际贸易的成本，提高了接入世界经济的能力和水平，激发了更大发展潜力、更强发展动力。世界银行《“一带一路”经济学：交通走廊的机遇与风险》研究报告显示，共建“一带一路”倡议提出之前，六大经济走廊的贸易低于其潜力的30%，外国直接投资低于其潜力的70%。共建“一带一路”实施以来，仅通过基础设施建设，就可使全球贸易成本降低1.8%，为全球贸易便利化和经济增长作出重要贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共建“一带一路”倡议在推进世界互联互通等方面取得丰硕成果，国际社会有目共睹。泰国副总理兼外长班比说，共建“一带一路”有效提升了共建国家互联互通水平，尤其是推动了铁路等基础设施建设。铁路将一些枢纽地区连接起来，使产品尤其是农产品得以便捷地运输出去。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;埃及《金字塔报》总编辑阿拉·萨比特表示：“共建&#39;一带一路&#39;带动了各大洲的公路、铁路、港口和能源管道等基础设施建设，促进了共建国家特别是亚洲和非洲国家之间的贸易畅通、互联互通和经济发展。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“实践证明，共建&#39;一带一路&#39;在促进互联互通方面成效卓著，实现了互利共赢。”印度尼西亚第一电视台首席执行官陶凡·埃科·纽克罗霍在接受本报记者采访时表示，共建“一带一路”倡议意义重大，有助于激发共建国家的发展潜能，不断增进民生福祉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; “充分释放共建国家各领域合作潜能”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;通车6年多来，连接东非第一大港口蒙巴萨和肯尼亚首都内罗毕的蒙内铁路，成为区域互联互通的大动脉，不仅给肯尼亚经济社会发展带来巨大改变，也使东非内陆国家经由肯尼亚的海路货运更为顺畅。肯尼亚非洲政策研究所在2021年年底发布的报告《共享繁荣：“一带一路”倡议在肯尼亚》中得出结论：共建“一带一路”正在拓展肯尼亚的发展空间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;蒙内铁路是共建“一带一路”深化互联互通、助力共同发展的一个缩影。10年来，从理念到行动，从愿景到现实，共建“一带一路”依托基础设施互联互通，推动各国全方位多领域联通，由点到线再到面，逐步放大发展辐射效应，为世界经济增长提供持续动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年10月2日，中国和印尼共建“一带一路”合作旗舰项目——雅万高铁正式启用，这是印尼和东南亚地区的首条高速铁路。10年来，共建国家共同推进国际骨干通道建设，打造连接亚洲各次区域以及亚欧非之间的基础设施网络。在泰国泰中“一带一路”研究中心主任威伦·披差翁帕迪看来，共建“一带一路”深化区域互联互通，“让发展所需的资金和技术得以在区域内自由流动，充分释放共建国家各领域合作潜能”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中国远洋海运集团与希腊方面携手努力下，希腊最大港口比雷埃夫斯港扭亏为盈，重焕勃勃生机。10年来，共建国家港口航运合作不断深化，货物运输效率大幅提升。希腊总理米佐塔基斯表示，比港项目有力促进了希腊经济复苏和社会发展，符合希腊国家和人民利益，得到希腊人民的支持。希方愿同中方携手努力，不断推动这一共建“一带一路”旗舰项目高质量发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郑州到卢森堡的“空中丝绸之路”，从最初的每周两班增至每周最多14班，目前该航线通航点已覆盖伦敦、芝加哥、米兰等全球15个城市。10年来，共建国家间航空航线网络加快拓展，空中联通水平稳步提升。“共建&#39;一带一路&#39;有助于全球发展，它将中国与全球数百个城市联通起来。”卢森堡货航飞行运营执行副总裁克洛德·泽伦如是说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自2014年5月启用以来，中哈（连云港）物流合作基地极大推动了中欧班列过境换装的作业速度，亚欧跨境运输枢纽联动效应不断显现。10年来，中欧班列、中欧陆海快线、西部陆海新通道、连云港—霍尔果斯新亚欧陆海联运等国际多式联运稳步发展。印尼阿拉扎大学校长亚瑟普·赛福鼎表示，共建“一带一路”是促进全球和平合作和共同发展的中国方案。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;吉尔吉斯斯坦国家战略研究所专家舍拉迪尔·巴克特古洛夫表示，吉中两国在基础设施领域开展了密切务实合作，中国对吉尔吉斯斯坦交通现代化升级改造提供了重要支持，共建“一带一路”让吉交通状况焕然一新，提升了中亚地区各国经济发展潜力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这一倡议为非洲发展带来真正的变革。”埃塞俄比亚智库政策研究所咨询顾问巴卢·德米西以东非第一条电气化铁路——亚吉铁路为例说，这条铁路在新冠疫情期间成为从吉布提港口至东非内陆的生命补给保障线，为地区经济复苏和区域联动发展作出巨大贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; “为推动全球发展和构建人类命运共同体作出不懈努力”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当前，国际局势变乱交织，加强各国互联互通，共建“一带一路”高质量发展，有助于建设开放型世界经济，推动世界各国走上和谐可持续的发展道路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴拿马经济学家、《丝绸之路与巴拿马》的作者埃迪·塔彼罗说，中国提出构建“一带一路”立体互联互通网络，意味着今后共建国家间的合作在陆海空各维度将向更高层面发展，是共建“一带一路”向更高阶段迈进的重要标志。构建“一带一路”立体互联互通网络对于提升互联互通水平、推动贸易投资合作和人文交流等具有重要意义。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;披差翁帕迪认为，构建“一带一路”立体互联互通网络是对现有“六廊六路多国多港”构成的互联互通基础框架的提升和完善，为促进广大发展中国家共同发展提供了新方案，期待共建“一带一路”为维护和平发展、推动多边主义、促进互联互通发挥更积极的作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿联酋沙迦美国大学国际研究系助理教授阿利舍尔·哈里亚罗夫表示，10年来，共建“一带一路”在推动互联互通建设方面取得丰硕成果，成为联通东西方的纽带，获得国际社会高度认可。构建“一带一路”立体互联互通网络有利于推动共建“一带一路”持续构建覆盖面更大更广的物流和技术网络。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿尔巴尼亚全球化研究所执行主任马塞拉·穆萨贝留表示，基础设施投资有利于推动经济增长和可持续发展，“我们看到中国以共建&#39;一带一路&#39;务实行动为推动全球发展和构建人类命运共同体作出不懈努力”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（本报北京、雅加达、曼谷、阿斯塔纳、约翰内斯堡、墨西哥城、迪拜10月22日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;记者俞懿春、李培松、曹师韵、杨一、李强、邹松、谢佳宁、张志文）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 23 Oct 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>