<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 河北加快建设新型能源体系]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/30/nw.D110000renmrb_20231030_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Monday, October 30, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: “We must increase the supply of clean energy, adjust the energy consumption structure, and persistently promote the ecology of the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region. Construction, accelerating the formation of spatial patterns, industrial structures, production methods, and lifestyles that conserve resources and protect the environment.&quot;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The cadres and masses of Hebei have thoroughly implemented the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech and strived to promote a comprehensive green transformation achieve new breakthroughs. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“The wind from Zhang Bei lights up the lights of Beijing.” This famous saying during the Beijing Winter Olympics has now been given new connotation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;As the country’s first national renewable energy demonstration zone, Zhangjiakou City fully empowers the Green Winter Olympics and emerges as a renewable energy city. At present, the installed capacity of renewable energy in Zhangjiakou City reaches 29.21 million kilowatts, accounting for 83.2% of the total installed electricity capacity. Through comprehensive utilization, it is expected that by 2025, the city will replace more than 21 million tons of standard coal per year in fossil energy and reduce annual emissions of 57 million tons of carbon dioxide, 11,000 tons of sulfur dioxide, and 12,000 tons of nitrogen oxides. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;From the capital Beijing to Xiongan New Area, the clean electricity brought by &quot;Zhangbei&#39;s wind&quot; is lighting up the lights of more cities. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Chasing the trend, Hebei coordinates the development of renewable energy sources such as photovoltaic and wind power, vigorously promotes the transformation and upgrading of energy production structure, improves the ability to guarantee the supply of clean energy, and accelerates the construction of new energy systems. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Bodhi Island Offshore Wind Farm is located in the waters of Laoting County, Tangshan City. Rows of white fans are firmly &quot;rooted&quot; in the sea, converting sea breeze into green electricity. This is the first offshore wind power project completed and put into operation in northern my country, with a total installed capacity of 300,000 kilowatts. &quot;The annual power generation is 760 million kilowatt hours, which can save about 262,000 tons of standard coal.&quot; Liu Xin, project operation and maintenance personnel, said. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Based on the advantages of wind and solar energy resources, Hebei strives to optimize the layout of key areas, build wind power photovoltaic power generation and green hydrogen manufacturing bases in Zhangjiakou and Chengde, and actively promote the layout in Tangshan, Cangzhou and other places that have the conditions for large-scale development 3 million-kilowatt photovoltaic development demonstration zones. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;As of the end of 2022, Hebei&#39;s total installed wind power and photovoltaic capacity is 66.52 million kilowatts; renewable energy power generation is 115.39 billion kilowatt hours, accounting for approximately 35% of the province&#39;s total power generation, a year-on-year increase of 6 percentage points. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Integrating new energy into the grid for consumption, Hebei will gradually optimize the energy consumption structure and promote cleanliness and diversification of energy consumption. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In 2022, Hebei will add 2.1 million kilowatts of pumped hydro storage installed capacity. In Fengning Manchu Autonomous County, Chengde City, the Yanshan Mountains are rolling hills, and the world&#39;s largest pumped storage power station with the largest installed capacity is &quot;hidden&quot; between two huge reservoirs. &quot;When electricity consumption is low, the surplus wind and solar energy pumps water from the lower reservoir to the upper reservoir; when electricity consumption peaks, water is released from the upper reservoir to generate electricity.&quot; said Wu Peizhi, deputy general manager of Hebei Fengning Pumped Storage Co., Ltd. The power station can consume 8.8 billion kilowatt-hours of excess electric energy every year, generate about 6.612 billion kilowatt-hours of electricity annually, and reduce carbon emissions by about 1.2 million tons. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In the Energy Management and Control Center of the Power Department of Tanggang New District of Hegang Group, various data such as blast furnace gas production, gas consumption of gas generating units, and steam consumption are displayed on the large monitoring screen. &quot;We integrate the blast furnace gas and coke oven gas of Tangshan Iron and Steel New District and its affiliated medium and heavy plate companies and Jiahua Coal Chemical Company to achieve regional sharing and interoperability, and use all the surplus gas for power generation.&quot; said Chen Xiaowei, head of the power department of Tangshan Iron and Steel New District. At present, the blast furnace gas in the factory has achieved zero emission, and the average proportion of purchased electricity is only 15%. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;During the &quot;Thirteenth Five-Year Plan&quot; period, Hebei has reduced and phased out a total of 82.12 million tons of steelmaking production capacity and 2.34 million kilowatts of thermal power production capacity, and its energy consumption per unit of regional GDP dropped by 22%. In 2022, coal will account for approximately 66% of Hebei&#39;s total energy consumption, a decrease of approximately 22 percentage points from 2012. The cleanliness of per capita energy consumption has become a highlight of Hebei&#39;s energy consumption in recent years. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“Focusing on building a clean, efficient and diversely supported new energy province, and focusing on building a multi-energy complementary energy pattern of &#39;wind, light, water, fire, nuclear, storage and hydrogen&#39;, Hebei will continue to accelerate construction New energy system.&quot; said Ni Yuefeng, Secretary of the Hebei Provincial Party Committee. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 中国将始终是世界发展的重要机遇]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/30/nw.D110000renmrb_20231030_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Monday, October 30, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;China’s development cannot be separated from the world, and the world’s prosperity also needs China. General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out, &quot;China will always be an important opportunity for world development. We open the door and welcome anyone who wants to cooperate with us.&quot; &quot;Looking to the future, as China&#39;s population of more than 1.4 billion moves towards modernization as a whole, China will definitely make a contribution to the world economy. greater contribution”. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Development is the eternal theme of human society, and shared development is an important path to building a better world. As the largest developing country, China has always placed its own development in the coordinate system of human development and used its own development to create new opportunities for world development. In the past 10 years, China&#39;s share of the global economy has increased from 11.3% in 2012 to about 18% in 2022. Its annual average contribution to world economic growth exceeds 30%, and it has always been an important factor in the stable growth of the world economy. Power source. Today, China is the world&#39;s largest trader in goods and a major trading partner of more than 140 countries and regions. It ranks among the top in attracting foreign capital and outbound investment, providing more market opportunities, investment opportunities, and growth opportunities for all countries. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Openness is a distinctive symbol of contemporary China. As the most potential large-scale market in the world, China is deeply interacting with the world, and its door is opening wider and wider. Since the new era, we have promoted trade and investment liberalization and facilitation, built a global high-standard free trade zone network, built free trade pilot zones and Hainan Free Trade Port, and promoted institutional opening up such as rules, regulations, management, and standards. my country has formed Open up to the outside world on a larger scale, in a wider field, and at a deeper level, and build an open economic system that is mutually beneficial, diversified, balanced, safe and efficient. In the first eight months of this year, the number of newly established foreign-invested enterprises across the country increased by 33% year-on-year. Against the background of the sluggish global cross-border investment, the &quot;magnetism&quot; of the Chinese market has become stronger and stronger, and continues to become a hot spot for attracting global investment, fully proving that reform and opening up is the The key move that determines the fate of contemporary China is also the key move that determines the success or failure of Chinese modernization. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Advance in the logic of historical progress and develop in the trend of the development of the times. Faced with the significantly increased instability and uncertainty in the world economy, China adheres to the correct direction of economic globalization, opposes protectionism, unilateral sanctions, generalized national security concepts, and opposes &quot;building walls and barriers&quot; and &quot;decoupling and breaking links&quot;, and strives to Let’s make the “cake” of mutually beneficial cooperation bigger so that development results can benefit people of all countries more equitably. China has signed cooperation documents on the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; with more than 150 countries and more than 30 international organizations. From 2013 to 2022, the total import and export volume between China and the co-building countries has accumulated to 19.1 trillion U.S. dollars, and the cumulative two-way investment with the co-building countries has exceeded 380 billion U.S. dollars. The cumulative value of China&#39;s newly signed contracts and completed turnover of projects contracted in the co-building countries has reached 2. Trillion dollars, $1.3 trillion. Practice has fully proved that when China is good, the world will be better. China is both a beneficiary and a contributor to economic globalization. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;This year marks the 45th anniversary of reform and opening up. China is proving with practical actions: China’s determination to expand high-level opening up will not change, its determination to share development opportunities with the world will not change, and it will promote economic globalization in a more dynamic direction. Our determination to develop in an open, inclusive, inclusive, balanced and win-win direction will not change. In January this year, the new version of the catalog of industries that encourage foreign investment was officially implemented, with 239 new entries, reaching a record high; in June, measures were introduced to take the lead in some qualified free trade pilot zones and the Hainan Free Trade Port to pilot docking with relevant international high standards. Economic and trade rules; in August, a new batch of highly targeted and valuable policies and measures were introduced to increase efforts to attract foreign investment; in October, China announced eight actions to support high-quality joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;... With great courage, we will promote opening up from a higher starting point, fulfill our firm promise that &quot;China&#39;s door of opening up will not close, but will only open wider and wider&quot;, and demonstrate its responsibility as a major country in &quot;continuously providing new opportunities for the world with China&#39;s new development&quot; . We firmly believe that a China that continues to modernize will provide the world with more opportunities, inject stronger impetus into international cooperation, and make greater contributions to the progress of all mankind. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The most important thing is simplicity. On the new journey, we will focus on promoting high-level opening up to the outside world, continue to comprehensively deepen reforms, steadily expand institutional opening up such as rules, regulations, management, and standards, create a market-oriented, legal, and international first-class business environment, and work with all parties to Promote the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; into a new stage of high-quality development, smooth the domestic and international dual cycles, make economic development more resilient and dynamic, and create more growth opportunities for the world while expanding the development space of Chinese-style modernization. Opportunities for transformation and innovation will allow China’s spring breeze of opening up to warm the world. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The world economy will prosper if it is open, and will decline if it is closed. Only openness can make progress. As we embark on a new journey, China will take more proactive and proactive actions to promote high-level opening up, develop a higher-level open economy, and always be an important promoter of global openness, working together with other countries in the world in the spirit of openness, cooperation, and win-win. Seek development and work together to create a better tomorrow for mankind. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 推动金融迈向高质量发展]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/30/nw.D110000renmrb_20231030_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Monday, October 30, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Finance is the core of the modern economy. Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, under the strong leadership of the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core, our country has unswervingly followed the path of financial development with Chinese characteristics and continued to promote high-quality development of the financial industry. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under the guidance of Xi Jinping’s Economic Thought, all localities and departments continue to deepen financial supply-side structural reforms, steadily expand financial opening, coordinate development and security, firmly guard the bottom line of no systemic risks, and work together to promote China’s The cause of financial reform and development is moving forward steadily. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Financial support has greatly improved the quality and efficiency of the real economy&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Finance is the blood of the real economy, and serving the real economy is the bounden duty of finance. Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, my country&#39;s financial sector has deepened its understanding of the nature and laws of finance, and has regarded serving the real economy as the foundation of the financial industry. The quality and efficiency of financial services to the real economy have been continuously improved. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A virtuous cycle between finance and the real economy has gradually formed -&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Having the world&#39;s largest banking system, the second largest insurance, stock and bond markets, and leading the world in inclusive finance, my country The financial system provides strong support for the long-term stable and healthy development of the economy and society. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Data from the People&#39;s Bank of China show that the balance of RMB loans to the real economy has climbed from 81.43 trillion yuan in 2014 to more than 230 trillion yuan in September 2023, with an average annual growth rate of 10 % or above, basically matching the nominal GDP growth rate. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Direct financing channels are also constantly opening up. From less than 30 trillion yuan in 2012 to more than 150 trillion yuan in custody balance today, China&#39;s bond market continues to grow and develop. &quot;Among the more than 5,200 A-share listed companies, there are nearly 2,900 listed companies in strategic emerging industries, empowering the high-quality development of the real economy.&quot; said Sun Nianrui, vice president of the China Association of Listed Companies. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Financial services in key areas and weak links have been continuously strengthened——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, the financial sector has continued to increase its support for manufacturing, technological innovation, small and micro enterprises, rural revitalization, green development, etc. Strengthen support in various fields and promote financial resources to be allocated to key areas and weak links. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Data from the financial management department show that as of the end of September this year, the balance of inclusive small and micro loans was 28.74 trillion yuan, with an average annual growth rate of about 25% in the past five years; the balance of green loans, medium and long-term manufacturing The balance of loans, the balance of &quot;specialized, special and new&quot; small and medium-sized enterprises, and the balance of agriculture-related loans increased by 36.8%, 38.2%, 18.6%, and 15.1% respectively year-on-year, which was much higher than the growth rate of various loans. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Serving the high-quality development of the economy, adjusting and improving the system of structural monetary policy tools, and playing a positive role in motivating and guiding financial institutions to optimize the allocation of credit resources.” Zou, Director of the Monetary Policy Department of the People’s Bank of China Lan said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The financing costs of real enterprises continue to decline——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, the formation and transmission mechanism of market-oriented interest rates have become increasingly perfect, the results of the reform of the loan market quotation rate (LPR) have continued to show, and the transmission of monetary policy Efficiency has gradually improved, driving social financing costs down significantly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The weighted average interest rate of new loans issued to Chinese enterprises in September was 3.85%, 14 basis points lower than the same period last year and at a historical low. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Effectively prevent and resolve financial risks&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Financial security is an important part of national security. Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of my country, our country has coordinated financial development and security, resolutely fought the battle to prevent and resolve major financial risks, and achieved important results in preventing and defusing financial risks. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The trend of financial assets turning from real to virtual has been reversed——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In response to phenomena such as idling funds and arbitrage, special management of market chaos has been carried out; new regulations on asset management have been fully implemented... In recent years , financial management departments resolutely clean up activities such as turning real money into virtual money and indiscriminately increasing leverage, and the scale of credit-like shadow banking has dropped by about 30 trillion yuan from its historical peak. In the past few years, capital flows to the real economy have increased significantly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The reform of small and medium-sized financial institutions and risk reduction are steadily advancing——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Recently, Liaoning Rural Commercial Bank has been approved to open, Shanxi Rural Commercial Bank and Henan Rural Commercial Bank have been approved to prepare for establishment... my country Important measures to steadily promote the reform of small and medium-sized financial institutions and reduce risks have been introduced one after another. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Institutional integration, equity restructuring, market exit... In recent years, our country has solidly promoted the reform and derisking of small and medium-sized financial institutions. Some institutions after reform and reorganization are gradually restoring their hematopoietic functions and achieving stable operations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the fourth quarter of 2022, the People&#39;s Bank of China completed ratings of 4,368 banking financial institutions. The results show that the number of high-risk institutions has dropped by nearly half compared with the peak pressure. There are no high-risk institutions within the jurisdiction of 10 provinces and cities. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The social financial order has basically realized &quot;from chaos to governance&quot; -&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strictly crack down on illegal financial activities, the &quot;Regulations on Preventing and Handling Illegal Fund-raising&quot; was promulgated, and joint management and group prevention were A comprehensive governance pattern for illegal fund-raising is taking shape, with collective governance, everyone doing his or her part, and collaborative efforts. The number of new cases of illegal fund-raising in my country, the amounts involved, and the number of people involved have been declining for many years. The special rectification work on P2P online lending was further promoted, and all P2P online lending institutions ceased operations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A number of financial policies have promoted the steady development of the real estate market——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, my country’s real estate market has experienced adjustments due to the impact of multiple factors. Promoting the stable development of the real estate market has become an important task to effectively prevent and resolve major economic and financial risks. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cooperate with the launch of 350 billion yuan of special loans for guaranteed housing, the establishment of a 200 billion yuan loan support plan for guaranteed housing, and the establishment of a 100 billion yuan rental housing loan support plan, reasonably optimize the down payment ratio and loan interest rate requirements, and steadily reduce Existing first-home loan interest rates... The financial &quot;combination punch&quot; has exerted force to promote the stable and healthy development of the real estate market. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To prevent and resolve financial risks, we must not only focus on key areas, but also establish and improve long-term mechanisms. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Start by rectifying shareholder equity and strengthen corporate governance of financial institutions; promulgate the &quot;Trial Measures for the Supervision and Management of Financial Holding Companies&quot;, &quot;Measures for the Assessment of Systemically Important Banks&quot;, &quot;Methods for the Assessment of Systemically Important Insurance Companies&quot;...to address both the symptoms and root causes. , make up for regulatory shortcomings and build a solid financial safety net. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Adhere to bottom-line thinking, strengthen the concept of systems, focus on resolving risks in key areas, and strictly adhere to the bottom line of no systemic risks. At present, my country&#39;s financial industry is operating generally stably, and all work to prevent and resolve risks is advancing in an orderly manner.&quot; National The person in charge of relevant work of the State Administration of Financial Supervision and Administration said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Financial reform and opening up are further advanced&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Continue to deepen financial supply-side structural reform and steadily expand financial opening... Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, my country’s financial Reform and opening up have been advanced in an orderly manner and new major breakthroughs have been achieved. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The financial regulatory system continues to improve -&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On May 18, the State Administration of Financial Supervision was officially launched, marking an important step in a new round of financial regulatory agency reform. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Central Financial Commission was established, the Central Financial Working Committee was established, the State Financial Supervision Administration was established, the reform of the local financial regulatory system was deepened, and the China Securities Regulatory Commission was adjusted to an agency directly under the State Council... In March this year, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China , The State Council issued the &quot;Party and State Institutional Reform Plan&quot;, many of which involve the field of financial supervision. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Industry insiders pointed out that from the last round of financial regulatory reforms, the establishment of the Financial Stability and Development Committee of the State Council and the establishment of the China Banking and Insurance Regulatory Commission, to the current round of major adjustments to the financial regulatory landscape, my country has continued to deepen financial regulation in recent years. System reform will promote the unification of regulatory standards and improve regulatory efficiency. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;System reform in the financial sector continues to make efforts -&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Establish the Science and Technology Innovation Board and pilot a registration system to support and encourage &quot;hard technology&quot; companies to go public; the GEM reform and pilot a registration system, Continuously improve support and services for innovative and entrepreneurial enterprises; establish the Beijing Stock Exchange to create a main position for serving innovative small and medium-sized enterprises... Focus on the supply side, identify the focus of financial services, and the capital market reform continues to deepen. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, reform has become a high-frequency word in the financial field. From promoting the loan market quoted interest rate (LPR) reform, to continuing to improve the corporate governance of financial institutions, from making significant progress in the third pillar pension insurance reform pilot, to the full implementation of the stock issuance registration system reform, a series of reforms have laid the foundation for promoting high-quality financial development. Institutional basis. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Financial opening is proceeding rapidly and steadily——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shanghai-Shenzhen-Hong Kong Stock Connect, Shanghai-London Stock Connect, Mainland and Hong Kong Bond Connect, and Swap Connect were launched, and Chinese bonds were included in the world&#39;s three major bond indexes. Lift restrictions on the shareholding ratio of foreign financial institutions in China and significantly expand the business scope of foreign financial institutions... In recent years, my country&#39;s financial market has shown a more open attitude, and foreign institutions have continued to increase investment in China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China’s financial market has sent a clear signal of opening up to the international community, and has also promoted the improvement of the global financial governance system and significantly enhanced global market confidence.” said Li Jiange, Director General of the Global Wealth Management Forum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Data show that as of the end of September this year, 202 banks from 52 countries and regions have established institutions in China; from 2020 to the end of September 2023, the total capital increase (injection) of foreign banks in China will be Reaching 18.73 billion yuan. As of the end of September this year, a total of 1,110 overseas institutions had entered the Chinese bond market, holding 3.3 trillion yuan of Chinese bonds. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;RMB internationalization is making steady progress. According to data from the Society for Worldwide Interbank Financial Telecommunication (SWIFT), in September 2023, the RMB accounted for 5.8% of global trade financing, a year-on-year increase of 1.6 percentage points, and its ranking rose to second place. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Finance is an important core competitiveness of the country. Under the guidance of Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, all localities and departments have actively promoted high-quality financial development. The path of financial development with Chinese characteristics will surely become wider and better, providing strong support for Chinese-style modernization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 29th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Reporters Zhao Xiaohui, Li Yanxia, ​​Wu Yu, Liu Hui)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 共绘新画卷  携手向未来]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/30/nw.D110000renmrb_20231030_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Monday, October 30, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;The 19th Asian Games in Hangzhou and the 4th Asian Paralympic Games in Hangzhou came to a successful conclusion. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hosting the Hangzhou Asian Games and the Asian Paralympic Games successfully is a major event in the work of the party and the country this year. Under the strong leadership of the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping at its core, Zhejiang Province and Hangzhou City have solidly advanced various preparations and carefully organized and guaranteed events to ensure that &quot;the two Asian Games are equally exciting.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When traveling across Asia, Hangzhou is the most memorable place. An Asian Games that is green, smart, frugal and civilized, and an Asian Para Games that is sunny, harmonious, self-reliant and shared, presents a beautiful sports picture to the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What did the Hangzhou Asian Games and Asian Para Games bring, what changed, and what was left behind? Walking on the river and the earth, the answer lies within. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;b>;A unique event&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the evening of October 28, after the closing ceremony of the Hangzhou Asian Para Games, all 36,000 people present left the venue. It takes 30 minutes. Relying on public transportation guarantees to achieve fast and safe movement of people, from the Asian Games to the Asian Para Games, the efficiency of the entry and exit of spectators at the opening and closing ceremonies was praised. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Behind the orderliness, there is both the &quot;hardware&quot; support of urban construction and the &quot;software&quot; assistance of urban management. Since the successful bid to host the Hangzhou Asian Games and Asian Para Games, Zhejiang has seized the opportunity and worked hard to promote urban infrastructure construction to a new level. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Numbers are the most intuitive thing about urban changes. In recent years, Hangzhou has built more than 500 kilometers of subway, and its highway network, express lanes, high-speed rail stations and other transportation facilities have been significantly improved; more than 1,000 kilometers of the Qiantang River Greenway has been put into use; more than 1,000 old communities have been renovated... Combined with promoting development and serving people&#39;s livelihood, let the people have a greater sense of gain and happiness. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Development is fast and warm. In recent years, Hangzhou has upgraded 140,000 barrier-free points and important public places, set up 380 sign language barrier-free service points, and launched hundreds of barrier-free cruising taxis. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Hangzhou is a very friendly city for people with disabilities.” Majid Rashid, Chairman of the Asian Paralympic Committee, said that from the service details of the games and the spirit of the citizens, we can feel the civilization of this city degree. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the Hangzhou Asian Games and Asian Para Games, the high-tech venues left a deep impression on people. Since the beginning of preparations, Zhejiang has put forward clear goals to make good use of various resources such as venue facilities and competition experience to continue to amplify the comprehensive effect. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All 56 competition venues have been opened to benefit the people ahead of schedule, and have received a total of more than 10 million fitness people. In accordance with the principle of &quot;for the event during the game, for the city after the game&quot;, 51 Asian Games venues have already determined their post-game utilization plans and operating units, allowing the masses to share the results of the Asian Games. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In today’s Zhijiang land, participating in fitness activities has become a new trend, and cycling and hiking are very popular. A large number of fitness venues are embedded in the &quot;life circle&quot;, and idle urban space has become a &quot;gold corner and silver edge&quot; for mass exercise, and the national fitness public service system has improved quality and efficiency. According to statistics, the number of people in Hangzhou who regularly participate in physical exercise has exceeded 5 million. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The host&#39;s outstanding organizational skills have polished the city&#39;s business card, and invitations have been issued to many international competitions. The Badminton World Tour Finals will be held in Hangzhou for four consecutive years starting from this year. Many international individual sports organizations such as the International Canoe Federation and the International Hockey Federation have reached cooperation intentions with Hangzhou. Accelerating the creation of an international &quot;game&quot; and &quot;meeting&quot; city, Hangzhou aims at a new starting point. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China once again hosted the Asian Games and the Asian Paralympic Games, and its practice of hosting games based on the strengths of others has won high praise from the international community. Singh, acting chairman of the Olympic Council of Asia, praised the Hangzhou Asian Games as &quot;splendid, unforgettable and an unprecedented success.&quot; Terek Soe, CEO of the Asian Paralympic Committee, said that the Asian Paralympic Games in Hangzhou is a unique event. &quot;Hangzhou has raised the standards for hosting events and set a benchmark.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;b>;The comprehensive effect of hosting large-scale games continues to appear&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The digital torchbearers &quot;tide-setters&quot; have come on the wave, and the Asian Games ignition method is refreshing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This scene shows the elegance of the host. Zhejiang adheres to reform and opening up, has accelerated high-quality development, is building a demonstration zone for common prosperity, and is a pioneer in Chinese-style modernization. The successful hosting of the Asian Games and Asian Para Games has injected new momentum into local economic and social development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Green is the background color of Zhejiang’s development, and it also runs through the entire process of hosting the competition. From the realization of green electricity supply in all competition venues and the use of zero-carbon fuel to light the main torch, to the &quot;careful calculation&quot; of operating energy consumption and the creation of the first large-scale &quot;no waste&quot; event, the practice of low-carbon environmental protection and simplicity and frugality are integrated into many details. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Green living has become a common practice and depends on the conscious actions of more and more citizens. Competing to buy &quot;zero-carbon mascots&quot;, actively choosing green travel, and actively participating in the &quot;Supporting Asian Games Carbon Neutral&quot; activities... Meng Xiangsheng, deputy director of the Environmental Protection Department of the Hangzhou Asian Games Organizing Committee, said that in the future, good practices and experiences from the Green Asian Games will be incorporated into Daily management services of the city to promote sustainable urban development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;100% of the core systems of the Asian Games are on the cloud, the &quot;City Brain&quot; system manages traffic in real time, and intelligent guide dogs provide accurate automatic navigation... Intelligent concepts are integrated into every aspect of organizing the games, and a large number of scientific and technological achievements and cutting-edge technologies are included. Highlight the unique advantages of Zhejiang’s digital economy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;These valuable explorations will benefit the local area for a long time after the game. The &quot;Smart Asian Games One Stop&quot; platform will be transformed into a digital city service platform; the 5G technology improvement and 5.5G technology pilot applied during the games will bring better network services; continue to use digital technology to accelerate the development of smart logistics...&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;Taking advantage of the competition, the cultural tourism market has gained traffic and further unleashed its consumption potential. As of October 5, the total market development revenue from the Hangzhou Asian Games and Asian Para Games reached 5.316 billion yuan. During this year’s Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday, Zhejiang received a total of 43.724 million tourists and achieved tourism revenue of 48.64 billion yuan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The &quot;Asian Games Economy&quot; not only brings new opportunities to the sports industry, but also empowers rural revitalization and promotes coordinated regional development. Hangzhou Chun&#39;an County has promoted the development of catering, accommodation and other related industries by holding high-quality events; Ningbo Xiangshan County has tested the &quot;events + folk customs&quot; model and has become an internet celebrity check-in place; Shaoxing Keqiao District has created a series of rural sports and tourism products; From January to August this year, Yiwu&#39;s sporting goods exports reached 5.08 billion yuan, a new high in the past five years... The comprehensive effect of hosting large-scale competitions continues to show. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From ecological beauty, innovation power to development vitality, through the window of the Asian Games and Asian Para Games, it provides more perspectives to understand the &quot;beauty of Zhejiang&quot; and &quot;the governance of China&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;b>;Every promise becomes a reality&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the closing ceremony of the Hangzhou Asian Para Games, when the mascot &quot;Feifei&quot; hovered in the night, Farewell to the main torch affectionately, &quot;the two Asian Games are equally exciting&quot; came to a successful conclusion. This warm journey engraves the beautiful memories of &quot;sharing the same love together&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the field, athletes inspire each other and write dreams-chasing stories with hard work and passion; in the athletes&#39; village, young people from all over Asia exchange badges and make friends; when parting, many athletes leave messages for volunteers Write a letter of thanks and meet again... The touching scenes brought the hearts of Asian people closer and their hands closer. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What is more important than winning is participation, and what is more dazzling than gold medals is friendship. In addition to competitive competitions, friendly exchanges between delegations continue to enhance understanding and build consensus. In the Mid-Autumn Festival gatherings, in the activities of experiencing intangible cultural heritage, and in the process of collecting the city&#39;s scenery, guests and friends from far away experienced and understood China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Using sports to promote peace, unity and tolerance, the Hangzhou Asian Games and Asian Para Games have used vivid practices and fruitful results to show the world the unique charm and role of sports. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The magnificent rivers and mountains of Asia, the cultural confidence of the great country and the connotation of the times are eloquently described. Whether it is the design of mascots, emblems, medals, etc., or the presentation of the opening and closing ceremonies, the time-honored excellent traditional Chinese culture and the pioneering and innovative modern civilization are cleverly integrated, and the unique charm of the poetic and picturesque Jiangnan is long-lasting. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sports paves the way and builds bridges for exchanges and mutual learning between civilizations. When the Asian family gathers in Hangzhou, they will never forget the unique landscapes and cityscapes, the sincere and warm cultural exchanges, and the warm and thoughtful volunteer services. This two-way journey will sow the seeds of working together and being open and inclusive in more hearts. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From bidding, preparation to hosting, the Hangzhou Asian Games and Asian Paralympic Games have turned promises into reality, once again demonstrating China&#39;s responsibility and Chinese style, and contributing to the development of the international Olympic movement and international sports for the disabled. make new contributions to development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From the theme slogan of the Hangzhou Asian Games, &quot;Hearts are in harmony, love the future&quot; to the theme slogan of the Hangzhou Asian Para Games, &quot;Hearts are together, dreams are shining&quot;, the Chinese people, together with the people of other countries, have played a vital role in promoting the construction of Asia and a community with a shared future for mankind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strengthen the foundation of sports, gather tremendous strength, and pursue your dreams. The new Asian miracle will unfold through joint creation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Our reporters Li Zhongwen, Wu Weizheng, Zheng Yi, Sun Longfei, Dou Hao)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 图片报道]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/30/nw.D110000renmrb_20231030_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Monday, October 30, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http ://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231030/1698611285787_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt; /TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;The latest agricultural dispatch from the Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs shows that the national autumn harvest is progressing in an orderly manner, and the harvest is currently over 85%. Agricultural departments in many places organized cross-regional mechanical harvests to speed up the harvest progress. Farmers from all over the country are taking advantage of the fine weather and giving full play to the advantages of mechanization to ensure that autumn grain grains are returned to warehouses. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The picture shows on October 28, large combine harvesters are harvesting rice in the high-standard farmland of Jiangsu Nongken Xinyang Farm in Sheyang County, Jiangsu Province. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Photographed by Zhang Weisheng (Image China)&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https: //feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color :orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 水质更洁净  饮水更安全]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/30/nw.D110000renmrb_20231030_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Monday, October 30, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;At dawn, Yan Keliang, the ranger of Shehe National Wetland Park in Fushun City, Liaoning Province, set out. This is the estuary where the Shehe River merges into the Dahuofang Reservoir. Yan Keliang walks the 3.8-kilometer-long road around the reservoir three times a day. &quot;I am always worried. I am guarding a &#39;big water tank&#39; for 23 million people.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the same time, in Xinglongtai District, Panjin City, more than 270 kilometers away, resident Zhang Ying turned on the kitchen faucet and filled the water for breakfast. &quot;The water I drank before was very &#39;hard&#39;. Over time, there was a thick layer of scale in the kettle. Now I drink the water from Dahuofang Reservoir, and the water quality is much better than before.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liaoning Dahuofang Water Source The Dahuofang Reservoir and Huanren Reservoir within the local area provide drinking water to about 23 million residents in Liaoning. They are &quot;big water tanks&quot; that are closely related to the lives of more than half of the population in Liaoning. Maintaining high standards of water quality and quantity in Dahufang water sources is related to the safety of drinking water for the people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In August 2022, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized during an inspection in Liaoning: &quot;A good ecological environment is a valuable resource for the economic and social development of the Northeast region and an advantage for revitalizing the Northeast. The concept of green development must be integrated into the ecology Protection, environmental construction, production and manufacturing, urban development, people&#39;s lives and other aspects, accelerating the construction of a beautiful China. The construction of ecological civilization can significantly enhance the people&#39;s sense of gain, and the people have the most profound experience.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Keep in mind General Secretary Xi Jinping Yin Yin requested that Liaoning thoroughly implement Xi Jinping’s thoughts on ecological civilization, establish the Dahuofang Water Source Protection Area Management Committee, launch the comprehensive management action of the Dahuofang Water Source Area, scientifically delineate the area of ​​​​8329.6 square kilometers of protected areas at all levels, and implement closed management and relocation at different levels. exit, upgrade and transformation, etc., and continue to improve and optimize the ecological compensation mechanism. In 2022, the provincial finance will arrange transfer payment funds of 400 million yuan for key ecological functional zones in Fushun and Benxi cities. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We have organized local ecological law enforcement and monitoring and supervision forces to continue to carry out cross-regional law enforcement and special supervision and assistance. This year, Fushun and Benxi cities have adopted a ‘mutual inspection and mutual inspection’ approach to further consolidate the effectiveness of law enforcement. .&quot; Jin Qilong, deputy director of the Liaoning Provincial Department of Ecology and Environment, introduced. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yan Keliang lives in Taigou Village, Shangma Town, Fushun County, Fushun City. The entrance to the village is less than 500 meters away from the Wetland Park. After Taigou Village was designated as a first-level protected area for drinking water sources, measures such as closed management and returning farmland to grassland were implemented. Yan Keliang became a caretaker and was responsible for guarding the fence and cleaning up garbage on a daily basis. &quot;The annual compensation for returning farmland is 1,000 yuan per mu, plus the monthly salary of 1,200 yuan for the management and care staff, so we can eat &#39;ecological rice&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first-level protected area will return farmland to land for cultivation and implement ecological compensation. Liaoning has established a vertical ecological compensation mechanism led by provincial financial investment. It arranges 41.18 million yuan in compensation funds for returning farmland every year, completes the conversion of 33,900 acres of land into grassland, and builds more than 600 kilometers of closed fences around the reservoir. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Nanzamu Town, Xinbin Manchu Autonomous County, which is located upstream of Dahuofang Reservoir and on the south bank of the Hun River, domestic sewage is collected and treated by the town’s new sewage treatment plant, and flows into the artificial wetland with clear and transparent water. &quot;The wetland also contains a 7-layer filtration system, and the quality of the water finally discharged into the river reaches Grade A standard.&quot; Wang Yingjun, deputy director of the Xinbin County Housing and Urban-Rural Development Bureau, said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Prevent and control non-point source pollution and strictly control the quality of water entering the reservoir. Fushun and Benxi cities have invested a total of nearly 400 million yuan in infrastructure construction and the upgrading and renovation of seven sewage treatment plants. The water quality of their water sources continues to remain above Class III level, and the water quality compliance rate of centralized drinking water sources is 100%. Within the reserve, the green organic agriculture demonstration base covers an area of ​​116,000 acres. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沿浑河而上，清原满族自治县英额门镇隆鑫中药材种植专业合作社种植基地内，种植着龙胆草、苍术等中药材。 “种植中药材用有机肥，龙胆草烘干后每斤能卖110元，一亩地收入3万多元。”合作社理事长于泽朋说，“去年，合作社药材种植和加工共收入2000多万元。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“生态好，中药材品质才好。”英额门镇党委书记杨雷介绍，短短几年，英额门镇中药材种植面积从2万亩发展到5万亩，全镇现有56家中药材合作社、16家中药材初加工厂，中药材产业促进人均年增收约1万元。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;登上抚顺市萨尔浒风景区的最高点俯瞰，大伙房水库如同蓝色的绸缎。 “景区游客多的时候，一天得开车往返10多趟。”景区电瓶车司机朴浩说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大伙房水源地如同生态“明珠”，点亮了辽东的苍翠群山，依水而建的萨尔浒风景区、红河峡谷漂流等景点尽显山水之美，清原县获评国家级生态示范区、全国休闲农业与乡村旅游示范县。今年上半年，抚顺市接待游客764.69万人次，同比增长40.42%；旅游总收入35.11亿元，同比增长39.49%。 &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 前三季度港口货物吞吐量同比增8.5%（新数据 新看点）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/30/nw.D110000renmrb_20231030_7-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月30日星期一&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报北京10月29日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者韩鑫）仅用不到9个月，浙江宁波舟山港累计完成货物吞吐量超10亿吨，领先全球其他主要港口；河北港口集团累计完成货物吞吐量超6亿吨，同比增长8.7%……今年以来，我国港口货物吞吐量增速保持较高水平。交通运输部近日发布的最新数据显示，前三季度，我国完成港口货物吞吐量125.4亿吨，同比增长8.5%；其中第三季度增长9.5%，与上半年相比加快1.5个百分点。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;快速增长的货物吞吐量折射出国内消费需求增长、经济运行企稳回升的向好态势，也彰显出我国交通运输经济运行持续稳定恢复，物流保通保畅成果进一步巩固的良好趋势。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;数据显示，前三季度我国集装箱吞吐量完成2.3亿标准箱，同比增长5.2%；其中第三季度增长5.9%，增速较上半年加快1个百分点。此外，今年以来我国主要大宗商品进口需求强劲，铁矿石、煤炭、粮食合计进口13.4亿吨，同比增长18.3%。外贸货物吞吐量37.7亿吨，同比增长10.1%。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 统筹好发展和安全（深度观察）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/30/nw.D110000renmrb_20231030_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月30日星期一&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;统筹好发展和安全，是确保经济持续健康发展和社会大局稳定的关键。其中，就业是最基本的民生，粮食和能源是必须牢牢端稳的“两个饭碗”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年以来，面对复杂严峻的外部环境和国内多重困难挑战，就业、粮食生产、能源保供形势怎么样？如何兜牢兜实安全底线，为发展奠定良好基础？记者就相关问题采访了多位专家学者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;就业形势总体稳定，城镇调查失业率稳中有降&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：国家统计局发布的数据显示，前三季度，全国城镇调查失业率平均值为5.3%，比上年同期下降0.3个百分点。您如何评价前三季度的就业形势？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中央党校（国家行政学院）社会和生态文明教研部副主任赖德胜：今年以来，各地区各有关部门突出做好稳增长、稳就业、稳物价工作，有力有效实施稳岗支持和扩岗激励措施，多渠道拓展就业空间，前三季度就业形势总体稳定、持续好转。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一是城镇调查失业率稳中有降。从三季度各月情况看，7月份城镇调查失业率为5.3%，8月份为5.2%，9月份为5%，逐月好转。二是农民工就业持续改善。随着接触型聚集型服务业明显回升，市场用工需求增加，前三季度，城镇外来农业户籍劳动力失业率平均值为5.1%，比上年同期下降0.5个百分点。三是就业质量稳步提升。前三季度，全国居民人均工资性收入比上年同期增长6.8%，快于全国居民收入增速0.5个百分点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国劳动和社会保障科学研究院就业创业研究室主任陈云：综合就业增长、失业水平等主要指标走势看，年初劳动力市场出现一段时间的回补性反弹后经历了短期调整，之后即转入稳步复苏的发展态势。1至9月份，全国城镇新增就业1022万人，完成全年目标任务的85%，超过时序进度。全国城镇调查失业率稳步回落，9月份为5%，为今年以来单月最低值。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，劳动力市场监测显示需求逐步回暖，供求保持动态平衡；社会对就业的当前感受和未来预期回升改善。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：下阶段，就业形势保持总体稳定还面临哪些压力？还需重点做好哪些方面的工作？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陈云：当前稳就业具有诸多有利因素，但受外部环境复杂严峻、国内经济恢复基础尚不稳固等多重因素叠加影响，也面临不少挑战。例如部分行业企业稳岗压力持续、青年人就业压力较大等。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;推动就业形势持续改善，要加大就业优先战略实施力度，提高政策和服务精准度。强化就业优先导向，实施扩大内需战略，推进新业态、新消费发展，促进综合零售、餐饮住宿、文旅娱乐等传统用工量大的行业巩固复苏势头；加大新型基础设施、城市更新改造、社会民生和基层治理等建设领域投资；发展数字经济、绿色经济、照护经济等，培育新的就业增长点，激发经济和就业增长新动能。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，发挥促进就业创业工作的协同效应，推动财政、货币、产业等政策与就业政策的衔接，更好支持稳岗扩岗。完善统一规范的人力资源市场，着力打造全方位公共就业服务体系，对就业困难群体提供精细化服务，帮助其尽快实现就业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;赖德胜：解决就业问题根本上要靠经济发展，但也要注意经济发展与就业的协同联动，提升经济发展促就业作用。要坚持稳中求进，把稳增长放在更加突出位置，推动经济实现质的有效提升和量的合理增长，实现与就业促进良性互动。要细化实化扩内需举措，持续扩投资促消费，提升就业带动力；不断壮大发展新动能，同时解决好新就业形态劳动者的权益维护和社会保障问题，为年轻人特别是高校毕业生创业就业开辟更多新领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;粮食安全基本盘稳固，秋粮有望再获丰收&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：如何评价我国今年以来的粮食安全形势和当前秋粮生产基础？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国农科院作物科学研究所党委书记、副所长刘录祥：从农业农村部农情调度数据来看，目前我国秋粮收获已超八成，冬小麦秋种已过半，2023年我国粮食产量可能再创历史新高。今年，我国夏粮生产虽然遭遇“烂场雨”等不利自然条件影响略有减产，但通过及时组织农技人员下沉一线、开展减灾救灾等各项综合措施有效应对，夏粮产量达到2923亿斤，仍居历史第二高位，早稻单产和总产实现双增长，牢牢守稳了粮食安全基本盘。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;秋粮约占我国全年粮食总产量的3/4，对于实现全年粮食生产目标至关重要。今年播种面积同比增加了700万亩左右，其中，高产作物玉米面积增加了1300万亩，大豆面积也有小幅增加。可以说，各地落实落细稳面积、推技术、提单产等各项措施，为秋粮生产打下良好基础。从当前看，玉米主产区普遍实现大面积丰产，在田作物长势总体正常，全国粮食有望再获丰收。后期还要紧盯机收和烘干等关键环节，强化收获减损，确保颗粒归仓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：今年中央一号文件提出“实施新一轮千亿斤粮食产能提升行动”。下一步，保障粮食安全，我们面临着怎样的形势，需要瞄准哪些领域重点发力？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国农业风险管理研究会会长张红宇：从粮食需求角度来看，消费结构升级、新型城镇化加快推进、国际形势复杂多变等因素对粮食生产提出更高要求，粮食和重要农产品仍将处于供需紧平衡。适应国内外形势变化，更好应对全球粮食安全挑战，需要不断强化粮食和重要农产品的产业链韧性，确保平时产得出、供得足，极端情况下顶得上、靠得住。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;下一步，在高基点上实现粮食生产新突破，要聚焦良种、良田、良法、良机、良制等关键环节和重点领域，推动科技创新和集成运用，把试验田产量转化为大田产量，提高粮食综合生产能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，进一步调动地方重农抓粮和农民务农种粮积极性，还需用足用好政策工具箱，健全政府投资与金融、社会投入联动机制，优化农业支持保护体系，补齐粮食生产投入短板，提升补贴政策效能。特别是针对气候、市场等不确定性因素，要加快建设多层次农业风险管理体系，降低全产业链风险，持续稳定种粮预期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;主要能源产品生产保持稳步增长，供需总体趋于平衡&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：今年以来能源供需形势如何？当前国际形势复杂多变、局部地区冲突频现，能源安全是否有保障？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国宏观经济研究院能源研究所研究员苏铭：今年以来，我国经济恢复向好，带动能源电力需求稳定增加。为保障民生和经济社会发展用能用电需求，我国持续做好能源增产保供工作。前三季度，规模以上工业原煤、原油和天然气产量同比分别增长3%、1.9%和6.4%，海外资源获取能力显著提高，煤炭、原油、天然气进口同比增长73.1%、14.6%、8.2%，风电、光伏发电等装机持续大幅增加，能源供需总体平衡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总体看，我国能源安全具备坚实支撑。一方面，我国持续增强一次能源生产能力，近年来能源自给率一直保持在80%以上。另一方面，我国始终强调用好国内国际两种资源、两个市场，面对国际复杂严峻形势，努力化被动为主动，更加灵活调整进口和出口，提升应对外部风险的能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国务院发展研究中心资源与环境政策研究所研究员郭焦锋：今年以来，我国能源供需总体平稳，具有较好的基础。煤炭和煤电继续做好兜底保障作用，前三季度，原煤生产同比上涨3%，火电发电量同比增长5.8%；非化石能源快速发展，核电、风电和太阳能发电量增长10.8%；能源进口来源继续保持多元，四大油气进口战略通道基本形成，资源配置能力大幅提升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者：如何看待接下来供暖季的能源供需形势，怎么确保能源供应、价格基本稳定？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;苏铭：进入供暖季，我国能源电力需求还将保持较快增长势头。当前，我国正为迎峰度冬能源保障做好准备，煤炭库存保持在高位，天然气储备能力进一步提高。总的来看，能源供需将保持总体平衡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时，我们要密切跟踪国际形势变化，防范非常规因素可能导致的油气供应受阻或价格上涨风险；此外，针对气温骤降或冰冻雨雪等极端天气未雨绸缪，做好国内电力热力负荷骤增的保障准备，防范极端天气对管道天然气进口和进口液化天然气入港的不利影响。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郭焦锋：为确保我国能源供应、价格基本稳定，需重点关注以下几方面工作：一是加强预测预警跟踪分析。建议能源、气象等部门强化联合研究，形成有效应急方案。二是加强煤炭、天然气、电力中长期合同签订和履约监管，保障开采、运输和交易环节畅通。三是进一步加强灵活性资源调度管理。建议电网企业统筹各种资源，优化调度方案，配合价格、管理等机制创新，尽可能在应急状态下利用更多的可调节性资源；进一步完善电力跨省跨区交易机制，更好发挥价格机制的资源配置作用，提升大电网平台作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 扎扎实实把金融工作做好]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/30/nw.D110000renmrb_20231030_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月30日星期一&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;习近平总书记指出，“金融是国家重要的核心竞争力，金融安全是国家安全的重要组成部分，金融制度是经济社会发展中重要的基础性制度。”“维护金融安全，是关系我国经济社会发展全局的一件带有战略性、根本性的大事。”&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;金融活，经济活；金融稳，经济稳。党的十八大以来，在以习近平同志为核心的党中央坚强领导下，我们持续深化金融改革、治理金融风险，推动金融业有序扩大开放，金融业保持快速发展，金融产品日益丰富，金融服务普惠性增强，金融监管得到加强和改进。金融领域完整准确全面贯彻新发展理念，助力加快构建新发展格局，服务经济高质量发展的能力和效率大幅提升。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;党的二十大报告提出，“深化金融体制改革，建设现代中央银行制度，加强和完善现代金融监管，强化金融稳定保障体系，依法将各类金融活动全部纳入监管，守住不发生系统性风险底线。”必须充分认识金融在经济发展和社会生活中的重要地位和作用，切实把维护金融安全作为治国理政的一件大事，扎扎实实把金融工作做好。要抓住完善金融服务、防范金融风险这个重点，推动金融业高质量发展，确保金融安全高效稳健运行，为实体经济发展提供源源不断的优质金融服务，为经济高质量发展贡献强有力的金融力量。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;服务好实体经济，夯实防范金融风险的根本。金融是实体经济的血脉，为实体经济服务是金融的天职，是金融的宗旨，也是防范金融风险的根本举措。必须增强金融服务实体经济能力，坚决打好防范化解包括金融风险在内的重大风险攻坚战，推动我国金融业健康发展。无论是管好货币信贷总闸门，还是提升金融服务质效，都要锚定实体经济、紧扣实体经济和服务实体经济。截至今年9月末，我国对实体经济发放的人民币贷款余额为232.78万亿元，同比增长10.7%。金融支持实体经济力度要够、节奏要稳、结构要优、价格要可持续，金融监管部门、金融机构和金融市场以实现经济质的有效提升和量的合理增长为目标，推动创新链产业链资金链人才链深度融合，为实体经济提供更有力支持，助力夯实中国式现代化的物质技术基础。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;坚定深化金融改革，不断增强风险防范能力。必须深化对国际国内金融形势的认识，正确把握金融本质，深化金融供给侧结构性改革，平衡好稳增长和防风险的关系，精准有效处置重点领域风险，深化金融改革开放，增强金融服务实体经济能力。党的十八大以来，我国金融改革有序前行，利率市场化改革取得突破进展、金融要素市场化改革取得重要进展、金融资源配置更加高效，推出科创板、设立北交所、全面实行股票发行注册制，金融产品与服务实现创新提质。以服务实体经济、服务人民生活为本，金融改革的持续深化，为实体经济发展提供更高质量、更有效率的金融服务，也进一步夯实自身安全高效稳健发展的根基。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;加强和完善现代金融监管，不断提高金融治理体系和治理能力现代化水平。优化金融体系治理是防范化解重大金融风险的重要方面，健全现代金融企业制度、推进构建现代金融监管框架、健全金融法治等是优化金融体系治理的重要举措。强化公司治理，深化国有商业银行改革，促进中小银行和农村信用社建立有效的治理制衡机制……近年来，金融监管部门坚决防范化解金融风险，推动建立常态化金融风险处置机制，逐步夯实防范化解金融风险长效机制，重点领域风险得到稳妥处置，守住不发生系统性风险的底线，金融治理体系和治理能力现代化水平的不断提升，为持续深化金融改革和对外开放营造了良好环境。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;防范化解金融风险，特别是防止发生系统性金融风险，是金融工作的根本性任务，也是金融工作的永恒主题。站在新的历史起点上，我们要坚持以习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想为指导，深刻认识防范化解重大金融风险的重要战略意义，深化对金融本质和规律的认识，立足中国实际，坚定不移走好中国特色金融发展之路，为全面建设社会主义现代化国家贡献力量。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 图片报道]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/30/nw.D110000renmrb_20231030_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月30日星期一&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231030/1698611134603_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;近年来，青海省海东市互助土族自治县把马铃薯产业作为乡村振兴的重要产业之一。今年该县马铃薯种植面积达21万亩。图为农民正在卓扎滩马铃薯种薯繁育基地捡拾马铃薯并装袋。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;本报记者&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;贺&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;勇摄&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 种业振兴行动取得关键性突破（经济新方位）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/30/nw.D110000renmrb_20231030_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月30日星期一&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;今年是我国实施种业振兴行动的第三年。2021年以来，农业农村部全面启动种质资源保护利用、创新攻关、企业扶优、基地提升、市场净化五大行动。农业农村部有关负责人表示，打好种业振兴行动这场翻身仗，必须进一步发挥制度优势，加快推动高水平种业科技自立自强，引导资源要素向种业企业聚集，实现种业全产业链现代化，推动我国种业高质量发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;从“满足量”转向“提升质”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第十五届中国国际种业博览会暨第二十届全国种子信息交流与产品交易会9月在安徽省合肥市召开。节水抗旱稻、无限生长型黄果小番茄、适合制作爆米花的爆裂玉米……围绕当前农业生产用种和市场多样化需求，超350家种业企业带来看家品种。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从“满足量”到“提升质”，一系列良种诠释着大食物观。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;农业农村部总农艺师曾衍德介绍，种业振兴行动实施以来，各地各部门集中优势资源聚力攻坚，在种质资源保护、重大品种和关键技术创新、国家级种业基地布局建设等方面取得了许多关键性突破和标志性成果。目前，全国新收集农作物、畜禽、水产种质资源53万余份，由216个农作物制种基地、300个种畜禽场站组成的良种繁育“国家队”，推动供种保障能力由70%提高到75%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“全国种子双交会是新优品种的展示台，也是同台竞技的擂台场。”全国农技中心副主任刘信介绍，20年来，大会展示推广品种突破5000个，有力推动生产主推品种更新换代，助力农民增收致富，百姓餐桌更加多元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;丰富的种质资源是育种材料的重要来源。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我国是种质资源大国，培育更多优良品种需要夯实源头基础。”中国工程院院士、国家农作物品种审定委员会主任万建民介绍，近年来，我国种质资源鉴定逐渐从单环境、低通量、粗放型鉴定向多环境、重点性状、高通量精准转变，种质资源保护与利用体系日趋完善。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前，农业农村部正组织开展48种农作物、7.6万份种质的精准鉴定。万建民建议，要进一步加强种质资源保护与利用，加强种业基础研究；攻克基因编辑、合成生物、全基因组选择、人工智能设计等关键技术，实现自主可控。在此基础上，加快培育重大突破性新品种，把握种业发展主动权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;种业全产业链融合发展&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科技创新是种业发展的“牛鼻子”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，全球范围内生物育种技术不断取得重大突破，现代种业已进入“常规育种+现代生物技术育种+信息化育种”的“4.0时代”。中国工程院院士、南京农业大学教授盖钧镒提出，要加快现代生物技术和信息技术融合发展，推动育种机械化、信息化、智能化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在浙江托普云农科技股份有限公司，一系列智能设备为科学育种提供全流程解决方案。“聚焦育种信息化、种子检验实验室数字化、制种基地现代化提升、数字种业综合监管实时化等多场景，为种业成果转化落地提供服务。”公司负责人陈曦说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在酒泉奥凯种子机械公司，自主研制的自走式玉米抽雄机，一小时能完成上百亩作业面积。“与人工抽雄日均一亩地相比，不仅节省劳动力，而且抽雄率达到95%。”公司中原区销售经理何生伟介绍，通过大型智能化玉米剥皮、烘干、脱粒、仓储成套生产线，实现了“制种全程不落地”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;企业是集聚资源要素、推动种业振兴的重要力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当前，我国国家种业振兴企业阵型已初步构建，农业农村部从全国3万多家种业企业中推出69家农作物、86家畜禽、121家水产优势企业，形成种业振兴骨干力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从一粒种子到产业链构建，立足锻长板、补短板，各地加快推进种业企业育繁推一体化和全产业链发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;安徽南陵县，每年春天成片盛开的紫云英“弋江籽”，已成为国家地理标志产品。芜湖青弋江种业有限公司选育推广的紫云英品种占全国市场的20%，总经理汪玮介绍，公司已建立稳定的紫云英原良种繁育基地。在南陵县，为进一步开展紫云英育种和全产业链技术推广，当地还与中国农业科学院开展合作，建设“长三角紫云英产业研究院”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;应当看到，我国种业企业“多小散弱”的特征仍较明显。如何进一步加快资源集聚，健全现代种业科技创新体系？&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;万建民认为，要贯通产业链和创新链，打造具有国际竞争力的领军种业集团。特别是鼓励优势科研院校和企业深度融合，以需求为导向，建立适应新形势的合作模式，形成高效组织体系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;农作物种子认证制度启动实施&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“种子认证是以高质量种子为目标、强调过程管理的标准化质量保证体系，是实现由&#39;好品种&#39;到&#39;好种子&#39;的有效途径。”全国农技中心种子检验处处长金石桥表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我国农作物种子认证制度已启动实施。作为首批取得资质的种子认证实施主体，北京京农科检测认证公司今年承担玉米、小麦、蔬菜、高粱等作物约10万亩制种基地的种子认证。“通过亲本质量检测、基地核查、种子质量检测等认证环节，对种子生产全流程进行把关，全面提升认证企业的种子质量和管理水平。”公司负责人易红梅说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，随着新修改的种子法、畜牧法加快实施，植物新品种保护制度进一步健全，我国建立起实质性派生品种和种子认证制度，种业知识产权保护专项整治和监管执法年活动深入开展，公检法等有关方面联合推出了严厉打击假冒伪劣、套牌侵权等违法行为的“组合拳”，为种业振兴营造了良好环境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专家表示，总体来看，我国种业科技处于世界先进水平，在种质资源挖掘利用、前沿育种技术、重大新品种研发以及企业创新能力等种业创新领域，有着广阔的发展空间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;打好种业振兴行动这场翻身仗，需要久久为功。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在挖掘优异种质资源方面，全面开展国家库（圃）种质资源精准鉴定，发布可供利用的农业种质资源目录，夯实育种创新资源基础。在推动大面积单产提升方面，统筹推进多层次育种创新联合攻关，加快选育一批高油高产大豆、短生育期油菜、耐盐碱作物等急需的突破性品种。在种业基地能力提升方面，深入推进南繁硅谷、甘肃玉米等育种制种基地建设，到2025年国家级种业基地供种保障率力争达到80%。在知识产权保护方面，实施品种身份证管理，建立全链条全流程监管机制，持续优化种业市场环境。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 30 Oct 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>