<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 铸牢中华民族共同体意识 推进新时代党的民族工作高质量发展]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/29/nw.D110000renmrb_20231029_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Sunday, October 29, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;■ To build a strong sense of community for the Chinese nation is to guide people of all ethnic groups to firmly establish the common sense of sharing weal and woe, sharing honor and disgrace, life and death, and destiny. The concept of a common community. It is necessary to fully implement the deployment of the 20th National Congress of the Party, accurately grasp the new stage characteristics of the Party&#39;s ethnic work, regard the building of a strong sense of the Chinese nation&#39;s community as the main line of the Party&#39;s ethnic work and all work in ethnic areas, and constantly strengthen and improve the Party&#39;s ethnic work. work, solidly promote the cause of ethnic unity and progress, and promote the high-quality development of the party’s ethnic work in the new era&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■Since ancient times, people of all ethnic groups in our country have jointly created the dazzling Chinese civilization and forged the great Chinese nation. Our party has always attached great importance to ethnic issues and ethnic work, and correctly handled ethnic relations. Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, our party has emphasized the concepts of the big family of the Chinese nation, the community of the Chinese nation, building a strong sense of the Chinese nation’s community, and promoting the construction of the Chinese nation’s community. It has clearly proposed that building a strong sense of the Chinese nation’s community should be the party’s national work in the new era. As the main line of all work in ethnic areas, we further expanded the correct path to solve ethnic issues with Chinese characteristics, formed the Party’s important thoughts on strengthening and improving ethnic work, opened up a new realm of adapting Marxist ethnic theory to the times, and the Party New historic achievements have been made in ethnic work&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■After the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, people of all ethnic groups across the country have embarked on a new journey to comprehensively promote the construction of a strong country and the great cause of national rejuvenation with Chinese-style modernization. Work is facing new situations and tasks. To build a modern and powerful socialist country in an all-round way, no nation can be left behind. We must vigorously promote the common unity and struggle of all ethnic groups and gather great strength for the construction of a strong country and national rejuvenation; we must comprehensively realize the common prosperity and development of all ethnic groups and allow people of all ethnic groups to share the great glory of building a strong country and national rejuvenation&lt;/P>;&lt;P>; ■To build a strong sense of the Chinese nation&#39;s community, it is necessary to build a scientific and complete theoretical system of the Chinese nation&#39;s community. Based on the long history of the Chinese nation, we must combine Marxist national theory with China&#39;s specific reality and China&#39;s excellent traditional culture, follow the historical logic and theoretical logic of the development of the Chinese nation, and scientifically reveal the principles, academic theories, and principles of the formation and development of the Chinese nation. Philosophy&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■ We must focus on building the modern civilization of the Chinese nation and constantly build a shared spiritual home for the Chinese nation. We must conform to the general development trend of the Chinese nation from history to the future, from tradition to modernity, and from diversity to unity, deeply understand and grasp the outstanding characteristics of Chinese civilization, and constantly build a shared spiritual home for the Chinese nation at a new historical starting point to forge a solid foundation. The consciousness of the Chinese nation&#39;s community has laid a solid spiritual and cultural foundation&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■ We must promote extensive exchanges, exchanges and integration among all ethnic groups, and promote Chinese-style modernization with the great unity of the Chinese nation. The process of building a strong country and rejuvenating the nation must be a process of extensive exchanges, exchanges and integration among all ethnic groups. It must be a process of unity, struggle and common prosperity and development of all ethnic groups. We must hold high the banner of the great unity of the Chinese nation and regard promoting all ethnic groups to work together to comprehensively build a modern socialist country as an important task of the party’s ethnic work in the new journey&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■ We must tell the story of the Chinese nation well and vigorously promote it Awareness of the Chinese nation’s community. It is necessary to vigorously publicize the history of the Chinese nation, the theory of the Chinese nation&#39;s community, the historic achievements of the party&#39;s national work in the new era, and the beautiful vision of the Chinese nation working together with people from all over the world to build a community with a shared future for mankind&lt;/P>;&lt; P>;■Forging a strong sense of community for the Chinese nation and promoting the high-quality development of the party’s ethnic work in the new era are the common tasks of the entire Party and people of all ethnic groups. Party committees and governments at all levels must adhere to the correct path of solving ethnic issues with Chinese characteristics, conscientiously implement the Party&#39;s various principles and policies on ethnic work, and promptly study and solve major issues related to ethnic work in their regions and units. Leading cadres at all levels must thoroughly study and implement the party&#39;s important thoughts on strengthening and improving ethnic work, improve their ability to do a good job in ethnic work, and make due contributions to promoting ethnic unity and progress&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;&lt;/P>;&lt;P >;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 28th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee held its ninth collective study session on the afternoon of October 27th on building a strong sense of community for the Chinese nation. When presiding over the study, Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China, emphasized that to build a strong sense of community for the Chinese nation is to guide people of all ethnic groups to firmly establish the concept of a community that shares weal and woe, honor and disgrace, life and death, and destiny. It is necessary to fully implement the deployment of the 20th National Congress of the Party, accurately grasp the new stage characteristics of the Party&#39;s ethnic work, regard the building of a strong sense of the Chinese nation&#39;s community as the main line of the Party&#39;s ethnic work and all work in ethnic areas, and constantly strengthen and improve the Party&#39;s ethnic work. work, solidly promote the cause of ethnic unity and progress, and promote the high-quality development of the party’s ethnic work in the new era. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Comrade Wang Yanzhong, director of the Institute of Ethnology and Anthropology of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences, explained this issue and put forward work suggestions. Comrades from the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee listened carefully to the explanation and held discussions. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping delivered an important speech after listening to the explanation and discussion. He pointed out that since ancient times, people of all ethnic groups in our country have jointly created the dazzling Chinese civilization and forged the great Chinese nation. Our party has always attached great importance to ethnic issues and ethnic work, and correctly handled ethnic relations. Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, our party has emphasized the concepts of the big family of the Chinese nation, the community of the Chinese nation, building a strong sense of the Chinese nation’s community, and promoting the construction of the Chinese nation’s community. It has clearly proposed that building a strong sense of the Chinese nation’s community should be the party’s national work in the new era. As the main line of all work in ethnic areas, we further expanded the correct path to solve ethnic issues with Chinese characteristics, formed the Party’s important thoughts on strengthening and improving ethnic work, opened up a new realm of adapting Marxist ethnic theory to the times, and the Party China&#39;s ethnic work has achieved new historic achievements. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that after the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, people of all ethnic groups across the country have embarked on a new journey to comprehensively promote the construction of a strong country and the great cause of national rejuvenation with Chinese-style modernization. The party’s ethnic work is facing new situations and tasks. . To build a modern and powerful socialist country in an all-round way, no nation can be left behind. We must vigorously promote the common unity and struggle of all ethnic groups and gather great strength for the construction of a strong country and national rejuvenation; we must comprehensively realize the common prosperity and development of all ethnic groups and allow people of all ethnic groups to share the great glory of building a strong country and national rejuvenation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that to solidify the consciousness of the Chinese nation&#39;s community, it is necessary to build a scientific and complete theoretical system of the Chinese nation&#39;s community. Based on the long history of the Chinese nation, we must combine Marxist national theory with China&#39;s specific reality and China&#39;s excellent traditional culture, follow the historical logic and theoretical logic of the development of the Chinese nation, and scientifically reveal the principles, academic theories, and principles of the formation and development of the Chinese nation. philosophy. It is necessary to optimize the subject setting, strengthen discipline construction, identify the correct research direction, deepen the research on major basic issues of the Chinese nation community, and accelerate the formation of China&#39;s independent historical material system, discourse system, and theoretical system of the Chinese nation community. Pay attention to stimulating the enthusiasm, initiative and creativity of experts and scholars, strengthen the training of young experts and scholars, provide them with good directions, build platforms, create opportunities, encourage them to study with concentration, accumulate experience, and launch research based on Chinese history, interpret Chinese practices, and answer Chinese questions. Original theoretical results. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that we must focus on building a modern civilization for the Chinese nation and continue to build a shared spiritual home for the Chinese nation. We must conform to the general development trend of the Chinese nation from history to the future, from tradition to modernity, and from diversity to unity, deeply understand and grasp the outstanding characteristics of Chinese civilization, and constantly build a shared spiritual home for the Chinese nation at a new historical starting point to forge a solid foundation. The sense of community of the Chinese nation has laid a solid spiritual and cultural foundation. We must strengthen education on the Party&#39;s theory, lines, principles, and policies for people of all ethnic groups, strengthen publicity and education on the history of the Party, the history of New China, the history of reform and opening up, the history of socialist development, and the history of the development of the Chinese nation. We must unite our hearts and souls with common ideals and beliefs, and deeply cultivate and practice the core socialist values. Deeply implement the red gene inheritance project, vigorously promote the national spirit with patriotism as the core and the spirit of the times with reform and innovation as the core, continuously enhance the sense of identity and pride in the Chinese nation, and inspire people of all ethnic groups to forge ahead on a new journey and make contributions in the new era. of spirit. Implement the inheritance and development project of China’s excellent traditional culture, study and excavate the excellent genes and contemporary value of Chinese traditional culture, promote the creative transformation and innovative development of China’s excellent traditional culture, prosper and develop advanced socialist culture, build and apply the characteristics of Chinese culture and the Chinese nation spirit and the expression system of China’s national image, constantly enhancing the Chinese cultural identity of people of all ethnic groups. Comprehensively promote and popularize the national common spoken and written language, comprehensively promote the use of nationally compiled teaching materials, and promote the connection of souls and destiny through language communication. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that it is necessary to promote extensive exchanges, exchanges and integration of all ethnic groups and promote Chinese-style modernization with the great unity of the Chinese nation. The process of building a strong country and rejuvenating the nation must be a process of extensive exchanges, exchanges and integration among all ethnic groups. It must be a process of unity, struggle and common prosperity and development of all ethnic groups. We must hold high the banner of the great unity of the Chinese nation and regard promoting all ethnic groups to work together to comprehensively build a modern socialist country as an important task of the party&#39;s ethnic work in the new journey. It is necessary to promote the mobility and integration of the population of all ethnic groups, build an inter-embedded social structure and community environment, create social conditions for people of all ethnic groups to live together, learn together, build and share, and work together to enjoy each other, and continue to deepen the creation of ethnic unity and progress. We should take improving people&#39;s livelihood and rallying people&#39;s hearts as the starting point and goal of the economic and social development of ethnic minority areas, promote the integration of ethnic minority areas into the new development pattern, achieve high-quality development, continuously improve the ability and level of public service guarantees, and promote development results to benefit people of all ethnic groups equitably. Uphold and improve the system of regional ethnic autonomy, improve the system of ethnic policies and laws and regulations, and promote the modernization of the ethnic affairs governance system and governance capabilities. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized the need to tell the story of the Chinese nation well and vigorously promote the awareness of the Chinese nation&#39;s community. It is necessary to vigorously publicize the history of the Chinese nation, the theory of the Chinese nation&#39;s community, the historic achievements of the party&#39;s national work in the new era, and the beautiful vision of the Chinese nation working together with people from all over the world to build a community with a shared future for mankind. Innovate the communication methods of ethnic-related propaganda, enrich the communication content, broaden the communication channels, tell the story of the Chinese nation community, make it clear that the leadership of the Communist Party of China and the socialist system are reliable guarantees for the common development and progress of all ethnic groups in our country, and make it clear that the Chinese nation has a strong A community with a shared future that has a strong sense of identity and cohesion, and clearly illustrates the obvious superiority of the correct path to solving ethnic issues with Chinese characteristics. Actively promote exchanges and interactions between Chinese and foreign academic circles and civil society groups. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that it is the common task of the entire Party and people of all ethnic groups to build a strong sense of community for the Chinese nation and promote the high-quality development of the Party’s ethnic work in the new era. Party committees and governments at all levels must adhere to the correct path of solving ethnic issues with Chinese characteristics, conscientiously implement the Party&#39;s various principles and policies on ethnic work, and promptly study and solve major issues related to ethnic work in their regions and units. Leading cadres at all levels must thoroughly study and implement the Party&#39;s important thoughts on strengthening and improving ethnic work, improve their ability to do a good job in ethnic work, and make due contributions to promoting ethnic unity and progress. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 05:56:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 前9月城镇新增就业1022万人（新数据 新看点）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/29/nw.D110000renmrb_20231029_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Sunday, October 29, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Our newspaper, Beijing, October 28th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Qiu Chaoyi) The reporter recently reported from the human resources and social A press conference held by the Ministry of Social Security was informed that in the first nine months of this year, 10.22 million new jobs were created in cities and towns across the country, and the employment situation remained generally stable. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The employment priority policy was implemented in depth. From January to September, policies such as phased reductions in unemployment and work-related injury insurance premiums, job stabilization returns, and one-time job expansion subsidies were continued, reducing costs for enterprises by 141.9 billion yuan and disbursing 80.9 billion yuan in employment subsidies. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The employment of key groups continues to be strengthened. We implemented a critical campaign to provide employment services for college graduates and other young people to help unemployed graduates find employment as early as possible; we organized and implemented the &quot;Three Supports and One Support&quot; plan, recruiting a total of 42,000 college graduates to serve at the grassroots level; we held a conference on labor cooperation and labor brand development, Carry out the campaign to prevent people from returning to poverty through employment. As of the end of September, the number of people working out of poverty reached 32.97 million. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Vocational skills training is carried out in a solid manner. Focus on key groups such as college graduates and rural migrant laborers, and carry out large-scale vocational skills training. From January to September, 8.99 million vocational training vouchers were issued, the subsidy policy for skills improvement was continued, and more than 13 million people received subsidized vocational skills training. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Employment services are constantly optimized. We have continued to launch activities such as Private Enterprise Service Month to optimize employment service guarantees for key enterprises. From January to September, more than 70,000 key enterprises have met their employment needs for more than 1.62 million people. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 05:56:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 携手同心筑梦  共绘美好未来]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/29/nw.D110000renmrb_20231029_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Sunday, October 29, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;On October 28, the closing ceremony of the 4th Asian Para Games in Hangzhou was held grandly. With moving melody and beautiful blessings, the Hangzhou Asian Para Games came to a successful conclusion. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The two Asian Games are equally exciting. In the past seven days, Zhejiang Province and Hangzhou City have adhered to the requirements of &quot;simple, safe and exciting&quot; hosting of the games, adhered to the same standards, the same services, and the same status as the Asian Games, organized and guaranteed the games at a high level, and strived to The world has dedicated an Asian Para Games of &quot;sunshine, harmony, self-improvement and sharing&quot;. From building the Asian Paralympic Village by adhering to the principles of &quot;obeying conventions, unifying standards, respecting individuality and paying attention to details&quot;, to completing the smooth conversion of competition venues in 10 days; from comprehensively updating the barrier-free environment of various public facilities in the city, to providing meticulous Volunteer service...Every work and every detail reflects &quot;athlete-centeredness.&quot; The complete success of the Hangzhou Asian Para Games has left a mark in the history of the development of sports for persons with disabilities. As Majid Rashid, chairman of the Asian Paralympic Committee, said: &quot;I have participated in many Paralympic Games, and I think the Asian Paralympic Games in Hangzhou will be the best one ever.&quot;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The most important thing is The struggle is heart-warming. On the field, when wheelchair fencers compete, they need to fix their wheelchairs on an adjustable track frame; blind goalball players need to listen to the sound to determine the direction of their own movement; weightlifters need to lie down and lift the barbell with both hands... facing ordinary people Despite the unimaginable difficulties, the participating disabled athletes were not afraid, faced the difficulties, and constantly achieved self-transcendence. Their all-out hard work and never-give-up spirit inspire more people to work hard and pursue their dreams bravely. At this Asian Paralympic Games, the Chinese disabled sports delegation achieved its “fourth consecutive championship” and achieved the best results in history, winning honors for the motherland and people. Chinese disabled athletes have continued to strive for self-improvement, united and worked hard, and played a triumphant song of life with perseverance, optimism and enterprising spirit, which fully demonstrated the spiritual outlook of Chinese disabled people in the new era, and also injected inspiration into the new journey of building a strong country and rejuvenating the nation for the whole party and people of all ethnic groups. Strong spiritual power. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The Hangzhou Asian Para Games not only showcases sports competition, but also promotes tolerance, integration and exchanges. General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out that &quot;use windows such as the Hangzhou Asian Games and the World Internet Conference to strengthen cultural exchanges and dissemination.&quot; The torch of the Asian Paralympic Games was passed on the &quot;Three Rivers and Two Banks&quot; in Hangzhou, showing the unique style of Zhejiang&#39;s &quot;Poetry Road Culture&quot;. At the opening ceremony, disabled athletes used smart bionic arms to light the main torch, demonstrating the integration of technology and humanity. On the field, athletes from different countries and regions not only compete with each other, but also encourage each other. The complete success of the Asian Para Games in Hangzhou has further enhanced the friendship among Asian people and sown the seeds of peace, unity and tolerance in the hearts of more people. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: &quot;Disabled people are equal members of the social family and an important force in the development of human civilization.&quot; The 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China outlined a plan to comprehensively promote the construction of a strong country with Chinese-style modernization , the grand blueprint for the great cause of national rejuvenation, puts forward clear requirements for improving the social security system and care service system for persons with disabilities, and promoting the all-round development of causes for persons with disabilities. Taking the Hangzhou Asian Para Games as an opportunity to further enhance the understanding of all walks of life on disabled sports and the cause of disabled people, let the value orientation of &quot;equality, integration and sharing&quot; become more deeply rooted in the hearts of the people, and let the whole society respect, understand, care and help the disabled A stronger human atmosphere will surely better promote the all-round development of the cause of persons with disabilities in the process of Chinese modernization and continue to create a happier and better life for persons with disabilities. China will always uphold the spirit of humanitarianism and internationalism, paint a magnificent picture of exchanges and mutual learning between different civilizations through sports exchanges and cooperation for persons with disabilities, and actively promote the building of a community with a shared future for mankind. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;When the surging sports passion meets the unyielding will to life, the beauty of life without fear of challenges shines brightly. The Hangzhou Asian Para Games will leave unforgettable memories for people and open a new chapter. Let us join hands to build dreams and draw a better future together! &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 05:56:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 韩正出席太湖世界文化论坛第七届年会并致辞]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/29/nw.D110000renmrb_20231029_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Sunday, October 29, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 28th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Vice Chairman Han Zheng attended the Taihu World Cultural Forum in Beijing on the 27th The seventh annual meeting and speech. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Han Zheng said that President Xi Jinping attaches great importance to exchanges and mutual learning among civilizations. This year marks the 10th anniversary of President Xi Jinping’s proposal of building a community with a shared future for mankind and the 10th anniversary of his proposal to jointly build the “Belt and Road” initiative. In the past 10 years, guided by the concept of building a community with a shared future for mankind, China has held high the banner of multilateralism, adhered to extensive consultation, joint contribution and shared benefits, and opened up a civilizational path of exchanges and mutual learning. In March this year, President Xi Jinping proposed the Global Civilization Initiative, advocating respect for the diversity of world civilizations and attaching importance to the inheritance and innovation of civilizations. These fully reflect China&#39;s sincere desire to promote the progress of human civilization and promote the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Han Zheng pointed out that the development of history, the prosperity of society, and the progress of mankind are all inseparable from the nourishment and guidance of civilization. Today, when the future and destiny of all countries in the world are closely linked, exchanges and mutual learning among civilizations have increasingly become a bridge that enhances friendship between peoples of various countries, a driving force for the progress of human society, and a bond for maintaining world peace. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Han Zheng put forward four initiatives. First, we must respect the diversity of civilization development. Civilizations are all different, but they are not superior or inferior. We must adhere to equality, mutual learning, dialogue and tolerance among civilizations, and promote mutual learning and understanding among different civilizations. Second, we must promote the common values ​​of all mankind. Different civilizations have different development processes and genes, but they have many similarities in the pursuit of common values. It is necessary to understand the understanding of value connotations of different civilizations and not to impose one&#39;s own values ​​​​and models on others. Third, we must promote civilization inheritance and innovation. Any civilization must keep pace with the times and constantly absorb the essence of the times. Chinese-style modernization is the result of cultural renewal and the modernization of the ancient Chinese civilization. We must respect people&#39;s creation and promote the creative transformation and innovative development of traditional culture. Fourth, we must strengthen exchanges and cooperation among civilizations. People are the best carrier for exchanges and mutual learning among civilizations. It is necessary to create more opportunities and better conditions, strengthen international people-to-people exchanges and cooperation, and build consensus among people of all countries to the greatest extent possible. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The theme of this Taihu World Cultural Forum Annual Conference is &quot;Mutual Learning among Civilizations: Co-Creating a New Form of Human Civilization&quot;, which aims to promote cultural exchanges and cooperation between China and foreign countries and the mutual learning of different civilizations. Nearly a thousand people including political figures from many countries, representatives of international organizations, experts and scholars attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 05:56:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 我国发现千亿方深煤层气田]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/29/nw.D110000renmrb_20231029_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Sunday, October 29, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231029/1698522352125_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/ TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Recently, CNOOC announced that a 100-billion-square-meter deep coalbed methane field was discovered in the 2,000-meter strata on the eastern edge of the Ordos Basin in Yulin City, Shaanxi Province. ——The Shenfu Deep Coal Seam Gas Field has proven geological reserves of over 110 billion cubic meters. The main coal seams in large gas fields are buried about 2,000 meters deep, with an average gas content of 15 cubic meters per ton of coal. This discovery will further enhance my country’s energy supply security capabilities. The picture shows the drilling rig operation site in the Shenfu deep coal seam gas field. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Our reporter&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Ran Yongping&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Ding Yitingwen&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Luo&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Photo by Biao (People&#39;s Vision)&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 05:56:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 何立峰出席全球可持续发展城市奖（上海奖）颁奖活动暨2023年世界城市日中国主场活动开幕式]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/29/nw.D110000renmrb_20231029_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Sunday, October 29, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Shanghai, October 28th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Global Sustainable City Award (Shanghai Award) Award Ceremony and The opening ceremony of the 2023 World Cities Day China home event was held in Shanghai on the 28th. He Lifeng, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Vice Premier of the State Council, attended the opening ceremony and presented awards to the first winning cities. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Before the opening ceremony, He Lifeng visited the urban construction and development case exhibition. He Lifeng pointed out that President Xi Jinping attaches great importance to urban sustainable development and has provided care and guidance on the establishment of the Global Sustainable City Award (Shanghai Award) many times, specifically for the 2022 World Cities Day global home event and the second Global Conference on Urban Sustainable Development. Send a congratulatory letter. The Chinese government is following the important instructions of President Xi Jinping to further promote the new type of urbanization that puts people at the core. It is willing to share China&#39;s plans and experiences with other countries around the world to jointly promote the sustainable development of global cities. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Chen Jining, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Secretary of the Shanghai Municipal Party Committee, and Maimouna Mohd Sharif, Deputy Secretary-General of the United Nations and Executive Director of UN-Habitat, attended relevant activities. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 05:56:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 把农业建设成为大产业（全面推进乡村振兴）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/29/nw.D110000renmrb_20231029_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Sunday, October 29, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;In the golden autumn season, pictures of harvests can be seen everywhere in the vast fields. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the rice fields in Qing&#39;an County, Heilongjiang Province, combine harvesters shuttle back and forth, and golden rice continuously flows into the grain loading trucks. &quot;The large base is equipped with large equipment, and the harvest is fast and good. There are more than 1.3 million acres of rice in the county, and the comprehensive mechanization rate of field operations reaches 96.8%.&quot; said Fan Jun, director of the Qing&#39;an County Agricultural Technology Extension Center. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhengyang Luhua Luzhou Peanut Oil Co., Ltd., Zhengyang County, Henan Province, has a fully automatic production line that operates non-stop, producing 6,000 barrels of high-quality peanut oil per hour. &quot;From selling raw materials to selling products and selling brands, the county has built a whole peanut industry chain covering planting, deep processing, futures delivery, spot trade, cultural tourism and other links.&quot; said Guan Xia, director of the Zhengyang County Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out during an inspection in Jiangxi: &quot;Adhere to promoting agriculture through industry, quality and green agriculture, and build agriculture into a big industry.&quot; During his inspection in Heilongjiang, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: “We must focus on the development of modern large-scale agriculture, accelerate the construction of large modern agricultural bases, large enterprises, and large industries, and take the lead in realizing the modernization of agricultural material equipment, science and technology, modernization of operation and management, and agricultural informatization. , Sustainable utilization of resources.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This year is the first year to fully implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China. It is a critical year to comprehensively promote rural revitalization and accelerate the construction of an agricultural power. Under the strong leadership of the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core, my country&#39;s agricultural modernization has made great progress. The planting industry has harvested crops, the animal husbandry industry has prospered, and rural characteristic industries have grown rapidly. The broad masses of cadres and the masses are working hard to make agriculture a better place. We will make unremitting efforts to build a large industry and realize the modernization of agriculture and rural areas at an early date. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Build a high-quality and efficient diversified supply system to ensure a stable and safe supply of grain and important agricultural products&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: “No matter the degree of social modernization, However, the stable supply of food and important agricultural products for more than 1.4 billion people has always been a top priority.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To build agriculture into a big industry and build a high-quality and efficient diversified supply system, we must first secure our jobs. Hold it in your own hand. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the harvest season, Huang Siwen, a major grain grower, is harvesting rice in the high-standard farmland of Sangtian Town, Nanfeng County, Jiangxi Province. &quot;This year, we planted 2,500 acres of mid-range rice, with an output of about 1,300 kilograms per mu.&quot; Huang Siwen said, &quot;Grain subsidies were received in time, agricultural technical guidance went directly to the fields, and &#39;Big Iron Bull&#39; assisted throughout the process. This year is another good harvest year.&quot;&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;A big base and big equipment must have strong support behind them. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strong policies - the country has improved the &quot;three-in-one&quot; policy system of price, subsidy and insurance, issued a one-time subsidy of 10 billion yuan to farmers who actually grow grains, and the central government has promptly released funds for agricultural disaster prevention and relief... policy measures are solid. , stabilize expectations and strengthen confidence. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strengthening science and technology - the introduction of improved seeds, good farming methods, and the rapid development of agricultural machinery. The national agricultural science and technology progress contribution rate has reached 62.4%, the coverage rate of improved crop varieties has exceeded 96%, and the comprehensive mechanization rate of crop cultivation and harvest has exceeded 73%. From &quot;knowing how to farm&quot; to &quot;intelligent farming&quot;, the &quot;golden pole&quot; continues to inject new momentum into modern agriculture. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strengthening the foundation - a multi-pronged approach to high-standard farmland construction, black soil protection, and the creation of high-yield demonstration areas will transform small fields into big fields and &quot;dividends&quot; will continue to be released. By the end of 2022, a total of 1 billion acres of high-standard farmland has been built across the country, stably ensuring a grain production capacity of more than 1 trillion kilograms. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strong service - grow good land, harvest more grain, and financial support is indispensable. As fiscal funds support “agriculture, rural areas and farmers” continue to increase, financial institutions have also continued to increase credit support. In the first three quarters of this year, the Agricultural Bank of China has provided a total of more than 200 billion yuan in loans to key grain fields. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strong support brings stable development. my country&#39;s grain production has had bumper harvests year after year, and the total output has remained stable at more than 1.3 trillion catties for eight consecutive years. The agricultural situation dispatch of the Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs shows that as of October 22, 81.3% of the national autumn grain harvest has been harvested. An increase in autumn grain production is a foregone conclusion, and the annual grain output is expected to hit a record high. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ask for food from forests, ask for food from rivers, lakes and seas, and ask for food from facility agriculture. Build agriculture into a big industry, coordinate grain, economics and feeding, develop agriculture, forestry, animal husbandry and fishery simultaneously, and build a high-quality and efficient diversified supply system. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the Gobi Ecological Agriculture Industrial Park in Suzhou District, Jiuquan City, Gansu Province, vegetables, melons and fruits are full of life. Vegetable grower Qin Cunguo said: &quot;Since the use of integrated water and fertilizer automatic control equipment, water irrigating the fields has turned into water irrigating the seedlings. The average water consumption per mu is nearly half compared with the field. It saves water and increases production, and fresh vegetables can be produced all year round.&quot;&lt;/ p>;&lt;p>;Beside the fish pond in Yuyue Town, Deqing County, Zhejiang Province, Gao Fuliang, a farmer in Qiantang Village, said: &quot;The fish pond facilities are constantly being upgraded and equipped with new green breeding technologies. When the water is better, the fish will grow better. ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Each region adapts to local conditions, based on resource endowments, and gives full play to its comparative advantages. In addition to more than 1.9 billion acres of cultivated land, more than 4 billion acres of forest land, nearly 4 billion acres of grassland, and a large number of rivers, lakes, and seas have gradually become An important component of a diversified food supply system. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Facility agriculture has contributed a lot. At present, the country&#39;s modern facility planting area reaches 40 million acres, and about 70% of meat, eggs, milk and 52% of aquaculture products are provided by facility breeding. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Extend the industrial chain, enhance the value chain, and expand the agricultural development space&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Industrial revitalization is the top priority for rural revitalization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When General Secretary Xi Jinping presided over a symposium on promoting the comprehensive revitalization of Northeast China in the new era, he pointed out: &quot;Coordinately promote the primary processing and intensive processing of agricultural products, extend the industrial chain, enhance the value chain, expand the space for agricultural development, and promote agricultural efficiency. , increase farmers&#39; income.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To build agriculture into a big industry, we must thoroughly understand the three words &quot;local specialties&quot; and build an agricultural industry system that integrates production, processing and marketing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the greenhouse of Shanghegu Food Co., Ltd. in Qianxi County, Hebei Province, chestnut mushrooms are growing well. Zhang Jixiao, the person in charge of the company, said: &quot;From growing chestnuts to growing chestnut mushrooms, the company is planning to build a production and processing base to extend the chestnut industry chain longer.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Data shows that Qianxi County is famous for its chestnut industry. The total cultivation volume of mushroom-based edible fungi industry has reached 100 million sticks, and the annual output of fresh mushrooms is 20,000 tons, with an output value of nearly 400 million yuan. A variety of chestnut powder, chestnut cakes, etc. are also available in hardcover. With a cultivation area of ​​750,000 acres, an annual output of 80,000 tons, and a brand value of 3.409 billion yuan, small chestnut has grown into a big industry in Qianxi. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking across the country, rural areas are suitable for business and industries are prosperous. Relying on characteristic resources, various localities have transformed rural resources, ecology, and cultural advantages into product and industrial advantages, forming a number of &quot;township brands&quot; and &quot;local brands&quot;, and local specialties have made a big impact. Up to now, the country has built 300 national modern agricultural industrial parks, 180 advantageous and characteristic industrial clusters, and 1,509 strong agricultural industry towns, and the agricultural product processing conversion rate has reached 72%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The relevant person in charge of the Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs said: &quot;In the future, the construction of the agricultural industry chain will be further strengthened, and efforts must be made in major links such as research and development, production, processing, storage and transportation, sales, branding, experience, consumption, and services. , comprehensively improve the stability of the industrial system, take multiple measures, solidly expand the space for agricultural value-added and efficiency, strengthen the industrial chain, and improve the system of increasing farmers’ income.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To build agriculture into a big industry, we must cultivate rural areas New industries and new business formats will promote agricultural efficiency and farmers’ income. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the live broadcast base of the E-commerce Industrial Park in Ningling County, Henan Province, the live broadcasters are recommending various agricultural products to netizens, and the atmosphere is heated. In the nearby logistics sorting center, workers are busy packing and loading trucks to transport various agricultural products to various places. With the help of more than 1,000 online stores in the e-commerce industrial park, the annual sales volume of Ningling Suli has exceeded 100 million kilograms. Not only do pears sell well, but tourists also come in droves. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;New industries and new business formats activate the huge potential of rural industries. There are more than 300,000 leisure agriculture business entities nationwide, with annual operating income exceeding 700 billion yuan. There are more than 30,000 agricultural-related e-commerce companies of various types, and rural online retail sales exceed 2 trillion yuan. The deep integration of primary, secondary and tertiary industries in rural areas has driven more farmers to find employment locally and nearby. In the first three quarters of this year, the per capita disposable income of rural residents was 15,705 yuan, an actual increase of 7.3% after deducting price factors. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Develop moderate-scale operations and accelerate the improvement of the agricultural social service system&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Agricultural modernization is inseparable from innovation in production and management methods. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: &quot;Developing moderate-scale operations is the direction of modern agriculture&quot; and &quot;accelerate and improve the agricultural socialization service system to provide good services and promote small farmers.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Innovate agricultural management systems and mechanisms and develop moderate-scale operations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;300,000 acres of peppers in Bozhou District, Zunyi City, Guizhou Province have entered the harvest season, and pepper farmers are very busy. &quot;I have planted 40 acres of peppers this year and have sold more than 10,000 kilograms. I have no worries about sales.&quot; He Congwei, a villager in Yuanyuan Village, Tiechang Town, picks peppers every morning and sends them to the village&#39;s processing workshop. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This workshop is an important part of the &quot;company + village collective + cooperative + rural workshop + farmer household&quot; order model. &quot;From seed supply to technical guidance, field management, and purchase, we provide farmers with a &#39;one-stop&#39; service. Currently, the daily purchase volume of peppers reaches 200 tons.&quot; said Tang Songbai, deputy general manager of Guizhou Zhuohao Food Co., Ltd. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Based on the basic national and agricultural conditions of small farmers in large countries, we must accelerate the modernization of agriculture and rural areas, and put innovative agricultural management systems and mechanisms in a prominent position, from the two dimensions of cultivating new agricultural business entities and developing the agricultural service outsourcing market. Improve agricultural scale efficiency.&quot; said Ye Xingqing, director of the Rural Economic Research Department of the Development Research Center of the State Council. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking across the country, there are more than 4 million family farms and 2.22 million farmer cooperatives. They are actively exploring areas such as the promotion of improved seed breeding, green unified prevention and control, and standardized production to drive farmers, connect with markets, lead development, and promote The level of agricultural intensification, specialization, organization and socialization has been continuously improved. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strengthen agricultural socialization service capabilities and solve production problems that cannot be done by each household, cannot be done well, and are not cost-effective. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“1,000 acres of soybeans are entrusted to Beidahuang Agricultural Services Group. With double rows of large ridges and dense planting, the yield per acre can be 70 kilograms higher than what we grow ourselves. This saves effort and worry and increases production.” Suihua City, Heilongjiang Province Lu Chunfeng, a villager in Xingfu Village, Xingfu Town, said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The socialized services of Beidahuang Agricultural Services Group are not only effective on a large scale and a large area, but are also applicable in the south, which is good at intensive farming. Xiaogang Village in Fengyang County, Anhui Province has used grid field transformation methods to increase the average field area to 27 acres, and can also realize driverless rice transplanting. The socialized service area of ​​Beidahuang Agricultural Services Group has reached 78 million acres, and its services have benefited 3.5 million small farmers. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Currently, there are more than 1.07 million agricultural social service organizations across the country that have become farmers’ caring “field nannies”. Their services have benefited more than 91 million small farmers, covering more than 1.97 billion acres. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The relevant person in charge of the Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs said: &quot;In the direction of consolidating the modern agricultural management system, we must also improve the mechanism of linking farmers and guiding farmers. We must adhere to the combination of strengthening the benefits and improving the ability to drive, scientific and reasonable Determine the mode of promotion and the degree of benefit, improve the long-term mechanism of &#39;precise promotion&#39;, &#39;stable promotion&#39; and &#39;long-term promotion&#39;, and promote the organic connection between small farmers and the development of modern agriculture.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A strong country must first Only by strengthening agriculture can the country be strong. The fundamental solution for agriculture lies in modernization.新时代新征程，在习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想指引下，亿万农民齐心协力共建美好生活，农业现代化阔步向前，广袤田野希望无限。 &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 杭州第四届亚洲残疾人运动会圆满闭幕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/29/nw.D110000renmrb_20231029_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月29日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;新华社杭州10月28日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;杭州第四届亚洲残疾人运动会28日晚在杭州圆满闭幕。国务委员谌贻琴出席闭幕式。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;两个亚运，同样精彩。在过去7天里，来自亚洲44个国家和地区的3000多名残疾人运动员勇于挑战、超越自我、顽强拼搏，展现奋进力量和卓越品格，共同奏响生命的强音。中国践行“阳光、和谐、自强、共享”的办赛理念，以出色的赛事组织、完善的无障碍设施，赢得了亚残奥委员会大家庭和国际社会的广泛好评。中国体育代表团获得214枚金牌、521枚奖牌，名列亚残运会金牌榜和奖牌榜首位。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;夜幕下的杭州奥体中心体育场，流淌着惜别的情谊。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;乐曲声中，谌贻琴同亚残奥委员会主席马吉德·拉什德等步入主席台，向观众挥手致意。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;约19时30分，以“乘梦飞&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;再相约”为主题的闭幕式开始。全体起立，高唱中华人民共和国国歌，鲜艳的五星红旗冉冉升起。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;伴着悠扬的旋律，听障少女手执绸伞登上舞台，富有特色的江南景致也出现在舞台之上。绸伞在夜色中闪闪发光，听障少女与荷花姑娘共同舞蹈，传递深情的祝福。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;各代表团旗帜和运动员代表入场。全场观众以热烈的掌声，向残疾人运动员表达敬意。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;现场大屏幕再现亚残运会赛场上，运动员们追逐人生梦想、展现自强风采的精神风貌。一幕幕充满体育之美的画面吸引全场观众的目光。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;杭州第四届亚洲残疾人运动会组委会主席、中国残疾人联合会主席程凯，亚残奥委员会主席马吉德·拉什德先后致辞。马吉德·拉什德宣布杭州第四届亚洲残疾人运动会闭幕。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;古琴艺术家奏响悠悠琴声，百名大学生构成茶礼方阵，诉说离情别绪。亚残运会赛场内外的动人瞬间出现在大屏幕上，铺展开运动员、志愿者和工作人员携手同行、残健共融的画卷。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;伴着亚残奥委员会会歌，亚残奥委员会会旗缓缓降下。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;亚残奥委员会会旗交接仪式开始。杭州第四届亚洲残疾人运动会组委会副主席兼秘书长、杭州市市长姚高员将会旗交给亚残奥委员会主席马吉德·拉什德。马吉德·拉什德将会旗交给下届亚残运会举办城市日本爱知县知事大村秀章和名古屋市副市长中田英雄。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;升日本国旗、奏日本国歌后，大屏幕上呈现了爱知县和名古屋市的文艺表演短片。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;20时25分，别具一格的熄火仪式开始。为盲人讲电影的义务讲解员向视障朋友讲述亚残运会火炬熄灭的难忘时刻。跨湖桥遗址博物馆里的“中华第一舟”，载着听障儿童和健全儿童一起向火炬前行。杭州亚残运会吉祥物“飞飞”盘旋于夜色之中，向主火炬深情告别，挥动翅膀熄灭火焰。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“亚细亚我们同一个家，走过春秋和冬夏……”歌声响起，全场共同唱响自强不息、逐梦飞翔的自豪，也唱响亚洲一家、彼此守望的深情。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;亚残奥委员会官员等出席闭幕式。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 图片报道]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/29/nw.D110000renmrb_20231029_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月29日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-10/29/02/rmrb2023102902p6_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;10月27日，南深高铁南玉段控制性工程——广西南宁六景郁江特大桥首节钢箱梁成功安装，标志着大桥正式进入钢箱梁施工阶段。&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;古建敖摄（影像中国）&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 把服务实体经济放到更加突出的位置]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/29/nw.D110000renmrb_20231029_5-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月29日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;金融是现代经济的核心，是推动经济社会发展的重要力量。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;习近平总书记指出：“保持经济平稳健康发展，一定要把金融搞好。”“金融要为实体经济服务，满足经济社会发展和人民群众需要。”&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;经济是肌体，金融是血脉，两者共生共荣。党的十八大以来，在以习近平同志为核心的党中央坚强领导下，我国金融改革发展取得新的重大成就，金融供给侧结构性改革不断深化，服务经济高质量发展的能力和效率大幅提升。在此过程中，我国金融业自身高质量发展也取得了长足进步，金融产品日益丰富，金融服务普惠性增强，金融改革有序推进，金融体系不断完善。截至今年6月末，我国金融业机构总资产达449.21万亿元。目前，中国银行业资产规模位居全球第一，股票、债券、保险规模位居全球第二，外汇储备规模稳居世界第一。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;高质量发展是全面建设社会主义现代化国家的首要任务。服务高质量发展和中国式现代化，我国金融业完整准确全面贯彻新发展理念，助力加快构建新发展格局，既实现了自身的跨越式发展，也为推动经济高质量发展奠定了坚实基础。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;撬动科技创新，让“第一动力”更澎湃。创新是引领发展的第一动力。近年来，金融机构以服务实体经济为出发点和落脚点，支持科技创新和产业升级的力度、广度、精度不断提升。截至今年6月末，我国科技型中小企业贷款余额2.36万亿元，同比增长25.1%，连续3年保持25%以上的较高增速。与此同时，以注册制改革为牵引，资本市场对科技创新的服务能力不断提升，科创板、创业板、北交所对科技型企业评价体系不断优化，更加精准地提升了科技型企业直接融资可得性。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;支持乡村振兴，为协调发展添动力。近年来，金融部门积极引导金融机构不断加大对“三农”领域的金融支持。截至今年8月末，全国涉农贷款余额54.98万亿元，同比增长15.4%；1—9月，债券市场支持银行发行“三农”专项金融债券467亿元。引金融活水润泽乡村沃土，不仅持续为“三农”发展注入更充沛动力与活力，也为金融机构拓展了高质量发展的广阔空间。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;绿色金融发力，擦亮高质量发展鲜明底色。中国式现代化是人与自然和谐共生的现代化。近年来，我国金融机构积极发展绿色金融，为生态文明建设提供多种形式的金融服务。目前，我国已经形成以绿色贷款和绿色债券为主、多种绿色金融工具蓬勃发展的多层次绿色金融市场体系。截至今年一季度末，我国本外币绿色贷款余额超过25万亿元，绿色债券余额超过1.5万亿元，均居全球前列。绿色金融成为我国参与全球经济金融治理的重要领域和亮点之一。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;金融开放不断扩大，助力打造高水平对外开放新格局。近年来，我国持续扩大金融业对内对外开放，双向开放的金融体系加速成形。人民币国际化稳步推进，今年1—9月，人民币跨境收付规模39万亿元，同比上升23%，人民币成为我国第一大跨境收付币种。金融对外开放的有序扩大，有助于我国更好利用全球资源，有力支持了经济高质量发展。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;高水平普惠金融体系加快构建，推动实现共同富裕。中国式现代化是人口规模巨大的现代化，也是全体人民共同富裕的现代化。近年来，我国金融业坚持以人民为中心的发展思想，推进普惠金融高质量发展，金融服务的覆盖面、便利性、可得性不断提升。目前，全国银行机构网点覆盖97.9%的乡镇，基本实现乡乡有机构、村村有服务、家家有账户，全国乡镇基本实现保险服务全覆盖。世界银行数据显示，中国的账户拥有率、数字支付使用率、储蓄参与率、借贷参与率等多项普惠金融指标位居前列。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;金融棋活，全盘皆活。站在新的历史起点上，金融系统要坚持以习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想为指导，把服务实体经济放到更加突出的位置，努力健全具有高度适应性、竞争力、普惠型的现代金融体系，让高质量发展更加“血脉畅通”，为全面建设社会主义现代化国家贡献力量。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 43个城市试点低效用地再开发]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/29/nw.D110000renmrb_20231029_6-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月29日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报北京10月28日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者常钦）日前，自然资源部印发《关于开展低效用地再开发试点工作的通知》（以下简称《通知》），决定在43个城市开展为期4年的低效用地再开发试点，聚焦盘活利用存量土地探索创新政策举措，完善激励约束机制，以提高土地利用效率、促进城乡高质量发展。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;《通知》明确，试点城市要在坚持“局部试点、全面探索、封闭运行、结果可控”的前提下，探索创新盘活利用存量土地的政策机制。坚持市场在资源配置中的决定性作用，强化政府在空间统筹、结构优化、资金平衡、组织推动等方面的作用，坚持公平公开、“净地”供应，充分调动市场参与的积极性。坚持把盘活的城乡空间资源更多地用于民生所需和实体经济发展，补齐基础设施和公共服务设施短板，改善城乡人居环境，保障产业项目落地和转型升级。健全平等协商机制，完善收益分享机制，充分尊重权利人意愿，妥善处理群众诉求，促进改造成果更多更公平惠及人民群众。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;《通知》围绕盘活利用存量用地，聚焦低效用地再开发，支持试点城市重点从4个方面探索创新：在规划统筹方面，加强规划统领，突出高质量发展导向，引导有序实施；在收储支撑方面，完善收储机制，拓展收储资金渠道，完善征收补偿办法；在政策激励方面，探索资源资产组合供应、完善土地供应方式、优化地价政策工具、完善收益分享机制、健全存量资源转换利用机制；在基础保障方面，严格调查认定和上图入库、做好不动产确权登记、妥善处理历史遗留用地等问题。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;按照《通知》要求，试点城市通过探索创新实现3项工作目标：一是统筹兼顾经济、生活、生态、安全等多元需要，促进国土空间布局更合理、结构更优化、功能更完善、设施更完备；二是增加建设用地有效供给，大幅提高利用存量用地的比重和新上工业项目的容积率，推广应用节地技术和节地模式，明显降低单位GDP建设用地使用面积；三是建立可复制推广的低效用地再开发政策体系和制度机制，为促进城乡内涵式、集约型、绿色化高质量发展提供土地制度保障。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;《通知》规定，未纳入试点范围的超大特大城市及具备条件的城区常住人口300万以上的大城市，实施城中村改造项目可参照本《通知》明确的试点政策执行。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;试点期间，自然资源部将组织开展中期评估，评价各试点城市实施成效并加强督促指导。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 29 Oct 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>