<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 中国妇女第十三次全国代表大会在京开幕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/24/nw.D110000renmrb_20231024_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, October 24, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-10/24/01/rmrb2023102401p29_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;October 23, China The Thirteenth National Congress of Women opened in the Great Hall of the People in Beijing. This is Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, President of the State, and Chairman of the Central Military Commission, paying tribute to the participants on the rostrum. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Xie Huanchi&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align= &quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-10/24/01/rmrb2023102401p28_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/ TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On October 23, the 13th National Congress of Chinese Women opened in the Great Hall of the People in Beijing. Xi Jinping, Li Qiang, Zhao Leji, Wang Huning, Cai Qi, Ding Xuexiang, Li Xi and others took their seats on the rostrum to congratulate the convening of the conference. &lt;BR/>;Photographed by Xinhua News Agency reporter Yao Dawei&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;This newspaper, Beijing, October 23rd&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;(Reporter Li Changyu) The 13th National Congress of Chinese Women opened on the morning of the 23rd at the Great Hall of the People. Xi Jinping, Li Qiang, Zhao Leji, Wang Huning, Cai Qi, Li Xi and other party and state leaders attended the meeting to congratulate. Ding Xuexiang delivered a speech on behalf of the Party Central Committee. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The atmosphere in the Great Hall of the People was solemn and warm. The emblem of the &quot;Thirteenth National Congress of Chinese Women&quot; hangs above the rostrum, and in the center of the background is the bright emblem of the All-China Women&#39;s Federation, with 10 red flags on both sides. Hanging on the balcony on the second floor is the slogan &quot;Guided by Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, fully implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Party, mobilize and lead women of all ethnic groups and all walks of life to unite for the comprehensive construction of a socialist modern country and comprehensively promote the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation. Fight!&quot; giant banner. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nearly 1,800 representatives of the 13th National Congress of Chinese Women from all walks of life and 90 specially invited representatives from the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region and the Macao Special Administrative Region attended the conference, shouldering the trust of hundreds of millions of women. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At 10 a.m., Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, President of the State, and Chairman of the Central Military Commission, entered the venue, and the audience burst into warm applause. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shen Yueyue, vice chairman of the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference and executive chairman of the presidium of the conference, announced the opening of the conference. Everyone stood up and sang the national anthem. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On behalf of the Party Central Committee, Ding Xuexiang delivered a speech entitled &quot;Writing a splendid chapter of &quot;Half the Sky&quot; in the new era for the great cause of building a strong country and national rejuvenation&quot; (see the second page for the full text of the speech), expressing his warm welcome to the convening of the conference Congratulations, cordial greetings to women and women workers across the country, and best wishes to female compatriots and overseas female compatriots in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, Macao Special Administrative Region and Taiwan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ding Xuexiang said in his speech that since the 12th National Congress of Chinese Women, under the strong leadership of the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core, hundreds of millions of women have worked hard on the main battlefield of poverty alleviation and at the forefront of scientific and technological innovation. Bravely climbing to the top, going retrograde at the critical moment of fighting the epidemic, taking the initiative in the family and community, silently guarding the front line of safety construction, daring to fight hard in the competitive arena, the role of &quot;half the sky&quot; is fully demonstrated, and women&#39;s development progresses in all directions. Women&#39;s federations at all levels strive to strengthen women&#39;s ideological and political leadership, unite and mobilize women to make contributions in the new era, innovate and promote the construction of family tutoring and family tradition, provide rights protection and care services with heart and soul, actively carry out international exchanges and cooperation, and continue to deepen the reform of women&#39;s federations, political and The advanced nature and mass character have been continuously enhanced, which has played an important role in consolidating the mass foundation of the party&#39;s governance. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ding Xuexiang said that the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China drew up a grand blueprint for comprehensively promoting the construction of a strong country and national rejuvenation with Chinese-style modernization, and clarified the central task of the party in the new era and new journey. The majority of women must work together with the Party and forge ahead with the Party, build a solid foundation of women’s beliefs while practicing new ideas, demonstrate women’s responsibilities in forging ahead on a new journey, demonstrate women’s unique role in leading new trends, and create women’s achievements in advancing to a new realm. Live a brilliant life, write a more splendid chapter of &quot;Half the Sky&quot; on the new journey with a stronger historical consciousness and a more high-spirited spiritual outlook. Women&#39;s federation organizations at all levels must unswervingly follow the path of socialist mass development with Chinese characteristics, conscientiously perform their functions of leadership, service, and contact, and pool the power and wisdom of women for the party&#39;s cause. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xu Liuping, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and First Secretary of the Secretariat of the All-China Federation of Trade Unions, represented the All-China Federation of Trade Unions, the Central Committee of the Communist Youth League of China, the China Federation of Literary and Art Circles, the Chinese Writers Association, the China Association for Science and Technology, The All-China Federation of Returned Overseas Chinese, the All-China Federation of Taiwan Compatriots, and the China Disabled Persons’ Federation sent congratulatory messages to the conference. The congratulatory message pointed out that on the new journey, mass organizations must uphold and strengthen the party&#39;s overall leadership, persist in using Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, and unswervingly follow the path of mass group development of socialism with Chinese characteristics. The great struggle has opened up a new world for the development of mass organizations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On behalf of the 12th Executive Committee of the All-China Women&#39;s Federation, Huang Xiaowei, executive chairman of the presidium of the conference, delivered a speech entitled &quot;Guided by Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Mobilizing and Leading Women to Strengthen the Country and united efforts to build national rejuvenation&quot; report. The report is divided into five parts: Chinese women and women&#39;s federation organizations who are determined to fight for the party; using Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era to guide the new voyage of Chinese women&#39;s cause; bravely shouldering the mission of women for the construction of a strong country and national rejuvenation; in the new era Promote the high-quality development of the Women&#39;s Federation work on the way to the exam; forge a Women&#39;s Federation organization that adapts to the requirements of Chinese-style modernization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The conference submitted a draft of the &quot;Constitution of the All-China Women&#39;s Federation (Amendment)&quot; in the form of a written report to the representatives for their review. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Secretary of the Secretariat of the CPC Central Committee and relevant leading comrades of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, the State Council, the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference, and the Central Military Commission attended the meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Relevant departments of the central and state agencies, various people&#39;s organizations, relevant military units and responsible comrades in Beijing, leaders of the central committees of democratic parties, leaders of the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce and representatives of people without party affiliation, and some female leading cadres at the ministerial level in Beijing Senior leaders of the All-China Women&#39;s Federation and women representatives from all walks of life in the capital attended the opening ceremony. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 坚持党对工会的全面领导  组织动员亿万职工积极投身强国建设民族复兴伟业]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/24/nw.D110000renmrb_20231024_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, October 24, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-10/24/01/rmrb2023102401p19_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;October 23, the Communist Party of China Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, President of the State, and Chairman of the Central Military Commission, held a collective conversation with members of the new leadership team of the All-China Federation of Trade Unions in Zhongnanhai and delivered an important speech. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Ju Peng&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;■my country’s labor movement is under the party’s leadership Developed under the leadership of the Party, the trade union is a mass organization of the working class under the leadership of the Party. We must uphold the Party’s overall leadership over the trade unions and never waver or deviate from it at any time and under any circumstances. We must adhere to the fundamental policy of relying wholeheartedly on the working class, fully mobilize the enthusiasm, initiative, and creativity of the broad masses of workers, and actively participate in the great cause of comprehensively promoting the construction of a strong country and national rejuvenation&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■ Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, Under the strong leadership of the Party Central Committee, our country&#39;s working class has played a major role in the development of the party and the country. The labor movement has made historic achievements, and trade union work has made all-round progress. In the past five years, the broad masses of employees have worked together with the Party and worked hard with the Party. In major tasks such as economic construction, scientific and technological innovation, poverty alleviation, rural revitalization, epidemic prevention and control, emergency rescue and disaster relief, they have demonstrated the courage to fight tough battles and shoulder heavy responsibilities. . The All-China Federation of Trade Unions and trade unions at all levels have strengthened the ideological and political guidance of employees, promoted the reform of building a team of industrial workers, protected the rights and interests of workers, maintained political security in the labor field, deepened the reform of the trade union system, and continuously enhanced its political, advanced and mass character. The Party Central Committee fully affirms the major contributions made to the working class and the new achievements made in trade union work. The Party Central Committee has placed high expectations on the new leadership team of the All-China Federation of Trade Unions&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■Insisting that the party’s leadership must be comprehensively and effectively implemented into the entire process and all aspects of trade union work. We must firmly safeguard the authority and centralized and unified leadership of the Party Central Committee, and always maintain a high degree of consistency with the Party Central Committee in terms of ideology, politics, and actions. We must unswervingly use the Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era to focus our minds and forge our souls, continue to promote theoretical arming to be more in-depth and practical, and continuously enhance our ideological consciousness and action consciousness in learning and practicing the Party&#39;s innovative theories. It is necessary to keep in mind the &quot;big one in the country&quot;, identify the connection point, entry point, and focus of trade union work and the party&#39;s central tasks, and promote the implementation of the Party Central Committee&#39;s decisions and arrangements in the trade union system. It is necessary to strengthen ideological and political guidance, do a good job in ideological and political work among employees, educate and guide the majority of employees to unswervingly listen to and follow the Party, and ensure that the working class is always the most solid and reliable class foundation for our Party&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■ It is necessary to unite the broad masses of workers closely around the party and work together to achieve the party&#39;s central tasks. It is necessary to focus on implementing new development concepts, building a new development pattern, and promoting high-quality development, and carry out extensive and in-depth various forms of labor and skills competitions to stimulate the enthusiasm and creative potential of employees, and give full play to the main role in all walks of life and all fields. . It is necessary to vigorously promote the spirit of model workers, the spirit of labor, and the spirit of craftsmen, give full play to the role of model workers and craftsmen in demonstrating and leading, and encourage employees to achieve their dreams through hard work, honest work, and creative work. We must focus on the in-depth implementation of the strategy of rejuvenating the country through science and education, the strategy of strengthening the country through talent, and the strategy of innovation-driven development, deepen the reform of the construction of the industrial worker team, accelerate the construction of an army of knowledge-based, skill-based, and innovative industrial workers, and cultivate more craftsmen and high-skilled talents in the country. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■The working class and the broad masses of working people are the main creators of social wealth. To achieve more obvious substantive progress in promoting the common prosperity of all people, it must first be reflected in hundreds of millions of workers. As the representatives and defenders of workers&#39; interests, trade unions must conscientiously perform their basic duties of rights protection services, focus on solving practical problems related to the vital interests of workers, and attach great importance to safeguarding the legitimate rights and interests of workers in new forms of employment. It is necessary to strengthen democratic management of enterprises and institutions, open channels for employees to express their demands, guide employees to safeguard their rights and interests in accordance with the law, and promote the establishment of harmonious labor relations&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■ It is necessary to continue to deepen the reform and construction of trade unions and firmly establish a clear direction of focusing on the grassroots , consolidate the grassroots foundation, stimulate grassroots vitality, and continuously enhance the leadership, organizational and service capabilities of grassroots trade unions. It is necessary to improve the existing organizational foundation and expand the coverage of trade union organizations. It is necessary to innovate working methods and strive to provide accurate and considerate services to employees. Trade union cadres must practice the party&#39;s mass line, conduct in-depth investigations and studies, promptly understand what employees think and expect, constantly enhance their ability to serve employees, and speak and act for employees sincerely. The All-China Federation of Trade Unions must take the lead in strengthening its own construction, set a benchmark and set an example, and become a model political organ that reassures the Party and satisfies the people&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■ Party committees at all levels must strengthen leadership over trade unions and trade union work, and select good candidates Establish a strong trade union leadership team, enthusiastically care for and strictly demand trade union cadres, and pay attention to the training and use of trade union cadres. We must pay attention to the role of trade union organizations, promptly study important issues encountered by employees and trade unions, and support trade unions in creative work. Governments at all levels should give full play to the role of joint meetings between the government and trade unions and actively help trade unions solve the practical difficulties and problems of employees&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 23rd &amp;nbsp;On the afternoon of the 23rd, Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, President of the State, and Chairman of the Central Military Commission, held a collective conversation with members of the new leadership team of the All-China Federation of Trade Unions in Zhongnanhai and delivered an important speech. Xi Jinping emphasized that my country’s labor movement developed under the leadership of the Party, and trade unions are mass organizations of the working class led by the Party. We must uphold the Party’s overall leadership over the trade unions and never waver or deviate from it at any time and under any circumstances. We must adhere to the fundamental policy of relying wholeheartedly on the working class, fully mobilize the enthusiasm, initiative and creativity of the broad masses of workers, and actively participate in the great cause of comprehensively promoting the construction of a strong country and national rejuvenation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cai Qi, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and secretary of the Secretariat of the CPC Central Committee, participated in the group conversation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping first said that since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, under the strong leadership of the Party Central Committee, our country’s working class has played a main role in the development of the party and the country. The labor movement has made historic achievements, and the trade unions have Work achieves all-round progress. In the past five years, the broad masses of employees have worked together with the Party and worked hard with the Party. In major tasks such as economic construction, scientific and technological innovation, poverty alleviation, rural revitalization, epidemic prevention and control, emergency rescue and disaster relief, they have demonstrated the courage to fight tough battles and shoulder heavy responsibilities. . The All-China Federation of Trade Unions and trade unions at all levels have strengthened the ideological and political guidance of employees, promoted the reform of building a team of industrial workers, protected the rights and interests of workers, maintained political security in the labor field, deepened the reform of the trade union system, and continuously enhanced its political, advanced and mass character. The Party Central Committee fully affirms the major contributions made to the working class and the new achievements made in trade union work. The Party Central Committee has placed high expectations on the new leadership team of the All-China Federation of Trade Unions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping emphasized that upholding the party’s leadership must be comprehensively and effectively implemented in the entire process and all aspects of trade union work. We must firmly safeguard the authority and centralized and unified leadership of the Party Central Committee, and always maintain a high degree of consistency with the Party Central Committee in terms of ideology, politics, and actions. We must unswervingly use the Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era to focus our minds and forge our souls, continue to promote theoretical arming to be more in-depth and practical, and continuously enhance our ideological consciousness and action consciousness in learning and practicing the Party&#39;s innovative theories. It is necessary to keep in mind the &quot;big one in the country&quot;, identify the connection point, entry point, and focus of trade union work and the party&#39;s central tasks, and promote the implementation of the Party Central Committee&#39;s decisions and arrangements in the trade union system. It is necessary to strengthen ideological and political guidance, do a good job in ideological and political work among employees, educate and guide the majority of employees to unswervingly listen to and follow the Party, and ensure that the working class is always the most solid and reliable class foundation for our Party. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that the broad masses of workers must be closely united around the party and work together to achieve the party&#39;s central tasks. It is necessary to focus on implementing new development concepts, building a new development pattern, and promoting high-quality development, and carry out extensive and in-depth various forms of labor and skills competitions to stimulate the enthusiasm and creative potential of employees, and give full play to the main role in all walks of life and all fields. . It is necessary to vigorously promote the spirit of model workers, the spirit of labor, and the spirit of craftsmen, give full play to the role of model workers and craftsmen in demonstrating and leading, and encourage employees to achieve their dreams through hard work, honest work, and creative work. We must focus on the in-depth implementation of the strategy of rejuvenating the country through science and education, the strategy of strengthening the country through talent, and the strategy of innovation-driven development, deepen the reform of the construction of the industrial worker team, accelerate the construction of an army of knowledge-based, skill-based, and innovative industrial workers, and cultivate more craftsmen and high-skilled talents in the country. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping emphasized that the working class and the broad masses of working people are the main creators of social wealth, and more obvious substantive progress in promoting the common prosperity of all people must first be reflected in hundreds of millions of workers. As the representatives and defenders of workers&#39; interests, trade unions must conscientiously perform their basic duties of rights protection services, focus on solving practical problems related to the vital interests of workers, and attach great importance to safeguarding the legitimate rights and interests of workers in new forms of employment. It is necessary to strengthen democratic management of enterprises and institutions, open channels for employees to express their demands, guide employees to safeguard their rights and interests in accordance with the law, and promote the establishment of harmonious labor relations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that it is necessary to continue to deepen the reform and construction of trade unions, firmly establish a clear direction of focusing on the grassroots, consolidate the grassroots foundation, stimulate grassroots vitality, and continuously enhance the leadership, organizational and service capabilities of grassroots trade unions. It is necessary to improve the existing organizational foundation and expand the coverage of trade union organizations. It is necessary to innovate working methods and strive to provide accurate and considerate services to employees. Trade union cadres must practice the party&#39;s mass line, conduct in-depth investigations and studies, promptly understand what employees think and expect, constantly enhance their ability to serve employees, and speak and act for employees sincerely. The All-China Federation of Trade Unions must take the lead in strengthening its own construction, set a benchmark and set an example, and become a model political organ that reassures the Party and satisfies the people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping emphasized that party committees at all levels must strengthen their leadership over trade unions and trade union work, select and equip strong trade union leadership teams, enthusiastically care for and strictly demand trade union cadres, and pay attention to the training and use of trade union cadres. We must pay attention to the role of trade union organizations, promptly study important issues encountered by employees and trade unions, and support trade unions in creative work. Governments at all levels should give full play to the role of joint meetings between the government and trade unions and actively help trade unions solve the practical difficulties and problems of employees. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On behalf of the new leadership team of the All-China Federation of Trade Unions, Wang Dongming, Chairman of the All-China Federation of Trade Unions, made a report on the situation related to the 18th National Congress of Chinese Trade Unions and the work arrangements of the trade union in the next five years. Vice Chairman of the All-China Federation of Trade Unions Xu Liuping, Yang Yudong and Gao Fenglin made speeches. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shi Taifeng, Li Ganjie, Li Shulei, Chen Wenqing, Liu Jinguo and Wang Xiaohong participated in the conversation. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 李强同日本首相岸田文雄就中日和平友好条约缔结45周年互致贺电]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/24/nw.D110000renmrb_20231024_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, October 24, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 23&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;On October 23, Premier Li Qiang of the State Council and Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida Exchanged congratulatory messages on the 45th anniversary of the signing of the Treaty of Peace and Friendship between China and Japan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Qiang said that 45 years ago, the older generation leaders and politicians of the two countries made the strategic decision to conclude a treaty of peace and friendship between China and Japan. The treaty established the general direction of peaceful coexistence and ever-lasting friendship for the two neighboring countries, China and Japan, in legal form, emphasized the opposition to hegemonism, and became an important milestone in the development of bilateral relations. Over the past 45 years, China-Japan relations have achieved hard-won development results, enhanced the well-being of the two peoples, and made positive contributions to peace, stability and prosperity in the region and the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Qiang pointed out that China is willing to work with Japan to review the spirit of the treaty, firmly grasp the correct development direction of bilateral relations, and strive to build Sino-Japanese relations that meet the requirements of the new era. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kishida Fumio said that the Japan-China Peace and Friendship Treaty is clearly written to develop lasting peace and friendly relations between the two countries. Over the past 45 years, both sides have used this as a guide to lay the foundation for the development of Japan-China relations and maintain and develop peaceful and friendly relations between the two countries. Japan and China shoulder important responsibilities for peace and prosperity in the region and even the world, and have cooperation potential in a wide range of fields. It is of great significance for both sides to work together to build a constructive and stable Japan-China relationship. Japan is willing to review the spirit of the treaty with China and strive to promote greater development of Japan-China relations. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 王沪宁会见巴基斯坦参议院主席桑吉拉尼]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/24/nw.D110000renmrb_20231024_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, October 24, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 23&amp;nbsp; Rani. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Wang Huning said that China and Pakistan are all-weather strategic partners and iron friends. Last week, President Xi Jinping had an in-depth exchange of views with Prime Minister Kakkar on the development of China-Pakistan relations and the high-quality joint construction of the China-Pakistan Economic Corridor. China is willing to work with Pakistan to further implement the important consensus reached by the leaders of the two countries, intensify high-level exchanges and strategic communication, deepen mutually beneficial cooperation in various fields, and accelerate the construction of a closer China-Pakistan community with a shared future in the new era. The National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference is willing to work with Pakistan to strengthen mutual learning of governance experience, create a good environment for China-Pakistan cooperation, and gather more positive energy. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Sanjrani said that the iron-clad friendship and mutually beneficial cooperation between Pakistan and China have brought great benefits to the Pakistani people and have become a model for state-to-state relations. Pakistan admires President Xi Jinping&#39;s wise leadership and foresight, appreciates China&#39;s display of responsibility as a major country, and will always firmly adhere to the one-China principle, firmly support each other with China, and inherit the traditional friendship between Pakistan and China. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Shi Taifeng, Wang Yong and Wang Dongfeng attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 为强国建设民族复兴伟业谱写新时代“半边天”的绚丽华章]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/24/nw.D110000renmrb_20231024_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, October 24, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Dear representatives and comrades:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 13th National Congress of Chinese Women opens grandly today . Entrusted by General Secretary Xi Jinping and the Party Central Committee, I would like to express warm congratulations on the convening of the conference! I would like to extend my cordial greetings to all women and women workers across the country! I would like to extend my best wishes to the female compatriots and overseas female compatriots in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region, Macao Special Administrative Region and Taiwan! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the 12th National Congress of Chinese Women, under the strong leadership of the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core, hundreds of millions of women have devoted themselves to the great practice of the new era with a strong sense of responsibility, working hard on the main battlefield of poverty alleviation, and in science and technology. The innovation frontier bravely reaches the peak, goes retrograde at the critical moment of anti-epidemic, takes the initiative in the family and community, silently guards on the front line of safety construction, dares to fight hard in the competitive arena, the role of &quot;half the sky&quot; is fully demonstrated, and women&#39;s development progresses in all aspects. It vividly demonstrates the style of women in the new era who are builders of great causes, advocates of civilization and fashion, and those who dare to pursue dreams. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past five years, women&#39;s federations at all levels have been guided by Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, deeply studied and implemented General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s important expositions on women, children and women&#39;s federations, and insisted on the party&#39;s overall leadership throughout , firmly grasp the functional positioning in the overall situation, strive to strengthen women&#39;s ideological and political leadership, unite and mobilize the majority of women to contribute to the new era, innovate and promote the construction of family tutoring and family tradition, provide rights protection and care services with heart and soul, actively carry out international exchanges and cooperation, and continue to deepen The reform of the Women&#39;s Federation has continuously enhanced its political, progressive and mass nature, and has played an important role in consolidating the mass basis for the party&#39;s governance. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping attaches great importance to the cause of women and children, and has made a series of important expositions on women, children and the work of the Women&#39;s Federation, and personally deployed and promoted the reform of the Women&#39;s Federation. Expressing holiday blessings and expressing high expectations on behalf of the Party Central Committee in different ways demonstrates the people&#39;s leaders&#39; deep feelings for the people that they care about women and children and the lights of thousands of homes, guiding China&#39;s women and children&#39;s cause to stride forward in the new era and creating a prosperous development new situation. Practice has fully proved that China’s achievements in the cause of women and children in the new era have attracted worldwide attention. The development path of socialism with Chinese characteristics for women and children is getting wider and wider. This is fundamentally due to the leadership and helm of General Secretary Xi Jinping and the scientific guidance of Xi Jinping’s socialist thought with Chinese characteristics for a new era. Practice has fully proved that Chinese women in the new era are worthy of the &quot;half the sky&quot; for upholding and developing socialism with Chinese characteristics, and the women&#39;s federation organizations of the new era are worthy of being a strong bridge between the party and the government and the women. The Party Central Committee fully affirms and has high hopes for the vast number of women and women&#39;s federation organizations at all levels! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China drew up a grand blueprint for comprehensively promoting the construction of a powerful country and the great cause of national rejuvenation through Chinese-style modernization, and clarified the central task of the party in the new era and new journey. The central task of the Party is the theme and direction of the cause of Chinese women and the work of the Women&#39;s Federation. The majority of women must work together with the Party and forge ahead with the Party. With a stronger sense of history and a more high-spirited spirit, they must strive to be writers of the times and strivers to pursue dreams, and write a more splendid chapter of &quot;Half the Sky&quot; on the new journey. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Build a solid foundation of women’s faith in practicing new ideas. On the new journey, women must conscientiously study and implement Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, deeply understand the decisive significance of the &quot;two establishments&quot;, strengthen the &quot;four consciousnesses&quot;, strengthen the &quot;four self-confidences&quot;, and achieve the &quot;two safeguards&quot; &quot;. We must firmly establish the lofty ideals of communism and the common ideals of socialism with Chinese characteristics, cherish today&#39;s hard-won good situation and happy life, and always move forward firmly in the direction guided by the Party Central Committee and General Secretary Xi Jinping. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Demonstrate the responsibility of women in the new journey of forging ahead. On the new journey, women must consciously link their own future and destiny with that of the country and nation, consciously integrate their life goals into the party&#39;s goals, and actively participate in the historical torrent of Chinese-style modernization. We must take pride in hard work and be proud of hard work, and use our wisdom to focus on major strategic deployments of the party and the country such as high-quality development, self-reliance in science and technology, rural revitalization, common prosperity, social governance, building a beautiful China, promoting the reunification of the motherland, and building a community with a shared future for mankind. Talent, strive to create first-class performance, and contribute to the construction of a strong country and national rejuvenation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Show the unique role of women in leading new trends. On the new journey, women must thoroughly study and implement Xi Jinping’s cultural thoughts, strengthen cultural self-confidence, take the lead in practicing the core socialist values, and contribute to promoting cultural prosperity, building a culturally powerful country, and building the modern civilization of the Chinese nation. It is necessary to cultivate the feelings of family and country, establish correct views on marriage, love, childbirth, and family, encourage family members to be good citizens of the society, good employees of the unit, and good members of the family, help children button the first button of life, and make patriotism a reality. The new trend of civilization of family, loving each other, doing good, co-building and sharing has filled thousands of households. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Create a brilliant life as a heroine while advancing to a new realm. On the new journey, women must firmly grasp new historical opportunities, keep up with the pace of the new era, be good at learning, diligent in thinking, brave in practice, dare to innovate, and hone their excellent skills in entrepreneurship. We must uphold the spirit of self-esteem, self-confidence, self-reliance, and self-improvement, carry forward the fine tradition of hard work, hard work, and perseverance, bravely face various difficulties and challenges on the road of life, and rely on tenacious struggle to create a new world for career development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Women&#39;s Federation is a women&#39;s mass organization founded and led by the Communist Party of China. It shoulders the historical mission of mobilizing and leading women to unite and strive to complete the Party&#39;s central tasks. On the new journey, women&#39;s federation organizations at all levels must unswervingly follow the path of socialist mass development with Chinese characteristics, conscientiously perform their functions of leadership, service, and contact, and pool the power and wisdom of women for the party&#39;s cause. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We must always adhere to the party’s overall leadership. The leadership of the party is the fundamental guarantee for doing a good job in women&#39;s work. Women&#39;s federations at all levels must take learning, understanding and practicing Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era as their primary political task, thoroughly study and implement General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s important expositions on women, children and the work of women&#39;s federations, and always be ideologically and politically consistent in their actions. The Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping at its core maintains a high degree of unity. It is necessary to innovate women&#39;s ideological and political leadership work, deepen &quot;women&#39;s study&quot; and &quot;women&#39;s propaganda&quot;, build souls with educated people and bacon, and guide the majority of women to unswervingly listen to the party and follow the party. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We must consciously serve the &quot;big one in the country&quot;. Focusing on the center and serving the overall situation is the main line of the Women&#39;s Federation&#39;s work. Women&#39;s federations at all levels must anchor the goals and tasks set out at the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, proactively align with the party and the country&#39;s major strategic deployments, identify the entry point, integration point, and focus of work, and empower &quot;women in rural revitalization action&quot; and &quot;women in scientific and technological innovation&quot;. Action&quot; and &quot;Action to Promote Women&#39;s Employment and Entrepreneurship&quot; and other new connotations, give full play to the leading role of advanced models such as the March 8th Red Flag Bearers, and maximize the enthusiasm, initiative and creativity of women. It is necessary to deepen the &quot;Every Family Happiness and Health Project&quot;, improve the effectiveness of the &quot;Most Beautiful Family&quot; propaganda and guidance, implement the &quot;Family Service Women Action&quot;, serve a better life for the majority of families, and contribute to supporting Chinese modernization with high-quality population development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We must pay close attention to rights protection and care services. Representing and safeguarding women&#39;s rights and interests, promoting gender equality and women&#39;s all-round development are the basic functions of women&#39;s federations. Women&#39;s federations at all levels must make good use of the resources and channels given by the party, increase source participation, and promote the strengthening of legal protection for women and children in the entire process of people&#39;s democracy. Rights protection work must be done on a daily basis, carried out on a regular basis, and dropped to the grassroots level, and regular visits, inspections, discovery reports, etc. must be carried out to promote the resolution of key and difficult issues. It is necessary to mobilize social forces, thoroughly implement the &quot;Spring Bud Plan - Dreaming of the Future&quot;, &quot;Healthy China Mother Action&quot;, etc., and send the party&#39;s care and warmth to women and children, so that the results of modernization can be distributed more and more equitably. Benefit women and children. It is necessary to improve long-term mechanisms to prevent and resolve hidden risks and resolutely safeguard political security in the field of women. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We must better play our role as bridges and ties. Only by having the courage to revolutionize ourselves can we keep up with the pace of the times and maintain vitality forever. Women&#39;s federations at all levels must take the party&#39;s political construction as their guide and comprehensively strengthen party building. It is necessary to focus on maintaining and enhancing the political, advanced and mass nature, establish a clear direction of focusing on the grassroots, promote reform and innovation with greater efforts, consolidate and improve the results of &quot;difficulty-solving actions&quot;, continue to expand organizational coverage, build strong work positions, and enrich As a carrier of activities, cultivate a team of high-quality cadres, build a new form of online work, continuously improve leadership, organizational and service capabilities, and serve as a powerful assistant for the party in carrying out women&#39;s work and a warm natal home that women can trust and rely on. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The cause of women and children is an important part of the cause of socialism with Chinese characteristics, and women&#39;s work is an important aspect of the party&#39;s mass work. Party committees at all levels must strengthen and improve their leadership over women&#39;s work and the work of women&#39;s federations, support women&#39;s federation organizations to carry out their work creatively, promptly study and solve major issues in the work of women and children, and create a society that respects and cares for women and children, cares about women&#39;s and children&#39;s causes, and supports women. A good working environment promotes the simultaneous and coordinated development of women&#39;s and children&#39;s undertakings and the economy and society. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dear representatives and comrades! The grand goals of building a strong country and rejuvenating the nation are inspiring, and there is a lot to be done for “half the sky.” Let us unite more closely around the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core, be confident and strong, move forward courageously, and work together to comprehensively build a modern socialist country and comprehensively promote the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I wish the 13th National Congress of Chinese Women a complete success! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 23)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 第六届进博会将全面线下举办（权威发布）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/24/nw.D110000renmrb_20231024_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Tuesday, October 24, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;The 6th CIIE will be held offline in Shanghai from November 5th to 10th. On October 23, the State Council Information Office held a press conference to introduce the relevant situation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Provide more market opportunities, investment opportunities, and growth opportunities&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vice Minister of Commerce Sheng Qiuping introduced several important issues at the 6th CIIE Features——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The &quot;Jinbo circle of friends&quot; continues to expand. This CIIE is expected to welcome guests from 154 countries, regions and international organizations. More than 3,400 exhibitors and 394,000 professional visitors have registered, fully returning to pre-epidemic levels. More than a hundred executives from the global headquarters of Fortune 500 companies and industry leading companies have confirmed that they will come to China to participate in the CIIE, a record-breaking scale. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The national exhibition fully demonstrates the willingness of all parties to open up and cooperate. Participating countries cover five continents, and 69 countries and 3 international organizations have confirmed that they will participate in the national exhibition. Among them, 11 countries participated in the exhibition for the first time, and 34 countries participated in the offline exhibition for the first time. Honduras, Kazakhstan, Serbia, South Africa, Vietnam, etc. served as the guest countries. The area of ​​the China Pavilion has increased to 2,500 square meters, the largest in its history. With the theme of &quot;New Achievements in Chinese Modernization Provide New Opportunities for the World&quot;, the &quot;10th Anniversary Achievements Exhibition of the Construction of China Free Trade Pilot Zone&quot; was established to focus on displaying the latest achievements of my country&#39;s promotion of high-level opening up and high-quality development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The quality and efficiency of corporate exhibitions have been significantly improved. The exhibition scale is larger and the quality of exhibitors is higher. The exhibition area is approximately 367,000 square meters, and the number of Fortune 500 companies and industry leading companies participating in the exhibition reaches 289, all exceeding the previous levels. The world&#39;s top 15 vehicle brands, top 10 industrial electrical companies, top 10 medical device companies, three major mining giants, four major grain merchants, and five major shipping companies have all confirmed their participation in the exhibition. The exhibition area is better set up and new products are unveiled together. The exhibition area is set up to focus on high-quality development and high-quality life. The exhibition area of ​​cutting-edge science and technology exhibition areas such as energy, low-carbon, artificial intelligence, and daily consumption themes has increased by 30%. More than 400 new products, new technologies, and new services will be displayed together. Accurate and professional docking, taking multiple measures to promote transactions. Various localities and relevant departments have established 39 government trading groups and 4 industry trading groups, with more than 750 trading sub-groups. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The opening theme of the Hongqiao Forum is more distinctive. With the theme of &quot;Working together to promote development and openness to win the future&quot;, we will continue to hold high the banner of openness and promote true multilateralism. Adhering to high-standard preparations, important events such as the opening ceremony and the &quot;Invest in China Year&quot; summit will be held, foreign-invested enterprise roundtables will be held on special topics, and the &quot;World Openness Report 2023&quot; and the latest World Openness Index will be released. Adhering to high-standard promotion, 22 sub-forums were carefully organized, covering green development, digital economy, smart technology and other global open hotspots. Adhering to high-quality discussions, more than 300 heavyweight speakers from the global political, business, academic and research circles will attend to conduct high-end dialogues and contribute &quot;Hongqiao wisdom&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们将与各方密切配合，全力以赴打造一届高标准、高质量、高水平的全球经贸盛会，为与会各方提供更多市场机遇、投资机遇、增长机遇，凝聚合力，共促发展。”盛秋平说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;服务高质量发展和高水平开放&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;进博会已成为中国构建新发展格局的窗口、推动高水平开放的平台和全球共享的国际公共产品。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为构建新发展格局的窗口，一方面，进博会畅通国内大循环，推动高质量发展。积极引进先进技术装备、高端零部件、中间品及消费品，展示全球产业发展趋势和前沿成果，助力产业升级，丰富国内供给，提升消费品质。另一方面，进博会连接国内国际双循环。展商、展品双境外的特点使进博会成为国内国际双循环天然的连接点。前5届进博会展示超过2000项代表性首发新产品、新技术、新服务，累计意向成交额近3500亿美元，助力稳住外贸外资基本盘。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为推动高水平开放的平台，进博会持续传递开放强音，成为宣示重大开放举措、展示开放决心的重要平台。一大批高端装备制造、绿色环保、生物技术等领域新品将在本届进博会上迎来首发首展；厄瓜多尔的麒麟果、贝宁的菠萝等产品将通过本届进博会进入中国市场。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为全球共享的国际公共产品，进博会充分彰显中国坚持真正的多边主义，践行人类命运共同体理念。包容性越来越强，持续与相关国际组织合作，积极推动各国实现互利共赢，促进世界经济包容性增长。影响力越来越大，虹桥论坛围绕“全球开放”主题和“国际公共产品”的功能定位，持续发布《世界开放报告》和世界开放指数，搭建国际政商学界高端对话交流平台。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上海市副市长华源介绍，作为进博会的主办地，上海加快建设进出口商品集散地，进博会“6天+365天”交易服务平台拓展至60家。上海努力推动参展商变投资商，已经连续6年推出优化营商环境行动方案，深化政企沟通圆桌会议、重点企业“服务包”制度。实际使用外资从2018年的166.61亿美元增至2022年的239.56亿美元，5年累计总额达到1013亿美元，较上个5年增长20.5%。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;积极扩大进口，促进外贸发展&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为世界上第一个以进口为主题的国家级展会，进博会已成为推动中国与世界市场对接、产业相融、创意互促、规则互鉴的国际大平台。下一步，商务部将与有关部门一道，多措并举促进全球优质产品进口，助推贸易高质量发展。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不断加大政策支持。保障大宗商品进口各环节稳定运行，增加能源资源产品和农产品进口供给。商务部将会同有关部门修订《鼓励进口技术和产品目录》，支持企业扩大先进技术、重要装备和关键零部件进口，促进产业结构调整和优化升级。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不断释放进口潜力。今年，我国对1020项商品（不含关税配额商品）实施进口暂定税率；根据已签署生效的自由贸易协定和优惠贸易安排，对19个协定项下、原产于29个国家或地区的部分进口货物实施协定税率，进一步降低税率水平。发挥跨境电商零售进口积极作用，继续释放消费品进口潜力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不断促进创新示范。目前全国共有43个进口贸易促进创新示范区。将指导各地结合地方特色和优势，积极开展政策创新，打造一批消费品进口平台和大宗商品交易中心，促进进口贸易与产业、消费的深度融合，在全国范围内形成进口促进创新的新局面，激发进口发展的动能和潜力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不断深化国际消费中心城市建设。近年来，商务部会同相关部门，加快推动培育建设国际消费中心城市，深入开展海南国际旅游消费中心建设，广泛聚集全球优质消费资源，扩大优质消费品进口。将加强政策创新、制度创新，扩大优质商品和服务进口，优化进口商品分销渠道，以更高质量的消费供给，更好满足人民品质生活需要。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不断推进展会交流。充分发挥进博会等重大展会贸易平台作用，放大各类展会溢出效应，推动更多优质商品、技术和服务进入中国，促进企业交流对接，让更多企业共享中国市场机遇。 &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 中国妇女第十三次全国代表大会在京开幕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/24/nw.D110000renmrb_20231024_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月24日星期二&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-10/24/01/rmrb2023102401p29_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;10月23日，中国妇女第十三次全国代表大会在北京人民大会堂开幕。这是中共中央总书记、国家主席、中央军委主席习近平在主席台向与会代表致意。&lt;BR/>;新华社记者谢环驰摄&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-10/24/01/rmrb2023102401p28_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;10月23日，中国妇女第十三次全国代表大会在北京人民大会堂开幕。习近平、李强、赵乐际、王沪宁、蔡奇、丁薛祥、李希等在主席台就座，祝贺大会召开。&lt;BR/>;新华社记者姚大伟摄&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;本报北京10月23日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者李昌禹）中国妇女第十三次全国代表大会23日上午在人民大会堂开幕。习近平、李强、赵乐际、王沪宁、蔡奇、李希等党和国家领导人到会祝贺，丁薛祥代表党中央致词。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人民大会堂大礼堂气氛庄重热烈。主席台上方悬挂着“中国妇女第十三次全国代表大会”会标，后幕正中是鲜艳的中华全国妇女联合会会徽，10面红旗分列两侧。二楼眺台悬挂着“以习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想为指导，全面贯彻党的二十大精神，动员引领各族各界妇女为全面建设社会主义现代化国家、全面推进中华民族伟大复兴而团结奋斗！”巨型横幅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近1800名来自全国各行各业的中国妇女十三大代表和90名来自香港特别行政区、澳门特别行政区的特邀代表，肩负着亿万妇女的重托出席大会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上午10时，中共中央总书记、国家主席、中央军委主席习近平等步入会场，全场响起热烈掌声。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全国政协副主席、大会主席团常务主席沈跃跃宣布大会开幕。全体起立，高唱国歌。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;丁薛祥代表党中央发表了题为《为强国建设民族复兴伟业谱写新时代“半边天”的绚丽华章》的致词（致词全文见第二版），向大会召开表示热烈祝贺，向全国广大妇女和妇女工作者致以亲切问候，向香港特别行政区、澳门特别行政区和台湾地区的女同胞、海外女侨胞致以良好祝愿。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;丁薛祥在致词中说，中国妇女十二大以来，在以习近平同志为核心的党中央坚强领导下，亿万妇女在脱贫攻坚主战场拼搏实干，在科技创新前沿勇攀高峰，在抗疫紧要关头逆行出征，在家庭和社区主动担当，在平安建设一线默默守护，在竞技赛场敢打敢拼，“半边天”作用全方位彰显，妇女发展全方位进步。各级妇联组织着力强化妇女思想政治引领，团结动员广大妇女建功新时代，创新推进家庭家教家风建设，用心用情做好维权关爱服务，积极开展国际交流合作，持续深化妇联改革，政治性、先进性、群众性不断增强，为巩固党执政的群众基础发挥了重要作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;丁薛祥表示，党的二十大擘画了以中国式现代化全面推进强国建设、民族复兴伟业的宏伟蓝图，明确了新时代新征程党的中心任务。广大妇女要与党同心、跟党奋进，在践行新思想中筑牢巾帼信仰之基，在奋进新征程中彰显巾帼担当作为，在引领新风尚中展现巾帼独特作用，在提升新境界中创造巾帼出彩人生，以更为强烈的历史自觉、更加昂扬的精神面貌，在新征程上谱写“半边天”更加绚丽的华章。各级妇联组织要坚定不移走中国特色社会主义群团发展道路，认真履行引领、服务、联系职能，为党的事业凝聚巾帼之力、汇集巾帼之智。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中华全国总工会党组书记、书记处第一书记徐留平代表中华全国总工会、中国共产主义青年团中央委员会、中国文学艺术界联合会、中国作家协会、中国科学技术协会、中华全国归国华侨联合会、中华全国台湾同胞联谊会、中国残疾人联合会向大会致贺词。贺词指出，新征程上，群团组织要坚持和加强党的全面领导，坚持不懈用习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想凝心铸魂，坚定不移走中国特色社会主义群团发展道路，以新的伟大奋斗打开群团事业发展新天地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大会主席团常务主席黄晓薇代表中华全国妇女联合会第十二届执行委员会作了题为《以习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想为指导&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;动员引领广大妇女为强国建设民族复兴而团结奋斗》的报告。报告分为5个部分：矢志不渝跟党奋斗的中国妇女和妇联组织；用习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想指引中国妇女事业新航程；为强国建设、民族复兴勇担巾帼使命；在新的赶考路上推动妇联工作高质量发展；锻造适应中国式现代化要求的妇联组织。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大会以书面报告形式向代表提交了《中华全国妇女联合会章程（修正案）》草案，请代表审议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中共中央书记处书记，全国人大常委会、国务院、全国政协、中央军委有关领导同志出席会议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中央和国家机关有关部门、各人民团体、军队有关单位和北京市负责同志，各民主党派中央、全国工商联负责人和无党派人士代表，部分在京部级女领导干部和全国妇联老领导，首都各界妇女代表等参加开幕会。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 坚持党对工会的全面领导  组织动员亿万职工积极投身强国建设民族复兴伟业]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/24/nw.D110000renmrb_20231024_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月24日星期二&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-10/24/01/rmrb2023102401p19_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;10月23日，中共中央总书记、国家主席、中央军委主席习近平在中南海同中华全国总工会新一届领导班子成员集体谈话并发表重要讲话。&lt;BR/>;新华社记者鞠鹏摄&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;■我国工运事业是在党的领导下发展起来的，工会是党领导的工人阶级群众组织。坚持党对工会的全面领导，任何时候、任何情况下都不能动摇、不能偏离。要坚持全心全意依靠工人阶级的根本方针，充分调动广大职工群众的积极性、主动性、创造性，积极投身全面推进强国建设、民族复兴的伟大事业&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■党的十八大以来，在党中央坚强领导下，我国工人阶级在党和国家事业发展中发挥了主力军作用，工运事业取得历史性成就，工会工作实现全方位进步。过去5年，广大职工群众与党同心、跟党奋斗，在经济建设、科技创新、脱贫攻坚、乡村振兴、疫情防控、抢险救灾等重大工作中，展现了敢打硬仗、勇挑重担的时代风采。全国总工会和各级工会加强职工思想政治引领，推进产业工人队伍建设改革，保障劳动者权益，维护劳动领域政治安全，深化工会系统改革，政治性、先进性、群众性不断增强。对工人阶级作出的重大贡献，对工会工作取得的新成绩，党中央是充分肯定的。党中央对全国总工会新一届领导班子寄予殷切期望&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■坚持党的领导必须全面地、有效地贯彻落实到工会工作全过程和各方面。要坚定维护党中央权威和集中统一领导，始终在思想上政治上行动上同党中央保持高度一致。要坚持不懈用新时代中国特色社会主义思想凝心铸魂，持续推动理论武装走深走实，不断增强学习践行党的创新理论的思想自觉和行动自觉。要牢记“国之大者”，找准工会工作与党的中心任务的结合点、切入点、着力点，推动党中央决策部署在工会系统落实落地。要加强思想政治引领，做好职工思想政治工作，教育引导广大职工坚定不移听党话、跟党走，确保工人阶级始终是我们党最坚实最可靠的阶级基础&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■要把广大职工群众紧密团结在党的周围，为实现党的中心任务而团结奋斗。要围绕贯彻新发展理念、构建新发展格局、推动高质量发展，广泛深入开展各种形式的劳动和技能竞赛，激发广大职工的劳动热情、创造潜能，在各行各业各个领域充分发挥主力军作用。要大力弘扬劳模精神、劳动精神、工匠精神，发挥好劳模工匠示范引领作用，激励广大职工在辛勤劳动、诚实劳动、创造性劳动中成就梦想。要围绕深入实施科教兴国战略、人才强国战略、创新驱动发展战略，深化产业工人队伍建设改革，加快建设一支知识型、技能型、创新型产业工人大军，培养造就更多大国工匠和高技能人才&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■工人阶级和广大劳动群众是社会财富的主要创造者，推动全体人民共同富裕取得更为明显的实质性进展，首先要体现在亿万劳动者身上。工会作为职工利益的代表者和维护者，要认真履行维权服务基本职责，着力解决关系职工群众切身利益的实际问题，重视维护新就业形态劳动者的合法权益。要加强企事业单位民主管理，畅通职工诉求表达渠道，引导职工依法维护自身权益，推动构建和谐劳动关系&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■要继续深化工会改革和建设，牢固树立大抓基层的鲜明导向，夯实基层基础，激发基层活力，不断增强基层工会的引领力、组织力、服务力。要健全已有的组织基础，扩大工会组织覆盖面。要创新工作方式，努力为职工群众提供精准、贴心的服务。工会干部要践行党的群众路线，深入调查研究，及时了解职工所思所想所盼，不断增强服务职工本领，真心实意为职工说话办事。全国总工会要带头加强自身建设，当标杆、作表率，成为让党放心、让人民满意的模范政治机关&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■各级党委要加强对工会和工会工作的领导，选好配强工会领导班子，热情关心和严格要求工会干部，重视培养和使用工会干部。要注重发挥工会组织作用，及时研究职工群众和工会工作遇到的重要问题，支持工会创造性开展工作。各级政府要发挥好政府和工会联席会议作用，积极帮助工会解决职工群众的实际困难和问题&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新华社北京10月23日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;中共中央总书记、国家主席、中央军委主席习近平23日下午在中南海同中华全国总工会新一届领导班子成员集体谈话并发表重要讲话。习近平强调，我国工运事业是在党的领导下发展起来的，工会是党领导的工人阶级群众组织。坚持党对工会的全面领导，任何时候、任何情况下都不能动摇、不能偏离。要坚持全心全意依靠工人阶级的根本方针，充分调动广大职工群众的积极性、主动性、创造性，积极投身全面推进强国建设、民族复兴的伟大事业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中共中央政治局常委、中央书记处书记蔡奇参加集体谈话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平首先表示，党的十八大以来，在党中央坚强领导下，我国工人阶级在党和国家事业发展中发挥了主力军作用，工运事业取得历史性成就，工会工作实现全方位进步。过去5年，广大职工群众与党同心、跟党奋斗，在经济建设、科技创新、脱贫攻坚、乡村振兴、疫情防控、抢险救灾等重大工作中，展现了敢打硬仗、勇挑重担的时代风采。全国总工会和各级工会加强职工思想政治引领，推进产业工人队伍建设改革，保障劳动者权益，维护劳动领域政治安全，深化工会系统改革，政治性、先进性、群众性不断增强。对工人阶级作出的重大贡献，对工会工作取得的新成绩，党中央是充分肯定的。党中央对全国总工会新一届领导班子寄予殷切期望。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平强调，坚持党的领导必须全面地、有效地贯彻落实到工会工作全过程和各方面。要坚定维护党中央权威和集中统一领导，始终在思想上政治上行动上同党中央保持高度一致。要坚持不懈用新时代中国特色社会主义思想凝心铸魂，持续推动理论武装走深走实，不断增强学习践行党的创新理论的思想自觉和行动自觉。要牢记“国之大者”，找准工会工作与党的中心任务的结合点、切入点、着力点，推动党中央决策部署在工会系统落实落地。要加强思想政治引领，做好职工思想政治工作，教育引导广大职工坚定不移听党话、跟党走，确保工人阶级始终是我们党最坚实最可靠的阶级基础。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平指出，要把广大职工群众紧密团结在党的周围，为实现党的中心任务而团结奋斗。要围绕贯彻新发展理念、构建新发展格局、推动高质量发展，广泛深入开展各种形式的劳动和技能竞赛，激发广大职工的劳动热情、创造潜能，在各行各业各个领域充分发挥主力军作用。要大力弘扬劳模精神、劳动精神、工匠精神，发挥好劳模工匠示范引领作用，激励广大职工在辛勤劳动、诚实劳动、创造性劳动中成就梦想。要围绕深入实施科教兴国战略、人才强国战略、创新驱动发展战略，深化产业工人队伍建设改革，加快建设一支知识型、技能型、创新型产业工人大军，培养造就更多大国工匠和高技能人才。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平强调，工人阶级和广大劳动群众是社会财富的主要创造者，推动全体人民共同富裕取得更为明显的实质性进展，首先要体现在亿万劳动者身上。工会作为职工利益的代表者和维护者，要认真履行维权服务基本职责，着力解决关系职工群众切身利益的实际问题，重视维护新就业形态劳动者的合法权益。要加强企事业单位民主管理，畅通职工诉求表达渠道，引导职工依法维护自身权益，推动构建和谐劳动关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平指出，要继续深化工会改革和建设，牢固树立大抓基层的鲜明导向，夯实基层基础，激发基层活力，不断增强基层工会的引领力、组织力、服务力。要健全已有的组织基础，扩大工会组织覆盖面。要创新工作方式，努力为职工群众提供精准、贴心的服务。工会干部要践行党的群众路线，深入调查研究，及时了解职工所思所想所盼，不断增强服务职工本领，真心实意为职工说话办事。全国总工会要带头加强自身建设，当标杆、作表率，成为让党放心、让人民满意的模范政治机关。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平强调，各级党委要加强对工会和工会工作的领导，选好配强工会领导班子，热情关心和严格要求工会干部，重视培养和使用工会干部。要注重发挥工会组织作用，及时研究职工群众和工会工作遇到的重要问题，支持工会创造性开展工作。各级政府要发挥好政府和工会联席会议作用，积极帮助工会解决职工群众的实际困难和问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中华全国总工会主席王东明代表中华全国总工会新一届领导班子就中国工会十八大有关情况和未来5年工会工作安排作了汇报。全国总工会副主席徐留平、杨宇栋、高凤林作了发言。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;石泰峰、李干杰、李书磊、陈文清、刘金国、王小洪参加谈话。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 李强同日本首相岸田文雄就中日和平友好条约缔结45周年互致贺电]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/24/nw.D110000renmrb_20231024_5-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月24日星期二&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;新华社北京10月23日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;10月23日，国务院总理李强同日本首相岸田文雄就中日和平友好条约缔结45周年互致贺电。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李强表示，45年前，两国老一辈领导人和政治家作出缔结中日和平友好条约的战略决断。条约以法律形式为中日这两个邻国确立了和平共处、世代友好的大方向，强调反对霸权主义，成为两国关系发展进程中的重要里程碑。45年来，中日关系取得了来之不易的发展成果，增进了两国人民福祉，也为地区乃至世界的和平、稳定与繁荣作出积极贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;李强指出，中方愿同日方一道，重温缔约精神，牢牢把握两国关系正确发展方向，致力于构建契合新时代要求的中日关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;岸田文雄表示，日中和平友好条约明确写入发展两国间持久的和平友好关系。45年来，双方以此为指引，为日中关系发展奠定基础，维护和发展了两国和平友好关系。日中两国对地区乃至世界的和平与繁荣肩负重要责任，在广泛领域拥有合作潜力，双方共同致力于构筑建设性、稳定的日中关系具有重要意义。日方愿同中方重温条约精神，努力推动日中关系取得更大发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 加强低收入人口动态监测做好分层分类社会救助工作]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/24/nw.D110000renmrb_20231024_6-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月24日星期二&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;新华社北京10月23日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;近日，国务院办公厅转发民政部、教育部、财政部、人力资源社会保障部、住房城乡建设部、农业农村部、国家卫生健康委、应急管理部、国家医保局、中国残联《关于加强低收入人口动态监测做好分层分类社会救助工作的意见》（以下简称《意见》），部署进一步加强低收入人口动态监测，健全完善分层分类社会救助体系。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;《意见》提出，要以习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想为指导，全面贯彻党的二十大精神，落实党中央、国务院关于改革完善社会救助制度、实现巩固拓展脱贫攻坚成果同乡村振兴有效衔接的决策部署，健全以基本生活救助、专项社会救助、急难社会救助为主体，社会力量参与为补充的分层分类社会救助体系，实现救助资源统筹衔接、救助信息聚合共享、救助效率有效提升，让改革发展成果更多更公平惠及困难群众，切实兜住兜准兜好基本民生底线。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;《意见》确定了需要救助帮扶的低收入人口范围并按困难程度进行分层，包括低保对象、特困人员、防止返贫监测对象、低保边缘家庭成员、刚性支出困难家庭成员，以及其他困难人员。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;《意见》提出，各级民政部门要逐步完善低收入人口动态监测信息平台，加强低收入人口动态监测。通过多种方式完善低收入人口数据库；开展跨部门信息比对，实时监测发现低收入人口的困难风险，分类处置预警信息。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;《意见》明确，要根据低收入人口动态监测预警信息，按照低收入人口困难程度和困难类型，分层分类提供常态化救助帮扶。对符合低保、特困人员救助供养条件的低收入人口，低保边缘家庭中的重病重残等特殊困难人员，纳入基本生活救助范围；符合条件的，要给予医疗、教育、住房、就业、受灾人员救助等专项救助；对遭遇突发性、紧迫性、灾难性困难导致基本生活暂时出现严重困难的人员，取消户籍地、居住地申请限制，在急难发生地按规定通过临时救助或生活无着流浪乞讨人员救助，及时给予急难社会救助。同时，积极发展服务类社会救助，做好其他救助帮扶，鼓励开展慈善帮扶。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;《意见》提出，要强化党委领导、政府负责、民政牵头、部门协同、社会参与的工作机制。相关部门要各司其职、主动作为、协同配合、齐抓共管，打通数据壁垒、加强信息共享，加大政策宣传解读力度，共同做好低收入人口动态监测和分层分类社会救助工作。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 跨越永定河特大桥主体完工]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/24/nw.D110000renmrb_20231024_7-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月24日星期二&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231024/1698091419976_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;近日，国道109新线高速军庄互通立交主线桥成功合龙，标志着这座跨越永定河的特大桥主体完工。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;大桥位于北京市门头沟区，是国道109新线高速全线重点控制性工程。国道109新线高速建成后，将成为连接河北与京西地区的快速交通走廊。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;本报记者&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;雷&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;声摄&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Tue, 24 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>