<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 用心耕好这块“大试验田”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/06/nw.D110000renmrb_20231006_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, October 6, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Shanghai, the forefront of reform and opening up, is an important window for the world to observe China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the golden autumn season, the China (Shanghai) Pilot Free Trade Zone celebrates its tenth anniversary - September 29, 2013. With the important task of building the first free trade pilot zone in the country, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone start sailing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May 2014, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized during his inspection in Shanghai that the Shanghai Free Trade Pilot Zone is a large experimental field. It is necessary to sow good seeds, cultivate it carefully, manage it carefully, and look forward to a good harvest. The experience of cultivating improved seeds was widely spread. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Keeping in mind General Secretary Xi Jinping’s instructions, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone will cultivate this “big experimental field” carefully, take institutional innovation as its core task, and focus on forming institutional results that can be replicated and promoted. Benchmark the highest standards and levels, basically establish a basic institutional system and regulatory model that is connected with the prevailing rules of international investment and trade, accelerate the construction of a stress test system that is compatible with the open economic system, and continue to optimize marketization, rule of law, and international In order to optimize the business environment, institutional innovation achievements continue to emerge, the comprehensive effect of serving the national strategy is further released, and the role of economic growth pole is more clearly demonstrated. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The &quot;nursery&quot; has become a &quot;forest&quot;, and a basic institutional system and regulatory model that are connected with international investment and trade rules have been basically established&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shanghai has At the beginning of the construction of the pilot trade zone, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized that we should boldly venture, boldly experiment, and make independent changes to form a batch of replicable and promoteable new systems as soon as possible, and accelerate the promotion of investment and trade facilitation, efficient and convenient supervision, and standardized legal environment. First, try out the first batch of practical and effective results. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Good at being a &quot;nursery&quot; for institutional innovation, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone focuses on areas such as investment facilitation, trade facilitation, financial openness and innovation, and ongoing and post-event supervision, and has formed a number of basic and core systems in the past ten years. Innovation, the basic institutional system and regulatory model that are connected with the prevailing rules of international investment and trade have been basically established. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Based on the prevailing international economic and trade rules, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone launched a negative list for foreign investment after its establishment. The admission of foreign investment outside the list has been changed from the review system to the registration system. Today, the special management measures for foreign investment access in the Pilot Free Trade Zone have been reduced from the original 190 to 27, and the manufacturing items have been reduced to zero. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In July this year, Umicore Group, headquartered in Belgium, invested 15 million euros to establish a technology development company in the Waigaoqiao Free Trade Zone. &quot;The fewer the terms, the fewer the restrictions, the access for foreign investment will become wider and wider, and it will be more convenient for enterprises to invest.&quot; Looking back on the new company registration process, Zhang Kefang, head of the relevant departments of Umicore Group, said with emotion. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Automobile manufacturing, financial services, medical services, value-added telecommunications... With the shortening of the negative list, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone has implemented a number of national first-of-its-kind projects in 60 open fields, promoting &quot;quasi- The &quot;pre-entry national treatment plus negative list management system&quot; has matured and been written into the Foreign Investment Law, promoting the expansion of the negative list management model into cross-border service trade, market access and other fields. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Talking about the opening up of the financial sector, Lu Fang, CEO of J.P. Morgan Securities (China) Co., Ltd., said: “Foreign investment in the financial sector used to have shareholding restrictions. The Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone is leading the way. The forefront of financial openness.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The creation of a &quot;single window&quot; for international trade is a major innovation in the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone&#39;s promotion of trade facilitation. As the head of the planning department of Shanghai Yitong International Co., Ltd., Pan Xiaodong participated in the construction of the &quot;single window&quot; platform for international trade 10 years ago. &quot;Like the &#39;one-stop service&#39; in the field of international trade, the platform integrates customs, quarantine, maritime, and border inspection.&quot; Opening up information has greatly facilitated customs clearance trade.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Yuanchu Shuzhi Technology Development Group Co., Ltd., which is mainly engaged in import and export customs declaration and other businesses, is one of the earliest beneficiaries of the &quot;single window&quot; in international trade. &quot;In the past, import and export documents had to be filled out and recorded one by one, and the paper documents had to be sent to the relevant departments. It took at least two days to complete one order. With the &#39;single window&#39;, the tax form can be issued in a few minutes. &quot; Yang Xiaofeng, the relevant person in charge of the company, said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To date, the international trade &quot;single window&quot; platform has served more than 600,000 trading companies, supporting data processing accounting for more than a quarter of the country&#39;s goods trade volume. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strive to create a highland for innovation in the trade system, Shanghai has built the Yangshan Special Comprehensive Bonded Zone to high standards, the customs supervision operation process has been systematically reshaped, and declaration models, trade controls, collaborative management, etc. have been continuously reformed and innovated. Zhang Yi, Deputy Commissioner of Shanghai Customs, said that the special customs supervision area in the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone has established a supervision model of “relaxation on the first line, control on the second line, and freedom within the zone” that is common in international free trade parks. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The enterprise name notification and commitment system, the registered capital subscription system, the enterprise credit information disclosure system... the achievements of institutional innovation have changed from &quot;nursery&quot; to &quot;forest&quot;. Among the 302 free trade pilot zone institutional innovations replicated and promoted at the national level, nearly half were initiated in Shanghai or were simultaneously piloted. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Enhance global resource allocation capabilities and accelerate the construction of a stress testing system compatible with the open economic system&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping celebrated the 30th anniversary of the development and opening up of Pudong The conference pointed out that “it is necessary to better leverage the role of the Lingang New Area of ​​the China (Shanghai) Pilot Free Trade Zone, benchmark against the highest standards and levels, conduct greater stress testing, and take the lead in achieving breakthroughs in several key areas.” “Enhancement Global resource allocation capabilities serve to build a new development pattern.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Dare to venture, dare to try, and be the first to try. The Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone continues to enhance its global resource allocation capabilities and accelerate the establishment of pressures that are compatible with the open economic system. Test system. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the big screen of the Shanghai International Energy Trading Center, crude oil futures prices continue to jump and change. This has become the third largest crude oil futures market in the world. Over the past ten years, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone has significantly improved the level of internationalization of the financial market and launched my country&#39;s first internationally oriented financial asset trading platform - the Gold International Board. It has successively listed No. 20 TSR, low-sulfur fuel oil and crude oil options, accounting for the nation&#39;s total. For more than half of the international futures and options varieties, the international influence of &quot;Shanghai prices&quot; such as &quot;Shanghai gold&quot;, &quot;Shanghai oil&quot; and &quot;Shanghai copper&quot; is increasing day by day. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Walking into the warehouse of Tianwei Logistics Co., Ltd. in the Waigaoqiao Port Comprehensive Free Trade Zone, I saw forklifts scooping up copper plates and moving them to the open space outside the warehouse. &quot;This &#39;shovel and release&#39; is of extraordinary significance.&quot; Xu Yun, deputy general manager of the company, said, &quot;The warehouse where we are located is a trading warehouse in the international copper market. When moving from the warehouse to the outside, the copper plates will move from the futures&#39; It becomes spot goods, and domestic buyers can directly transport the copper plates here.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past, it was not so simple for buyers to pull goods. For international futures trading, goods must be transported to delivery warehouses in Busan, South Korea and other places; for domestic market transactions, goods must be transported to non-bonded warehouses. The change occurred in November 2014. The Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone, which was established more than a year ago, took the lead in launching a pilot program for cargo status classification supervision. Non-bonded goods can also be stored in the special customs supervision area of ​​the Pilot Free Trade Zone, and can be consolidated, distributed, managed and distributed together with bonded goods. &quot;Through this reform, global commodity transactions can be conducted in the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone, which is a real allocation of global resources.&quot; said Chen Yu, deputy director of the Finance and Financial Services Department of the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone Administration. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Finance is an important area for free trade experiments. &quot;In the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone and the Lingang New Area, innovative measures for financial opening-up have been continuously launched, and a large number of innovative financial systems have been put on trial,&quot; said Sun Hui, deputy director of the Shanghai Headquarters of the People&#39;s Bank of China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The free trade account integrating domestic and foreign currencies launched by the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone is a &quot;vanguard&quot; in cross-border RMB business innovation, with integrated domestic and foreign currency financial services such as cross-border settlement and cross-border financing. Function. So far, Shanghai has opened a total of 144,000 free trade accounts, handling cross-border settlements equivalent to RMB 142 trillion, with an average annual growth of 61%. The total domestic and foreign currency financing obtained by enterprises through free trade accounts is equivalent to RMB 2.8 trillion. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The free trade account has provided us with great help.” said Wang Cheng, deputy secretary of the Party Committee of Shanghai Zhenhua Heavy Industries (Group) Co., Ltd. Since starting to use free trade accounts in 2015, ZPMC has received a total of more than 52 billion yuan in overseas loans and enjoyed interest rate concessions to varying degrees, effectively reducing the company&#39;s capital cost pressure. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;International asset management institutions have also gathered in the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone. Zhang Lan, general manager of Schroders Fund Management (China) Co., Ltd., said: &quot;We are firmly optimistic about the Chinese market and will continue to bring various advantageous resources to Shanghai to explore new models for the development of asset management companies in China.&quot; Since 2020, Nine of the world&#39;s top ten asset management companies have settled in Pudong. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the establishment of the Lingang New Area, pilot projects such as the facilitation of cross-border RMB settlement for high-quality enterprises and the cross-border transfer of domestic trade financing assets will be further launched. In 2022, the country&#39;s first batch of high-level open pilots for cross-border trade and investment will be launched, with the cumulative business volume of the pilots exceeding US$40 billion. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Promote reform and development with high-level opening up, and continue to optimize the market-oriented, legal and international business environment&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Integrate expanding openness with reforming the system In combination, Shanghai systematically promotes the transformation of government functions, innovation of management models, optimization of operating mechanisms, and transformation of service methods, promotes reform and development with high-level opening up, and continues to optimize the market-oriented, legal and international business environment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The service hall of the Pudong New Area Administrative Service Center has witnessed countless stories of the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone promoting reform through opening up. &quot;In the same hall, the way of doing things has been revolutionized several times, and the company&#39;s experience is very different.&quot; said Huang Haixia, deputy director of the center. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In November 2017, Pudong New Area took the lead in piloting the &quot;single-window all-in-one service&quot; in Shanghai, establishing a comprehensive service model of &quot;one-window acceptance, classified approval, and one-stop issuance of certificates&quot;. For corporate services, you no longer need to go to multiple counters, you only need to find one window. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Focusing on the &quot;one license&quot; and &quot;one certificate&quot; of business licenses and business licenses, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone insists on pioneering trials. After the implementation of &quot;license first, then certificate&quot;, measures such as &quot;separation of licenses from licenses&quot;, &quot;one certificate for one industry&quot; and &quot;one certificate for culture, sports and tourism&quot; were successively introduced. Through digital means, measures that are convenient for the people and enterprises, such as &quot;intelligent assistance&quot;, &quot;direct assistance&quot; and &quot;no need to apply&quot;, have also been introduced one after another. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Lawson Convenience Store just opened a new store in Pudong, and the procedures went smoothly.” Jin Ye, deputy director of the business risk management and control department of Shanghai Lawson Convenience Co., Ltd. said, “In the past, it took a long time to go through the procedures to open a store. In the past two months, it now only takes two or three days.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Pilot Free Trade Zone is the forefront of Shanghai’s efforts to transform government functions and optimize the business environment.” Ruan Qing, deputy director of the Shanghai Municipal Development and Reform Commission Said that Shanghai has delegated more than 100 municipal administrative approval items to the Pudong New Area government. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As of the end of September this year, the Shanghai Municipal People’s Congress Standing Committee has issued 18 Pudong New Area regulations and 2 local regulations and Pudong special chapters. The Pudong New Area People’s Congress Standing Committee and the government have issued 19 management measures. Shanghai Free Trade Pilot The legal guarantee system for district construction has been continuously improved. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In response to the needs of industrial development, Shanghai continues to increase institutional supply and change supervision methods. Chen Li, Chairman and CEO of Hualing Pharmaceutical Technology (Shanghai) Co., Ltd., said: “With the drug marketing authorization holder system, R&amp;D-based biopharmaceutical companies can entrust pharmaceutical companies to produce new drugs developed by themselves, which not only accelerates the industrialization process , and also created conditions for focusing on the research and development of more new drugs.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the implementation of the drug marketing authorization holder system, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone achieved my country’s first independently developed tumor treatment drug approved for marketing, 11 Each Class I new drug is launched through OEM production. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ten years of hard work have yielded fruitful results. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As of the end of 2022, there have been more than 84,000 newly registered companies in the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone, more than 14,000 new foreign-invested projects, and a total of US$58.6 billion in foreign investment. In 2022, Pudong New Area will achieve a regional GDP of 1.6 trillion yuan, 2.5 times that of 2013. Since its establishment, the Lingang New Area&#39;s GDP has grown at an average annual rate of 21.2%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China’s free trade pilot zones have grown from a single flower to a garden filled with hundreds of flowers. The 21 free trade pilot zones across the country and the Hainan Free Trade Port have exerted the ‘head goose’ effect of institutional innovation and created an open development environment. A vivid example.&quot; said Zhu Zhisong, member of the Standing Committee of the Shanghai Municipal Party Committee, Secretary of the Pudong New Area Party Committee, and Director of the Management Committee of the China (Shanghai) Pilot Free Trade Zone. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On September 20 this year, at the theme forum for the 10th anniversary of the construction of the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone, Chen Jining, Secretary of the Shanghai Municipal Party Committee, said, “We will expand our opening up with an open mind and innovate with the spirit of daring to be the first. , demonstrate inclusiveness with an integrated and win-win ecology, and build the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone and Lingang New Area better.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After ten years, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone has a good scenery and a high level of external openness. The new picture will be opened and spread quickly. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 05:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 全国秋粮收获已超四成（新数据 新看点）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/06/nw.D110000renmrb_20231006_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, October 6, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, October 5th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Gao Yuncai) The Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs’ agricultural sentiment on October 5th According to statistics, 42.2% of the national autumn grain harvest has been harvested. In terms of crops, the harvest of medium-sized rice exceeds 50%, the harvest of corn exceeds 40%, and the harvest of soybeans nearly 40%. Moisture conditions are relatively good in most winter wheat and winter rape production areas. Winter wheat sowing has exceeded 20% and winter rapeseed nearly 50% has been sown in the northwest. Winter rapeseed has been sown more than 20% in the middle and lower reaches of the Yangtze River. Sowing has begun in Huang-Huai-Hai and southwest regions. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Thousand-layered waves of rice paddies, harvesters roaring in the vast fields, and scenes of harvest everywhere in China. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“Among the 850 acres of land I transferred, 500 acres were selected as provincial intensive farming demonstration fields. The green production method allowed me to increase my output by 100 pounds per mu this year!” Qiaodong, Xuqiao Town, Taihu County, Anhui Province Liu Xiaobao, a large farmer in the village, said. Liu Chun, chairman of the Northeast Paddy Modern Agricultural Machinery Professional Cooperative in Fujin City, Heilongjiang Province, said that rice transplanting is done scientifically and densely, and the harvest is aided by science and technology. &quot;The ears of rice are big and the grains are full. You can hold a handful in your hand and it&#39;s heavy.&quot;&lt;/P >;&lt;P>;All regions and departments strictly implement the party and government&#39;s shared responsibilities for food security, stabilize area, increase yield, and increase efficiency, implement the strategy of storing grain in the ground and storing grain in technology in the fields, innovate agricultural management methods, and promote the planting industry With structural adjustment, a bumper harvest of grain production across the country is expected. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 05:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 文旅消费热  内需动力强（走进市场看信心·聚焦中秋国庆假期）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/06/nw.D110000renmrb_20231006_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, October 6, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231006/1696534474128_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;During the festival, every day in Lizhuang Ancient Town, Yibin City, Sichuan The passenger flow exceeds 40,000. The picture shows on October 5th, the oar boat sailed across the water, integrating with the houses, small bridges and green mountains, forming a simple and beautiful picture. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Wang Yu (Photo China)&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;On the sixth day of the Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday, article The travel market continues to be hot. In Qinhuangdao, Hebei, you can go to the foot of the Great Wall to enjoy the spectacular scenery and feel the rich culture; in Xinyang, Henan, you can walk into the beautiful countryside to enjoy the autumn scenery, taste the charm and fruits of autumn; in Haikou, Hainan, you can stroll through tourist resorts and tourist leisure streets. Watch performances, taste delicious food, buy good things, and enjoy the &quot;one-stop&quot; cultural, business, tourism and sports consumption experience...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cultural and tourism consumption is an effective way to expand domestic demand, and it is also an important carrier to meet the people&#39;s needs for a better life. During this Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday, my country&#39;s demand for culture, leisure, and tourism has been intensively released. Culture and tourism have been deeply integrated. New business formats, new models, and new supplies are constantly emerging, making tourism a popular choice. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The data center of the Ministry of Culture and Tourism predicts that the popularity of tourism during the Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday will reach a new high. Domestic tourism trips are expected to reach 896 million, a year-on-year increase of 86%, and domestic tourism revenue will be 782.5 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase. 138%. The boom in cultural and tourism consumption during holidays reflects the vitality and huge potential of the consumer market and highlights the strong domestic demand driving force of the Chinese economy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The recovery of cultural tourism industry is accelerating, and bookings for multiple businesses are booming&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It’s very fun for adults and children to play together.” Newly opened in Shenzhen Happy Valley Theme Park At the &quot;Mini World·Adventure Mountain&quot; amusement area, Wang Han, a tourist who has just experienced the catapult roller coaster project, said. Various buildings and colorful decorations attract many tourists to take photos, and various immersive themed amusement equipment provide people with diverse experiences. In the three days before the holiday, Shenzhen Happy Valley received nearly 100,000 tourists. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Feel the charm of intangible cultural heritage during the journey, and new experiences bring new gains.” said Li Shan, a tourist from Sichuan who was experiencing the intangible cultural heritage handicrafts of round fans in the Longhu Mountain Scenic Area in Jiangxi. Longhu Mountain Scenic Area combines intangible cultural heritage and innovates the supply of holiday products to meet the ever-escalating cultural and tourism consumption needs. It launches on-site handicrafts such as round fans and lanterns, as well as acrobatic performances such as bowl-topping and vat-topping, allowing tourists to experience the excellent traditional Chinese culture up close. Charm. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This holiday is both for leisure and entertainment and for physical fitness. This holiday is very meaningful.” said Han Fei, a tourist who had just skied down the ski slopes at the Guangzhou Rexue Miracle Indoor Ski Resort. With the in-depth integration of culture, tourism and sports, &quot;sports + tourism&quot; formats such as skiing have emerged. During the Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday, this ski resort held theme night skiing, snow sports games and other activities, and the number of tourists it received increased rapidly year-on-year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the beginning of this year, the culture and tourism industry has accelerated its recovery, and cultural and tourism consumer demand has been intensively released during the Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holidays. Data from the data center of the Ministry of Culture and Tourism shows that in the first three days of the holiday, a total of 395 million domestic tourism trips were made, a year-on-year increase of 75.8%; domestic tourism revenue was 342.24 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 125.3%. Booking data from major platforms show that products and services such as scenic sightseeing, urban leisure, and rural tourism have received high attention, and bookings for hotels, transportation, scenic spots, and other businesses continue to be hot. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Innovate market supply and stimulate new consumption vitality&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Starting from Hubei Qianjiang Expressway Service Area, all the way to Eco Lobster City, Chu Qian Village Yun Farm, Moling Village, sharing the joy of harvest with shrimps and rice... During the Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday, Sun Yue, a tourist from Hunan, embarked on a journey to the &quot;Hometown of Shrimps and Rice&quot; in Qianjiang, Hubei Province. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This route is one of the 149 &quot;orange-yellow-orange-green&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;rural scenic spots&quot; national rural tourism boutique routes launched by the Ministry of Culture and Tourism. This holiday season, the Ministry of Culture and Tourism focuses on the rural tourism market and launches high-quality rural tourism routes, inviting tourists to experience the diverse and integrated rural tourism industry. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Walking into the &quot;Chang&#39;an Twelve Hours&quot; themed neighborhood in Qujiang New District, Xi&#39;an, Shaanxi Province, a strong cultural atmosphere hits your face. On the singing platform, actors vividly restored the famous Tang Dynasty painting &quot;Lady with Hairpins&quot;; among the green mountains and rivers, tourists and ancients &quot;dialogued through the air&quot;... As you walked and watched, the wonderful interpretation of history and culture gradually became better. The first batch of 24 national smart tourism immersive experience new space cultivation pilot projects was officially awarded not long ago and has become a popular destination for many tourists. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“My child has been interested in the history of the steel industry since he was a child, and I took him here to experience it during the holidays.” said Huang Yang, a tourist visiting the Wuhan Iron and Steel Cultural Tourism Zone within the Wuhan Iron and Steel Factory in Hubei Province. Industrial tourism, which focuses on industrial sites, factory features, production processes, labor scenes, etc., has become a new tourism format popular with tourists. Recently, the Ministry of Culture and Tourism announced a new batch of industrial tourism demonstration bases, providing tourists with more choices for holiday travel. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The market boom is due to new supply. During the Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday, many scenic spots and cultural tourism-related companies closely follow the new trend of cultural tourism consumption upgrades, create new cultural tourism products, new business formats, and new scenes, launch more high-quality products and services that meet the needs of tourists, and stimulate a stronger cultural tourism market. development motivation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The relevant person in charge of the Ministry of Culture and Tourism introduced that in order to enrich the supply of cultural and tourism products, relevant departments and localities have released a list of national tourism performing arts products, and launched a group of culturally rich, artistically exquisite, well-received and popular performances. Tourism performing arts boutique projects provide more special tourism products suitable for family travel. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Service quality continues to improve, and consumption momentum continues to be released&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Although there are many tourists, they are in order and feel good.” At the entrance to the Temple of Heaven Park Scenic Area in Beijing , said Zhao Ze, a tourist who was queuing up to enter the scenic spot. During the Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday, civilized tourism has become a conscious behavior for more and more tourists. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Travel is a happy industry. During this holiday season, all local departments have done their best to optimize the tourist experience and continuously improve service quality to make people travel more comfortable. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before the holidays, the Ministry of Culture and Tourism issued relevant reminders to remind tourists to arrange their itineraries reasonably, understand the weather, transportation and tourist attraction openings and ticket reservation measures in advance, and plan travel routes and travel routes reasonably. Time, safe, healthy, civilized and green travel. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In view of the peak travel period, the Ministry of Culture and Tourism has made arrangements in advance for reservations, reception, safety and other aspects of holiday tourist attractions, guiding scenic spots to optimize reservation measures, implement scientific management, and achieve the unity of principle and flexibility. Scientifically set up online and offline ticket purchase and reservation channels, actively adopt new technologies and new methods, unblock reservation channels for scenic spots, museums and other places, simplify reservation procedures, and improve the convenience of reservation operations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the holidays, various local departments focused on key areas of the cultural tourism market and stepped up enforcement inspections of illegal and illegal business activities to ensure the safety, stability and orderliness of the holiday market. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The continued release of cultural tourism consumption momentum will surely further boost market confidence and better leverage the fundamental role of consumption in driving economic growth. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 05:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 服务千家万户  守护平安幸福]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/06/nw.D110000renmrb_20231006_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, October 6, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out: &quot;Happiness is the result of struggle, and struggle itself is a kind of happiness.&quot;&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;During the National Day holiday, many workers stick to their jobs and work hard at the grassroots level to serve thousands of households and protect safety and happiness. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Maintaining quality, quantity and progress&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the holidays, workers roll up their sleeves, sweat and devote themselves to project construction to ensure quality, quantity and progress. Don’t miss the deadline. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On October 5, at the construction site of the Hebei Airlines Daxing Airport Operation Base Project in Langfang Airport Economic Zone, workers were carrying out indoor wall plastering, roof waterproofing construction, curtain wall keel installation and other operations. &quot;This holiday, more than 300 builders stayed on the front line to ensure that the construction was at full production.&quot; Li Zhihui, project manager of Hebei Airlines Daxing Airport Operation Base of China Construction Installation Company, said, &quot;The union arranged dinners and holiday condolences, which made us feel very warm .&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the National Day holiday, the construction of Longcheng Expressway in Longsheng Autonomous County of Guangxi Province continued non-stop. With iron arms waving and machines rumbling, workers tied steel bars and transportation vehicles and road rollers shuttled back and forth. More than 3,000 highway builders are working hard at their jobs to ensure quality, meet deadlines, and make every effort to speed up construction operations to ensure the smooth completion of construction tasks at each node. Construction technician Chen Baizhou said: &quot;Working hard with the workers on the construction site, this festival is fulfilling and meaningful!&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On October 5, Wu Xiaofeng, an electrician of the Southwest Company of China Construction Seventh Engineering Bureau, packed up the test pen , wire cutters, etc., arrived at the construction site of Yunnan Cancer Hospital-related projects early. &quot;We will follow the construction needs and work hard to ensure the progress of the project.&quot; At the construction site, nearly 100 workers were working at the same time. Quality inspector Yang Linhua pointed to a steel cage Said: &quot;This is the 1,478th engineering pile steel cage that I have inspected and accepted in this project, and it is also the last steel cage for pile foundation construction. I am on duty during the holidays and contribute to the construction of people&#39;s livelihood projects.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gao Yuan The ultraviolet rays at the construction site are strong and the temperature difference between day and night is more than 20 degrees Celsius. At the construction site of the eighth section of the Lhasa-Shigatse Airport section of the Ya&#39;an-Yecheng Expressway (Lhasa-Japan Expressway) constructed by the China Railway 21st Bureau, more than 600 workers were not afraid of hard work and worked hard on the front line. On October 1, the longest tunnel on the Lari Expressway, the Padangshan Tunnel, was fully completed. &quot;The next step is to carry out the construction of the tunnel invert and ancillary facilities. Before pouring the concrete, use a 3D scanner to conduct cross-section scanning and measurement to ensure that the thickness of the reinforced concrete meets the requirements. We must not relax in quality and safety.&quot; Party Party of the Project Department Li Enhui, deputy secretary of the branch, said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sincerely for the people&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the National Day holiday, public security officers, medical staff, community workers, etc. stayed at their posts to protect the safety and happiness of the people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At noon on October 5, the number of visitors to the Shanghai Zoo reached its peak. The Changning Branch of the Shanghai Public Security Bureau communicated with the park in advance to improve the guidance plan. On the same day, the police conducted foot patrols and video patrols from the command room to improve response speed. &quot;The police and auxiliary police on duty work closely with the staff in the park and rely on the mobile police workstation to guide the passenger flow in a timely manner.&quot; said Wang Yunan, a police officer from Chengjiaqiao Police Station of Changning Public Security Bureau. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the National Day holiday, patients continued to come to the emergency department of Lanzhou University First Hospital. Emergency department medical staff stayed at their posts and arranged staff to be on duty 24 hours a day to ensure that patients received timely treatment. At the No. 1 Social Welfare Institute in Changsha City, Hunan Province, frontline medical staff are on duty around the clock and conduct regular ward rounds twice a day to protect the health of hundreds of elderly people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The holiday is coming to an end. In Jinhuayuan Street, Guanshanhu District, Guiyang City, Guizhou Province, Xie Yi, the head of the grid service center, still sticks to his post, dispatching and handling the &quot;12345 Guiyang Convenient Government Service Platform&quot; case as soon as possible . Road damage, noise from renovations... problems reported by citizens are echoed in every case. &quot;We have handled more than 70 cases. People&#39;s livelihood is no small matter, and it must be handled with heart and emotion.&quot; Xie Yi said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In rural areas, grassroots cadres go deep into the fields and work hard to ensure that the villagers can have a good harvest. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the National Day holiday, in Shawan Village, Shangqing Town, Yingtan City, Jiangxi Province, Wu Jianbo, the village party secretary, always ran to the taro field to check the water storage in the ditches. &quot;The soil must be kept moist, otherwise the taro will not taste good.&quot; Wu Jianbo introduced new taro varieties from other places this year and planted 260 acres in the village. &quot;It is expected that the yield will increase by 40%. The villagers are looking forward to it, and they must take care of the last step.&quot; &quot;After checking the taro, Wu Jianbo rushed to the office again and energetically carried out live broadcasts to help the villagers sell honey. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the morning of October 4, Wu Xiaodong, the first secretary of Hanhe Village, Daqiao Town, Xihe County, Longnan City, Gansu Province, came to the village’s warehouse to check the status of the tarps for storage materials. When he found that some peppercorns were damp, he immediately organized everyone to dry them. &quot;This year, pepper and rapeseed oil in the village are very popular. During the National Day holiday, agricultural products have been sold for more than 3 million yuan.&quot; Wu Xiaodong said, &quot;The folks have a good harvest, and our work is worth it.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>; Keep up the good work&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This holiday season, people from all walks of life are persevering and struggling. &quot;Keep up the good work and make contributions&quot; and &quot;I am responsible for the rejuvenation of a strong country&quot; are the aspirations of many people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On a 60-meter-long working surface in Tianjin Binhai New Area, an excavator is performing excavation operations. This project is an electric power relocation project implemented for the construction of Xingang Expressway. Pan Guang, project manager of State Grid Tianjin Construction Company, said: &quot;Workers stick to their posts during the holidays, control safety and quality, and strive to build demonstration projects.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some projects of the Hangzhou Asian Games are competing at the Jinhua Sports Center in Zhejiang . Before each game, staff from State Grid Zhejiang Electric Power will conduct detailed inspections of the venue&#39;s power equipment. Shu Chengye, captain of the Asian Games Power Supply Youth Commando of Jinhua Sports Center, said, &quot;We maintain good working conditions and strive to provide reliable power support for the venues.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Panbei Village, Potou District, Zhanjiang City, Guangdong , the former site where the People&#39;s Anti-Japanese Liberation Army was founded on South Road, many parents came with their children to follow the red footprints. The lecturer Huang Anqin combined the local folk culture and added vivid expressions to the explanations to attract visitors to listen attentively. &quot;It is very meaningful to tell the red story to everyone during the National Day holiday.&quot; Huang Anqin said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the Mu Us Sandy Land in northern Shaanxi, at the 1,000-kilovolt UHV Hengshan Switching Station, the machines kept running. Station director Li Han and his colleagues checked various equipment with inspection cards and thermometers. In order to ensure normal power supply during the festival, Li Han and his colleagues strengthened inspection measures and strived to eliminate faults as soon as possible. &quot;It is my responsibility to help energy cross mountains and rivers and let everyone use satisfactory and green electricity,&quot; Li Han said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Comprehensive reporting by our reporters Shi Ziqiang, Pang Geping, Yang Wenming, Yuan Quan, Ju Yunpeng, Wang Yunna, Zhao Shuaijie, Su Bin, Zhou Huan, Wang Jintao, Wu Shaomin, Jin Bo, Dou Hao, Luo Aihua, Gong Shijian ; Coordinator of this issue: Liu Nian)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 05:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 以青春风采书写亚运精彩（今日谈）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/06/nw.D110000renmrb_20231006_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, October 6, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;13-year-old street skateboarding champion Cui Chenxi, 17-year-old shooting champion Huang Yuting, 19-year-old men&#39;s 100-meter freestyle Champion Pan Zhanle, 22-year-old table tennis champion Sun Yingsha... The Hangzhou Asian Games is in full swing. In the past few days, a group of young athletes have been fighting bravely and achieving great results. With vigorous vitality and courage to fight, they have competed in the Asian Games. It shows the bright youthful style and bursts out the heroic youthful passion. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;China will be strong if young people and young people are strong, and if sports are strong, China will be strong. Among the 886 participants in the Chinese sports delegation at the Hangzhou Asian Games, 630 are participating in the Asian Games for the first time, and the vast majority are in their prime. From skateboards that jump off the ground, to shooting that is both stable and accurate, from gymnastics with light posture, to martial arts with smooth movements... Whether it is an event with traditional advantages or a fiercely competitive field, young athletes persevere and struggle in the struggle. Growing up in the game reflects the superb competitive level and the positive spiritual strength. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: &quot;Only youth that has fought passionately, only youth that has fought tenaciously, and only youth that has made contributions to the people will leave a legacy that is fulfilling, warm, lasting, and without regrets.&quot; Memories of youth.&quot; Strive to surpass yourself and strive to achieve your dreams. If you inspire youth with a fighting attitude, live up to the times and live up to your years, you will surely be able to fly your life dreams in the fiery youth and achieve a splendid career in the hard-working youth. The excitement of the Hangzhou Asian Games continues, and we look forward to more emerging youth forces writing more exciting chapters. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 05:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 桂花香甜产业兴（点赞新时代）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/06/nw.D110000renmrb_20231006_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, October 6, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;During the festival, the sweet-scented osmanthus is blooming, and the fragrance of the flowers fills the entire city of Guilin. On the branches, clusters of sweet-scented osmanthus are golden and dense. When the bamboo pole is knocked, they fall rustlingly. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;On October 4, Yang Zhihui, a girl born in the 1990s, gathered flowers under a tree. &quot;Although the osmanthus is small, the industry is huge!&quot;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Yang Zhihui is from Guilin City, Guangxi. A native of Zhongyong Town, Gui District, he is also the general manager of Guilin Qingluofang Food Co., Ltd. He is an e-commerce company and sells sweet-scented osmanthus. Despite her young age, she is well-known in the local area: the company&#39;s annual operating income exceeds 8 million yuan, driving 1,800 farmers to increase their income. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;During the National Day holiday, the company’s order volume was gratifying. Yang Zhihui is busy ensuring production, theme marketing, and channel promotion... &quot;The number of orders in one day is three times that of previous years! The flowers are more abundant these days, and everyone is busy.&quot;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Yang Zhihui Hui and Osmanthus have a long-standing relationship. As a child, Yang Zhihui most looked forward to the blooming of sweet-scented osmanthus. Sugar osmanthus, osmanthus cake, osmanthus wine... My mother is very skillful, and the dried osmanthus will always turn into various foods in her hands, which are sweet and fragrant. &quot;My parents are busy away from home all year round, and they only return home when the sweet-scented osmanthus is ripe.&quot; Yang Zhihui said, &quot;At that time, I didn&#39;t understand what the festival was. I only knew that people reunited when the sweet-scented osmanthus bloomed.&quot;&lt;/P>;&lt;P >;In my junior year of college, e-commerce was developing rapidly. Yang Zhihui had a sudden idea to open an online store to sell sweet-scented osmanthus. There were only a dozen orders a day, but she saved up and actually made some money. In 2017, Yang Zhihui gave up her job as a designer and decided to return to her hometown to start a business. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;What industry do you do? &quot;Osmanthus!&quot; Yang Zhihui did not hesitate. &quot;Let&#39;s do it together!&quot; Yang Zhihui&#39;s husband Qin Changsheng was very supportive. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Collecting flowers, baking, transporting, packaging... the young couple is as busy as clockwork. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>; &quot;Osmanthus fragrans is afraid of both rain and sunshine. The scent of osmanthus is weak when it rains, and it wilts easily when the sun is too bright.&quot; Yang Zhihui introduced, &quot;It takes time to harvest osmanthus, often late at night or early in the morning. In the morning You cannot lay flowers after 9 o&#39;clock.&quot; Under sunlight, the flowers will oxidize and turn black, and must be dried within two hours. 6 pounds of fresh flowers can only produce 1 pound of dried flowers. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In 2021, Yang Zhihui took the lead in organizing the &quot;Osmanthus Playing Competition&quot; in Zhongyong Town. The more flowers the villagers planted, the more she bought. The purchase price of each catty of flowers was more than 10 yuan. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Wei Yong from Jinling Village, Zhongyong Town won the first place that year. &quot;You have to cut the sweet-scented osmanthus diagonally, otherwise it won&#39;t bloom the next year. In a good year, a sweet-scented osmanthus tree with a diameter of 20 centimeters can produce more than 20 kilograms of flowers.&quot; Wei Yong said that he now has 130 sweet-scented osmanthus trees at home, which produce sweet-scented osmanthus every year. 3,000 pounds, no need to go out to work. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“It is a meaningful thing to bring everyone together to increase their income.” Yang Zhihui can now purchase 480,000 kilograms of fresh osmanthus from Lingui, Yangshuo, Lingchuan and other counties a year.桂花，还有桂花茶、桂花蜜酱等，网销全国。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;如今，临桂区共种植桂花树约10万亩，相关产业带动就业1万余人次。 “近年来，我们每年在桂花盛开时组织开展桂花文化旅游季活动，邀游客一同赏桂花、游美景、观比赛、品美食，积极推介桂花系列产品，助力乡村振兴。”临桂区区长何兵说。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“嘀嘀嘀……”阳志慧公司里的快递单打印机几乎没停过。阳志慧说：“未来，我打算继续添置设备，让桂花香从桂林飘向全国，靠奋斗把日子过得更甜。”&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 05:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 直播带货干劲足（点赞新时代）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/06/nw.D110000renmrb_20231006_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月06日星期五&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;10月3日，重庆市璧山区大路街道团坝村的一家生态农庄里，窗户上贴了喜字，彩灯点缀其间。门前草坪的桌上，摆着糖果和婚纱照，爱心形状的鲜花之门迎来了一对新人。梁范祥和妻子赵梅的婚礼开始了。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“梁老弟，祝贺哟！新婚快乐！”附近的村民都来道贺。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“来，吃喜糖！”新郎梁范祥招呼着宾客。从2015年参军到2020年退伍，5年的军旅时光把梁范祥一张娃娃脸磨砺得棱角分明。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;从小生长在农村，无论是在部队还是退伍后，梁范祥都有浓浓的思乡情。退伍后，梁范祥有很多去外地工作的机会，但他还是决定回到家乡。不仅是想家，更多思考的是，“总要为乡亲们做些什么。”&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;2021年，梁范祥接触到电商直播，动了心思：“庄稼地里有新鲜的红薯、土豆，果园里有大家喜欢的香甜水果，如果帮助乡亲们带货，不知道能不能成？”&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;说干就干。可第一次面对镜头，梁范祥话都说不利索，整场直播只卖出去两单。“还是亲戚帮忙买的。”回忆往事，梁范祥不好意思地笑了。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;梁范祥并没有气馁，而是重整旗鼓。选产品、练口才、学剪辑……半年后，梁范祥不仅可以自信地面对镜头直播，还一点点积累起数万粉丝。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;通过直播带货，梁范祥帮助周边镇街生产的甜玉米、花椒等农产品打开了市场，2022年销售额约500万元。他还开设课程帮助农民提升参与直播电商的能力。如何使用手机剪视频，怎样拍摄瓜果蔬菜，视频文案如何准备……梁范祥常讲得口干舌燥，却不觉得累。在他的带领下，一些村民的直播也搞得有声有色，有些人的粉丝达到十几万。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;在璧山区退役军人事务局和区商务委的帮助下，梁范祥申请到贷款，投资了如今举办婚礼的生态农庄。“这边是带货直播间，那里是亲子游乐场，经过这片果园后，就是我们打造的民宿……”梁范祥边走边介绍。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;与发展同行，也与幸福结缘。梁范祥和赵梅是在直播带货的过程中走到一起的。两人一起挑选农产品，一起架起了农户和市场之间的桥梁。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;梁范祥的父亲梁老伯常给儿子帮忙。“娃娃有出息，在部队长了见识、磨砺了心性，回到家乡，和乡亲们一起干劲十足咧！”梁老伯说，生态农庄刚开业没多久就生意兴隆，“我们还打算在这里设立农产品展示台，让游客带走更多山里货。”&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;在璧山，电商直播的队伍越来越壮大。越来越多退伍军人、大学生加入助农事业中。“报纸上天天讲乡村振兴，国家给了好政策，我们绝不能掉队呀。”梁范祥说。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 05:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 为“一带一路”提供高水平开放平台、高能级服务支撑（共建“一带一路”·权威访谈）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/06/nw.D110000renmrb_20231006_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月06日星期五&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;在共建“一带一路”国家投资超过300亿美元，承包工程合同额超过800亿美元，货物贸易总额超过1.5万亿美元……十年来，上海服务“一带一路”建设成效卓著。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上海市副市长华源近日接受新华社记者专访表示，上海始终遵循国家“一带一路”建设统一部署，围绕标志性工程和重大战略平台精雕细琢，全力实施好一批示范性项目，为高质量共建“一带一路”贡献“上海力量”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;推动国际经贸投资“双向奔赴”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在巴基斯坦，上海电气运营的塔尔煤田煤电一体化项目保障当地400万户家庭用电需求；上港集团投资建设的以色列海法新港码头一期项目是当地60年来建成的首个新码头；上海企业建设的中国印尼综合产业园区青山园区为当地创造直接就业岗位超6.7万个……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;经贸投资合作是共建“一带一路”的重要内容。上海积极推动国际经贸投资“双向奔赴”和“共商共建共享”，从2013年到2023年6月，上海对共建“一带一路”国家累计投资336.73亿美元，累计承包工程合同额811.25亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“上海把参与高质量共建&#39;一带一路&#39;作为打造国内大循环中心节点和国内国际双循环战略链接的重要内容，立足城市功能优势，取得了一系列标志性、首创性、示范性成果。”华源说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至2023年上半年，上海的跨国公司地区总部、外资研发中心累计分别达到922家和544家。落实经贸合作协议，上海积极推动共建“一带一路”国家企业来沪投资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华源介绍，在深化经贸投资合作中，上海不断创新方式方法：设立上海市“一带一路”综合服务中心，开发建设服务“一带一路”的“丝路e启行”小程序，推动政府、企业、涉企服务资源三方联动等。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“软硬联通”铺就合作之路&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着中国期货市场逐步扩大开放，一批“上海价格”走向海外，见证上海与共建“一带一路”国家的高水平互联互通。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;统计显示，2022年，位于上海的人民币跨境支付系统（CIPS）新增59家共建“一带一路”国家参与者。在上海证券交易所，有超过千家境外机构主体通过直接投资渠道和“债券通”渠道进入银行间债券市场，其中包括来自新加坡、马来西亚、泰国、阿联酋和菲律宾等共建“一带一路”国家的163家境外机构主体，持债规模近万亿元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“上海以金融为重点全面提升专业服务能力，为&#39;一带一路&#39;建设提供高能级服务支撑。”华源说，上海持续推进金融市场双向开放，支持“上海金”“上海油”“上海铜”等基准价格在“一带一路”金融市场使用，打造“一带一路”投融资中心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了规则标准“软联通”，上海还依托海港、空港、数字港，持续推动基础设施“硬联通”。上海港已成为国内集装箱航线最多、航班最密、覆盖面最广的港口，与共建“一带一路”国家之间的海运航班数、集装箱吞吐量逐年增长；中欧班列—上海号初步实现中欧线、中俄线、中亚线去程和回程全覆盖；积极探索建设“丝路电商”合作先行区，澳大利亚、智利、瓦努阿图、萨摩亚等“丝路电商”国家馆已入驻。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华源表示，未来上海将充分发挥全球经贸联系广泛、国际平台众多、营商环境一流的优势，实现上海国际经济、金融、贸易、航运、科创中心“五个中心”建设与政策沟通、设施联通、贸易畅通、资金融通、民心相通“五通”双向赋能，促进“一带一路”建设与长三角一体化发展、长江经济带发展等重大国家战略深度融合。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;持续强化重大开放平台建设&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上海自贸试验区持续强化服务“一带一路”功能，推动共建“一带一路”国家检验检测结果采信与认证机构互认；在上海举办的中国国际进口博览会成为开放合作的重要平台和全球共享的国际公共产品，五届进博会累计引进各类展品21.4万种，2000多项新产品、新技术、新服务加速应用……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华源介绍，十年来，服务“一带一路”建设，上海聚焦重大平台牵引，打造了一批多元互动、广聚共识的核心载体。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，上海充分发挥科技人文交流平台在扩大开放中的作用。作为上海国际电影节的重要板块，“一带一路”电影周用电影开启对话，每年汇聚“一带一路”国家电影展映、联动。数据显示，“一带一路”电影节联盟已扩展到48个国家和地区的55个机构电影节。2017年在上海成立的丝绸之路国际艺术节联盟，汇聚了来自49个国家和地区的178家成员机构，达成相关合作意向200多个。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;青年是未来的希望。上海市在全国率先设立“一带一路”青年科学家交流项目，已吸引40余个共建“一带一路”国家的优秀青年科学家来沪开展科研工作，形成一批重要技术成果并在境内外推广应用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;华源表示，下一步上海将顺应全球发展新趋势新要求，打造更高质量双向投资贸易的重要通道、更高效率基础设施互联互通的重要枢纽、更高能级专业服务的重要支撑、更高层次民心相通的重要纽带、更高水平对外开放的重要平台，为共建“一带一路”作出新贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（新华社上海10月5日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;记者何欣荣、李海伟、桑彤）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 05:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 用心耕好这块“大试验田”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/06/nw.D110000renmrb_20231006_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月06日星期五&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;上海，改革开放的前沿阵地，世界观察中国的重要窗口。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;金秋时节，中国（上海）自由贸易试验区迎来建设十周年——2013年9月29日，肩负建设全国第一个自由贸易试验区的重任，上海自贸试验区扬帆起航。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2014年5月，习近平总书记在上海考察时强调，上海自由贸易试验区是块大试验田，要播下良种，精心耕作，精心管护，期待有好收成，并且把培育良种的经验推广开来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;牢记习近平总书记殷殷嘱托，上海自贸试验区用心耕好这块“大试验田”，把制度创新作为核心任务，以形成可复制、可推广的制度成果为着力点，对标最高标准、最高水平，基本建立与国际投资、贸易通行规则相衔接的基本制度体系和监管模式，加快构筑与开放型经济体制相适应的压力测试体系，持续优化市场化、法治化、国际化营商环境，制度创新成果不断涌现，服务国家战略的综合效应进一步释放，经济增长极的作用更加彰显。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“苗圃”变成“森林”，与国际投资、贸易通行规则相衔接的基本制度体系和监管模式基本建立&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上海自贸试验区建设之初，习近平总书记强调，要大胆闯、大胆试、自主改，尽快形成一批可复制、可推广的新制度，加快在促进投资贸易便利、监管高效便捷、法制环境规范等方面先试出首批管用、有效的成果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;善做制度创新的“苗圃”，上海自贸试验区聚焦投资便利、贸易便利、金融开放创新和事中事后监管等领域，十年来形成一批基础性制度和核心制度创新，与国际投资、贸易通行规则相衔接的基本制度体系和监管模式基本建立。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;对标国际经贸通行规则，上海自贸试验区成立后推出外商投资负面清单。清单外的外商投资准入从审核制改为备案制。如今，自贸试验区外商投资准入特别管理措施从最初的190项缩减至27项，制造业条目已经归零。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年7月，总部位于比利时的优美科集团投资1500万欧元，在外高桥保税区成立一家科技开发公司。“条目越少，限制就越少，外资准入越来越宽广，企业投资更加便捷。”回顾新公司注册经过，优美科集团相关部门负责人张可方感慨道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;汽车整车制造、金融服务、医疗服务、增值电信……随着负面清单的缩短，上海自贸试验区在60个开放领域实现一批全国首创项目落地，推动“准入前国民待遇加负面清单管理制度”成熟定型并写入外商投资法，推动负面清单管理模式向跨境服务贸易、市场准入等领域拓展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谈起金融领域的开放，摩根大通证券（中国）有限公司首席执行官陆芳说：“金融领域外商投资过去是有股比限制的。上海自贸试验区走在了金融开放的前沿。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;创设国际贸易“单一窗口”，是上海自贸试验区推进贸易便利化的一项重大创新。作为上海亿通国际股份有限公司企划部负责人，潘小东10年前参与了国际贸易“单一窗口”平台建设，“如同国际贸易领域的&#39;一网通办&#39;，平台将海关、检疫、海事、边检的信息打通，极大便利了通关贸易。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;主营进出口报关等业务的元初数智科技发展集团有限公司，是国际贸易“单一窗口”最早的受益者之一。“过去进出口单据要一单一单填、一单一单录，还要将纸质单据送到相关部门。一个单子做完至少需要两天。有了&#39;单一窗口&#39;，几分钟就能出税单。”公司相关负责人杨晓峰说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;迄今，国际贸易“单一窗口”平台服务的贸易企业累计超过60万家，支撑占全国1/4多货物贸易量的数据处理。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;着力打造贸易制度创新高地，上海高标准建设洋山特殊综合保税区，海关监管作业流程被系统性重塑，申报模式、贸易管制、协同管理等不断改革创新。上海海关副关长张翼表示，上海自贸试验区内海关特殊监管区域已建立国际自由贸易园区通行的“一线放开、二线管住、区内自由”的监管模式。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;企业名称告知承诺制、注册资本认缴制、企业信用信息公示制……制度性创新成果已由“苗圃”变成“森林”。在国家层面复制推广的302项自贸试验区制度创新成果中，近一半源自上海首创或同步先行先试。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;增强全球资源配置能力，加快构筑与开放型经济体制相适应的压力测试体系&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记在浦东开发开放30周年庆祝大会上指出，“要更好发挥中国（上海）自由贸易试验区临港新片区作用，对标最高标准、最高水平，实行更大程度的压力测试，在若干重点领域率先实现突破。”“增强全球资源配置能力，服务构建新发展格局。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;敢闯敢试先行先试，上海自贸试验区不断增强全球资源配置能力，加快构筑与开放型经济体制相适应的压力测试体系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上海国际能源交易中心大屏上，原油期货行情不断跳跃变化，这里已成为全球第三大原油期货市场。十年来，上海自贸试验区大幅提升金融市场国际化水平，推出我国第一个面向国际的金融资产交易平台——黄金国际板，先后上市20号胶、低硫燃料油和原油期权等占全国一半以上的国际化期货期权品种，“上海金”“上海油”“上海铜”等“上海价格”的国际影响力日益提升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;走进外高桥港综合保税区的世天威物流有限公司仓库，只见叉车铲起铜板，移放至仓库外的空地上。“这&#39;一铲一放&#39;，意义非同一般。”公司副总经理徐赟说，“我们所在的仓库是国际铜市场的一个交易库。从库内挪到库外，铜板就从期货&#39;变&#39;成现货，国内买家可直接在这里把铜板运走。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以前，买家拉货可没有这么简单。国际期货交易，要将货物运到韩国釜山等地的交割仓；国内市场交易，则要运到非保税类仓库。变化发生在2014年11月，成立一年多的上海自贸试验区率先启动货物状态分类监管试点。非保税货物也可以进入自贸试验区海关特殊监管区域储存，与保税货物一道集拼、分拨、管理和配送。“通过这项改革，全球大宗商品交易都可以在上海自贸试验区进行，这是真正配置全球资源。”上海自贸试验区保税区管理局财政和金融服务处副处长陈宇说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;金融，是自由贸易试验的一个重要领域。“在上海自贸试验区和临港新片区，金融开放创新举措持续推出，一大批首创性金融制度先行先试。”中国人民银行上海总部副主任孙辉说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上海自贸试验区推出的本外币一体化的自由贸易账户，是跨境人民币业务创新方面的“排头兵”，具有跨境结算、跨境融资等本外币一体化金融服务功能。截至目前，上海已累计开设14.4万个自由贸易账户，办理跨境结算折合人民币142万亿元，年均增长61%，企业通过自由贸易账户获得的本外币融资总额折合人民币2.8万亿元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“自由贸易账户为我们提供了很大帮助。”上海振华重工（集团）股份有限公司党委副书记王成说。2015年开始使用自由贸易账户以来，振华重工累计获得境外贷款520多亿元人民币，不同程度享受了利率优惠，有效减少了企业的资金成本压力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国际资产管理机构也纷纷在上海自贸试验区集聚。施罗德基金管理（中国）有限公司总经理张兰说：“我们坚定看好中国市场，将把各种优势资源持续带到上海，探索资产管理公司在中国发展的新模式。”2020年以来，全球排名前十的资产管理公司已有9家落户浦东。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;临港新片区设立后，进一步推出优质企业跨境人民币结算便利化、境内贸易融资资产跨境转让等试点。2022年，又启动国内首批跨境贸易投资高水平开放试点，试点业务金额累计超过400亿美元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;以高水平开放促改革、促发展，持续优化市场化、法治化、国际化营商环境&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;把扩大开放同改革体制相结合，上海系统推进政府职能转变、管理模式创新、运行机制优化、服务方式转变，以高水平开放促改革、促发展，持续优化市场化、法治化、国际化营商环境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;浦东新区行政服务中心办事大厅，见证了上海自贸试验区无数个以开放促改革的故事。“同样是这个大厅，办事方式几经革新，企业感受大不相同。”中心副主任黄海霞说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2017年11月，浦东新区在上海率先试点“单窗通办”，建立“一窗受理、分类审批、一口发证”的综合服务模式。企业办事，再不用跑多个柜台，只需找一个窗口。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;聚焦营业执照、经营许可证这“一照”“一证”，上海自贸试验区坚持先行先试。“先照后证”实行后，“证照分离”“一业一证”和文体旅“一证通”等措施相继推出。通过数字化手段，“智能帮办”“直达帮办”“免申即办”等便民利企措施也接连出台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“罗森便利店刚在浦东开了一家新店，手续办得很顺利。”上海罗森便利有限公司业务风险管控部副部长金烨说，“过去开店办手续要花近两个月，现在只需两三天。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“自贸试验区是上海推动政府职能转变和营商环境优化的前沿地带。”上海市发展改革委副主任阮青说，上海先后向浦东新区政府下放100多项市级行政审批事项。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至今年9月底，上海市人大常委会出台18部浦东新区法规和2部地方性法规浦东专章，浦东新区人大常委会和政府出台19部管理措施，上海自贸试验区建设的法治保障体系不断完善。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;针对产业发展需求，上海不断加大制度供给、改变监管方式。华领医药技术（上海）有限公司董事长、首席执行官陈力说：“有了药品上市许可持有人制度，研发型生物医药企业可以委托药厂生产自己研发的新药，不仅产业化进程加速，也为集中精力研发更多新药创造了条件。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;药品上市许可持有人制度施行后，上海自贸试验区实现我国首个自主研发肿瘤治疗药获批上市、11个一类新药通过代工生产上市。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十年耕耘，硕果累累。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至2022年底，上海自贸试验区新注册企业超8.4万家，新设外资项目超1.4万个，累计实到外资586亿美元。2022年，浦东新区实现地区生产总值1.6万亿元，是2013年的2.5倍。临港新片区自成立以来生产总值年均增长21.2%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国自由贸易试验区从一花独放到百花满园，全国21个自贸试验区及海南自由贸易港发挥了制度创新的&#39;头雁&#39;效应，打造了开放发展的生动样板。”上海市委常委、浦东新区区委书记、中国（上海）自由贸易试验区管委会主任朱芝松说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年9月20日，在上海自贸试验区建设十周年主题论坛上，上海市委书记陈吉宁表示，“我们将以海纳百川的胸怀扩大开放，以敢为人先的精神锐意创新，以融通共赢的生态展示包容，把上海自贸试验区和临港新片区建设得更好。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;走过十年，上海自贸试验区风景正好，高水平对外开放新画卷加速铺展。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 05:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 文旅消费热  内需动力强（走进市场看信心·聚焦中秋国庆假期）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/06/nw.D110000renmrb_20231006_5-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月06日星期五&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231006/1696534474128_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;节日期间，四川宜宾市李庄古镇每天客流量超4万人次。图为10月5日，摇橹船驶过水面，与民居、小桥、青山融为一体，构成一幅古朴优美的画卷。&lt;BR/>;王宇摄（影像中国）&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;中秋国庆假期第六天，文旅市场热度持续。在河北秦皇岛，来到长城脚下，欣赏壮观美景、感受厚重文化；在河南信阳，走进美丽乡村，赏秋景、品秋韵、享秋实；在海南海口，漫步旅游度假区和旅游休闲街区，看演出、品美食、买好物，享受“一站式”文商旅体消费体验……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文旅消费是扩大内需的有效途径，也是满足人民群众美好生活需求的重要载体。这个中秋国庆假期，我国文化休闲、旅游出行需求集中释放，文旅深度融合，新业态、新模式、新供给不断涌现，旅游出行成为热门选择。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文化和旅游部数据中心预测，中秋国庆假期旅游热度将创新高，国内旅游出游预计将达到8.96亿人次，同比增长86%，将实现国内旅游收入7825亿元，同比增长138%。假期文旅消费的火热，折射出消费市场的蓬勃活力和巨大潜力，彰显中国经济强大的内需动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;文旅行业加速复苏，多业态预订火热&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“大人小孩一起玩，特别开心。”在深圳欢乐谷主题公园新开的“迷你世界·冒险山”游乐区，刚刚体验完弹射过山车项目的游客王晗说。造型多样的建筑、缤纷多彩的装饰吸引众多游客拍照，各种沉浸式主题游乐设备为人们提供了多样化体验。假期前三天，深圳欢乐谷接待游客近10万人次。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“旅途中感受非遗的魅力，新体验带来新收获。”江西龙虎山景区，正在体验团扇非遗手作的四川游客李珊说。龙虎山景区结合非遗文化，创新假期产品供给，满足不断升级的文旅消费需求，推出团扇、灯笼等现场手作和顶碗、顶缸等杂技表演，让游客近距离感受中华优秀传统文化的魅力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“既是休闲娱乐，也能强身健体，这个假期过得很有意义。”在广州热雪奇迹室内滑雪场，刚刚从雪道上滑下来的游客韩菲说。随着文旅体深度融合，滑雪等“体育+旅游”业态兴起。中秋国庆假期，这家滑雪场举办了主题夜滑、雪上运动会等活动，接待游客人次同比实现较快增长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年以来，文化和旅游行业加速复苏，中秋国庆假期文旅消费需求更是集中释放。文化和旅游部数据中心的数据显示，假期前三天，国内旅游出游合计3.95亿人次，同比增长75.8%；实现国内旅游收入3422.4亿元，同比增长125.3%。各大平台预订数据显示，景区观光、都市休闲、乡村旅游等产品服务关注度高，酒店、交通、景区等业态预订持续火热。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;创新市场供给，激发消费新活力&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从湖北潜江高速服务区出发，一路抵达生态龙虾城、楚潜村韵农庄、莫岭村，分享虾肥稻香的丰收喜悦……中秋国庆假期，湖南游客孙悦踏上湖北潜江“虾稻之乡&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;田园丰收”之旅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这条路线是文化和旅游部推出的149条“橙黄橘绿&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;乡村胜景”全国乡村旅游精品线路之一。这个假期，文化和旅游部聚焦乡村旅游市场，推出乡村旅游精品线路，邀请广大游客体验多元融合的乡村旅游业态。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;走进陕西西安曲江新区“长安十二时辰”主题街区，浓浓的文化气息扑面而来。踏歌台上，演员生动还原唐代名画《簪花仕女图》；青绿山水间，游客与古人“隔空对话”……边走边看，历史文化的美妙演绎渐入佳境。第一批24家全国智慧旅游沉浸式体验新空间培育试点项目不久前正式授牌，成为很多游客出游的热门目的地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“孩子从小就对钢铁工业的历史感兴趣，假期带着他来现场感受。”在湖北武汉武钢厂区内的武钢文化旅游区参观的游客黄阳说。以工业遗址、工厂风貌、生产过程、劳动场景等为参观体验对象的工业旅游，成为受游客欢迎的新型旅游业态。日前，文化和旅游部公布了新一批工业旅游示范基地，为游客假期出游提供了更加丰富的选择。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;市场热得益于供给新。中秋国庆假期，许多景区和文旅相关企业紧跟文旅消费升级新趋势，打造文旅新产品、新业态、新场景，推出更多符合游客需求的优质产品和服务，激发文旅市场更加强劲的发展动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文化和旅游部相关负责人介绍，为丰富文化和旅游产品供给，相关部门和地方发布全国旅游演艺精品名录，推出一批文化内涵丰富、艺术水平精湛、叫好又叫座的旅游演艺精品项目，提供更多适合家庭出游的特色旅游产品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;服务品质不断提升，消费动能持续释放&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“游客虽多，但秩序井然，感觉很好。”北京天坛公园景区入口处，正在排队进入景区游览的游客赵泽说。中秋国庆假期，文明旅游成为越来越多游客的自觉行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;旅游是幸福产业。这个假期，围绕优化游客体验，各地各部门做足了功课，不断提升服务品质，让人们出游更舒心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;假期前，文化和旅游部发布相关提示，提醒广大游客合理安排行程，提前了解途经地、目的地天气、交通及旅游景区开放情况和门票预约措施，合理规划旅游线路和时间，平安健康文明绿色出游。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;针对出游高峰，文化和旅游部提前部署假日旅游景区的预约、接待、安全等各方面工作，引导景区优化预约措施，实施科学管理，实现原则性和灵活性相统一，科学设置线上、线下购票预约渠道，积极采用新技术、新手段，畅通景区、博物馆等场所预约渠道，简化预约程序，提高预约操作便捷性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;假期期间，各地各部门聚焦文旅市场重点领域关键环节，加大对违法违规经营行为执法检查力度，保障假日市场安全平稳有序。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;文旅消费动能的持续释放，必将进一步提振市场信心，更好地发挥消费拉动经济增长的基础性作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 05:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 杭州亚运会铭刻文化自信（人民论坛）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/06/nw.D110000renmrb_20231006_6-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月06日星期五&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;亚运赛事正酣，中秋佳节共度，体育盛会遇见传统节日，尽显“中国式浪漫”。制作花灯、团扇作画、用模具为月饼印上图案，运动员村里的中秋主题日体验活动精彩纷呈；浙派古琴、苏州评弹、昆曲、点茶，西湖中秋赏月雅集活动广受欢迎。通过亚运会，中华优秀传统文化的独特魅力呈现在世界面前。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;越是民族的，就越是世界的。人文盛会、江南情致，杭州亚运会体现着独特的中国气派，为世界打开了一扇观察中华文化的时代新窗。特别是开幕式上，国风少年以地为画、踏墨而舞，“一抹丹青”将时光拉回千年前；地屏上，在水光潋滟的江南画境中，宋韵女子的清雅身姿和芭蕾舞步相互映衬；全景立体影像构筑的拱宸桥跃然于大运河之上，形态逼真、栩栩生动，一岸连过往，一岸通当今……“中国风”贯穿始终，“中国味”融入细节，“中国情”感动人心，中国元素刷新了体育盛会的审美，拨动着无数人的心弦。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;文化是岁月的陈酿、时间的沉淀，不仅关乎过去，更关乎现在与未来。极具地域风韵的短片《相约杭州》，让古今杭州隔空对话，展现杭州作为“历史文化名城、创新活力之城、生态文明之都”的多元风采。开幕式上，由超过1亿人参与传递汇聚而成的“数字火炬手”高擎火炬，从钱塘江踏浪而来，与主火炬手共同点燃主火炬塔，彰显着传统与现代激荡、科技与文化融合。各场馆内，新一代数字技术广泛应用，智慧运营赋能赛事活动；场馆之外，新能源汽车优先使用，户外项目呈现生态之美，赛场内外无不体现浙江跑出高质量发展的加速度。可以说，透过一届“中国特色、亚洲风采、精彩纷呈”的体育盛会，人们既能思接千载，感受中国深厚的文化底蕴；又能视通万里，看见中国的时代风采，见证新时代中国的发展进步和精神风貌。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;亚洲地域广阔，人口众多，文化多元，历史悠久。杭州亚运会如同一座桥，不仅让活跃在某一地区的特色项目走进大众视野，更让不同文化以体育为媒交流互鉴。武术、藤球、板球、柔术、克柔术等5个项目分别代表了东亚、东南亚、南亚、中亚和西亚的地域特色，这些非奥项目丰富了亚运会的竞赛内容，诠释着亚洲体育、亚洲文化多元之美。这样的设置，为体育和文化交相辉映提供了舞台，是亚洲文化兼收并蓄、博采众长、充满活力的生动写照。正如习近平主席所强调的：“作为山海相连、人文相亲的命运共同体，我们要以体育促和平，坚持与邻为善和互利共赢，抵制冷战思维和阵营对抗，将亚洲打造成世界和平的稳定锚。”&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;文明因交流而多彩，文明因互鉴而丰富。杭州亚运会开幕式文艺表演下篇《携手同行》中，“白鹭精灵”遨游星海，数百名大学生手持发光金桂点亮绵延悠长的“金桂之江”，亚洲各个国家和地区的地标性建筑共同呈现，构成美轮美奂的亚洲画卷。亚运火炬，点亮江南夜空；亚洲宾朋，齐聚钱塘内外。从各美其美到美美与共，杭州亚运会把“你”“我”汇聚成了“我们”，架起亚洲不同国家和地区人民沟通的桥梁，为多样文明交流互鉴提供了舞台，为推动构建人类命运共同体注入了强大动力。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;涓滴成海，奔涌成潮。潮，是钱塘奔涌澎湃的记忆，是体育奋勇争先的跃动，是时代强劲有力的脉搏。潮起钱塘江，中华优秀传统文化绵延千年、薪火相传；潮涌新时代，中国在旧邦新命中不断创造新的奇迹。从杭州亚运会看向未来，让我们以梦想为帆、以奋斗作桨，共绘亚运会新的画卷、共创亚洲更美好的明天。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 06 Oct 2023 05:26:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>