<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 李克强同志遗体在京火化]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/03/nw.D110000renmrb_20231103_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 3, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/03/01/rmrb2023110301p33_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;November 2, Li Keqiang The remains of the comrade were cremated at the Babaoshan Revolutionary Cemetery in Beijing. Xi Jinping, Li Qiang, Zhao Leji, Wang Huning, Cai Qi, Ding Xuexiang, Li Xi, Han Zheng and others went to Babao Mountain to bid farewell. Hu Jintao sent wreaths to express condolences. This is Xi Jinping shaking hands with Li Keqiang’s relatives to express his deep condolences. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Xie Huanchi&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 2 &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;An outstanding member of the Communist Party of China, a time-tested and loyal communist fighter, an outstanding proletarian revolutionist and politician, and an outstanding leader of the party and the country. The body of Comrade Li Keqiang, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and former Premier of the State Council, was cremated at the Babaoshan Revolutionary Cemetery in Beijing on the 2nd. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Comrade Li Keqiang died of a sudden heart attack in Shanghai at 0:10 on October 27, 2023 after all-out efforts to rescue him failed. He was 68 years old. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;During the rescue period and after the death of Comrade Li Keqiang, Xi Jinping, Li Qiang, Zhao Leji, Wang Huning, Cai Qi, Ding Xuexiang, Li Xi, Han Zheng, Hu Jintao and other comrades went to the hospital to visit or express their condolences to Comrade Li Keqiang in various ways. Express my deepest condolences and express my deep condolences to his relatives. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;On the morning of the 2nd, the auditorium of Babaoshan Revolutionary Cemetery was solemn and solemn, with low sorrow and joy. A banner with white characters on a black background &quot;deeply mourns Comrade Li Keqiang&quot; hangs above the main hall. Below the banner is Comrade Li Keqiang&#39;s portrait. The body of Comrade Li Keqiang lies among the flowers and cypresses, covered with the bright red flag of the Communist Party of China. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;At around 9 a.m., Xi Jinping, his wife Peng Liyuan, Li Qiang, Zhao Leji, Wang Huning, Cai Qi, Ding Xuexiang, Li Xi, Han Zheng, etc., slowly came to the body of Comrade Li Keqiang and stood in silence amidst the sounds of mourning music. , bowed three times to Comrade Li Keqiang’s body, shook hands with Comrade Li Keqiang’s relatives one by one, and expressed condolences. Hu Jintao sent wreaths to express condolences for the death of Comrade Li Keqiang. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Relevant leading comrades of the party and the state went to bid farewell or express condolences in various ways. Responsible comrades of relevant departments of the central and state agencies, representatives of Comrade Li Keqiang&#39;s friends and hometown also went to see him off. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 以金融高质量发展助力强国建设、民族复兴伟业]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/03/nw.D110000renmrb_20231103_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 3, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;High-quality financial development is related to the overall situation of China-style modernization. At the Central Financial Work Conference held recently, General Secretary Xi Jinping deployed financial work for the current and future periods from the strategic perspective of the overall development of the party and the country&#39;s cause. This meeting clearly stated that we should accelerate the construction of a strong financial country and use high-quality financial development to support the construction of a strong country and the great cause of national rejuvenation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, under the centralized and unified leadership of the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core, we have placed the prevention and control of financial risks in a more important position and firmly guarded against the occurrence of systemic financial risks. The bottom line is to grasp the development trend, the financial system strongly supports the overall economic and social development, and finance has become an important force in promoting economic and social development. At present, my country&#39;s development is facing new strategic opportunities, new strategic tasks, new strategic stages, new strategic requirements, and new strategic environments. Only by accelerating the construction of a strong financial country, unswervingly following the path of financial development with Chinese characteristics, and promoting high-quality financial development in our country can we provide strong support for comprehensively promoting the construction of a strong country and the great cause of national rejuvenation with Chinese-style modernization. To do a good job in financial work at present and in the future, we must firmly grasp the theme of promoting high-quality financial development, accelerate the construction of a modern financial system with Chinese characteristics, strive to provide high-quality financial services for economic and social development, comprehensively strengthen financial supervision, and effectively prevent and resolve financial problems. risks, continue to meet economic and social development and the people’s growing financial needs, and constantly create new situations in financial work in the new era. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The report of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China proposed that &quot;high-quality development is the primary task of comprehensively building a modern socialist country&quot;, which pointed out the direction and goals for optimizing financial services. In recent years, my country&#39;s financial system has completely, accurately and comprehensively implemented new development concepts, helping to accelerate the construction of a new development pattern, and its ability and efficiency to serve high-quality development have been greatly improved. To provide high-quality financial services for economic and social development, we must strive to create a good monetary and financial environment and effectively strengthen high-quality financial services for major strategies, key areas and weak links. Monetary policy pays more attention to cross-cyclical and counter-cyclical adjustments, and Multiple financial resources are used to promote technological innovation, advanced manufacturing, green development and small, medium and micro enterprises, improve the efficiency of fund use, and do five major articles on technology finance, green finance, inclusive finance, pension finance, and digital finance; and strive to create modern finance Institutions and market systems, unblock the channels for funds to enter the real economy, optimize the financing structure, improve the positioning of institutions, create a financial market with unified rules and coordinated supervision, and improve the modern financial enterprise system with Chinese characteristics; strive to promote high-level financial opening up, adhere to the principle of &quot;bringing in&quot; &quot;We should attach equal importance to &quot;going global&quot; and steadily expand the institutional opening up of the financial sector to ensure the country&#39;s financial and economic security. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Preventing and defusing financial risks, especially preventing systemic financial risks, is the fundamental task of financial work. To do a good job in financial work with a focus on comprehensively strengthening supervision and preventing and resolving risks, we must conscientiously implement the work arrangements made by the Central Financial Work Conference, effectively improve the effectiveness of financial supervision, bring all financial activities under supervision in accordance with the law, and promptly handle the risks of small and medium-sized financial institutions , establish a long-term mechanism to prevent and resolve local debt risks, promote a virtuous cycle of finance and real estate, and maintain the stable operation of the financial market. To prevent and resolve financial risks, we must grasp the relationship between rights and responsibilities, and improve the risk disposal responsibility mechanism with consistent rights and responsibilities, and compatible incentives and constraints; grasp the relationship between speed and stability, grasp the timeliness and effectiveness on the premise of stabilizing the overall situation, and be solid and steady. Defuse risks, resolutely punish illegal, criminal and corrupt behaviors, and strictly prevent moral hazards; early identification, early warning, early exposure, and early disposal of risks, and improve the early correction mechanism of financial risks with hard constraints. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Finance is an important core competitiveness of the country, financial security is an important part of national security, and the financial system is an important basic system in economic and social development. On the new journey, guided by Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, we will thoroughly study and implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech at the Central Financial Work Conference and the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, with the goal of accelerating the construction of a financial power, adhere to goal-oriented, Problem-oriented, coordinating development and security, focusing on current key tasks in the financial field, intensifying policy implementation and work advancement, and using new atmosphere and new actions to promote high-quality financial development and achieve new results, we will certainly be able to contribute to the construction of a strong country and the great cause of national rejuvenation. . &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 运用主题教育成果促进乡村振兴（学思想 强党性 重实践 建新功）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/03/nw.D110000renmrb_20231103_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 3, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Since the launch of the second batch of thematic education on studying and implementing Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, all localities have insisted on two-pronged approach and two-promotion , implement practical requirements throughout the entire process, guide party members and cadres to focus their energy on comprehensively promoting rural revitalization, research policies, plan measures, deploy work, guide and promote, and transform thematic education results into actual results in comprehensively promoting rural revitalization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;b>;Promote cadres through learning&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Develop industries&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The key to rural revitalization is to revitalize industry. In the theme education, the majority of party members and cadres insist on promoting learning to do, develop characteristic industries according to local conditions, and develop and expand the village collective economy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“300 kilograms of large-fruited hazelnuts and 100 kilograms of iron-skinned persimmons were sold out in 2 hours.” At the &quot;Party Building Leading, Common Wealth&quot; famous and special agricultural products exhibition and sales event in Fushun City, Liaoning Province, Hailang Township, Fushun County Li Jiangtian, first secretary of the Songshuzui Village Party Branch, said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Fushun City carried out the &quot;Party and the Masses Get Prosperous Together&quot; activity in combination with thematic education, gave full play to the existing working mechanism, divided the party and the masses&#39; common prosperity responsibility areas, gave play to the demonstration and leading role of the &quot;head goose&quot;, and helped incubate a large number of Professional cooperatives, and at the same time establish an industrial joint party committee to coordinate and gather forces. Up to now, 134 professional cooperatives have been established under the leadership of the party organizations in each village. The village collective income has increased by 4.17 million yuan, and the villagers&#39; income has increased by 11.78 million yuan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Little peanuts, big industry. In Junan County, Shandong Province, one peanut can be processed into more than a hundred products. The county has a peanut planting area of ​​400,000 acres and more than 300 peanut processing companies. It is a veritable industry that enriches the people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taking the theme education as an opportunity, Junan County further integrated the policy advantages and resource advantages of government departments, and established the Junan County Peanut Industry Chain Party Building Alliance and the Junan County Peanut Industry Assistance and Service Party Building Alliance. Through solid advancement The key work of the theme education focuses on solving the urgent, difficult and anxious problems of enterprises related to the peanut industry chain, promoting the mutual integration and mutual promotion of party building work and corporate business, and assisting the high-quality development of the peanut industry chain. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the past, many small businesses were competitors, but now we have developed as a team. Under the leadership of the alliance, we cooperate with major online platforms to achieve ‘buy global, sell global’.” Shizilu Street, Junan County In the conference room, participants actively discussed at the joint meeting related to the peanut industry chain in the third quarter. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;b>;Combining learning and doing&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;implementation and results&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From the party’s innovative theory, we understand the rules, clarify the direction, learn methods, and increase wisdom. Party members from all over the country , cadres should apply the learned thinking methods and working methods to their entrepreneurship and promote implementation to achieve results. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On October 29, special party classes were held one after another in Niujiaogou Village, Pengxi County, Suining City, Sichuan Province. On this day, more than 500 party members from more than 30 grassroots party organizations attended party classes here. In recent years, Niujiaogou Village has developed experiential teaching courses and upgraded red venues and supporting teaching facilities, making it a good place to carry out party education. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the theme education, Suining City focuses on integrating party member education and training into rural revitalization practice, gathering 43 on-site teaching points to form a 15-minute teaching circle for party member education and training, making full use of red resources, inheriting red genes, and educating and guiding Party members and cadres must strengthen their ideals and beliefs, keep their original aspiration and mission in mind, actively forge ahead, and have the courage to take on their responsibilities. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Food security is &quot;the most important thing in a country&quot;. Ensuring the supply of important agricultural products, especially grain, is the primary task of implementing the rural revitalization strategy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Suihua City, Heilongjiang Province is a major grain-producing city. The local area has carried out the second batch of thematic education in a solid manner to promote the theme education to be deeper and more solid. Focusing on the national strategic needs and the deployment of the Provincial Party Committee, Suihua City has implemented the task of structural adjustment, established a leading group to promote the development of grain and soybean production, formulated and issued an implementation plan for the development of grain and soybean production, quantified and decomposed the soybean production task indicators, and further consolidated various tasks. Counties (cities, districts) are responsible for expanding soybean production. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;b>;Based on the position&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Doing practical things well&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To carry out the second batch of thematic education, the word &quot;practical&quot; must be highlighted. The majority of party members and cadres went deep into the fields to investigate agricultural conditions, bent down to listen to the voices of the masses, handled the affairs around the masses well, and continuously improved the masses&#39; satisfaction and sense of gain. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Luanping County, Hebei Province has carried out activities such as &quot;contributing based on the position&quot; and &quot;learning from the role models around you&quot; as a starting point to guide party members and cadres to fully play a pioneering and exemplary role in promoting development, grassroots governance, and serving the people. . Relying on the New Era Civilization Practice Center, it has carried out more than 1,300 voluntary service activities such as theoretical policy propaganda, culture and art, and student support and teaching, attracting 155,000 people to participate, solving the urgent, difficult and anxious problems of the masses with emotion and efforts, and striving to create a good social atmosphere. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the weather turns cooler, in the blueberry greenhouse at the home of Pang Shufen, a villager in Zhaili Village, Huangdao District, Qingdao City, Shandong Province, the family is busy repairing the greenhouse in preparation for the coming winter. But the temperature and humidity in the shed have not been constant, which makes Pang Shufen a little distressed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On October 12, the village’s electricity convenience service point was put into use, and a master was sent to inspect the greenhouse temperature, water pump control box and drip irrigation equipment, solving the family’s problems. In the theme education, State Grid Qingdao Huangdao District Power Supply Company organized and implemented the special action of &quot;Doing Practical Things and Solving People&#39;s Concerns&quot;, focusing on the transformation and upgrading of rural power supply service models, and working with village-level party organizations to create &quot;Village Network Co-construction&quot; electric power convenience for the people The service model adopts a joint system for accepting business requests and strives to achieve zero-distance power supply services for villagers without leaving the village. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;How to further improve rural governance and continuously meet the people’s needs for a better life is a must-answer question in promoting rural revitalization. In thematic education, party organizations at all levels continue to explore new experiences and new practices based on reality. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Walking into the Laowan Courtyard of Yihe Village, Wanzhou District, Chongqing City, the houses are well-proportioned, the courtyard is fragrant with flowers, and everything is clean and tidy... The dilapidated courtyard in the past has now become an internet celebrity check-in place where citizens rush to go. . This is due to the &quot;Courtyard Theme Day&quot; mechanism created by Wanzhou District, which allows everyone to sit down and discuss how to improve the courtyard. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Now in Wanzhou District, the &quot;Courtyard Theme Day&quot; builds a bridge to understand people&#39;s sentiments and collect public opinions. The 413 villages in the district are divided into 2,421 courtyards, and &quot;conflict and dispute resolution&quot; are held once a month. &quot;Service activities such as &quot;Mass appeals are handled&quot; organize and mobilize villagers to discuss and solve public environmental problems, resolve conflicts and disputes, and harmonize neighbors. Services to the people are carried out in the courtyard, conflicts are resolved in the courtyard, and people&#39;s deliberations and autonomy are in the courtyard. , solved the urgent, difficult and anxious problems of a large number of people. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 全国政协十四届常委会第四次会议闭幕]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/03/nw.D110000renmrb_20231103_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 3, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 2nd&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Fourth Meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th CPPCC National Committee The meeting concluded in Beijing on the morning of the 2nd. The meeting focused on “strengthening ecological and environmental protection and promoting the construction of a beautiful China” as the topic of consultation and discussion. Wang Huning, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Chairman of the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference, presided over the closing meeting and delivered a speech. He said that since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, my country&#39;s ecological civilization construction has undergone historic, turning and overall changes, and the construction of a beautiful China has taken major steps. It is necessary to thoroughly study and implement Xi Jinping’s thoughts on ecological civilization, implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech at the National Ecological Environmental Protection Conference, increase special consultation and democratic supervision on ecological civilization construction, and accelerate the construction of a beautiful China and promote the harmonious symbiosis between man and nature. Contribute to the modernization of the country. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Wang Huning said that the next five years will be an important period for the construction of a beautiful China. The CPPCC must find out the direction and focus of its duties in promoting the construction of a beautiful China, carry out in-depth investigations and studies, fully consult and discuss, and improve the quality of its deliberations. The pertinence and effectiveness of suggestions. It is necessary to focus on major theoretical and practical issues in the construction of ecological civilization, enhance the penetrating power of research and analysis, expand the depth of consultation and discussion, and put forward more weighty opinions and suggestions. It is necessary to closely implement the major decisions and arrangements of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China to carry out democratic supervision, adhere to the positioning of consultative supervision, and improve the ability of democratic supervision. It is necessary to actively publicize Xi Jinping’s Thoughts on Ecological Civilization to people from all walks of life and the general public, tell vivid stories of various regions and relevant departments establishing and practicing the concept of clear waters and lush mountains as valuable assets, and broadly build a consensus on building a beautiful China. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Wang Huning said that all tasks must be completed cautiously and consistently, and the work should be made more systematic, forward-looking, targeted and effective. It is necessary to carry out high-quality preparations for the second session of the 14th National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The closing meeting adopted the revised &quot;Regulations on the Proposal Work of the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference&quot;. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;After the closing meeting, Wang Xuedian, member of the Standing Committee of the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference and executive director of the Institute of Advanced Confucian Studies at Shandong University, was invited to give a lecture entitled &quot;Keeping the &#39;root&#39; and &#39;soul&#39; of the Chinese nation and building a modern civilization of the Chinese nation.&quot; Lectures. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Shi Taifeng, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Vice Chairman of the National Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference, Hu Chunhua, Shen Yueyue, Wang Yong, Zhou Qiang, Ho Hau Wah, Leung Chun-ying, Battelle, Shao Hong, Gao Yunlong, Chen Wu, Mu Hong, Xian Hui, Wang Dongfeng, Jiang Xinzhi, Jiang Zuojun, He Baoxiang, Wang Guangqian, Qin Boyong, Zhu Yongxin and Yang Zhen attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 各地区各部门扎实推动城乡融合发展（走进市场看信心）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/03/nw.D110000renmrb_20231103_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 3, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out that we should give full play to the important role of rural areas as a consumer market and factor market, comprehensively promote rural revitalization, and promote Urbanization construction with counties as an important carrier promotes the integrated development of urban and rural areas, strengthens urban-rural economic connections, and smoothes the urban-rural economic cycle. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Data from the National Bureau of Statistics show that from January to September this year, rural retail sales of consumer goods were 4,569.7 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 7.4%; in the first three quarters, the per capita disposable income of rural residents was 15,705 yuan, a year-on-year nominal increase of 7.6% , excluding price factors, the actual growth was 7.3%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;my country&#39;s vast county areas have a good market foundation and great potential, and play an important role in expanding domestic demand and smoothing circulation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;All regions and departments take effective actions to increase residents’ income and security levels, improve the supply of products and services, unblock consumption channels, stimulate the vitality of domestic demand in county areas, and accelerate the construction of a unified national market and smooth the national economy. Circulation injects vital impetus. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Strengthening the construction of the market system&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;my country’s economy has huge development resilience and potential, and its long-term positive fundamentals have not changed. Rural areas are both a huge consumer market and a huge factor market. Accelerating the release of market potential is of great significance to expanding domestic demand and stabilizing growth. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Currently, the consumer market at the township and village levels accounts for 38% of my country’s consumer market and is a key node in expanding domestic demand and promoting circulation. Various regions and departments have launched a series of measures to enhance consumption capacity, vigorously expand investment space, and promote the steady development of county economy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Take multiple measures to fully stimulate consumption potential. The Ministry of Commerce has designated 2023 as the &quot;Consumption Boost Year&quot;. Many county areas have taken advantage of the trend to launch a series of activities to improve consumption conditions, innovate consumption scenarios, drive the sales of large-ticket commodities such as home appliances and automobiles, and green building materials to the countryside, and promote service consumption. Improving quality and expanding capacity will promote the continued recovery of the consumer market. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Promote rural revitalization and expand investment space. Gansu Province has proposed to create 20 provincial-level modern agricultural industrial parks this year, and basically achieve full coverage of modern agricultural industrial parks at the county level in the next three to five years. Anhui Province proposed to build 2 million acres of high-standard farmland, cultivate a number of agricultural product processing industries to strengthen counties, parks, and enterprises, and add 10 leading enterprises with an output value of more than 1 billion yuan and 3 processing parks with an output value of more than 5 billion yuan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strengthening the construction of the market system can effectively improve residents’ quality of life, better satisfy people’s yearning for a better life, and is an effective starting point for forming a strong domestic market. All regions actively explore and innovate and form a batch of good experiences and practices, which will promote greater vitality in the market. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;There is an upgrading trend in consumption&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;40-year-old Zhao Dongxiao is a native of Dongsu Village, Xisu Town, Yongnian District, Handan City, Hebei Province, and has benefited from local employment promotion policies. , Zhao Dongxiao became a &quot;monthly nanny&quot;, earning seven to eight thousand yuan a month. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, Zhao Dongxiao and his friends walked into the town’s commercial pedestrian street to feel the vitality of the town. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Per capita income continues to increase, commercial facilities are more complete, and e-commerce is innovatively developed... At present, favorable conditions for promoting consumption, expanding investment, and smoothing the economic cycle are constantly accumulating in county areas, which is an important step in promoting rural revitalization and urban-rural integration. Development and solid foundation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The trend of consumption upgrading is obvious, and there is huge room for expansion in the rural consumer market. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Recently, at a new energy vehicle exhibition in Housi Village, Huojia County, Henan Province, villager Ma Yue who came for a test drive said: &quot;New energy vehicles are both fashionable and environmentally friendly, and can also enjoy policy subsidies. I am ready to Book one.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;New energy vehicles, smartphones, smart home appliances, quality furniture... Nowadays, more and more consumer upgrade products have entered people&#39;s lives. Residents&#39; demand for development-oriented and quality-oriented consumption has increased significantly, digital consumption has grown rapidly and application scenarios have become more optimized. Relevant research shows that during the &quot;14th Five-Year Plan&quot; period, the level of urbanization in counties will increase by 2 percentage points. In addition to driving the rapid growth of furniture and decoration consumption in the real estate downstream industry, it will also promote corresponding childcare, early education, elderly care, information and other services. further expansion of consumption. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The business network continues to improve, and the rural logistics and distribution system continues to improve. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Multiple departments have strengthened policy support, guided various localities to further promote the construction of county commercial systems and achieved positive results, further unblocking the circulation channels of urban and rural goods, services and production factors, and improving rural production and living conditions. In 2022, 983 county comprehensive business service centers, 3,941 township business centers and markets will be constructed and renovated nationwide, and 506 county-level logistics and distribution centers will be constructed and renovated, and 650 township express logistics stations will be supported. The rural logistics and distribution system will be more complete. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The dividends of innovation and entrepreneurship policies continue to be released, injecting impetus into urban and rural development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The key to rural revitalization lies in people. In May last year, the General Office of the CPC Central Committee and the General Office of the State Council issued the &quot;Opinions on Promoting Urbanization Construction with County Towns as an Important Carrier&quot;, proposing to &quot;enhance the function of industrial platforms. Relying on various development zones, industrial clusters, entrepreneurship parks for migrant workers returning home, etc.&quot; platform to guide the concentrated development of county industries.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs has implemented an action to cultivate rural innovation and entrepreneurship leaders and implemented support policies such as one-time subsidies for entrepreneurship to encourage farmers to start businesses locally and find jobs nearby. Many places have launched targeted policies and measures to strengthen the supply of business talents in counties, give play to the hub role of counties and towns, and support talents who are interested in innovation and entrepreneurship in counties through tax incentives, technology investment, and the establishment of incubation institutions. Driven by a number of policies, the source of innovation, entrepreneurship and creation has fully flowed into the county, driving urban and rural development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Accelerate the release of market potential&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The circulation system, commercial facilities, and consumption environment in our country’s counties have been greatly improved, but in infrastructure, commodities and There are still some shortcomings in service supply, business entities, market demand and other aspects. It is necessary to adhere to the problem orientation, make up for the shortcomings of county commercial development, focus on channel sinking, further expand and strengthen the county market, promote the further recovery and expansion of rural consumption, expand the effective investment space in rural areas, better assist rural revitalization, and promote county The market is moving towards high-quality development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Accelerate the improvement of rural consumption environment and improve the supply of high-quality products and services. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Linquan County, Fuyang City, Anhui Province, Liu Yanhong’s family has been operating a small supermarket there for more than 20 years. In line with the development trend of new business formats such as instant retail, Liu Yanhong’s store became one of the first merchants in Linquan County to enter the takeout platform. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In order to increase sales, the platform sends counselors to help small stores refine operations. The platform is driven by real-time data, accurately matches supply, and dynamically and intelligently schedules, and can handle tens of thousands of orders in a short time, allowing Stores and riders have achieved rapid product updates and fast delivery. We provide 24-hour real-time services to nearby residents, which makes people’s lives more convenient, and business is getting better and better,&quot; said Liu Yanhong. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Experts said that it is necessary to speed up the improvement of the rural consumption environment, adhere to the principle of marketization, and give full play to the guiding role of fiscal funds. Transform and upgrade a number of &quot;township marts&quot; and new rural convenience stores, improve county and rural logistics and distribution systems, develop new models such as instant retail and joint distribution, innovate consumption scenarios, and stimulate consumption potential. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Promote the high-quality development of rural e-commerce to help sell agricultural products and increase farmers’ income. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Recently, in Nanhai Village, Ma&#39;an Town, Yilong County, Nanchong City, Sichuan Province, 34-year-old Cao Hailong purchased fresh duck eggs from villagers and purchased nearly a thousand fresh duck eggs in half a day. Cao Hailong is the person in charge of Yilong County Deshengyuan Agricultural Development Co., Ltd. He runs an egg processing business and sells eggs through a combination of online and offline methods. During the peak sales season, express trucks drive directly to the door of the processing factory every day, and the products are sold all over the country. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to Zheng Ping, deputy director of the Yilong County Private Economic Development and E-commerce Service Center, the county is actively promoting the construction of a public service system at the county, township and village levels and giving full play to the county-level e-commerce industrial park demonstration cluster. As a result, 11 township (town)-level e-commerce operation service centers have been built, equipped with specialized service teams to provide comprehensive services for village-level e-commerce sites, effectively driving the development of local specialty industries and promoting people to increase their income and become rich. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The relevant person in charge of the Ministry of Agriculture and Rural Affairs stated that it is necessary to further promote agricultural production and the &quot;three products and one standard&quot; of agricultural products, increase the supply of green and high-quality agricultural products, and guide the upgrading of food consumption. Improve the rural market circulation system to ensure smooth circulation of urban and rural products, promote the growth of consumption of durable goods such as home appliances and furniture, improve the supply of rural production and living services, and expand service consumption. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to reports, the Ministry of Commerce will work with relevant departments to speed up the summary of preliminary work experience and replicate and promote it, and strive to basically establish a relatively complete county and rural business system in counties with qualified conditions by 2025 to better meet the needs of rural people. production and living needs. At the same time, we should adapt to local conditions, explore and innovate, mobilize the enthusiasm of local governments, enterprises and the masses, create a number of county business models, and play a leading role in demonstration. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I believe that as my country’s rural market system becomes more complete, the market potential will be released at an accelerated pace, making greater contributions to the steady and long-term development of China’s economic ship. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 我国基础教育经费投入达3.2万亿元]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/03/nw.D110000renmrb_20231103_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 3, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Our newspaper, Beijing, November 2&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Zhao Grace, Ding Yasong) Reporter from the Ministry of Education Learned: In 2022, my country&#39;s fiscal education funding for basic education will reach 3.2 trillion yuan, an increase of 1.3 trillion yuan from 2015, with an average annual growth rate of 7.7%. Since the &quot;Thirteenth Five-Year Plan&quot;, the total financial investment and per-student expenditure in each stage of basic education have only increased year by year, providing strong support for promoting the high-quality and balanced development of basic education. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Investment has been expanded, and the scale of funding has grown steadily. The average general public budget education funding for preschool education, compulsory education, and ordinary high school students increased by 91%, 33%, and 53% respectively compared with 2015, and the per-student investment level increased significantly. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Promote fairness and the educational gap continues to narrow. In terms of promoting coordinated regional development, more than 80% of the central government&#39;s education transfer funds are used in central and western provinces; in terms of promoting integrated urban and rural development, the benchmark quotas for public funds for urban and rural compulsory education are unified; in terms of ensuring the common development of disadvantaged groups, establishing and improving coverage The student financial aid policy system for all levels and types of education will be implemented, and the nutritional improvement plan for rural compulsory education students will be implemented. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Adjust the structure and optimize the funding structure. More funds will be used for the construction of teaching staff and school connotation, and gradually realize the transformation of the focus of education investment from &quot;materials&quot; to &quot;people&quot;. The central government finances the implementation of the special post plan, which provides more than 50,000 teachers to rural areas in the central and western regions every year. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 不断开创金融高质量发展新局面]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/03/nw.D110000renmrb_20231103_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, November 3, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;The Central Financial Work Conference clearly proposed the goal of “accelerating the construction of a financial power” and emphasized the promotion of high-quality financial development in our country, in order to Chinese-style modernization provides strong support for comprehensively promoting the construction of a strong country and the great cause of national rejuvenation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past few days, departments across the country have carefully studied and understood the spirit of the Central Financial Work Conference. Everyone said that the meeting clarified the goals and tasks of financial work at present and in the future period, pointed out the direction for financial development and strengthened confidence. It is necessary to thoroughly study and implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech and the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, and continue to use the new atmosphere and new actions. Create a new situation for high-quality financial development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Those who have “the greatness of the country” in mind will contribute to the great cause of building a strong country and national rejuvenation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, under the leadership of Comrade Xi Jinping as the core Under the strong leadership of the Party Central Committee, various localities and departments continue to promote high-quality development of the financial industry, and the financial system strongly supports the overall economic and social development. In the face of new goals and tasks, this meeting highlighted the theme of promoting high-quality financial development and made careful arrangements for this. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Since the new era, under the strong leadership of the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core, the financial industry has been based on serving the real economy, striving for our country to build a moderately prosperous society in an all-round way as scheduled and achieve the first centenary year. Guan Tao, global chief economist of BOCI Securities, said that the conference elevated high-quality financial development to the level of building a strong country and national rejuvenation, further strengthening the responsibility and role of finance in serving the overall national situation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen Daofu, deputy director of the Financial Research Institute of the Development Research Center of the State Council, said that in promoting the construction of a strong country, the role of finance has undoubtedly become more prominent. Whether it is solving the problem of unbalanced and inadequate development, building a modern industrial system, and continuously improving people&#39;s quality of life, high-quality financial development is needed as strong support. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Financial blood nourishes the economic body. Walking into the 300-acre ginger planting base in Jialongtang Village, Mugang Town, Liuzhi Special Zone, Liupanshui City, Guizhou Province, the spicy fragrance of ginger hits your face. &quot;Our ginger planting has taken root and thrived under the water of finance, and has become an industry that enriches the people.&quot; Zhang Yong, secretary of the Party branch of Jialongtang Village, said that this year&#39;s per capita income in the village is expected to increase by 15% from last year&#39;s 14,000 yuan. about. &quot;When finance helps rural revitalization, villagers&#39; lives will definitely become more prosperous.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;We must keep in mind the &#39;greatest country&#39; and continue to strengthen the fundamentals of financial services for the real economy and being people-centered.&quot; People&#39;s Bank of China Li Bin, director of the Macro-Prudential Administration, said, “In the next step, we will continue to strengthen financial macro-control, promote the reform of financial institutions, expand high-level financial opening up, reform, adjust and optimize the financial supply system, and provide higher quality and more efficient services for the development of the real economy. Efficient and safer financial services.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Anchor the goal of becoming a financial power and provide high-quality services for economic and social development&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;High-quality development is a comprehensive construction The primary task of a modern socialist country is to provide high-quality financial services for economic and social development. The meeting proposed &quot;three focuses&quot; to identify the path to promote high-quality financial development: focus on creating a good monetary and financial environment, focus on building modern financial institutions and market systems, and focus on promoting high-level financial openness. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zeng Gang, director of the Shanghai Finance and Development Laboratory, said that the goal of becoming a financial power was first mentioned at the meeting, which means that the role and status of finance in supporting the development of the real economy have been greatly enhanced. &quot;Five major articles on technology finance, green finance, inclusive finance, pension finance, and digital finance&quot; are exactly the targeted deployment to improve the quality and efficiency of financial services to the real economy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Le Yugui, general manager of the Strategy and Policy Coordination Department of China Construction Bank, said that the five major areas deployed at the meeting have been incorporated into China Construction Bank’s development strategy and strategic measures. In the next step, China Construction Bank will accelerate product, service and model innovation , improve the adaptability of resource allocation and assessment and incentive policies, and write five major articles on finance in the new era. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the factory of Hefei Ruishi Digital Technology Co., Ltd., High-tech Zone, Hefei City, Anhui Province, staff are assembling clinical all-digital PET equipment. Thanks to the support of relevant financial loans, the company has successfully entered the market with 7 different models of equipment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We are deeply encouraged by the meeting’s proposal to use more financial resources to promote technological innovation, advanced manufacturing, green development and small, medium and micro enterprises.” Zhang Bo, general manager of the company, said, “We will further strengthen We will conduct scientific research and strive to achieve high-quality and large-scale application of digital PET equipment as soon as possible.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unblocking the channels for funds to enter the real economy is an important part of the high-quality development of financial services. Lian Ping, chairman of the China Chief Economist Forum, said that plans such as &quot;improving institutional positioning&quot; and &quot;strengthening market rules to create a financial market with unified rules and coordinated supervision&quot; will help speed up the construction of a multi-level capital market and promote efficient allocation of resources. , providing enterprises with more investment and financing channels. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The high-quality development of financial services is inseparable from the hub function of the capital market. &quot;We will firmly grasp the fundamental purpose of serving the real economy, coordinate &#39;equity&#39; and &#39;debt&#39;, adhere to the linkage of stocks and bonds, optimize the financing structure, unblock all kinds of capital elements into the real economy, and provide high-quality financial services for economic and social development .&quot; said Zhou Xiaozhou, director of the Bond Department of the China Securities Regulatory Commission. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Coordinate development and safety to promote the steady progress of the financial industry&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Safety is the prerequisite for development, and development is the guarantee of safety. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cui Weijie, deputy director of the Institute of International Trade and Economic Cooperation of the Ministry of Commerce, said that the meeting released a lot of new information on how to coordinate development and security, especially the proposal to insist on coordinating financial openness and security, and steadily expand the institutional type in the financial field. Opening up and other contents are considerations to adapt to the new development situation at home and abroad, ensure that financial management capabilities match the level of openness, and are also necessary to build a financial power. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the Xiamen area of ​​China (Fujian) Pilot Free Trade Zone, the exploration of combining financial openness and risk prevention has been ongoing.该片区管委会副主任郑耀说：“开放创新要管得住才放得开，我们要对标会议精神，稳步扩大金融领域制度型开放，积极对接国际高标准，提升跨境投融资便利化。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;防控风险是金融工作的永恒主题。在中信建投证券首席经济学家黄文涛看来，会议直面问题，回应了市场关注的多个热点，包括处置中小金融机构风险、建立防范化解地方债务风险长效机制、促进金融与房地产良性循环、加强外汇市场管理等方面。他表示，会议将房地产和金融问题统一来看，强调加强监管和风险防范，并通过建设保障性住房等房地产发展新模式应对目前市场供求关系的深刻变化，这些举措意义重大，影响深远。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“会议将全面加强金融监管、有效防范化解金融风险作为重点，提出对风险早识别、早预警、早暴露、早处置，释放了强监管、严监管的信号。”金融监管总局风险处置工作负责人何国锋说，金融监管部门将认真落实会议提出的“全面强化机构监管、行为监管、功能监管、穿透式监管、持续监管”要求，着力提升监管能力和有效性，坚决消除监管空白和盲区，牢牢守住风险底线。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新征程，新使命。 “中央金融工作会议为坚定不移走好中国特色金融发展之路、推动金融高质量发展提供了根本遵循。”中国银行副行长张小东表示，国有金融机构要坚决当好服务实体经济的主力军和维护金融稳定的压舱石，为加快建设金融强国持续贡献力量。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（新华社北京11月2日电）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 加力推进农机装备补短板和农业机械稳链强链]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/03/nw.D110000renmrb_20231103_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月03日星期五&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报北京11月2日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者郁静娴）日前，农业农村部、工业和信息化部联合召开全国农机装备补短板暨农业机械稳链强链工作会议，要求加力推进农机装备补短板和农业机械稳链强链工作走深走实，为全面推进乡村振兴、加快建设农业强国提供有力的装备支撑。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;记者从会上获悉：农业农村部、工业和信息化部联合启动农机装备补短板行动两年来，聚焦大型大马力机械、丘陵山区适用小型机械以及智能化等领域的农机装备短板扎实开展攻关，一批关键机具研发应用取得明显进展，一些地方农机装备产业集群正在形成，产业链韧性进一步增强，农机装备正加快向“大中小型兼备、绿色高效智能一体”迈进，但对标农业生产一线急需和国际先进水平还有差距。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;据介绍，当前要重点围绕主要粮油作物大面积提升单产、大豆油料生产水平提升、现代设施农业和智慧农业发展、农业防灾减灾救灾等重点领域，加力推进高性能精量播种机、轻简型玉米收获机、移动式烘干机等急需急用农机装备研发应用。要深刻认识新时代新征程发展农机装备的重要性、紧迫性，紧紧围绕保障国家粮食和重要农产品稳定安全供给、推动农业高质量发展，着眼于农业急需、农民急用，坚持“一大一小”加智能化方向，推动大马力机械迭代升级，加大轻简型适用机具研发推广力度，推进智能化关键部件攻关等，努力补上农机领域突出短板，实现农业机械稳链强链。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;要全产业全链条协同推进农机装备补短板和农业机械稳链强链。针对已经梳理排查出的短板弱项，区分轻重缓急、列出优先序，用足用好相关政策，支持优势企业承担专项任务，分级分类推进研发攻关。加快样机熟化定型，在“一大一小”农机装备研发制造推广应用先导区启动建设一批标准化规范化的熟化定型和推广应用基地，建立快速便利鉴定与检验检测通道。在农田建设中充分考虑农机作业和通行条件改善，将宜机化作为品种培育的重要要求，因地制宜探索形成并推广宜机化种植模式，持续拓展农业机具装备应用场景。扶优建强农机应用主体，加快培育建设一批平急两用的区域性农机社会化服务中心，强化机手田间实训、实机操作，抓好作业质量监测。着力培育优质企业，努力打造具有生态主导力的产业链“链主”企业，支持专精特新中小企业打造更多“独门绝技”，推动工程机械、汽车、电子信息等领域企业助力农机装备发展，培育建设一批农机装备特色产业集群。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 普惠小微贷款余额同比增长24.1%]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/03/nw.D110000renmrb_20231103_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月03日星期五&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报北京11月2日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者吴秋余）中国人民银行发布的今年三季度金融机构贷款投向统计报告显示，三季度我国普惠金融各领域贷款增长较快。截至今年三季度末，普惠小微贷款余额28.74万亿元，同比增长24.1%，增速比上年末高0.3个百分点，前三季度增加4.95万亿元，同比多增1.01万亿元。农户生产经营贷款余额9.15万亿元，同比增长17.8%。创业担保贷款余额2965亿元，同比增长10.1%。助学贷款余额1651亿元，同比增长23.6%。全国脱贫人口贷款余额1.14万亿元，同比增长12.2%，前三季度累计发放7145亿元。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;与此同时，三季度涉农贷款持续增长。截至三季度末，本外币涉农贷款余额55.8万亿元，同比增长15.1%，增速比上年末高1.1个百分点；前三季度增加6.63万亿元，同比多增1.17万亿元。农村（县及县以下）贷款余额46.6万亿元，同比增长15.4%。农户贷款余额16.67万亿元，同比增长12.6%。农业贷款余额5.8万亿元，同比增长14.6%。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;此外，三季度我国贷款支持科创企业力度较大。截至三季度末，获得贷款支持的科技型中小企业21.28万家，获贷率47%，比上年末高2.7个百分点。科技型中小企业本外币贷款余额2.42万亿元，同比增长22.6%，比上年末低3.1个百分点，比同期各项贷款增速高12.4个百分点。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 各地区各部门扎实推动城乡融合发展（走进市场看信心）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/03/nw.D110000renmrb_20231103_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月03日星期五&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;习近平总书记指出，充分发挥乡村作为消费市场和要素市场的重要作用，全面推进乡村振兴，推进以县城为重要载体的城镇化建设，推动城乡融合发展，增强城乡经济联系，畅通城乡经济循环。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家统计局数据显示，今年1至9月，乡村消费品零售额45697亿元，同比增长7.4%；前三季度，农村居民人均可支配收入15705元，同比名义增长7.6%，扣除价格因素，实际增长7.3%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我国广阔的县域地区市场基础好、潜力大，在扩大内需、畅通循环方面发挥着重要作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;各地区各部门采取有效行动，提高居民收入和保障水平，提升产品与服务供给水平，畅通消费渠道，激发县域地区内需活力，为加快建设全国统一大市场、畅通国民经济循环注入重要动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;加强市场体系建设&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我国经济具有巨大的发展韧性和潜力，长期向好的基本面没有改变。乡村既是巨大的消费市场，又是巨大的要素市场，加快释放市场潜力，对扩内需、稳增长意义重大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当前，乡镇和村两级消费市场占我国消费市场的38%，是扩内需、促循环的关键节点。各地区各部门推出一系列举措，着力增强消费能力，大力拓展投资空间，推动县域经济稳步发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多措并举，全面激发消费潜力。商务部将2023年定为“消费提振年”，许多县域地区顺势推出一系列活动，改善消费条件，创新消费场景，带动家电、汽车等大件商品以及绿色建材下乡热销，促进服务消费提质扩容，推动消费市场继续回升向好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;推进乡村振兴，拓展投资空间。甘肃省提出，今年将创建20个省级现代农业产业园，未来3至5年基本实现现代农业产业园县级全覆盖。安徽省提出，新建高标准农田200万亩，培育一批农产品加工业强县、强园、强企，新增产值超10亿元龙头企业10家、产值超50亿元加工园区3家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加强市场体系建设能够有效提升居民生活品质，更好满足人们对美好生活的向往，更是形成强大国内市场的有效抓手。各地区积极探索创新，形成一批好经验好做法，将推动市场迸发更大活力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;消费出现升级趋势&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年40岁的赵东晓是河北省邯郸市永年区西苏镇东苏村人，受益于当地促就业政策，赵东晓当起了“月嫂”，每月能挣七八千元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前些天，赵东晓和朋友走进镇上商业步行街，感受小镇的活力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人均收入持续增加、商业设施更加完善、电子商务创新发展……当前，县域地区促进消费、扩大投资、畅通经济循环的有利条件不断积聚，为推进乡村振兴、推动城乡融合发展夯实基础。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;消费升级趋势明显，乡村消费市场扩容空间大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近日，在河南省获嘉县后寺村新能源汽车展销会现场，来试驾的村民马跃说：“新能源汽车既时尚又环保，还能享受政策补贴，我准备预订一辆。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新能源汽车、智能手机、智慧家电、品质家具……如今，越来越多的消费升级类产品进入百姓生活。居民发展型、品质型消费需求显著增强，数字化消费快速增长且应用场景更加优化。相关研究表明，“十四五”时期，县域城镇化水平将提高2个百分点，除带动房地产下游行业的家具和装修消费快速增长外，也将促进相应的托育、早教、养老、信息等服务消费的进一步扩大。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;商业网络不断完善，农村物流配送体系持续健全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多部门加强政策支持，指导各地深入推进县域商业体系建设并取得积极成效，进一步畅通了城乡商品、服务和生产要素流通渠道，改善了农村生产生活条件。2022年，全国建设改造县域综合商贸服务中心983个，乡镇商贸中心、集贸市场3941个，支持建设改造县级物流配送中心506个，乡镇快递物流站点650个，农村物流配送体系更加健全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;创新创业政策红利持续释放，为城乡发展注入动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乡村振兴，关键在人。去年5月，中办、国办印发《关于推进以县城为重要载体的城镇化建设的意见》，提出“提升产业平台功能。依托各类开发区、产业集聚区、农民工返乡创业园等平台，引导县域产业集中集聚发展”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;农业农村部通过实施农村创新创业带头人培育行动，落实创业一次性补贴等扶持政策，带动农民就地创业、就近就业。许多地方推出针对性的政策措施，强化县域商业人才供给，发挥县城和乡镇的枢纽作用，通过税收优惠、技术注资、成立孵化机构等措施，扶持有志于在县域创新创业的人才。在多项政策推动下，创新创业创造的源泉在县域充分涌流，带动了城乡发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;加快释放市场潜力&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;我国县域的流通体系、商业设施、消费环境都得到了很大改善，但在基础设施、商品和服务供给、经营主体、市场需求等方面还有一些不足。要坚持问题导向，补齐县域商业发展短板，以渠道下沉为主线，进一步做大做强县域市场，推动农村消费进一步恢复和扩大，拓展农村有效投资空间，更好助力乡村振兴，推动县域市场迈向高质量发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——加快改善农村消费环境，提高优质产品与服务供给水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在安徽省阜阳市临泉县，刘艳红一家人在当地经营了20多年小超市。顺应即时零售等新业态发展趋势，刘艳红的小店成为临泉县最早入驻外卖平台的商家之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“为了增加销售量，平台派出辅导员帮助小店精细化运营。平台通过实时数据驱动，精准匹配供给，动态智能调度，短时间内就能处理上万笔订单，让小店和骑手实现了快速更新货品和快速配送。我们为附近居民提供24小时即时服务，方便了群众生活，生意也越做越好了。”刘艳红说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;专家表示，要加快改善农村消费环境，坚持市场化原则，发挥财政资金引导作用。改造升级一批“乡镇大集”、农村新型便利店，健全县乡村物流配送体系，发展即时零售、共同配送等新模式，创新消费场景，激发消费潜力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——推动农村电商高质量发展，助力农产品销售和农民增收。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近日，在四川省南充市仪陇县马鞍镇南海村，34岁的曹海龙向村民收购新鲜鸭蛋，半天时间就收购了近千枚鲜鸭蛋。曹海龙是仪陇县德笙源农业开发有限公司负责人，经营蛋类加工生意，通过线上线下相结合的方式销售。在销售旺季，每天都有一辆辆快递车直接开到加工厂门口，产品销往全国各地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据仪陇县民营经济发展和电子商务服务中心副主任郑平介绍，全县积极推进县、乡、村三级公共服务体系建设，充分发挥县级电商产业园示范集聚效应，建成了11个乡（镇）级电商运营服务中心，配备专门的服务团队，为村级电商站点提供综合服务，有力带动当地特色产业发展，促进老百姓增收致富。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;农业农村部相关负责人表示，要深入推进农业生产和农产品“三品一标”，增加绿色优质农产品供给，引导食品消费升级。健全农村市场流通体系，让城市的产品和农村的产品通行顺畅，促进家电家具等耐用品消费增长，改善农村生产生活服务供给，扩大服务消费。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据介绍，商务部将会同有关部门加快总结前期工作经验并复制推广，争取到2025年在具备条件的县，基本建立较为完善的县乡村商业体系，更好满足农村群众的生产生活需要。同时，因地制宜、探索创新，调动地方、企业和群众的积极性，打造一批县域商业典型，发挥示范引领作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;相信随着我国乡村市场体系更加完善，市场潜力将加快释放，为推动中国经济大船行稳致远作出更大贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 绿色贷款余额至三季度末超28万亿元]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/03/nw.D110000renmrb_20231103_5-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月03日星期五&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报北京11月2日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者吴秋余）中国人民银行发布数据显示：截至2023年三季度末，我国本外币绿色贷款余额28.58万亿元，同比增长36.8%，高于各项贷款增速26.6个百分点，比年初增加6.98万亿元。其中，投向具有直接和间接碳减排效益项目的贷款分别为9.96万亿元和9.14万亿元，合计占绿色贷款的66.8%。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;分用途看，基础设施绿色升级产业、清洁能源产业和节能环保产业贷款余额分别为12.45万亿元、7.27万亿元和4.13万亿元，同比分别增长32.8%、36.2%和42.3%，比年初分别增加2.74万亿元、1.73万亿元和1.16万亿元。分行业看，电力、热力、燃气及水生产和供应业绿色贷款余额6.8万亿元，同比增长27.6%，比年初增加1.3万亿元；交通运输、仓储和邮政业绿色贷款余额5.1万亿元，同比增长13.8%。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 03 Nov 2023 05:56:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>