<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平出席金砖国家领导人巴以问题特别视频峰会]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20231122_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 22, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/22/01/rmrb2023112201p19_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the evening of November 21, President Xi Jinping attended the BRICS leaders’ special video summit on the Palestinian-Israeli issue and delivered an important speech titled &quot;Promoting Ceasefire and War to Achieve Lasting Peace and Security.&quot; &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Huang Jingwen&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot; center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/22/01/rmrb2023112201p18_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR >; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the evening of November 21, President Xi Jinping attended the BRICS leaders’ special video summit on the Palestinian-Israeli issue and delivered an important speech titled &quot;Promoting Ceasefire and War to Achieve Lasting Peace and Security.&quot; &lt;BR/>;Photographed by Xinhua News Agency reporter Liu Bin&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;■This summit is the BRICS expansion The first leaders’ meeting since. Under the current situation, it is very timely and necessary for the BRICS countries to make a voice of justice and peace on the Palestinian-Israeli issue. The conflict in Gaza has lasted for more than a month, causing a large number of civilian casualties and humanitarian disasters, and showing a trend of expanding spillover. China is deeply concerned. The top priority is that all parties to the conflict must immediately cease fire and fighting, stop all violence and attacks against civilians, and release detained civilians to avoid more serious devastation. The second is to ensure the safe and smooth flow of humanitarian relief channels, provide more humanitarian assistance to the Gaza people, and stop forced relocation, water, electricity and oil cuts and other collective punishments against the Gaza people. Third, the international community must take practical measures to prevent the conflict from expanding and affecting the stability of the entire Middle East region. All parties should implement the requirements of the relevant resolutions of the United Nations General Assembly and the Security Council&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■The fundamental reason why the situation between Palestine and Israel has developed to this day is that the Palestinian people&#39;s rights to statehood, survival, and return have been ignored for a long time. The fundamental way out to resolve the recurring conflict between Palestine and Israel is to implement the &quot;two-state solution&quot;, restore the legitimate rights of the Palestinian nation, and establish an independent Palestinian state. Without an unfair solution to the Palestinian issue, there will be no lasting peace and stability in the Middle East. China calls for a more authoritative international peace conference to be convened as soon as possible to build international consensus on peace promotion and promote an early comprehensive, just and lasting solution to the Palestinian issue&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■Since the outbreak of this round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict, China has actively promoted peace Promote talks, promote a ceasefire and an end to the war, provide emergency humanitarian assistance to the Gaza Strip, and will continue to provide material assistance based on the needs of the Gaza people. As the rotating president of the United Nations Security Council this month, China has pushed the Security Council to pass relevant resolutions, requiring the extension of the humanitarian moratorium and humanitarian corridors, the protection of civilians, and the development of humanitarian assistance.&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■ The BRICS cooperation mechanism is an emerging It is an important platform for market countries and developing countries to strengthen unity and cooperation and safeguard common interests. Today, we coordinated our positions and took actions on the Palestinian-Israeli issue, making a good start for the &quot;Greater BRICS Cooperation&quot; after the expansion. China is willing to work with other members to create a new era of BRICS cooperation&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 21. On the evening of November 21, President Xi Jinping attended the BRICS Leaders of BRIC countries held a special video summit on the Palestinian-Israeli issue and delivered an important speech titled &quot;Promoting Ceasefire and War Ending to Achieve Lasting Peace and Security.&quot; (See the second page for the full text of his speech)&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that this summit is the first leaders’ meeting after the expansion of the BRICS. Under the current situation, it is very timely and necessary for the BRICS countries to make a voice of justice and peace on the Palestinian-Israeli issue. The conflict in Gaza has lasted for more than a month, causing a large number of civilian casualties and humanitarian disasters, and showing a trend of expanding spillover. China is deeply concerned. The top priority is that all parties to the conflict must immediately cease fire and fighting, stop all violence and attacks against civilians, and release detained civilians to avoid more serious devastation. The second is to ensure the safe and smooth flow of humanitarian relief channels, provide more humanitarian assistance to the Gaza people, and stop forced relocation, water, electricity and oil cuts and other collective punishments against the Gaza people. Third, the international community must take practical measures to prevent the conflict from expanding and affecting the stability of the entire Middle East region. All parties should implement the requirements of relevant resolutions of the United Nations General Assembly and Security Council. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that the fundamental reason why the situation between Palestine and Israel has developed to this day is that the Palestinian people&#39;s rights to statehood, survival, and return have been ignored for a long time. The fundamental way out to resolve the recurring conflict between Palestine and Israel is to implement the &quot;two-state solution&quot;, restore the legitimate rights of the Palestinian nation, and establish an independent Palestinian state. Without an unfair solution to the Palestinian issue, there will be no lasting peace and stability in the Middle East. China calls for a more authoritative international peace conference to be convened as soon as possible to build international consensus on promoting peace and promote an early comprehensive, just and lasting solution to the Palestinian issue. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that since the current round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict broke out, China has actively promoted peace talks, promoted a ceasefire and an end to the war, provided emergency humanitarian assistance to the Gaza Strip, and will continue to provide material assistance according to the needs of the Gaza people. . As the rotating president of the United Nations Security Council this month, China has pushed the Security Council to pass relevant resolutions, requiring the extension of the humanitarian moratorium and humanitarian corridors, the protection of civilians, and the provision of humanitarian assistance. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that the BRICS cooperation mechanism is an important platform for emerging market countries and developing countries to strengthen unity and cooperation and safeguard common interests. Today, we coordinated our positions and took actions on the Palestinian-Israeli issue, making a good start for the &quot;Greater BRICS Cooperation&quot; after the expansion. China is willing to work with other members to create a new era of BRICS cooperation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;South African President Ramaphosa presided over the summit. Brazilian President Lula, Russian President Putin, Saudi Crown Prince Mohammed, Egyptian President Sisi, Iranian President Raisi, UAE President Mohammed, Ethiopian Prime Minister Abiy, and Indian, The Argentine Foreign Minister attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The leaders at the meeting expressed serious concern about the situation between Palestine and Israel, condemned all acts of violence against civilians, stressed the need to protect civilians in accordance with international humanitarian law, and called for the immediate implementation of a lasting and sustained humanitarian truce and the provision of humanitarian assistance. , emphasizing the resolution of disputes through dialogue and supporting all efforts conducive to peaceful resolution of crises. The leaders called on the international community to support a just solution to the Palestinian issue, promote the realization of the &quot;two-state solution&quot; and establish an independent Palestinian state with full sovereignty. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cai Qi, Wang Yi and others attended the summit. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 前三季度国家铁路共发送货物28.97亿吨（新数据 新看点）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20231122_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 22, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Our newspaper, Beijing, November 21 (Reporter Li Xinping) A reporter recently reported from China State Railway Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;National Railway Group&quot;) was informed that in the first three quarters of this year, the national railways shipped a total of 2.897 billion tons of cargo, with an average of 176,600 vehicles loaded per day, and cargo transportation maintained a high level. Among them, 1.135 billion tons of thermal coal were sent. As of the end of September, the number of days of coal storage in 371 direct railway power plants across the country remained at more than 37 days. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Freight transportation capacity continues to expand. China Railway Group implements &quot;one port, one policy&quot; and &quot;one enterprise, one policy&quot;, actively promotes &quot;road-to-rail&quot; transportation, and increases railway transportation volume. The country&#39;s major ports and railways load an average of 31,500 vehicles per day, a year-on-year increase of 5.8%, ore The average daily loading volume was 28,100 vehicles, a year-on-year increase of 2.2%. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;International transport improves quality and efficiency. We continued to implement measures to expand the number and tonnage of China-Europe trains and improve train marshalling and port station handover capabilities. In the third quarter, major railway ports delivered an average of 2,479 vehicles per day, an increase of 271 vehicles year-on-year; and received an average of 3,176 vehicles per day, an increase of 565 vehicles year-on-year. Hit another record high. In the first three quarters, China-Europe freight trains operated a total of 13,000 trains and sent 1.42 million TEUs of goods, a year-on-year increase of 7% and 20% respectively; the Western Land-Sea Corridor sea-rail combined transport containers sent a total of 633,000 TEUs of goods, a year-on-year increase of 14.2%; The old railway has transported a total of 3.55 million tons of cross-border cargo, a year-on-year increase of 143%. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Freight products have been optimized and improved. In the first three quarters, the national railway container dispatched 24.29 million TEUs, a year-on-year increase of 5.7%, and the rail-water combined transport completed 9.45 million TEUs, a year-on-year increase of 10.3%. Successfully launched a full train of high-speed rail express trains, a 50-foot container rail multi-link express train, and a 35-ton wide-body container rail-sea express line. The cargo transportation timeliness and comprehensive logistics costs have been continuously reduced, better meeting the diverse transportation needs of customers. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 李强将出席二十国集团领导人视频峰会]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20231122_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 22, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 21st&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Foreign Ministry Spokesperson Mao Ning announced on the 21st: In response to the Government of the Republic of India Invited, Premier Li Qiang of the State Council will attend the G20 Leaders’ Video Summit on November 22. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 赵乐际同俄罗斯国家杜马主席沃洛金举行会谈]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20231122_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 22, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 21 (reporter permission) Zhao Leji, Chairman of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, on the 21st In the afternoon, he held talks with Volodin, Chairman of the Russian State Duma, at the Great Hall of the People. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Zhao Leji said that under the strategic guidance of President Xi Jinping and President Putin, the China-Russia Comprehensive Strategic Partnership for a New Era has always maintained the right direction, with political mutual trust constantly consolidated, pragmatic cooperation flourishing, and people-to-people exchanges and local exchanges continuing. deepened and set a model for a new type of major-country relations. No matter how the international situation changes, China and Russia must abide by the major principles of &quot;four mutual and firm support&quot; established by the two heads of state, work together to consolidate and develop comprehensive strategic coordination, continue to benefit the two peoples, and safeguard international fairness and justice. The two sides should continue to promote the integration of the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; and the Eurasian Economic Union, achieve more practical cooperation results, and promote cooperation in mechanisms such as the Shanghai Cooperation Organization and BRICS. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Zhao Leji said that the high level of exchanges between the legislative bodies of China and Russia is one of the important symbols of the strategic and special nature of the relations between the two countries. The China-Russia Parliamentary Cooperation Committee established by both parties is a solid and effective platform to enhance political mutual trust, promote practical cooperation, and inherit the friendship between the peoples. The National People&#39;s Congress of China is willing to work with the Russian Federation Council to implement the important consensus reached by the two heads of state as a top priority, further intensify exchanges and exchanges, and help the two countries continue to develop their comprehensive strategic partnership of coordination for a new era. Thank you to the Russian State Duma and all political parties for their long-term work in promoting friendly cooperation between China and Russia. We are willing to take the opportunity of celebrating the 75th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between the two countries next year to build on the existing good cooperation foundation and successful practices of both parties, give full play to the role of exchange mechanisms, special committees, bilateral friendship groups, offices and other platforms, and carry out in-depth multi-level and multi-field exchanges and cooperation , strengthen the exchange of experience in foreign-related legislation, and provide a solid legal guarantee for promoting cooperation between the two countries in the fields of economy, trade, finance, investment, security, information, humanities, and local areas. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Volodin said that President Putin and President Xi Jinping reached an important consensus on continuously deepening the Russia-China comprehensive strategic partnership of coordination, leading the development of bilateral relations to the best level in history. Russia firmly adheres to the one-China principle. All parties and groups in the Russian State Duma unanimously support the continuous development of friendly relations with China. The Russian State Duma is willing to work with the National People&#39;s Congress of China to implement the consensus reached by the two heads of state through legislation and other forms, give play to the active role of the Russian-Chinese Parliamentary Cooperation Committee, provide legal guarantee for promoting practical cooperation between the two countries, and enhance the relationship between Russian parliamentarians and China The mutual understanding and friendship between the deputies of the National People&#39;s Congress and the people of the two countries have contributed to the development of Russia-China relations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Peng Qinghua attended the talks. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 中国新闻奖、长江韬奋奖颁奖报告会举行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20231122_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 22, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Our newspaper, Beijing, November 21&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Zhang Shuo) Thirty-two and thirty-three The 2018 China Journalism Awards and the 17th Yangtze River Taofen Award Awards Presentation Ceremony was held in Beijing on the 21st. Cai Qi, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and secretary of the Secretariat of the CPC Central Committee, met with the award-winning representatives. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;At 9:30 a.m., Cai Qi came to the North Hall of the Great Hall of the People to express warm congratulations to the award-winning representatives and took photos with everyone. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Li Shulei, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and director of the Propaganda Department of the CPC Central Committee, attended the meeting, attended the report meeting and delivered a speech. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The meeting requires that the majority of journalists should take the study of Xi Jinping’s cultural thoughts as a required course, deeply understand the significance, rich connotation and practical requirements of this important thought, and consciously implement it in all aspects of news and public opinion work Throughout the whole process, we strive to be a new-era journalist with feelings, skills, and responsibility. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The meeting emphasized that the news front should strengthen positive publicity with a focus on strong confidence, use new concepts, new categories, and new expressions that integrate both China and foreign countries to tell the story of China, the story of the Communist Party of China, and the story of the new era, and actively use new technologies and new technologies. The new means of the platform promote the construction of the all-media communication system and continuously create new situations in news and public opinion work. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;He Ping, Chairman of the China Journalists Association, delivered a speech at the meeting. Representatives from the People&#39;s Navy Newspaper, Workers&#39; Daily, People&#39;s Daily, Xinhua News Agency, China Central Radio and Television, Zhejiang Radio and Television Group, and Harbin Daily spoke successively. About 310 people attended the meeting, including members of the Central Leading Group for Propaganda, Ideology and Culture, relevant departments of the Central and State agencies, responsible comrades of major central news units and representatives of journalists. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 锚定目标任务  见行动出实效（学思想 强党性 重实践 建新功）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20231122_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 22, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;In the course of studying and implementing the theme education of Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, Chongqing fully implemented the Party Central Committee’s decisions and arrangements, and closely Keep the main thread of the theme, anchor the goals and tasks, make careful arrangements and organize carefully, summarize and apply the successful experience of the first batch of thematic education, and promote the second batch of thematic education to be deeper and more practical. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Study, think, practice, and learn theory into the brain and heart&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the second batch of thematic education, Chongqing has always regarded theoretical learning as a way to strengthen ideals and beliefs. It is an important way to promote Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era into the mind and heart through rich and diverse forms. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Nan&#39;an District focuses on the key points of learning and carries out targeted thematic education according to the different characteristics of each level to ensure deep understanding and achieve effective integration of party classes and seminars. &quot;Party classes have begun&quot; and &quot;cadre lecture hall&quot; Various activities were carried out in depth. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In order to ensure full coverage of theoretical learning, Nan&#39;an District has given full play to its role as a party-mass service center and has set up more than 100 learning &quot;check-in points&quot; and &quot;charging stations&quot;, using methods such as door-to-door delivery of books and pairing to help students. Relying on the theoretical propaganda team, more than 450 theoretical lectures were carried out for grassroots party members, covering more than 20,000 people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The leadership team at or above the county level in Chongqing has implemented &quot;learning and thinking&quot; throughout, and adopted methods such as party committee (party group) meetings, reading classes, central group study, and individual self-study to learn from the original source and realize it seriously. Based on their job responsibilities, district and county leading cadres carefully studied the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speeches and important instructions. After completing no less than 7 days of reading class study, the district and county leading teams insisted on conducting no less than 1 central group special topic every month. discussion. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;In-depth research, benchmarking and deployment&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Each district and county formulates specific plans in different areas according to different levels and characteristics of different objects, and refines the implementation. chemical work measures. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Catch the &quot;nose&quot; and choose the topic accurately. Jiangbei District focused on the most prominent and urgent issues and focused on &quot;small incisions.&quot; District-level leaders and members of the leadership team of 95 district-administered units determined research topics. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Resettlement of real estate rights, resolution of property conflicts and disputes, installation of elevators in old communities, new small and micro parking spaces... Focusing on the &quot;Eight Problem List&quot; and people&#39;s livelihood issues that have been strongly reported by the masses, Jiangbei District Housing Urban and Rural The Construction Committee has identified 8 research topics and typical cases of one positive and one negative. All members of the leadership team have conducted in-depth investigations on the front lines of enterprises, construction project sites, and property communities, and have proposed 37 solutions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strengthen the coordination of research and development, and do not engage in large-scale research. The Liangjiang New Area Party Working Committee strengthened coordination, sorted out hot spots according to the division-level cadre survey plan, and made adjustments in advance to effectively avoid clustered surveys, multiple surveys, and repeated surveys. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the second batch of thematic education, Chongqing cooperated with the Central Committee’s Eighth Circuit Steering Group to conduct in-depth research and guidance in 12 districts and counties through on-site visits, discussions and exchanges; it dispatched 20 roving supervision groups and 5 investigation teams The unannounced investigation team strictly supervises and guides the districts and counties “from one pole to the end”. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For problems discovered during the investigation, ensure that rectifications are implemented without compromise. By establishing a working mechanism for linking up and down rectification and rectification, and smoothing the channels for handing over problems, Chongqing promoted the vertical integration and two-way recognition of the rectification of problems in the first and second batches of thematic education units to form a &quot;loop&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Benefit the people and do practical things &quot;at the grassroots level&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In order to do a good job in linking the first batch of thematic education with the second batch of thematic education , Chongqing closely combines thematic education with solving practical problems at the grassroots level, and promotes leading cadres to &quot;go to the grassroots level four times&quot;. They visit the grassroots level every month, receive interviews, work on-site, publicize policies, respond to people&#39;s demands, resolve backlog of petitions, and solve a number of people&#39;s complaints. Urgent, difficult and anxious issues. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On November 10, more than 7,000 teachers and students from Sichuan Instrument Industrial School took the first customized bus in Chengjiang Town, Beibei District, enjoying &quot;point-to-point&quot; travel services. In the past, there was congestion at the school gate during rush hours, causing transportation inconvenience to teachers and students. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After discovering that there was inconvenience in the travel of teachers and students of Sichuan Instrument Industrial School, the Beibei District Transportation Bureau immediately took the lead in linking the traffic law enforcement brigade, transportation management departments, bus companies and other relevant responsible units to the school to conduct visits and surveys, focusing on students We distributed questionnaires on travel issues to understand students’ travel modes and directions, adjusted bus arrangements in a timely manner, and added customized buses from the school gate to Beibei City to deliver convenient services to the hearts of teachers and students. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Can charging be done on rainy days? Will there be electricity leakage without a canopy...&quot; On rainy days, Yang Xiaolian, a resident of Xinfeng Community, Jinfeng Town, High-tech Zone, is worried about hidden dangers in charging, so she goes through the integrated management of Jinfeng Town The smart governance platform reflects the problem of the lack of canopies at charging piles. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After receiving the task assigned by the platform, the community grid staff immediately went into the community to conduct research and visits, checked the charging pile situation on site, invited professional power personnel to conduct on-site inspections, formed a research report and filled it in through the mobile phone Relevant research situations. After receiving the report from the grid members, the Jinfeng Town Grassroots Governance Command Center provided a solution to install canopies. Behind the rapid solution to people&#39;s livelihood problems, it is Jinfeng Town&#39;s smart grassroots governance system that plays a role. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At present, all districts and counties in Chongqing are deeply implementing actions to benefit the people, warm their hearts and provide good services, and vigorously promote the integrated service of &quot;one thing, one time&quot;. At the same time, we will understand social conditions and public opinion through livelihood hotlines, WeChat platforms, online surveys and other channels, and strive to solve outstanding problems in employment, education, medical care, childcare, housing, elderly care and other fields. The disaster-stricken areas and counties have seized the opportunity to promote post-disaster recovery work such as house repair and reconstruction, so that the people can truly feel the actual effectiveness of thematic education. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 韩正会见乌兹别克斯坦外长赛义多夫]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20231122_7-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 22, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 21st&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;On November 21st, Vice President Han Zheng met with Uzbekistan in Beijing Stan Saidov, Minister of Foreign Affairs. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Han Zheng said that China and Uzbekistan are both ancient civilizations in the world, and the ancient Silk Road has witnessed the friendly exchanges between the two peoples for more than two thousand years. Since the establishment of diplomatic relations 31 years ago, the two sides have always treated each other as equals, respected each other, and trusted each other, promoting the sustained, healthy and stable development of China-Uzbekistan relations. Under the strategic guidance and personal promotion of the two heads of state, the development of China-Uzbekistan relations has entered a new era, and cooperation in various fields has entered a fast lane, injecting new impetus into the common development and prosperity of the two countries. China is willing to increase mutual support with Uzbekistan, accelerate the docking of development strategies, and transform the high-level political relations between the two countries into tangible results to better benefit the two peoples. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Saidov said that Ukraine-China relations are at the best and highest level in history. Uzbekistan regards China as its most important comprehensive strategic partner and is willing to strengthen strategic dialogue with China, implement the important consensus reached by the two heads of state, and continuously deepen mutually beneficial cooperation between the two countries in various fields. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 推动停火止战  实现持久和平安全]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20231122_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, 22 November 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Dear President Ramaphosa,&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dear colleagues:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; This summit is the first leaders’ meeting after the BRICS expansion. First of all, I would like to welcome the leaders of the new BRICS members and thank President Ramaphosa and the South African government for their efforts in this meeting. Under the current situation, it is very timely and necessary for the BRICS countries to make a voice of justice and peace on the Palestinian-Israeli issue. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The conflict in Gaza has lasted for more than a month, causing a large number of civilian casualties and humanitarian disasters, and showing a trend of expanding spillover. China is deeply concerned. The top priority is that all parties to the conflict must immediately cease fire and fighting, stop all violence and attacks against civilians, and release detained civilians to avoid more serious devastation. The second is to ensure the safe and smooth flow of humanitarian relief channels, provide more humanitarian assistance to the Gaza people, and stop forced relocation, water, electricity and oil cuts and other collective punishments against the Gaza people. Third, the international community must take practical measures to prevent the conflict from expanding and affecting the stability of the entire Middle East region. China supports the resolution passed on October 27 at the emergency special session of the United Nations General Assembly on the Palestinian-Israeli conflict. As the rotating president of the United Nations Security Council, China presided over the adoption of Security Council Resolution 2712. All parties should implement the resolution&#39;s requirements. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fundamental reason why the situation between Palestine and Israel has developed to this day is that the Palestinian people&#39;s rights to statehood, survival, and return have been ignored for a long time. I have emphasized many times that the fundamental way to resolve the cycle of Palestinian-Israeli conflicts is to implement the &quot;two-state solution&quot;, restore the legitimate rights of the Palestinian nation, and establish an independent Palestinian state. Without an unfair solution to the Palestinian issue, there will be no lasting peace and stability in the Middle East. China calls for a more authoritative international peace conference to be convened as soon as possible to build international consensus on promoting peace and promote an early comprehensive, just and lasting solution to the Palestinian issue. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the current round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict broke out, China has actively promoted peace talks and promoted a ceasefire and an end to the war. In order to alleviate the humanitarian situation in Gaza, China has provided $2 million in emergency humanitarian assistance through the Palestinian National Authority and United Nations agencies, provided food, medicine and other emergency humanitarian supplies worth 15 million yuan to the Gaza Strip through Egypt, and Material assistance will continue to be provided based on the needs of the Gaza people. As the rotating president of the United Nations Security Council this month, China has pushed the Security Council to pass relevant resolutions, requiring the extension of the humanitarian moratorium and humanitarian corridors, the protection of civilians, and the provision of humanitarian assistance. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dear colleagues! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The BRICS cooperation mechanism is an important platform for emerging market countries and developing countries to strengthen unity and cooperation and safeguard common interests. Today, we coordinated our positions and took actions on the Palestinian-Israeli issue, making a good start for the &quot;Greater BRICS Cooperation&quot; after the expansion. China appreciates South Africa&#39;s important contribution to promoting the development of BRICS as this year&#39;s chairmanship. Russia will take over the presidency next year, and China is willing to work with other members to support Russia&#39;s work and create a new era of BRICS cooperation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thank you everyone! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 21)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 护安澜  畅航道  送绿电（经济新方位·重大工程一线）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20231122_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 22, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231122/1700597019737_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;The picture shows the Dadengxia Water Conservancy Project. &lt;BR/>;Photo provided by Dateng Gorge Company&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;The deep river is winding with green water, and the green mountains on the bank are Welcome the ship. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From northwest to southeast, the rushing river passes through Dadeng Gorge, the longest and largest canyon in Guangxi, adding a magnificent landscape among the green mountains and green waters. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the Nutan Beach at the exit of Dateng Gorge, a dam about 1.2 kilometers long lies across the river. There is a power plant next to the discharge gate dam, a ship lock is built on the left bank, and the factory building on the right bank is closely connected to the retaining dam. It is also convenient. The Qianjiang fishway for fish migration, the auxiliary dam and the Nanmujiang ecological fishway are upstream of the main dam - this is the Dadengxia water conservancy hub, one of the country&#39;s 172 major water conservancy projects for water conservation and water supply, and an important backbone project of the national water network. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On September 2, with the last unit officially put into operation for power generation, the main project of the Dadengxia Water Conservancy Project was completed after nine years of arduous construction. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Two and a half months after its completion, reporters came to the project site to see how the project achieved comprehensive benefits such as flood control, water resources allocation, shipping, power generation, and irrigation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;b>;Improve coastal flood control standards and significantly shorten the basin’s emergency water replenishment response time&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “The multi-year average total water resources in the Pearl River Basin is second only to the Yangtze River. The biggest feature is that The water is abundant.&quot; Huang Jun, chief engineer of Guangxi Datangxia Water Conservancy Development Co., Ltd. (hereinafter referred to as &quot;Datengxia Company&quot;) pointed to the water system map and said, &quot;The Datangxia Water Conservancy Project has significant benefits in terms of flood control and water resources regulation.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Pearl River Basin covers an area of ​​453,700 square kilometers, of which the Xijiang River is the largest river. The drainage area of ​​the water system accounts for about 75% of the Pearl River Basin area. The Datangxia Dam site controls 56% of the Xijiang River Basin area and has become a key control project in the Pearl River Basin. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The climate in the Pearl River Basin is warm, humid and rainy, with precipitation in the flood season accounting for more than 80% of the year. In the past, the peaks of the Xijiang River in the upper reaches and the Beijiang River in the lower reaches met, often causing floods in the Pearl River Delta region. How to prevent the flood peaks of the two rivers from meeting through engineering means? It has become the first important issue of the Dadengxia Water Conservancy Project. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We looked up the maximum water inflow of historical floods and designed engineering flood control standards in accordance with the requirements of ‘once in a thousand years’.” Huang Jun said, “The flood control storage capacity is limited, and ensuring the flood control effect means more gates and scheduling. Be accurate.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Overlooking the Dadengxia Water Conservancy Project from a bird&#39;s eye view, the rushing river water flows down through 26 arc-shaped working gates. Liu Gang, deputy director of the engineering construction department of Datangxia Company, told reporters: &quot;The design of the arc-shaped gate can control the gate more accurately and ensure a good discharge state.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to reports, these 26 gates are the most popular in China. It ranks at the forefront of dam-type projects, with a maximum thrust load of a single door of 6,820 tons and a maximum total discharge capacity of 66,200 cubic meters per second. Through joint watershed dispatching, the flood control standards of Wuzhou, a national key flood control city, will be raised from a once-in-50-year flood to a once-in-a-hundred-year flood. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the Digital Twin Dadengxia Application Center, hub management center engineer Li Ying is conducting analysis operations. The status of each gate is displayed in real time on a large screen. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Through data cooperation with relevant departments, project situation awareness is all on one map.&quot; Li Ying tapped the screen, and a watershed information map unfolded in front of her eyes, &quot;You can know half a month in advance In which places it rains, which power stations increase water discharge, and how much flow will be generated, forecasts, early warnings, rehearsals, and plans can be realized.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Water regime dispatching requires both flood control and drought relief. In addition to adjusting the gates during flood control , and adjustments must also be made during water resource dispatch.&quot; Li Ying said. The precipitation in the Pearl River Basin during the dry season is less than 20%, which can easily lead to consecutive droughts in winter and spring, and salt tides in the Pearl River Estuary. &quot;In the past, it took 7-10 days to transfer water to Macau through the Tianshengqiao Reservoir and Longtan Reservoir in the upper reaches. Now it only takes 3 days to transfer water from Dateng Gorge.&quot; days.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At present, the Dadengxia Water Conservancy Project has participated in emergency water transfers 12 times, with a cumulative water replenishment volume of 1.8 billion cubic meters, strongly supporting the water supply security of the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;b>;Shipping safety and navigation capacity have been greatly improved, and the average annual cargo volume is designed to be transported 52 million tons&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking at the Qianjiang River, huge cargo ships are fully loaded with cargo and are crossing the river. The whistle sounded one after another, creating a busy scene. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Guigang is valuable because it has a port.” Guigang City is bounded by Southwest China to the west and the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area to the east. In recent years, Guangxi has proposed to enhance the Pearl River-Xijiang Economic Belt and give full play to the role of Guigang as a core port hub, through which a large number of goods will be transferred to the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ship owner Huang Huirong asked his son to help him register on his mobile phone to pass through the Dateng Gorge lock. The cargo ship entered the berth and waited for passage. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the past, when sailing across Lema Beach, one had to be energetic and flexible to pass the barrier.” 62-year-old Huang Huirong has been sailing on the Xijiang River for decades. He still has lingering fears when talking about his past experience of crossing the dangerous shoal. “That The Pearl River often collides with ships and runs aground on the rocks. Some shippers spend three to five thousand yuan to hire someone to help them sail over.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As an important water transportation channel, the Pearl River is known as the &quot;golden waterway&quot; and is the most important inland area in southwest China. It is an important link connecting the region to Guangdong, Hong Kong and Macao, and is also an important support for the joint construction of the “Belt and Road”, the construction of the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area and the construction of the Pearl River-Xijiang Economic Belt. Previously, it was a pity that the shipping advantages could not be fully utilized due to the shallow beach and strong water. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2020, the Dateng Gorge Ship Lock was opened to navigation. By raising the water level and channelizing the waterway, shipping safety and navigation capacity were greatly improved. The designed annual average cargo volume reached 52 million tons. &quot;Ship sailing has been much more stable in the past two years, and large-tonnage cargo ships can also run, and there is no charge for passing through the lock.&quot; Huang Huirong told reporters that last year he replaced his old 1,000-ton ship with a 3,000-ton ship. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Coming to the Dateng Gorge Ship Lock Management Center, a new round of water filling operations in the lock has been completed. As the water is discharged smoothly, the bell rings, the lock opens, and the cargo ship loaded with sand and gravel and other basic materials sails out smoothly. . &quot;Through the operation of filling and releasing water in the ship lock, the ship can smoothly &#39;turn&#39; over the dam.&quot; Wu Haijin, deputy director of the ship lock center, pointed to the ship lock door and said, &quot;The lower herringbone gate at the head of the lock is 47.5 meters high and the single door weighs 1,295 meters. tons, the Dateng Gorge Ship Lock is currently the highest single-stage ship lock in the world.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the lock was opened to navigation, 94,900 ships have passed through the lock, with a cumulative nuclear load of 224 million tons, and the navigation efficiency has reached the advanced level of similar types of ship locks. . In August this year, the navigation volume of the ship lock increased by 53% year-on-year, and the cargo passing through the lock increased by 222% year-on-year, reaching a record high. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;b>;Eight sets of the largest axial-flow propeller hydroelectric generator sets in China, with a designed annual power generation of 6.055 billion kilowatt-hours&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Enter the Datangxia Water Conservancy Project In the power plant building on the right bank, the blue and white generator sets flash red lights, and the cabinet screen displays the running unit parameters. Leaning over and listening, you can seem to hear the rumbling sound of running water under the cement factory building. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;What you see in the factory is only the upper part of the generator set. The continuous water flowing day and night washes the rotating paddles in the lower part of the generator set to drive power generation.&quot; Wu Yibin, deputy director of the Dateng Gorge Hydropower Plant, told reporters, &quot;Eight sets of the largest axial-flow propeller hydroelectric generator units in China, with a single unit capacity of 200,000 kilowatts, ranking first among similar units.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Datengxia Water Conservancy Project was approved by the State Council in the &quot;Hongshui River Comprehensive Water Conservancy Project&quot; In the &quot;Utilization Plan&quot;, it is the last level of the 10-level power station and an important part of the Hongshui River Hydropower Base. The hub power plant has a total installed capacity of 1.6 million kilowatts and a designed annual power generation of 6.055 billion kilowatt hours. It is responsible for power generation and peak load regulation of the power grid and is the main power station of the Guangxi power grid. At present, the units in operation have generated more than 12.5 billion kilowatt-hours of electricity, providing important support for regional power security. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It takes 10 minutes to drive from Dadengxia Water Conservancy Project to Bailan Resettlement Site. The spacious road is lined with neat, brand-new houses and street trees. Huang Huirong and his neighbors chatted in the sun at the door. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The resettlement of Dateng Gorge involves three cities in Guangxi, Guigang, Laibin and Liuzhou, with a relocated population of 14,340. The local government took the resettlement opportunity as an opportunity and combined with the rural revitalization plan to build 11 resettlement sites including Dachengtang, Liming, Dutou, and Bailan. All of them have been completed and put into use. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“When floods came in the past, you could hear a ‘rumbling’ sound in the house.” Huang Huirong recalled the old house in Bailan Village and expressed her fear. The reporter followed him into his new home and saw brand-new furniture and elaborate furnishings. &quot;It was always flooded before and I wanted to move but couldn&#39;t. I didn&#39;t expect that I could live in a bungalow at this age. Of course I have to decorate it well.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>; It took 9 years to be completed and put into operation. The comprehensive benefits of the main project of the Datangxia Water Conservancy Project are exciting: the Pearl River Delta is a key flood control protection object, and the flood control standard will be raised from a return event in 50 years to a return event in 100-200 years; the navigation tonnage of the Qianjiang River can be increased from 300 to 100-200 years. The tonnage has been increased to the 3,000-ton level, the highest level for China&#39;s inland river shipping; through joint dispatching with the basin reservoir group, the problem of drought and water shortage for the 1.38 million people in the basin will be solved. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 中国创新能力升至第十位]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20231122_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 22, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, November 21 (Reporter Wu Yuehui) The national innovation index reflects the country’s comprehensive innovation capabilities important indicators. On the 21st, the &quot;National Innovation Index Report 2022-2023&quot; released by the China Academy of Science and Technology Development Strategies showed that the global innovation landscape maintains a tripartite posture of Asia, the United States and Europe, the trend of science and technology innovation centers moving eastward is more significant, and China&#39;s comprehensive ranking of innovation capabilities has risen to Ranked tenth, further moving towards the forefront of innovative countries. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The &quot;National Innovation Index Report&quot; selects 40 countries that are comparable to my country (their total R&amp;D investment accounts for more than 95% of the world, and the total GDP accounts for more than 85% of the world) as the evaluation objects, from the perspective of innovation resources An evaluation index system has been constructed from five dimensions: knowledge creation, enterprise innovation, innovation performance and innovation environment. It uses authoritative international organizations and national official statistical survey data to objectively judge my country’s position in the international scientific and technological innovation landscape and comprehensively reflect my country’s scientific and technological innovation. Input, output and ability to support economic and social development. The results show that in 2023, China&#39;s National Innovation Index ranked tenth in the world, up three places from the previous period, and was the only developing country to enter the top 15. The country&#39;s innovation capabilities have made significant progress, rapidly rising from 38th place in 2000 to 20th place in 2011, and then steadily rising to 10th place. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Judging from the five sub-indexes of the National Innovation Index, our country has performed well in all dimensions. It performed particularly well in &quot;knowledge creation&quot;, scoring 83.7 points and ranking third. In 2020, China&#39;s number of highly cited papers was 37,000, accounting for 23% of the world&#39;s share, ranking second in the world after the United States; China&#39;s number of valid invention patents reached 2.279 million, ranking first in the world; a billion-dollar industry Ranked first in the number of value-added industrial design registration applications. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 515家企业和机构将参展首届链博会]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/22/nw.D110000renmrb_20231122_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 22, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, November 21st&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Luo Shanshan) The first China International Supply Chain Promotion Expo (below) (referred to as &quot;Chain Expo&quot;) will be held in Beijing from November 28th to December 2nd. On the 21st, the China Council for the Promotion of International Trade held a special press conference to introduce the relevant situation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>; Zhang Shaogang, Vice President of China Council for the Promotion of International Trade, introduced that the first Chain Expo has a total exhibition area of ​​100,000 square meters and will set up five major chains including smart automobile chain, green agricultural chain, clean energy chain, digital technology chain, and healthy life chain. and supply chain services exhibition area. 515 Chinese and foreign companies and institutions participated in the exhibition, focusing on displaying new technologies, new products and new services in key links of the upstream, midstream and downstream chains. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The first Chain Expo will build a professional, authoritative and international platform to promote exchanges and negotiations, mutually beneficial cooperation and win-win results between Chinese and foreign merchants. The proportion of exhibitors from abroad reached 26%. The Fortune 500 and leading companies in the global supply chain system participated in the exhibition, covering 55 countries and regions. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 22 Nov 2023 05:56:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>