<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 国家繁荣富强  人民幸福安康]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/02/nw.D110000renmrb_20231002_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Monday, October 2, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http ://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231002/1696189871453_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On October 1, the national flag was solemnly raised The ceremony was held in Beijing&#39;s Tiananmen Square. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Ju Huanzong&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;The flag fluttering inspires patriotic power; the national anthem is majestic, Play the movement of endeavor. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“On our new journey, our future is bright,” General Secretary Xi Jinping said affectionately at the reception celebrating the 74th anniversary of the founding of the People’s Republic of China, inspiring hundreds of millions of Chinese people to unswervingly move towards building a strong country and The grand goal of national rejuvenation is marching forward bravely. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On October 1st, various places carried out a variety of activities to express patriotism, sharpen the ambition to strengthen the country, warmly celebrate the 74th anniversary of the founding of the People&#39;s Republic of China, and jointly wish the country prosperity and strength, and wish the people of all ethnic groups happiness and well-being. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Hoist the same national flag&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Sing patriotic hymns&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On October 1, from the vastness From the countryside to the city streets, from the snowy plateau to the land of plenty, the five-star red flag rose slowly and fluttered in the wind across the land of China. People of all ethnic groups across the country expressed their deep blessings to the 74th anniversary of the founding of New China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At about 6 o&#39;clock in the morning on October 1, with the first ray of sunshine in the morning, more than 300,000 people from all walks of life witnessed the solemn moment of the five-star red flag rising in Tiananmen Square in Beijing. &quot;Salute to the National Flag!&quot; Along with the slogans of the honor guard, the &quot;March of the Volunteers&quot; resounded throughout Tiananmen Square. After the flag-raising ceremony, people waved their national flags and sang patriotic hymns to the music of &quot;Singing the Motherland&quot;. Cheers of &quot;Bless the Motherland&quot; and &quot;Long Live the Motherland&quot; echoed over the square for a long time. &quot;As a college student, I will work hard to grow into a pillar responsible for national rejuvenation!&quot; Zhang Qixuan, a student at the School of Software and Microelectronics at Peking University, could not conceal his excitement after watching the flag-raising ceremony. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;About 90 kilometers west of Tiananmen Square, among the green mountains, the five-star red flag rises slowly against the rising sun. Facing the national flag, 35 firefighters dressed in &quot;flame blue&quot; lined up neatly. During the recent flood relief operations, the commanders and fighters of the Zhaitang Fire Rescue Station of the Mentougou District Fire Rescue Detachment in Beijing were at the forefront, adhering to the front line and rescuing and evacuating more than 600 people. &quot;We are united as one to effectively respond to flood disasters. No difficulty can defeat the heroic Chinese people.&quot; said Huang Zhichuan, deputy director of Zhaitang Fire Rescue Station. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the national anthem played, Su Shijian, a policeman from Team 7 of the Heilongjiang Heihe Entry-Exit Border Inspection Station, waved his arms and the five-star red flag slowly rose. The originally noisy Heihe Water Transport Passenger Inspection Port Square became quiet. Dozens of immigration police and tourists waiting to leave the country stopped and stared at the five-star red flag for a long time. &quot;I am extremely proud to be able to raise the national flag at the gate of the country.&quot; Su Shijian said, &quot;During the National Day, my comrades and I will continue to stick to our posts and go all out to do our jobs.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Zhuhai, Guangdong At the construction site of the Hengqin Science City (Phase III) project in the Hengqin Guangdong-Macao Deep Cooperation Zone, construction workers and managers saluted with attention in front of the national flag, accompanied by the majestic national anthem. &quot;Watching the national flag rising, I feel excited beyond words. We will continue to contribute to the country&#39;s construction and development with our own hands and make contributions based on our positions.&quot; said Du Bing, project production manager of China Construction Fifth Engineering Bureau. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At about 7 o&#39;clock in the morning on October 1, the five-star red flag rose slowly against the sea breeze on Yongxing Island, Sansha City, Hainan. Sansha City officials and employees, officers and soldiers stationed on the island, and representatives from all walks of life sang the national anthem together to express their deep patriotism. &quot;Where the flag is, there is responsibility. Every time I see the flag raised on the island, I feel extremely sacred and glorious.&quot; He Sheng, director of the Yongxing Coast Police Station in Sansha City, said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At 10 a.m. on October 1, nearly 2,000 cadres and masses of all ethnic groups and people from all walks of life participated in the flag-raising ceremony at the Potala Palace Square in Lhasa, Tibet. Basang Gyem, a resident of Muru Community, Jibenggang Street, Chengguan District, Lhasa City, comes to participate in the flag-raising ceremony every National Day. “Every time I watch the flag-raising ceremony, I am shocked. Under the leadership of the party, the lives of people of all ethnic groups in Tibet will be better every year.” It’s better than every year and we are getting happier.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the occasion of the National Day, the officers and soldiers of the Chinese People’s Liberation Army and the Armed Police Force stayed in their fighting positions, trained and prepared for war, and at the same time carried out a variety of activities to celebrate the 74th anniversary of the founding of the People’s Republic of China. anniversary. On October 1, all officers and soldiers of the Navy&#39;s Xining ship held a flag-raising ceremony on the flight deck. The bright five-star red flag slowly rose on the main mast of the Xining ship. The officers and soldiers were in high spirits and solemnly saluted the flag. Zhang Langbo, a marine technician in the electromechanical department, said: &quot;As a ship electromechanical soldier who has served for 24 years, I shoulder the sacred responsibility of ensuring that warships sail thousands of miles. Please rest assured that the motherland and the people will have a strong army!&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;&lt;strong>;Pursuing red memories&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Growing feelings for home and country&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Celebrating the National Day is a review of the glorious history and a patriotism ism resonance. Cadres and masses from all over the country paid homage to the old revolutionary sites, watched historical exhibitions, relived the red years, deepened their feelings for their family and country, inherited the heroic spirit, absorbed the strength of progress, and determined to walk the Long March in the new era. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the banks of Taiping Lake in Shanghai, the special National Day landscape &quot;in its prime&quot;, designed based on the site of the National Congress of the Communist Party of China, adds a solemn and festive atmosphere to the festival. &quot;The site of the National Congress of the Communist Party of China is a typical Shikumen building...&quot; At the intersection of Huangpi South Road and Xingye Road, volunteer Wang Zhi was telling the story of the site of the National Congress of the Communist Party of China. Xiao Youbo, a student of Donghua University, listened carefully, &quot;Studying the red history on the spot can deeply feel the hard-won happiness of today&#39;s life.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On October 1, Anhui Tongling Museum visited &quot;Will Conquers Steel - —The 70th Anniversary Commemorative Exhibition of the Victory of the Chinese People’s Volunteers in Resisting U.S. Aggression and Aiding Korea” attracted an endless stream of visitors. &quot;The museum hopes to carry forward the great spirit of resisting U.S. aggression and aiding Korea, inheriting the red gene, and fostering feelings for the family and the country through holding exhibitions,&quot; said Yao Cheng, deputy director of Tongling Museum. Mr. Zhou, a citizen, specially brought his children to visit: &quot;On this special day, we will receive a patriotic education so that our children can understand and remember this history from an early age.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;October 1, Xiangtan, Hunan Dongshan Academy in Xiangxiang City welcomed many visitors. Xie Bingqi, a first-grade student at Donggao School in Xiangxiang City, told everyone the story of the revolutionary ancestors who studied in Dongshan Academy and became talented and determined to serve the country. After becoming the &quot;little commentator&quot; of Xiangxiang&#39;s red culture three years ago, she often used her holidays to tell red stories and inherit red genes in Dongshan Academy and other places. Her wonderful explanations attracted many visitors to stop and listen. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Entering the Shaanxi Fumei Campaign Memorial Hall from the main entrance, a 19.49-meter-high monument in the center of the memorial square comes into view. In the early morning of the 1st, Li Shaohui, a cadre from Changxing Town, Mei County, and his colleagues came to the memorial square to pay their respects and draw strength for their progress. &quot;Without the sacrifices of the revolutionary martyrs, there would be no happy and beautiful life today. I will continue to perform my duties and serve the people with practical actions.&quot; Li Shaohui said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Express patriotism&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Strengthen the ambition of a strong country&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Be patriotic and serve the country with sincerity . Cadres and masses from all over the country expressed their patriotism with songs, sharpened their aspirations to strengthen the country through struggle, and fully felt the greatness of the Communist Party of China, the progress of New China, and the happiness of being Chinese. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On October 1, the People’s Square in Taikang County, Henan Province was extremely lively. More than 1,000 party members and cadres and people from all walks of life waved national flags and sang patriotic poems loudly to the music &quot;I Love You, China&quot;. . The sonorous and powerful voice attracted many pedestrians to stop and recite word for word. &quot;I have served the Party gloriously for more than 50 years. Reciting patriotic poems today has further inspired the patriotic enthusiasm in my heart.&quot; said Gao Jiaming, a villager in Weizhuang Village, Xumukou Town, Taikang County. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On October 1, professional actors from Wuhan Song and Dance Theater and Wuhan Acrobatic Troupe presented the National Day special &quot;Power of China&quot; to the audience at the Memorial Hall Square of the Former Site of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China in Shengli Street, Jiang&#39;an District, Wuhan City, Hubei Province Theatrical performances. The acrobatic &quot;Power of China&quot; was both strong and soft, and the song &quot;My Motherland and Me&quot; was melodious and melodious. The atmosphere at the scene was boiling with bursts of cheers. &quot;I feel very honored to be able to sing loudly for the people on this day of national celebration.&quot; said Yang Shuo, a young actor from Wuhan Song and Dance Theater. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The towering green mountains stretch and the rolling rivers flow endlessly. In Tucheng Town, Xishui County, Zunyi City, Guizhou Province, sonorous and powerful songs echoed along the Chishui River, singing high-spirited heroic spirit. On the morning of October 1, the Sidu Chishui Memorial Hall in Tucheng Town performed the &quot;Long March Suite&quot; concert. The Sidu Chishui Art Troupe composed of local people performed classic songs affectionately, praising the great new era with their songs and blessing the country with prosperity. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On October 1, the Memorial Hall of the Chinese Workers’ and Peasants’ Red Army West Route Army in Gaotai County, Gansu welcomed a group of young spectators. The displays of objects and historical pictures reproduce the heroic fighting history of the Western Route Army, attracting students to stop and watch. &quot;Today&#39;s happy life is hard-won and cannot be separated from the bloody battles of the revolutionary martyrs. I will study hard, serve the country, and strive to be a determined fighter.&quot; said Xia Ruohan, a fifth-year student at Jiefang Street Primary School in Gaotai County. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Inspire patriotism and build the Chinese dream together. After 74 years of glorious history, the land of China has become more vibrant, socialist China has become more prosperous, and the entire Party and people of all ethnic groups have become more confident and stronger. Hundreds of millions of Chinese sons and daughters will strengthen their confidence, inspire their spirits, and work in unity, which will surely inspire the confidence and confidence to forge ahead on a new journey and build a new era of success, and gather the majestic power of patriotic struggle. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Comprehensive reporting by our reporters Wang Haonan, Shi Fang, Zhang Yikai, Jiang Xiaodan, Cao Wenxuan, Qiongda Zhuoga, Jin Zhengbo, Cao Lingjuan, Xu Jing, Shen Zhilin, Zhang Danhua, Bi Jingjin, Fan Haotian, Cheng Huan, and Zhao Shuaijie; Coordinator of this issue: Zhao Zheng)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot; _blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 05:56:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 努力实现全年经济社会发展目标]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/02/nw.D110000renmrb_20231002_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Monday, October 2, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;“Currently, the century-old changes in the world are accelerating and the international environment has undergone profound changes. We still face many risks and challenges on the way forward. .&quot; At the reception celebrating the 74th anniversary of the founding of the People&#39;s Republic of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized that we must &quot;strive to increase macro-control, expand domestic effective demand, stimulate the vitality of business entities, and continuously promote the sustained improvement of economic operations and endogenous power. We will continue to strengthen and social expectations continue to improve, effectively prevent and resolve major risks, and strive to achieve the annual economic and social development goals.&quot; &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Since the beginning of this year, under the strong leadership of the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core, and the joint efforts of the whole country, our country&#39;s economy has generally rebounded for the better, high-quality development has been solidly advanced, grain production is expected to have a bumper harvest, and people&#39;s lives continue to improve. , the overall social situation remains stable, laying a good foundation for achieving the annual economic and social development goals. my country&#39;s economic recovery speed is in a leading position among the world&#39;s major economies and remains the main driving force for world economic growth. These achievements were achieved at a time when external demand has weakened, changes in the international environment have had an increasing adverse impact on my country, domestic cyclical structural contradictions have intertwined and overlapped, and risks and hazards in some fields have gradually emerged. They are hard-won and exciting. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out: &quot;Unity is strength, and confidence is stronger than gold.&quot; It should be noted that after the epidemic prevention and control has stabilized, economic recovery will be a process of wave-like development and tortuous progress. Look at China&#39;s economic development from a comprehensive, dialectical and long-term perspective. China&#39;s economy has always developed by overcoming challenges, grown by ups and downs, and grown stronger by going through trials. By adhering to the principle of seeking progress while maintaining stability, proceeding step by step, and continuing to advance, China&#39;s current economic stability has a firmer foundation and more momentum for progress. Stable prices have expanded the space for “advance”; “stable consumption” has enhanced the motivation for “advance”; stable employment has enhanced the effectiveness of “advance”. Today&#39;s Chinese economy is unswervingly moving towards high-quality development, and we are full of confidence in China&#39;s development prospects. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;This confidence lies in the fact that our country’s economy is highly resilient, has great potential, and is full of vitality. Its long-term positive fundamentals will not change, and its development still has a good supporting foundation and many favorable conditions. In the short term, all relevant parties will increase the implementation of macro policies, continue to optimize a number of phased policies, study and introduce a number of highly targeted new measures, actively plan and launch a number of reserve policies, and continue to consolidate the positive momentum of economic recovery. In the long term, my country has the institutional advantages of a socialist market economy, the demand advantage of a very large-scale market, the supply advantage of a complete industrial system, and the talent advantage of a large number of high-quality workers and entrepreneurs. Taken together, fully stimulating the advantages and vitality of all aspects can promote the continuous improvement of the economic structure, continuous enhancement of growth momentum, continuous improvement of development trends, and achieve effective improvement in economic quality and reasonable growth in quantity. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;This year is the first year to implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China. It is also a critical year for the implementation of the &quot;14th Five-Year Plan&quot; to build on the past and usher in the future. Doing a good job in economic and social development throughout the year and promoting the overall improvement of economic operations are crucial to getting off to a good start in building a modern socialist country in an all-round way. Focusing on promoting high-quality development, we must fully, accurately and comprehensively implement the new development concept, accelerate the construction of a new development pattern, focus on increasing macro-control, focus on expanding domestic effective demand, focus on stimulating the vitality of business entities, and promote high-quality development with new atmosphere and new actions. Achieve new results. Focusing on promoting high-level opening up to the outside world, we must continue to comprehensively deepen reforms, steadily expand institutional opening up such as rules, regulations, management, and standards, promote high-quality development in the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, smooth domestic and international dual cycles, and make economic development more resilient , more energetic. Focusing on meeting the people&#39;s growing needs for a better life, we must increase people&#39;s livelihood protection, focus on expanding employment, solve the people&#39;s urgent, difficult and anxious problems, and continuously enhance the people&#39;s sense of gain, happiness and security. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Empty talk will harm the country, but hard work will prosper the country; seize the day and night, and time waits for no one. Let us unite more closely around the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core, adhere to the guidance of Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, fully implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Party, be down-to-earth, work hard, and do a solid job in economic development. We will carry out various social development tasks, strive to achieve the annual economic and social development goals, and make new and greater contributions to promoting the construction of a strong country and the great cause of national rejuvenation. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 05:56:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 中欧班列谱写丝路新传奇]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/02/nw.D110000renmrb_20231002_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Monday, October 2, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;With a long whistle, a China-Europe train carrying 54 containers of auto parts, daily necessities and other goods recently Depart from Tianjin Xingang Station and bound for Erenhot Port in Inner Mongolia. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the vast Eurasian continent, there were camel bells along the Silk Road in ancient times, and today there are &quot;steel camel teams&quot; galloping non-stop. After 10 years of development, China-Europe freight trains have operated a total of 77,000 trains, transporting 7.31 million TEUs of goods with a value of more than 340 billion US dollars, becoming an important bridge for international economic and trade cooperation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Connecting Asia and Europe, opening up new transportation channels&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On September 15, at the China-Europe Railway International Cooperation Forum, China State Railway Group Co., Ltd. (hereinafter) (referred to as &quot;China Railway Group&quot;) announced: China-Europe trains have opened 5 lines in the full timetable, with a total of 80 trains running. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Take Xi&#39;an to Duisburg, Germany as an example. It departs from Xi&#39;an International Port Station at 3:55 a.m. every Wednesday and Saturday and runs 9,908 kilometers. It can reach Duisburg in 10 days and the entire journey is in operation. The time is compressed by more than 30% compared with ordinary trains. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Up to now, China-Europe trains have connected 112 cities in my country, more than 200 cities in 25 European countries and regions, and more than 100 cities in 11 Asian countries and regions along the way, opening up Asia. A new European overland transport corridor. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——The channel network is gradually improved. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the China-Kazakhstan (Lianyungang) Logistics Cooperation Base, locomotives shuttle and operations are busy, and the goods take ships to sea as soon as they get off the train; at the China-Europe Express (Shenyang) assembly center, cranes grab each one with &quot;China Containers with the &quot;Railway&quot; logo are loaded onto the train; at the Erenhot port in Inner Mongolia, a China-Europe train has completed the reloading work and is waiting to leave the country...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Data from the State Railway Group shows that the China-Europe train has formed a route through Ala There are 3 west, middle and east exit channels at Shankou, Horgos, Erenhot, Manzhouli, Suifenhe and Tongjiang ports. There are 86 planned China-Europe train lines with a speed of 120 kilometers per hour, realizing an international intermodal transport network between Asia and Europe. change. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Port capabilities have been significantly improved. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The port is an important node during the transportation of China-Europe trains. The train will complete reloading, customs declaration, customs clearance, exit and other procedures here. Over the past 10 years, countries along the China-Europe Railway Express have strengthened the expansion of existing port capabilities, opened new ports, and continuously improved their international transport capabilities to meet the growing transportation needs. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Overlooking the Manzhouli Railway Port, rows of China-Europe freight trains are rolling out on the wide standard-gauge line, and tall gantry cranes use their &quot;giant hands&quot; to neatly stack colorful containers. After multiple upgrades, the daily loading capacity of international intermodal transport trains at the Manzhouli Railway Port has increased to 840 TEUs. The loading capacity has doubled compared with 2020, making international combined transport more efficient and convenient. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Data from the State Railway Group shows that in 2022, 5,141, 3,150, 4,838, 2,549, and 884 China-Europe freight trains will pass through Alashankou, Horgos, Manzhouli, Erenhot, and Suifenhe ports respectively. , an increase of 3981, 3080, 4527, 2388 and 884 respectively compared to 2016. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——The hub function continues to be enhanced. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past 10 years, our country has actively promoted the construction of demonstration projects for China-Europe freight train collection centers in Zhengzhou, Chongqing, Chengdu, Xi&#39;an, and Urumqi, creating modern logistics hubs with excellent services, high efficiency, and low costs, and promoting China-Europe freight trains. China Development Bank has transformed from “point-to-point” to “hub-to-hub”. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Take Xi&#39;an International Port Station as an example. From the original fourth-class station to the current first-class freight station, Xi&#39;an has become an important gathering center for China-Europe freight trains. This year, Xi&#39;an International Port Station has been upgraded again: the number of cargo loading and unloading lines has increased from 19 to 29, 12 cargo lines have been transformed and have direct departure functions, and the loading and unloading capacity has increased by 30%. Today, Xi&#39;an International Port Station has successfully become a world-class inland port, with a designed annual container throughput of 5.4 million TEUs and an annual railway freight volume of 66 million tons. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Data show that in 2022, the five assembly centers will operate a total of 8,800 China-Europe trains, accounting for 53% of the total number of China-Europe trains. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Quality and quality have improved, and new logistics models have been innovated&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Containers are stacked on top of each other, and gantry cranes are busy loading and unloading. The Chengdu International Railway Port is very busy. &quot;It&#39;s well-deserved. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There are containers at the end of the production line, and the railway port is next to the workshop.” said Yang Yi, financial director of TCL Optoelectronics Technology (Chengdu) Co., Ltd. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After ten years of development, China-Europe trains have built an all-weather, large-volume, green and low-carbon logistics channel, creating a new situation in international transportation cooperation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It has outstanding economic and environmental advantages and is widely welcomed by corporate cargo owners. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Inner Mongolia Ulanqab City Jiaze Wood Industry Co., Ltd. is mainly engaged in wood processing. One of the places that company leader Guo Jinhai goes to most is Qisumu Logistics Park, Inner Mongolia’s largest China-Europe freight train assembly base. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Guo Jinhai calculated an account for reporters: for every ton of wood imported, China-Europe freight train transportation can save 50 yuan compared with highway transportation. Based on the annual usage of 200,000 tons, it can save nearly 10 million yuan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Data shows that for the same shipment of goods from China to Europe, the transportation cost of the China-Europe Express is about 1/5 of air transportation, the transportation time is about 1/4 of sea transportation, and it has high stability. It has comparative advantages in meeting specific logistics needs such as high added value and strong timeliness. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Not only that, the average carbon emissions of China-Europe trains are 1/15 of air transportation and 1/7 of road transportation, playing a positive role in addressing global climate change and sustainable development of transportation.” National The relevant person in charge of the freight department of the Railway Group said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Multimodal transport has developed rapidly and service capabilities have been greatly improved. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When arriving at Xiamen Haicang Bonded Port Area, a container liner from Vietnam has successfully docked at the port. The site is busy organizing the unloading of containers into the station. The containers will take the China-Europe train to Kazakhstan, achieving a seamless connection between the &quot;Maritime Silk Road&quot; and the &quot;Continental Silk Road&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For enterprises in East and Southeast Asian countries and regions, choosing to arrive in Xiamen by sea and then taking the China-Europe Railway Express to Europe saves nearly half the time compared to the entire sea transportation. This is the unique solution of the China-Europe Railway Express (Xiamen). It has advantages in international sea-rail combined transport,&quot; said Zhao Liqiang, director of Haicang Station of Zhangzhou Depot of China Railway Nanchang Bureau Group Co., Ltd. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The multimodal transport of sea-rail, road-rail and air-rail allows the efficiency of China-Europe trains to be better unleashed. According to data from the National Development and Reform Commission, there are currently 29 China-Europe freight train lines starting from coastal ports such as Dalian Port, Tianjin Port, Qingdao Port, and Lianyungang Port; cities such as Guangzhou and Chengdu have relied on China-Europe freight trains to create &quot;air freight trains.&quot; The new cross-border e-commerce export model of &quot;rail combined transport&quot; promotes the integrated development of &quot;rail, sea, public air and mail&quot; comprehensive transportation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Mutual benefits and win-win results, building a new platform for cooperation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The continuous China-Europe freight trains bring new development opportunities to the development of countries and regions along the way. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Speed ​​up the exchange of goods and optimize the open pattern. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhengzhou is located in the hinterland of the Central Plains. In the past, bulk goods exported to Europe had to be transported to eastern seaports and then transported into Europe by sea. Now relying on China-Europe freight trains, Zhengzhou has become a new highland for inland opening up. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Since 2013, the China-Europe freight trains (Zhengzhou) have gone from a single trip per week to a maximum of 34 round-trips per week. The number of trains has become more frequent, and the number of domestic and foreign partners has reached more than 6,000 , forming an industrial complementary and healthy development pattern of &#39;transportation leads to trade and trade promotes transportation&#39;.&quot; Gao Fei, director of Putian Station of China Railway Zhengzhou Bureau Group Co., Ltd., said that relying on China-Europe freight trains, Henan opened Dongfanghong Tractor and Xinyang Tea , Nanyang mushrooms, Shangqiu cotton and other customized cooperation trains to promote special agricultural products to go abroad. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Data from the National Development and Reform Commission show that the proportion of the value of goods transported by China-Europe freight trains in China-Europe goods trade has increased year by year, from 1% in 2015 to 9% in 2021. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Gather together industrial clusters and expand development space. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the years, Chongqing has been approved as a first-class national railway port, a complete vehicle import port, and the first pharmaceutical import port. &quot;The establishment of the complete vehicle import port has driven the export of complete vehicles and parts of Changan, Dongfeng and other brands, promoted the development and expansion of the automobile industry cluster in Chongqing and even the west, and opened a new chapter in the import of complete vehicles in the inland western China.&quot; Yu Xin said Liu Taiping, general manager of Ou (Chongqing) Supply Chain Management Co., Ltd. From January to August this year, China-Europe Railway Express (Chongqing) imported and exported 64,000 complete vehicles, an increase of approximately 36.7 times. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——China Unicom connects the vast market and opens the &quot;win-win door&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the &quot;World Supermarket&quot; Yiwu, Zhejiang, there is a Spanish product import pavilion covering an area of ​​more than 500 square meters, selling Spanish red wine, olive oil and other products. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the past, many high-quality Spanish products were unable to open the market due to lack of sales channels.” Jin Haijun, head of the import pavilion, said that after the opening of the China-Europe freight train, these products were sold to China by Chinese buyers. Even Japan, South Korea and other places. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the same time, Yiwu’s small commodities are also continuously transported to Madrid, Spain via China-Europe trains, helping it become an important small commodity distribution center in Europe. Since the beginning of this year, China-Europe freight trains (Yiwu) have operated more than 1,000 trains, with more than 50,000 product categories. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to reports, in recent years, the categories of goods shipped from China to Europe via China-Europe trains have expanded from the initial mobile phones and computers to 53 categories such as complete automobiles, machinery and equipment, and electronic products. The types of goods shipped to China have gradually expanded from the early timber, automobiles and spare parts to mechanical and electrical products, food, medical equipment, etc. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China-Europe freight trains have strong development momentum. From January to August this year, a total of 11,638 trains were opened and 1.262 million TEUs of goods were sent, a year-on-year increase of 10% and 23% respectively. In the future, the &quot;Steel Camel Team&quot; will definitely bring more opportunities to international economic and trade cooperation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Our reporters Zhu Peixian, Jin Bo, Liu Hongchao, Bai Guangdi and Zhai Qinqi participated in the reporting)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 05:56:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 杭州亚运会赛程过半]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/02/nw.D110000renmrb_20231002_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Monday, October 2, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Our newspaper, Hangzhou, October 1st&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;October 1st is the eighth day after the opening of the Hangzhou Asian Games game day. Since the start of this Asian Games, the events have been splendid and highlights have appeared frequently. Athletes from all delegations have worked hard and continuously achieved great results, demonstrating the vitality of the Asian sports world. The Hangzhou Asian Games schedule is over halfway. As of October 1, a total of 36 delegations have won medals. The Chinese sports delegation had a good start and maintained a good momentum of winning gold medals. The overall performance was better than expected. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In the completed events, the Chinese sports delegation performed well. Swimming, taekwondo and other events achieved the best results in the history of the Asian Games. Rowing, sailing, modern pentathlon and other events won gold medals in multiple Olympic events. The women&#39;s foil team won another Asian Games gold medal after 29 years. Beach volleyball The women&#39;s team won six consecutive championships and won three gold medals in four skateboarding events. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In the first half of the competition, the Chinese sports delegation achieved a number of high-value results. The shooting event has set three world records, swimming, track cycling and other events have set multiple Asian records or Asian Games records, and sailing, modern pentathlon, tennis and other events have obtained multiple qualifications for the Paris Olympics. Many Olympic champion athletes showed good competitive condition and won gold medals in the Asian Games. A group of young athletes have emerged on the field and bravely shouldered heavy responsibilities, demonstrating the depth of China&#39;s sports talents. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The players of the Chinese sports delegation respected the rules, the referees, and their opponents on the field, showing a good spirit and competitive level. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;(Our reporters Zheng Yi, Fan Jiayuan, Sun Longfei, Tao Xiangan)&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;(Special reports on the Hangzhou Asian Games are available on pages five and six)&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/ enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:/ /feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br >;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 05:56:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 太阳能发电装机容量超5亿千瓦（新数据 新看点）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/02/nw.D110000renmrb_20231002_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Monday, October 2, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http ://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-10/02/01/rmrb2023100201p10_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;Data source: National Energy Bureau and others&lt;BR/>;Drawing: Zhang Danfeng&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, October 1st&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;(Reporter Ding Yiting) The reporter recently learned from the National Energy Administration: In the first eight months of this year, the country’s newly installed solar power generation capacity exceeded 100 million kilowatts, accounting for approximately 57% of all newly installed power generation capacity. As of the end of August, the installed capacity of solar power generation was approximately 510 million kilowatts, a year-on-year increase of 44.4%. 510 million kilowatts is equivalent to the total installed capacity of 23 Three Gorges power stations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Data show that as of the end of August, the country’s cumulative installed power generation capacity was approximately 2.76 billion kilowatts, a year-on-year increase of 11.9%. Among them, the installed hydropower capacity is approximately 420 million kilowatts, a year-on-year increase of 3.9%; the wind power installed capacity is approximately 400 million kilowatts, a year-on-year increase of 14.8%. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In August, the growth rate of nuclear power and solar power accelerated, and the growth rate of hydropower turned from falling to increasing. Among them, hydropower increased by 18.5%; nuclear power increased by 5.5%, 2.6 percentage points faster than July; solar power increased by 13.9%, and the growth rate was 7.5 percentage points faster than July. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The &quot;dual carbon&quot; strategy has led to the vigorous development of photovoltaic and other industries. Data show that from January to July, my country&#39;s solar cell output was 276.6 GW, a year-on-year increase of more than 56%, and the total export of photovoltaic products including silicon wafers, cells, modules, etc. reached US$32.47 billion. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In the first eight months of this year, the country&#39;s major power generation companies completed investment of 470.3 billion yuan in power supply projects, a year-on-year increase of 46.6%. Among them, solar power generation was 187.3 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 82.7%; nuclear power was 52.2 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 56.9%; wind power was 114.9 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 38.7%. The investment in power grid projects was 270.5 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 1.4%. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 05:56:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 把爱我中华的种子埋入心灵深处（今日谈）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/02/nw.D110000renmrb_20231002_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Monday, October 2, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;On the occasion of National Day, the No. 2 Primary School of Tianjin Road, Maojian District, Shiyan City, Hubei Province carried out &quot;I take a photo with the national flag&quot; &quot; and other series of activities guide students to bury the seeds of love for China deep in their hearts. The pledge of &quot;please rest assured the party, I have a strong country; revitalize China, and we will strengthen ourselves&quot; is inspiring. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Adolescence is a critical period for the formation of values, outlook on life, outlook on motherland, and outlook on nation. General Secretary Xi Jinping sent a message to &quot;let the spirit of patriotism be passed down and carried forward from generation to generation&quot;, encouraging &quot;to learn more about the historical knowledge of China&#39;s revolution, construction, and reform, to learn more from heroic and model figures, to love the party, the motherland, and the people&quot;, and stressed that &quot;strengthening Revolutionary traditional education, patriotism education, and young people’s ideological and moral education should inherit the red gene well and ensure that the red country will never change its color.” General Secretary Xi Jinping has always cared about and kept in mind the mission of serving the country with aspirations and practice. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Water the flowers and roots to educate people and minds. To carry forward the spirit of patriotism, patriotic education must be regarded as an eternal theme. On the new journey, we must place the strengthening of patriotism education for young people in a more prominent position, tell the story of the party, the story of revolution, and the story of heroes, continue, in-depth, and vividly carry out patriotism publicity and education, and encourage young people to realize their ideals. With the future of the motherland, closely link his life with the destiny of the nation, and strive to grow into a new man of the era who takes on the responsibility of national rejuvenation. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 05:56:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 三湘大地稻米香（打好夺取秋粮丰收这场硬仗）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/02/nw.D110000renmrb_20231002_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Monday, October 2, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Walking around the land of Sanxiang, you can see high-quality rice production bases everywhere: the late rice is filling and growing well, the middle rice is fragrant, The sickles are blooming one after another, and the regenerated rice is blooming to give birth to a new harvest. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Huguang is ripe and the world is rich.” Hunan’s rice planting area ranks among the top in the country all year round. In order to protect the &quot;rice bag&quot;, Hunan has shouldered its responsibility for food security, improved its agricultural science and technology support system, optimized the structure of planting varieties, and continuously improved its food production capacity. Since the beginning of this year, various regions across the province have actively introduced policies and measures to stabilize production capacity, tap potential, increase efficiency, stimulate farmers&#39; enthusiasm for growing grain, and lay a solid foundation for a bumper autumn grain harvest in all aspects. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;High-quality seeds and good opportunities, technology helps increase grain yields&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the rice fields of Qiliping Village, Baishui Town, Qiyang City, tender green grows on the gray-yellow rice piles of sprouts. This is the regeneration rice promoted in Hunan&#39;s first-season rice-producing areas in recent years. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We tried planting last year and increased it to 400 acres this year. We are still exploring.” Xiao Mengchu, head of Liulin Agricultural Machinery Cooperative, took agricultural technology expert Deng Yuancai to the fields of Qiliping Village to check the growth of regenerated rice. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Deng Yuancai, deputy director of the Qiyang Municipal Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau and senior agronomist, said: “After the first harvest, the dormant buds surviving on the rice piles are used under appropriate environmental conditions such as moisture, nutrients, temperature, and light. , you can grow another crop of rice and harvest another season.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Technology &quot;savvy people&quot; go to the fields to provide guidance, giving grain farmers new options for growing rice. Deng Yuancai said that on the basis of ensuring double-cropping rice planting area, Qiyang promoted regenerated rice according to local conditions, which was very popular among grain farmers. Xiao Mengchu did some calculations: &quot;Last year, we harvested 1,400 kilograms per mu in the first season of rice planting, and another 300 kilograms in the second season. This is a double harvest, increasing production by 20%, saving water and labor. We plan to expand to more than 1,000 acres next year.&quot;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;In order to support the development of regeneration rice cultivation, Hunan has screened and promoted a batch of high-quality rice seeds. This year, the regeneration rice planting area has reached 3.16 million acres. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Improved varieties also need good opportunities. Not long ago, a thousand-acre demonstration plot in Qingquanhe Village, Zifu Town, Ningxiang City carried out production testing and acceptance. The regenerated rice combine harvester developed by the Hunan Agricultural Equipment Research Institute made its &quot;debut&quot; in the field. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The new harvester can significantly reduce damage to rice piles, which is beneficial to the growth and harvesting of regenerated rice.” Fang Baohua, a researcher at the Hunan Provincial Rice Research Institute, said, “Comprehensive calculations can drive an increase in the average income of regenerated rice. 200 yuan.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Technological empowerment helps farmers use good technology to grow good food. This year, Hunan has innovatively established a mechanism for agricultural science and technology personnel to &quot;unveil the list and take charge&quot; to lead the demonstration film, and implemented six special actions to increase the yield per unit area in large areas, which can increase the yield per unit area of ​​major grain and oil crops by about 1 percentage point; the provincial-level grain production average of 10,000 acres of early rice demonstration film The yield per mu reached 556 kilograms, an increase of 4.2% over the previous year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Adjust the structure of intercropping to tap the potential of increasing grain and oil production&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From Baishui Town to Fuqiao Village, farmer Li Dechun has just harvested soybeans and corn, and the crop straws were immediately recycled Loading the car. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Dechun has been planting soybeans and corn in a strip compound for three years. The planting area is getting larger year by year, and the benefits are getting better year by year. &quot;With 4 rows of soybeans and 2 rows of corn, the yield of corn per mu is 1,200 jins, and the yield of soybeans per acre is 300 jins. The straws of soybeans and corns can also be returned to the fields and sold for money.&quot; .&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past, this sloping land had insufficient soil fertility and the yield could not increase. Li Dechun asked the local agricultural technology station for help. Experts suggested interplanting soybeans and using the nitrogen-fixing effect of soybean rhizobia to improve the soil. 2021年开始，地养好了，他又在农业农村部门的建议下，开始进行大豆玉米带状复合种植。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“同一块地，高低搭配，既有玉米又有大豆，再算上秸秆收入，一亩地毛收入就有2000元左右。带状复合种植还有补贴。”李德纯说，得益于新种法，土地如今越种越肥，“明年计划扩种1000亩，水肥一体，还准备上新农机收玉米，全程机械化。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年，祁阳大豆玉米带状复合种植推广面积达到2.5万亩，比2022年增长7000亩，是2021年的8倍多。在邓远财看来，这一模式还有潜力可挖：“在保持玉米不减产的基础上，每亩能增收100多公斤大豆。开展机械化作业，种植户积极性越来越高。新开垦的旱土、园地都可以因地制宜开展间作套种，挖掘粮油生产潜力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;湖南同时扩大油菜种植面积，在传统非双季稻优势区，重点推广“一季稻+油菜”生产模式。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在长沙市望城区茶亭镇，稻油轮作有了新办法。创联农机专业合作社联合社去年连片种了2000多亩油菜，统一集中育秧移栽，统一生产技术规程，亩产比普通田块增收50多斤，还实现了油菜观赏、食用的双重效应。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;望城区农技服务中心主任马煜霁介绍，如今在茶亭，连片种植油菜已超万亩，在保障油料供应的同时，以油菜花海为主题的观光农业在长沙打响了品牌，进一步提升了稻油轮作的综合效益。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;记者从湖南省农业农村厅了解到，今年，湖南完成大豆玉米带状复合种植面积110.4万亩，同时在非双季稻优势区发展稻油轮作80万亩，最大限度利用光能、空间和时间资源，提高农作物产量。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;延伸粮食产业链，发展社会化服务&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“上次区里组织惠农直播，我们的盒装优质稻米卖出了500多盒。”茶亭镇静慎村哲浩农机专业合作社理事长姚鹏飞说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;姚鹏飞是90后，前些年返乡回家从事水稻种植，牵头成立哲浩农机专业合作社，经营范围涵盖从选种、育秧到种植、加工的稻米全产业链。他贷款40多万元，上加工设备、建仓储基地，种的中稻、晚稻可以全部实现自己加工。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;延伸加工，还要创响品牌。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“优质才能优价。”经过反复试验、筛选，姚鹏飞选定了“玉针香”“野香优莉丝”“黄华占”等优质品种，创立自己的大米品牌，很受市场欢迎，卖出了好价钱。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;聚力粮食规模化品牌化发展，鼓励农业企业发展连片种植，采用统一品种，发展精细化加工，延伸粮食产业链，“一企一片一种”的新模式正在湖南各地逐步推开。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在益阳市赫山区兰溪镇罗湖村“农田谋士”服务点，种粮大户龚明华忙着查看服务项目。 “代育秧、代旋耕、代插秧，大企业带着我们种订单，一大片就种一个粮食品种。每亩节省成本200元以上，350亩田能省下7万多元。”龚明华说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“农田谋士”提供社会化服务，由龙头企业带动，提供标准化服务，进行早稻专业化集中育秧，优质晚稻集中连片种植。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“以前在赫山区，一个村就种七八个水稻品种，田间管理效率低，效益一直上不去。”湖南农田谋士现代农业集团有限公司董事长简丽蓉介绍，今年，“农田谋士”为湖南6个区县的100多名种粮大户托管稻田2.8万亩，开展绿色生产、统防统治16.5万亩。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“优质品种，标准种植，质量稳定，种粮有赚头！”简丽蓉算了一笔账：农资集中采购，开展农机社会化服务，种粮综合成本降低5%以上；订单生产的稻谷收购价普遍比粮食最低收购价高20%以上；打造区域公共品牌“赫山兰溪大米”，销售价格比普通大米高4倍以上。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多打粮，打好粮。湖南省农业农村厅相关负责人介绍，湖南深入实施绿色高质高效行动，加快建设“一企一片一种”优质稻标准化基地，预计今年专用型早稻、高档优质晚稻种植面积将分别达到700万亩、1600万亩。 &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 05:56:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 欢度国庆  祝福祖国]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/02/nw.D110000renmrb_20231002_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月02日星期一&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231002/1696188496132_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;10月1日，河南洛阳汝阳县张河社区杨树岭村举行锣鼓赛，祝福祖国欣欣向荣、国泰民安。&lt;BR/>;康红军摄（人民视觉）&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231002/1696188505977_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;10月1日，广东汕头举行英歌舞巡演和大型花车巡游活动，近20万人现场观看，超12万华侨华人通过网络收看现场直播，共同庆祝中华人民共和国成立74周年。&lt;BR/>;方淦明摄（人民视觉）&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231002/1696188513667_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;10月1日，浙江杭州西湖景区游人如织。杭州亚运会赛期恰逢国庆假期，各地游客前来感受亚运氛围，游览杭州美景。&lt;BR/>;本报记者伊霄摄&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 05:56:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 香港、澳门特区政府举行升旗仪式和酒会庆祝新中国成立74周年]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/02/nw.D110000renmrb_20231002_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月02日星期一&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报香港10月1日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者冯学知）香港特区政府1日上午举行升旗仪式和国庆酒会，庆祝中华人民共和国成立74周年。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;升旗仪式上午8时在金紫荆广场举行。全国政协副主席梁振英，香港特区行政长官李家超，香港中联办、驻港国家安全公署、外交部驻港特派员公署、解放军驻港部队负责人，以及香港社会各界知名人士等出席。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;升旗仪式结束后，观礼嘉宾移步香港会议展览中心内出席国庆酒会。李家超在酒会上致辞表示，在强国建设、民族复兴的征程上，国家坚持开放、全面推动高质量发展，为香港带来源源不绝的机遇。要继续运用好“一国两制”下背靠祖国、联通世界的独特优势，主动积极融入国家发展大局，对接“十四五”规划、粤港澳大湾区建设、“一带一路”倡议等，提升国际竞争力，推动经济发展。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;李家超表示，香港正处于由治及兴的关键时刻，我们要珍惜机会，谋发展、拼经济、拼竞争力，很高兴看到香港在这方面的共识非常强烈。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;本报澳门10月1日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（富子梅、唐佳）澳门特区政府1日举行升旗仪式和酒会，庆祝中华人民共和国成立74周年。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;全国政协副主席何厚铧，澳门特区行政长官贺一诚，澳门中联办、外交部驻澳特派员公署、解放军驻澳部队负责人，以及澳门社会各界知名人士分别出席了升旗仪式和庆祝酒会。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;升旗仪式上午8时在金莲花广场举行。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;庆祝酒会当日在中国与葡语国家商贸合作服务平台综合体举行。贺一诚致辞时表示，祖国是澳门的最强大后盾，是澳门应对各种困难和挑战的最大信心和底气，澳门特区的繁荣稳定和各项事业取得进步，离不开中央长期以来的大力支持。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;贺一诚表示，澳门经济复苏势头良好，特区政府将抓住有利时机，全力推动社会经济复苏发展。进一步完善国家安全的法律制度和执行机制，坚定维护国家主权、安全、发展利益。加快推进经济适度多元发展。持续保障和改善民生。全力推进横琴粤澳深度合作区建设。 &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 05:56:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 国家繁荣富强  人民幸福安康]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/02/nw.D110000renmrb_20231002_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月02日星期一&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231002/1696189871453_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;10月1日，隆重的升国旗仪式在北京天安门广场举行。&lt;BR/>;新华社记者鞠焕宗摄&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;国旗飘扬，激发爱国力量；国歌雄壮，奏响奋进乐章。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“新征程上，我们的前途一片光明”，在庆祝中华人民共和国成立74周年招待会上，习近平总书记深情寄语，激励亿万中华儿女坚定不移朝着强国建设、民族复兴的宏伟目标奋勇前进。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10月1日，各地开展丰富多彩的活动，抒发爱国之情，砥砺强国之志，热烈庆祝中华人民共和国成立74周年，共同祝愿国家繁荣富强，祝福各族人民幸福安康。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;同升一面国旗&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;唱响爱国赞歌&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10月1日，从广袤乡野到城市街巷，从雪域高原到鱼米之乡，五星红旗在神州大地冉冉升起、迎风飘扬，全国各族人民向新中国成立74周年表达深深的祝福。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10月1日早晨6时许，伴随着清晨的第一缕阳光，30多万各界群众在北京天安门广场共同见证五星红旗冉冉升起的庄严时刻。“向国旗——敬礼！”随着仪仗队员的口号声，《义勇军进行曲》响彻天安门广场。升旗仪式结束后，伴随着《歌唱祖国》的奏乐，人们挥舞着手中的国旗，尽情唱响爱国赞歌，“祝福祖国”“祖国万岁”的欢呼声在广场上空久久回荡。“作为大学生，我将努力成长为担当民族复兴重任的栋梁之材！”北京大学软件与微电子学院学生张琦暄观看完升旗仪式后难掩激动之情。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;天安门广场向西约90公里，苍翠的群山间，五星红旗迎着朝阳冉冉升起。面朝国旗，35名身着“火焰蓝”的消防员整齐列队。在不久前的抗洪救灾中，北京门头沟区消防救援支队斋堂消防救援站的指战员冲锋在前，坚守一线，先后营救、转移群众600余人。“我们众志成城，有效应对洪涝灾害，任何困难都打不倒英雄的中国人民。”斋堂消防救援站副站长黄志川说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着国歌响起，黑龙江黑河出入境边防检查站执勤七队民警苏仕健展臂一挥，五星红旗冉冉升起。原本喧闹的黑河水运旅检口岸广场安静下来，数十名移民管理警察和等待出境的游客纷纷驻足，久久凝望五星红旗。“能在国门下升起国旗，我无比骄傲。”苏仕健说，“国庆期间，我和战友们会继续坚守岗位，全力以赴做好本职工作。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在位于广东珠海横琴粤澳深度合作区的横琴科学城（三期）项目工地上，伴随着雄壮的国歌声，建筑工人与管理人员面朝国旗行注目礼。“看着国旗冉冉升起，心中的激动无以言表。我们将继续通过自己的双手为国家的建设发展添砖加瓦，立足岗位作贡献。”中建五局项目生产经理杜兵说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10月1日早晨7时许，五星红旗迎着海风在海南三沙市永兴岛冉冉升起。三沙市干部职工、驻岛官兵、各行各业代表齐唱国歌，表达深深的爱国之情。“国旗所在就是责任所在，每次看到国旗在海岛上升起，我都感到无比神圣、光荣。”三沙市永兴海岸派出所所长贺胜说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10月1日上午10时，西藏拉萨市布达拉宫广场，近2000名各族各界干部群众参加升国旗仪式。拉萨市城关区吉崩岗街道木如社区居民巴桑杰姆每年国庆都会来参加升国旗仪式，“每次来看升旗都很震撼。在党的领导下，西藏各族群众的生活会一年比一年好，越来越幸福。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国庆之际，中国人民解放军指战员、武警部队官兵坚守战位、练兵备战，同时开展丰富多彩的活动，庆祝中华人民共和国成立74周年。10月1日，海军西宁舰全体官兵在飞行甲板举行升旗仪式。鲜艳的五星红旗在西宁舰主桅冉冉升起，官兵们精神抖擞，面向国旗庄严敬礼。机电部门轮机技师张波浪说：“作为一名服役24年的舰艇机电兵，我肩负着保障战舰劈波万里的神圣职责。请祖国和人民放心，强军有我！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;追寻红色记忆&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;厚植家国情怀&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欢度国庆，是对光辉历程的回望，也是爱国主义的共鸣。各地干部群众瞻仰革命旧址、观看历史展览，重温红色岁月、厚植家国情怀，传承英烈精神、汲取奋进力量，立志走好新时代的长征路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上海太平湖畔，以中共一大会址为设计原型的国庆特别景观“风华正茂”增添了庄重喜庆的节日氛围。“中共一大会址是一栋典型的石库门建筑……”黄陂南路与兴业路交叉口，志愿者王智正在讲述中共一大会址的故事。东华大学学生肖佑波认真聆听，“实地学习红色历史，更能深刻感受到今天幸福生活的来之不易。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10月1日，安徽铜陵博物馆，参观“意志战胜钢铁——中国人民志愿军抗美援朝胜利70周年纪念展”的观众络绎不绝。“博物馆希望通过举办展览，弘扬伟大抗美援朝精神，传承红色基因，厚植家国情怀。”铜陵博物馆副馆长姚琤介绍。市民周先生特地带着孩子前来参观：“在这个特殊的日子里接受一次爱国主义教育，让孩子从小就了解和铭记这段历史。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10月1日，湖南湘潭市湘乡市东山书院迎来了众多参观者。湘乡市东皋学校初一学生谢冰骐向大家讲述革命先辈在东山书院求学成才、立志报国的故事。3年前成为湘乡红色文化“小小讲解员”后，她经常利用假期在东山书院等地讲述红色故事、传承红色基因，精彩的讲解吸引众多参观者驻足聆听。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从正门进入陕西扶眉战役纪念馆，纪念广场正中心一座高19.49米的纪念碑映入眼帘。1日清晨，眉县常兴镇干部李少辉和同事们来到纪念广场瞻仰，汲取奋进力量。“没有革命先烈的牺牲，就没有今天幸福美好的生活。我将继续用实际行动履职尽责、服务群众。”李少辉说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;抒发爱国之情&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;砥砺强国之志&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拳拳爱国心，殷殷报国情。各地干部群众用歌声抒发爱国之情，用奋斗砥砺强国之志，充分感受到中国共产党的伟大，充分感受到新中国的进步，充分感受到作为中国人的幸福。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10月1日，河南太康县人民广场格外热闹，1000多名党员干部和社会各界群众挥舞国旗，伴着音乐《我爱你，中国》，高声齐诵爱国诗篇。铿锵有力的声音吸引许多行人停下脚步，一字一句跟诵。“我已经光荣在党50多年了，今天诵读爱国诗篇，更加激发了心中的爱国热情。”太康县逊母口镇魏庄村村民高伽明老人说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10月1日，湖北武汉市江岸区胜利街武汉中共中央机关旧址纪念馆广场上，来自武汉歌舞剧院、武汉杂技团的专业演员们为观众带来国庆专场“中国力量”文艺演出。杂技《中国力量》刚柔并济，歌曲《我和我的祖国》悠扬动听，现场气氛在阵阵欢呼声中沸腾起来。“在这个举国欢庆的日子能为人民群众放声歌唱，我感到非常光荣。”武汉歌舞剧院青年演员杨烁表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巍巍青山绵延苍翠，滚滚河水奔流不息，在贵州遵义市习水县土城镇，赤水河畔回荡着铿锵有力的歌声，唱出了气势昂扬的英雄气概。10月1日上午，位于土城镇的四渡赤水纪念馆上演《长征组歌》音乐会，由当地群众组成的四渡赤水艺术团深情演绎经典歌曲，用歌声赞颂伟大新时代，祝福国家繁荣昌盛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10月1日，甘肃高台县中国工农红军西路军纪念馆迎来一批青少年观众。一件件展陈实物、一张张历史图片，再现当年西路军英勇奋战的历程，吸引同学们驻足观看。“今天的幸福生活来之不易，离不开革命先烈的浴血奋战。我要努力学习、报效国家，争做矢志不渝的奋斗者。”高台县解放街小学五年级学生夏若菡说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;激扬爱国情，共筑中国梦。走过74年光辉历程，神州大地更加生机勃勃，社会主义中国更加欣欣向荣，全党全国各族人民更加自信自强。亿万中华儿女坚定信心，振奋精神，团结奋斗，必将激发起奋进新征程、建功新时代的信心底气，汇聚起爱国奋斗的磅礴力量。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（综合本报记者王昊男、施芳、张艺开、姜晓丹、曹文轩、琼达卓嘎、金正波、曹玲娟、徐靖、申智林、张丹华、毕京津、范昊天、程焕、赵帅杰报道；本期统筹：赵政）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 05:56:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 中欧班列谱写丝路新传奇]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/02/nw.D110000renmrb_20231002_5-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年10月02日星期一&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;随着一声汽笛长鸣，一列搭载着54个集装箱汽车配件、日用品等货物的中欧班列近日从天津新港站开出，开往内蒙古二连浩特口岸。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;广袤的亚欧大陆上，古有丝绸之路驼铃阵阵，今有“钢铁驼队”奔驰不息。经过10年发展，中欧班列已累计开行7.7万列，运送货物731万标准箱，货值超3400亿美元，成为国际经贸合作的重要桥梁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;联通亚欧，开辟运输新通道&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;9月15日，中欧班列国际合作论坛上，中国国家铁路集团有限公司（以下简称“国铁集团”）宣布：全程时刻表中欧班列已开通5条线路，累计开行80列。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以西安至德国杜伊斯堡为例，每周三、周六凌晨3时55分从西安国际港站发车，运行9908公里，10日后可抵达杜伊斯堡，全程运行时间较普通班列压缩30%以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至目前，中欧班列已联通我国境内112座城市，通达欧洲25个国家和地区的200多座城市，以及沿途11个亚洲国家和地区的100多座城市，开辟亚欧陆路运输新通道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——通道网络逐步完善。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在中哈（连云港）物流合作基地，机车穿梭、作业繁忙，货物一下班列便搭乘轮船出海；在中欧班列（沈阳）集结中心，起重机抓取一个个有“中国铁路”标识的集装箱装至班列上；在内蒙古二连浩特口岸，一列列中欧班列完成换装工作，等待出境……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国铁集团数据显示，中欧班列已形成经阿拉山口、霍尔果斯、二连浩特、满洲里、绥芬河、同江口岸出境的西、中、东3条通道，时速120公里图定中欧班列运行线已达86条，实现了亚欧国际联运的网络化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——口岸能力大幅提升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;口岸，是中欧班列运输途中的重要节点。班列将在这里完成换装、报关、清关、出境等手续。10年来，中欧班列沿线国家加强既有口岸能力扩建，开辟新口岸，不断提升国际联运能力，满足日益增长的运输需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;俯瞰满洲里铁路口岸，一列列中欧班列在宽准轨线路上铺展开来，高高耸立的龙门吊用“巨手”将色彩斑斓的集装箱整齐码垛。经过多次升级，满洲里铁路口岸国际联运列车日换装量增至840标准箱，换装能力比2020年提升1倍，国际联运更加高效便捷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国铁集团数据显示，2022年，阿拉山口、霍尔果斯、满洲里、二连浩特、绥芬河等口岸分别过境中欧班列5141列、3150列、4838列、2549列、884列，比2016年分别增3981列、3080列、4527列、2388列、884列。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——枢纽功能持续增强。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10年来，我国积极推动郑州、重庆、成都、西安、乌鲁木齐等中欧班列集结中心示范工程建设，打造服务优、效率高、成本低的现代物流枢纽，促进中欧班列开行由“点对点”向“枢纽对枢纽”转变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以西安国际港站为例，从最初的四等小站到如今的一等货运站，西安已经成为中欧班列重要的集结中心。今年，西安国际港站再次升级：货物装卸线路由19条增至29条，12条货物线完成改造，具备直接发车功能，装卸能力提升30%。如今，西安国际港站成功跃升世界一流内陆港，设计年集装箱吞吐量540万标准箱、年铁路货运量6600万吨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数据显示，2022年5个集结中心共开行中欧班列8800列，占中欧班列开行总数的53%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;量质齐升，创新物流新模式&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;集装箱层层堆叠，龙门吊忙碌装卸，成都国际铁路港一派繁忙，“陆上港口”名不虚传。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“产线尽头就是集装箱，车间隔壁就是铁路港。”TCL光电科技（成都）有限公司财务负责人杨怡说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;十年发展，中欧班列构建了一条全天候、大运量、绿色低碳的物流大通道，开创了国际运输合作新局面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;经济环保优势突出，广受企业货主欢迎。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;内蒙古乌兰察布市嘉泽木业有限公司主营木材加工。企业负责人郭进海最常去的一个地方，就是内蒙古最大的中欧班列集结基地——七苏木物流园。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郭进海给记者算了一笔账：每进口一吨木材，中欧班列运输可比公路省50元，按每年20万吨的使用量来算，可节约近1000万元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数据显示，同样运一批货物从中国到欧洲，中欧班列运输费用约是航空运输的1/5，运输时间约是海运的1/4，且具有稳定性高的特点，在满足高附加值、强时效性等特定物流需求方面具有比较优势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“不仅如此，中欧班列平均碳排放量为航空运输的1/15、公路运输的1/7，为应对全球气候变化、交通可持续发展发挥了积极作用。”国铁集团货运部有关负责人说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多式联运快速发展，服务能力大幅提升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来到厦门海沧保税港区，一艘来自越南的集装箱班轮已顺利靠港。现场正忙碌地组织集装箱卸船进站，集装箱将搭乘中欧班列前往哈萨克斯坦，实现“海丝”“陆丝”无缝衔接。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“对东亚、东南亚国家和地区的企业而言，选择海运抵达厦门，再搭乘中欧班列前往欧洲，比全程海运节省近一半时间，这是中欧班列（厦门）独有的国际海铁联运优势。”中国铁路南昌局集团有限公司漳州车务段海沧站站长赵励强说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;海铁、公铁、空铁多式联运，让中欧班列效能更好释放。国家发展改革委数据显示，目前，以大连港、天津港、青岛港、连云港港等沿海港口为起点的中欧班列线路已达29条；广州、成都等城市已依托中欧班列打造了“空铁联运”跨境电商出口新模式，推动“铁海公空邮”综合运输一体化融合发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;互利共赢，搭建合作新平台&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;驰而不息的中欧班列，为沿途国家、地区发展带来发展新机遇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——提速货物往来，优化开放格局。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;郑州，地处中原腹地。过去，大宗货物出口欧洲，需先运至东部海港，再经海运入欧。如今依托中欧班列，郑州一跃成为内陆开放新高地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“2013年以来，中欧班列（郑州）从每周&#39;单趟对开&#39;到现在每周最高往返34列，车次越开越密，境内外合作伙伴达到6000多家，形成&#39;以运带贸、以贸促运&#39;的产业互补良性发展格局。”中国铁路郑州局集团有限公司圃田站站长郜飞说，依托中欧班列，河南开行东方红拖拉机、信阳茶叶、南阳香菇、商丘棉花等定制合作班列，推动特色农贸产品走出国门。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家发展改革委数据显示，中欧班列运送货物货值占中欧货物贸易的比重逐年提升，从2015年的1%增至2021年的9%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——聚拢产业集群，拓宽发展空间。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多年来，重庆先后获批国家铁路一类口岸、整车进口口岸、首次药品进口口岸等。“汽车整车进口口岸的设立，带动长安、东风等品牌汽车整车及零部件出口，促进了重庆乃至西部汽车产业集群的发展壮大，开启了中国西部内陆整车进口新篇章。”渝新欧（重庆）供应链管理有限公司总经理刘太平说。今年1至8月，中欧班列（重庆）进出口整车6.4万台、增长约36.7倍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——联通广阔市场，打开“共赢大门”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在“世界超市”浙江义乌，有一家500多平方米的西班牙商品进口馆，销售西班牙红酒与橄榄油等商品。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“以前，苦于没有销售渠道，不少西班牙的优质产品一直无法打开市场。”进口馆负责人金海军说，中欧班列开通后，这些产品被中国采购商销售至中国乃至日本、韩国等地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与此同时，义乌的小商品也通过中欧班列源源不断运往西班牙马德里，助力其成为欧洲重要的小商品集散地。今年以来，中欧班列（义乌）累计开行超1000列，商品品类达5万多种。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据介绍，这些年，从中国通过中欧班列运往欧洲的货物品类，从最初的手机、电脑等，拓展到汽车整车、机械设备、电子产品等53大门类，欧洲运往中国的货物品类从早期的木材、汽车及零配件等逐步拓展到机电产品、食品、医疗器械等。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中欧班列发展势头强劲。今年1至8月，共开行11638列、发送货物126.2万标准箱，同比分别增长10%、23%。未来，“钢铁驼队”必将给国际经贸合作带来更多机遇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（本报记者朱佩娴、靳博、刘洪超、白光迪、翟钦奇参与采写）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Mon, 02 Oct 2023 05:56:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>