<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平出席亚太经合组织第三十次领导人非正式会议并发表重要讲话]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20231119_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Sunday, November 19, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/19/01/rmrb2023111901p25_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;November 10, local time On the morning of the 7th, the 30th APEC Economic Leaders’ Meeting was held at the Moscone Center in San Francisco, USA. President Xi Jinping attended the meeting and delivered an important speech entitled &quot;Stick to the Original Aspirations, Unite and Cooperate to Work Together to Promote High-Quality Growth in the Asia-Pacific.&quot; &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Li Xueren&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;■Since APEC established a regular leadership meeting mechanism , has always been at the forefront of global openness and development, effectively promoted regional trade and investment liberalization and facilitation, economic and technological development, and the flow of materials and people, creating the world-renowned &quot;Asia-Pacific Miracle.&quot; Currently, the century-old changes in the world are accelerating and the world economy is facing various risks and challenges. As the engine of global growth, the Asia-Pacific shoulders greater responsibilities of the times. As leaders of the Asia-Pacific region, we must think deeply about what kind of Asia-Pacific we want to bring to the middle of this century. How to create the next &quot;golden thirty years&quot; of Asia-Pacific development? How can APEC better play its role in this process? &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■ We should uphold the original intention of Asia-Pacific cooperation, respond responsibly to the call of the times, work together to respond to global challenges, fully implement Putrajaya’s vision, and build an open, dynamic, strong, and peaceful Asia-Pacific community. Achieve common prosperity for the people of the Asia-Pacific and future generations&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■First, adhere to the innovation-driven approach. Second, adhere to the orientation of openness. Third, adhere to green development. Fourth, insist on universal benefit and sharing&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■China is comprehensively advancing the great cause of building a strong country and rejuvenating the nation with Chinese-style modernization. China adheres to the path of peaceful development, adheres to high-quality development, adheres to high-level opening up, and uses Chinese-style modernization to provide new opportunities for promoting the modernization of countries around the world. China is willing to work with all parties to promote Asia-Pacific cooperation to achieve more fruitful results and jointly create the next &quot;golden thirty years&quot; of the Asia-Pacific.&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>; San Francisco, November 17, this newspaper &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Chen Yiming and Song Jingsi) On the morning of November 17, local time, the 30th APEC Leaders’ Informal Meeting was held at the Mosconi Center in San Francisco, the United States. President Xi Jinping attended the meeting and delivered an important speech titled &quot;Stick to the Original Aspirations, Unite and Cooperate, and Work Together to Promote High-Quality Growth in the Asia-Pacific.&quot; (See the second edition for the full text of his speech)&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that since the establishment of the regular leadership meeting mechanism, APEC has always been at the forefront of global openness and development, effectively promoting regional trade and investment liberalization and facilitation, and economic development. Technological development and the flow of materials and personnel have created the “Asia-Pacific Miracle” that has attracted worldwide attention. Currently, the century-old changes in the world are accelerating and the world economy is facing various risks and challenges. As the engine of global growth, the Asia-Pacific shoulders greater responsibilities of the times. As leaders of the Asia-Pacific region, we must think deeply about what kind of Asia-Pacific we want to bring to the middle of this century. How to create the next &quot;golden thirty years&quot; of Asia-Pacific development? How can APEC better play its role in this process? &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that we should uphold the original intention of Asia-Pacific cooperation, respond responsibly to the call of the times, work together to respond to global challenges, fully implement the Putrajaya vision, and build an open, dynamic, strong, and peaceful Asia-Pacific community to achieve common prosperity for the people of the Asia-Pacific and future generations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;First, adhere to the innovation-driven approach. We must more actively promote scientific and technological exchanges and cooperation and work together to create an open, fair, just and non-discriminatory scientific and technological development environment. Accelerate digital transformation, narrow the digital divide, support the application of new technologies such as big data, cloud computing, artificial intelligence, and quantum computing, and continuously shape new momentum and new advantages for the development of the Asia-Pacific. China has proposed APEC initiatives such as digital rural construction, corporate digital identity, and the use of digital technology to promote green and low-carbon transformation to better empower the development of the Asia-Pacific. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Second, adhere to an open orientation. We must safeguard free and open trade and investment, support and strengthen the multilateral trading system with the World Trade Organization as its core, maintain the stability and smoothness of global industrial and supply chains, and oppose the politicization, weaponization, and pan-security of economic and trade issues. We must unswervingly promote regional economic integration and accelerate the process of the Asia-Pacific Free Trade Area. China successfully hosted the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum, injecting new impetus into promoting global connectivity and building an open world economy. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Third, adhere to green development. We must adhere to the harmonious coexistence of man and nature, accelerate the green and low-carbon transformation of the development model, coordinately promote carbon reduction, pollution reduction, green expansion and growth, and cultivate a green foundation for Asia-Pacific growth. China adheres to the path of ecological priority and green development, and actively and steadily promotes carbon peak and carbon neutrality. We propose APEC cooperation initiatives on green agriculture, sustainable cities, low-carbon energy transformation, and marine pollution prevention and control to promote joint efforts to build a clean and beautiful Asia-Pacific. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Fourth, insist on inclusive sharing. It is necessary to fully implement the United Nations 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development, promote development issues to return to the center of the international agenda, deepen the alignment of development strategies, and jointly solve the global development deficit. All parties are welcome to actively participate in global development initiatives, deepen cooperation in poverty reduction, food security, industrialization, development financing and other fields, and build a global development community so that people of all countries can share the fruits of modernization. China will continue to support APEC in carrying out economic and technological cooperation and jointly make the Asia-Pacific development pie bigger. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that China is comprehensively promoting the construction of a strong country and the great cause of national rejuvenation with Chinese-style modernization. China adheres to the path of peaceful development, adheres to high-quality development, adheres to high-level opening up, and uses Chinese-style modernization to provide new opportunities for promoting the modernization of countries around the world. China is willing to work with all parties to promote Asia-Pacific cooperation to achieve more fruitful results and jointly create the next &quot;Golden Thirty Years&quot; in the Asia-Pacific! &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The meeting was chaired by US President Biden, with the theme of &quot;Creating a Strong and Sustainable Future for All.&quot; &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The meeting issued the &quot;2023 APEC Leaders San Francisco Declaration&quot;. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Wang Yi attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 05:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平回到北京]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20231119_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Sunday, November 19, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Our newspaper, Beijing, November 18th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;On the evening of November 18th, President Xi Jinping held a press conference in San Francisco After meeting with the President of the United States and attending the 30th APEC Economic Leaders&#39; Meeting, he returned to Beijing by special plane. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;On the afternoon of November 17, local time, when Xi Jinping left San Francisco, San Francisco Mayor Breed and other U.S. representatives went to the airport to see him off. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;On the way to the airport, representatives of overseas Chinese and Chinese students gathered on both sides of the road, waving the national flags of China and the United States, warmly bid farewell to President Xi Jinping and congratulated the visit on a complete success. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cai Qi, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and director of the General Office of the CPC Central Committee, Wang Yi, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Minister of Foreign Affairs and other accompanying personnel returned on the same plane. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 05:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - “在历史关头，我们共同作出了正确的选择”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20231119_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Sunday, November 19, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;“This is another separate invitation that is different from the 30th APEC Economic Leaders’ Meeting. &quot;A Sino-US &#39;summit&#39;.&quot; When the news came out that President Xi Jinping was going to the United States to attend the meeting between the heads of state of China and the United States, the world put a spotlight on this trip and defined this trip with &quot;hope.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing-San Francisco spans nearly 10,000 kilometers across the vast Pacific Ocean. The journey has not been smooth. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After decades of ups and downs, &quot;a lot has happened&quot; in Sino-US relations in the past year. Just as President Xi Jinping described it, even though we have reached the end of the road, there will always be a bright future. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The establishment of diplomatic relations between China and the United States was a major event in the past 50 years, and in the next 50 years, &quot;the most important thing in international relations is that China and the United States must find the right way to get along.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;How to get along with the world&#39;s two largest economies, which have different social systems and different stages of development, requires wisdom, structure, foresight and responsibility. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China’s attitude is consistent. President Xi Jinping&#39;s trip itself conveyed a constructive attitude of being responsible for history. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 15th was the day after he arrived in San Francisco, and it was also a day when Sino-US relations went down in history. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping attended two events. One was a meeting at the manor; the other was a welcome banquet jointly organized by American friendship groups. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The direction of Sino-US relations depends on both sides of the table in the Manor Meeting Hall, and also depends on the common choices of more than 1.7 billion Chinese and American people. President Xi Jinping said to President Biden: &quot;Mr. President and I are at the helm of Sino-US relations and bear heavy responsibilities for the people, the world, and history.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Excellent leaders of the older generation , once shouldered heavy responsibilities and made far-sighted strategic choices with a handshake across the Pacific. &quot;So many things are always urgent; the world is changing and time is running out.&quot; &quot;Seize the day and night&quot; quoted during the China-US ice-breaking trip, is this not the current situation and trend faced by China-US relations today? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China-U.S. relations must be thought and planned against the backdrop of the accelerating changes in the world over the past century.” Today, in an era of intertwined events, the creation of the “San Francisco Vision” “brings great benefits to the people of the two countries.” to bring welfare and show responsibility for human progress.&quot; Like the other shore in front of the ocean, people in the storm can see hope and peace. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Our descendants will say that at this historical juncture, we jointly made the right choice.&quot; President Xi Jinping&#39;s eyes were profound and firm. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;A rival or a partner? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“This is a fundamental and management issue”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the morning of the 15th, President Xi Jinping drove into Fiji in a red flag car. Lowry Manor. This is a century-old country estate outside San Francisco. The sky is high, the clouds are wide, the grass and flowers are blooming, and the rich pastoral scenery is as far as the eye can see. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Biden is waiting at the gate of the meeting building. He walked down the steps to greet the Chinese guests who had come from afar. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This meeting in San Francisco is &quot;a year and a day&quot; away from the meeting in Bali. Some people have described the downward spiral of Sino-US relations some time ago as a &quot;roller coaster&quot; with ups and downs that is heart-wrenching. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In front of the magenta checkered wooden door, the two heads of state smiled and shook hands, walked into the meeting hall side by side, and left their expectations to the camera. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The world is looking forward to a turnaround in Sino-US relations. The international community needs a stable Sino-US relationship more than ever. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the meeting hall, just like the last meeting in Bali, President Biden first started by talking about the exchanges between the two heads of state: &quot;We have spent a lot of time together in the past ten years or so.&quot;&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping expressed the same emotion: &quot;I also remembered that 12 years ago, as the Vice President of the United States, you invited me, then the Vice President of China, to visit the United States. That meeting is still vivid in my mind, and I am filled with emotion.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Head-of-state diplomacy is the most powerful chapter in the long history of state-to-state relations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, meetings at the manor, night talks in Yingtai, autumn talks in the White House, long talks at the West Lake... every meeting and in-depth conversation between the heads of state of China and the United States has become a historical milestone in the relationship between the two countries, stirring up excitement. Long-lasting echoes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After long-term dealings, China has formed the fundamental principles for handling Sino-US relations: &quot;mutual respect, peaceful coexistence, and win-win cooperation.&quot; During the meeting, President Xi Jinping said sincerely: &quot;This is not only the experience extracted from the 50 years of Sino-US relations, but also the inspiration brought by the conflicts between major powers in history. It should be the direction of joint efforts between China and the United States.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>; &quot;He who gets the big can take the small.&quot; This ancient proverb from Ouyang Xiu, a great scholar in the Northern Song Dynasty, contains Eastern philosophy. President Xi Jinping has cited it many times, and it seems to be a window into China’s handling of Sino-US relations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“One is to strengthen unity and cooperation” and “the other is to adopt a zero-sum mentality.” President Xi Jinping pointed out concisely and comprehensively: “The two choices represent two directions and will determine the future of mankind and the future of the earth. .&quot; The grand framework focuses on the strategic, overall and directional issues of Sino-US relations, looking beyond the two sides to the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This scene touches the depths of history. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 1972, the handshake between Chairman Mao Zedong and President Nixon melted the long-standing ice. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;More than 50 years have passed in the blink of an eye. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On this day, President Xi Jinping elaborated on the issue he has &quot;been thinking about&quot;: &quot;How to make the giant ship of China-U.S. relations avoid reefs and shoals, sail through strong winds and waves, and not yaw, stall, or collide?&quot; ? The first thing to answer is whether China and the United States are rivals or partners. This is a fundamental and overarching question.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The fundamental and overarching question is the &quot;journey of the great road.&quot; . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the meeting, President Xi Jinping came up with solutions to the problem: &quot;establish a correct understanding&quot;, &quot;effectively manage differences&quot;, &quot;promote mutually beneficial cooperation&quot;, &quot;take on the responsibilities of a major country&quot; and &quot;promote people-to-people and cultural exchanges&quot;. Each item is defined by &quot;common&quot;, which also clearly states China&#39;s attitude: &quot;China is willing to be a partner and friend with the United States.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In meetings, luncheons, and walks, the heads of state of China and the United States attended We spent more than 4 hours together in the manor. Meeting tables, banquet halls, flagstone paths, their topics are wide-ranging and in-depth. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two sides talked about the Taiwan issue. This is also the most important and sensitive issue in Sino-US relations. President Xi Jinping pointed out the key point: &quot;The United States should embody its stance of not supporting &#39;Taiwan independence&#39; in concrete actions, stop arming Taiwan, and support China&#39;s peaceful reunification. China will eventually be reunified and will inevitably be reunified.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From From Bali to San Francisco, President Biden continued his promise of “four no-nos and one no-no”. &quot;I would like to reiterate the five-point commitment made at the Bali meeting, namely: the United States does not seek a new Cold War, does not seek to change China&#39;s system, does not seek to strengthen alliances against China, does not support &#39;Taiwan independence,&#39; and has no intention of conflict with China .&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;We adhere to the one-China policy, and I will not change this.&quot; President Biden emphasized again at the press conference after the heads of state meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“You can see from a distance that the wind and waves are small, and from the sky you can feel that the sea is flat.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That night, when he met with Newsom, the governor of California, President Xi Jinping talked about the meeting and told The frankness and in-depthness of the meeting at the manor: &quot;President Biden and I have known each other for many years, so when we met, we were all straightforward.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Is it you who loses and I win, or win-win cooperation? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&quot;It is completely possible for mutual achievement, mutual benefit and win-win&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the four seasons come and go, they breed upward power and bury the seeds of great change. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At that time, when the &quot;Shanghai Communique&quot; was drafting, which was a symbol of breaking the ice in Sino-US relations, the &quot;trade and exchanges&quot; part did not arouse much interest from the US representative Kissinger: &quot;No matter how hard we work, we will continue to work hard.&quot; At most, it only accounts for a very small share of our overall economy.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At that time, it was impossible to imagine that the &quot;marginal fields&quot; they defined would grow into a magnificent chapter that would stir up the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China and the United States are the world’s top two economies, with an economic aggregate exceeding one-third of the world’s, a total population accounting for nearly a quarter of the world’s, and bilateral trade accounting for approximately one-fifth of the world’s. , the interests of both sides are very closely intertwined.&quot; President Xi Jinping recently used this set of data to illustrate the broad foundation of cooperation between the two countries and the vast space for win-win results. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At Philoli Manor, President Xi Jinping detailed the cooperation blueprint to President Biden: &quot;China and the United States have broad common interests in many fields, including traditional fields such as economy, trade, and agriculture, as well as climate change, artificial intelligence, etc. and other emerging areas.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Biden responded positively: &quot;The United States is willing to continue to develop economic and trade relations with China, strengthen cooperation in important fields such as climate change, drug control, and artificial intelligence, and is happy to see the two countries increase direct flights. , expand exchanges in education science and technology and personnel exchanges.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“China and the United States’ respective successes are opportunities for each other” and “can achieve mutual success and achieve mutual benefit and win-win results.” These judgments of President Xi Jinping are consolidating Sino-US relations. cornerstone of development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before the joint welcome banquet of American friendship groups that night, President Xi Jinping met with thirty or forty representatives of the American business community and shook hands with them one by one. Many people vividly described their stories of win-win cooperation with China in short words. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the subsequent dinner, when President Xi Jinping talked about &quot;making the list of cooperation longer and making the cake of cooperation bigger,&quot; there was a wave of applause. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the era of globalization, the development of the two major &quot;locomotives&quot; of the world economy is destined to be one among you and one among me. The leaders of the two countries also interacted from time to time around &quot;Made in China&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At Philoli Manor, after the meeting, President Biden sent President Xi Jinping to the car. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;This car is so beautiful.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Hongqi car, made in China.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Time goes back to 2015. During that visit to the United States, President Xi Jinping talked with then-U.S. Vice President Biden on the eve of the meeting. Biden introduced that his tie was “made in China.” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The quality of your tie should be good. When you wear it, it is equivalent to advertising for them. I wonder if they will pay advertising fees?&quot; President Xi Jinping said wittily. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Across the Pacific Ocean, the fields of cooperation are vast and vast. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking at economy and trade, bilateral trade volume has reached 760 billion US dollars, an increase of hundreds of times since the establishment of diplomatic relations, accounting for 1/5 of the world; looking at employment, two-way investment between China and the United States has supported millions of jobs in both countries. Jobs; looking at people&#39;s livelihood, Sino-US trade saves hundreds of dollars in costs for every American family every year...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the west coast of the Pacific, San Francisco&#39;s sister city of Shanghai, the sixth CIIE has just concluded. Participating American companies have become the highlight of this CIIE: the number exceeds 200, the highest number ever. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Continue backtracking. In March this year, the China Development Forum attracted 67 foreign business leaders, many of whom were from the United States. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Tesla, Microsoft, Apple, Intel, General Motors... Since the beginning of this year, the &quot;heads&quot; of American companies have visited China intensively. The detailed transoceanic route just confirms President Xi Jinping’s profound insights during the meeting: “Under the current situation, the common interests of the two countries have not been reduced, but have become more.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Always think about the overall situation. Go in the right direction; always keep an eye on the general trend, which is the most powerful.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the one hand, there is the need for cooperation and win-win opportunities, and on the other hand, there is the escalation of friction and the risk of confrontation, resulting in a clear sense of gap in economic globalization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the meeting, President Xi Jinping made no secret of the issues between China and the United States: &quot;The United States continues to take measures against China in terms of export controls, investment reviews, and unilateral sanctions, which seriously damages China&#39;s legitimate interests.&quot; We hope that the United States will take China&#39;s concerns seriously, take action to lift unilateral sanctions, and provide a fair, just and non-discriminatory environment for Chinese companies.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the face of this concern, President Biden made clear his stance: &quot; The U.S. and China are economically interdependent, and the United States is happy to see China develop and prosper, and does not seek to suppress or contain China&#39;s development, nor does it seek to decouple from China.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Can these dialogues and consultations, these struggles and efforts dispel misunderstandings and misunderstandings? Build a high wall of sanctions to dispel the haze in Sino-US relations? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The world is waiting. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Is it a natural chasm or a thoroughfare? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“I still remember the house number is 2911 Bonny Street” &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Firolli Manor, before the luncheon, President Biden I pulled out an old photo from my phone and asked President Xi Jinping with a smile: &quot;Do you know this young man?&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That was when Xi Jinping, then secretary of the Zhengding County Party Committee, visited San Francisco in 1985. Photo in front of the Golden Gate Bridge. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That was also young Xi Jinping’s first trip to the United States. In the next 38 years, one arc after another was drawn on the Pacific Ocean. I have been there many times and met many American friends in China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kissinger, Bill Gates, Schumer, Newsom... Over the past year, American friends and guests have visited China one after another, and President Xi Jinping cordially received them; &quot;US-China Youth Student Exchange Association&quot; in Washington State, USA Friends from all walks of life, Chairman of the U.S.-China Aviation Heritage Foundation and Flying Tigers veterans, and Ma Siyi, President and CEO of the Philadelphia Orchestra... Over the past year, President Xi Jinping has replied to American friends many times. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Time is the proof. The friendship formed has deep roots and flourishes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the evening of the 15th, President Xi Jinping made time to meet with old friends in the United States. Talk about memories, current situation, plans, meet again after a long absence, talk about endless things. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The meeting was immediately followed by a joint welcome banquet of American friendship groups. President Xi Jinping stepped onto the podium, and the audience stood up and applauded warmly and continuously. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In his speech at the banquet, President Xi Jinping frequently mentioned old friends. The speech was titled &quot;Gathering the Power of the People of the Two Countries to Promote the Cause of Sino-US Friendship.&quot; It told people&#39;s friendship stories, including many of his own stories. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The photo of the Golden Gate Bridge was clicked at the beginning. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;This morning, President Biden didn&#39;t know where he pulled it out and showed it to me.&quot; President Xi Jinping talked about the episode of the heads of state meeting, and the audience burst into applause and laughter. one slice. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The vivid memories and warm moments are profound because of the close relationship between people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;When I first visited the United States, I stayed at the home of Mr. and Mrs. Dvorchak in Iowa. I still remember that the house number was 2911 Bonny Street.&quot; Applause swept through the venue again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 1985, young Xi Jinping led a Shijiazhuang corn inspection delegation to the &quot;sister provinces and states&quot; on the other side of the ocean. At that time, China and the United States had not long since established diplomatic relations, and the two peoples had a strong desire for exchanges. Local newspapers hailed the &quot;Chinese visitor&quot; as the town&#39;s superstar. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping was deeply impressed by this experience: &quot;To me, they are the United States.&quot; To local residents, young Xi Jinping and his colleagues are China. The Chinese people&#39;s humility, studiousness, friendliness and affection quickly eliminated their doubts about China. This is the law of communication: Only by communicating with heart can you gain trust; only by communicating with affection can you stir up resonance. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At this moment, Sarah Landi, who has white hair like snow, is sitting in the audience, listening intently. When young Xi Jinping visited Muscatine, Randy was in charge of the reception. Every time President Xi Jinping sees her in these years, he always chats cordially for a while. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Dvorcheck brothers also came to the scene. As soon as President Xi Jinping saw his brother Gary, who had left home to study, he said to him: &quot;I was living in your room at that time, and I remember that I had sports clothes and football equipment. Your mother made a sumptuous breakfast the next day, and you said I still remember the name of the dish.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The past events of 38 years ago are so treasured. I can treasure those years in my heart full of great things, just because I cherish and care for the friendship thousands of miles apart. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;No matter how thick the ice is, no matter how high the courtyard wall is, it will be dissolved by the connection of hearts. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Country-to-country exchanges are not always smooth sailing. China and the United States have also been isolated and opposed for 22 years. It is their common interests that allow China and the United States to transcend their differences, and it is the people&#39;s desire that allows the two countries to break the ice. From a game of &quot;small ball turning big ball&quot; to a Sino-US &quot;Shanghai Communique&quot; with historical weight, to now, bilateral trade of 760 billion U.S. dollars and a total of more than 260 billion U.S. dollars of two-way investment, 284 pairs of sister provinces and states With sister-city relations, there are up to more than 300 flights per week and more than 5 million mutual exchanges every year... This is a magnificent picture jointly drawn by nearly a quarter of the world&#39;s population. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Recently, Flying Tigers veterans, 103-year-old Moyer and 98-year-old McMullen came to China, climbed the Great Wall, and were warmly welcomed by the Chinese people.&quot; President Xi Jinping said here , looking at the veterans sitting in the audience, Moyer waved. Applause rang out to pay tribute to the turbulent years of fighting side by side. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There are also members of the &quot;Friends of Guling&quot; who specially wore red Tang suits and red ties today because &quot;red represents happiness in China.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the nearly 40-minute speech, the packed banquet hall burst into long and warm applause nearly twenty times. Of course, there were also laughter and admiration, and some old friends shed tears while listening. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the morning of that day, the heads of state of China and the United States reached a consensus that the two countries would launch more measures to facilitate personnel exchanges and promote people-to-people and cultural exchanges. The Pacific Admiral will thus build more bridges. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The foundation of Sino-US relations is laid by the people, the door is opened by the people, the story is written by the people, and the future is created by the people. &quot;It is the trickle-down flow of goodwill and friendship that makes the vast Pacific no longer a natural chasm; it is the people&#39;s two-way rush that makes China-US relations return to the right track from the bottom time and time again.&quot; President Xi Jinping said emotionally. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The story of friendship between the two peoples is still being written. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Is it a challenge or an opportunity? &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“Show the pattern of a big country, take on the responsibilities of a big country, and play the role of a big country”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The world has an extraordinary view of the “big guy” China of curiosity. From poverty to the largest developing country and the world&#39;s second largest economy, China&#39;s growth rate and the governance behind it have attracted the attention of the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Is China a challenge or an opportunity to the world? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The trip to San Francisco was a vivid narration of China on the world stage. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From President Xi Jinping’s rich agenda, it is not difficult to read what “doing China’s affairs well is the greatest contribution to the world” and what “the Chinese people not only hope for a good life for themselves, but also hope for People of all countries are living well.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A large country accounting for nearly one-fifth of the world’s population has created a miracle in the history of human poverty reduction. During the dinner speech, President Xi Jinping shared his personal experience. It has lifted nearly 100 million people out of poverty in eight years, which can be called a &quot;miracle in the annals of history.&quot; This process &quot;achieved the poverty reduction goals of the United Nations 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development 10 years ahead of schedule.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A large country occupying 1/15 of the world’s land area is committed to sustainable development. Whether it is the implementation of the Paris Agreement or the implementation of the goal of &quot;peak carbon neutrality&quot;, China is taking action. “We don’t talk big words, we do what we say.” The thunderous applause echoed that China must be true to its words and resolute in its deeds. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A country that used to be poor, weak, and full of waste, has explored a Chinese-style modernization path that is very different from the West, and created a new form of human civilization. This is &quot;the creation of the brave.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping profoundly explained China-style modernization to President Biden and the American people. Its five characteristics correspond to unity and struggle, common prosperity, all-round development, sustainable development and peaceful development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some observers of international issues commented on this speech: &quot;In every sentence, we can discover what China is thinking and China&#39;s opportunities. We all know that China&#39;s opportunities are also opportunities for the world.&quot; ”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;So, is China’s development a threat to the United States? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The &quot;Thucydides Trap&quot; has almost been regarded as the &quot;iron law&quot; of international relations. As time passes to the 21st century, Sino-US relations have become a new focus. Does the vast earth have enough space to accommodate China and the United States? President Xi Jinping has emphasized this many times: &quot;There is no &#39;Thucydides Trap&#39; in the world, but repeated strategic misjudgments among major powers may create a &#39;Thucydides Trap&#39; for themselves.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt; p>;Across the Pacific, the road is at your feet. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;As the largest developing and developed countries in the world, China and the United States must deal with each other well. Facing a world of chaos, China and the United States need to have a broad mind, show the pattern of big countries, and take on the responsibilities of big countries. , play the role of a major country.&quot; China is on the right side of history. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Political diplomacy, cultural exchanges, global governance, military security... This meeting between the heads of state of China and the United States reached more than 20 consensuses, involving all dimensions of the global governance order, injecting stability and positive energy into a world intertwined with chaos. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strengthen cooperation in important fields such as climate change, drug control, and artificial intelligence; exchange views on international and regional issues of common concern such as the Palestinian-Israeli conflict... At the meeting table and in the banquet hall, the heads of state of China and the United States focused on Not only bilateral relations, but also thorny problems that need to be solved in the region and the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Solving the troubles facing human society cannot be separated from the cooperation of major powers. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The method, path and sincerity of cooperation determine the result. President Xi Jinping made two points in this regard. The first is to &quot;set an example&quot; and &quot;provide more public goods to the world&quot;; the second is &quot;the initiatives put forward by both sides must be open to each other and can be coordinated and docked to form synergy and benefit the world.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the eve of the trip to San Francisco, the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum has just been successfully held. Ten years, a drop in the ocean, has created tremendous changes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The Belt and Road Initiative, as well as the global development initiative, global security initiative, and global civilization initiative proposed by China, have always been open to all countries, including the United States. China is also willing to participate in the multilateral cooperation initiatives proposed by the United States. &quot;When planning for profit, you should plan for the benefit of the world. This is China&#39;s ambition. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During the speech, there was one place where the applause was particularly lasting, that was when President Xi Jinping shared his thoughts. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Recalling his visit to the countryside in a small village in northern Shaanxi when he was young, he said emotionally: &quot;Half a century has passed from then to now. I feel at ease among the people. Being with the people makes me feel at ease.&quot; I have strength. I will be selfless and live up to the people. This is my lifelong belief.&quot; There was another warm applause at the venue. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A lifelong belief is also the logical starting point for understanding China. &quot;The people&#39;s yearning for a better life is our goal, and it is the people&#39;s hearts that must be kept.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For the people, we also rely on the people. When meeting with friendly people, President Xi Jinping met with Adam Foster, a descendant of Edgar Snow, the author of &quot;Red Star Over China&quot;. He said: &quot;The Chinese people have always remembered Snow, who was the first to introduce the Chinese Red Army to the world.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Today&#39;s world&#39;s impression of China, as conveyed in this book, has experienced The baptism of the Long March became more and more courageous, full of faith and yearning for the future. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Decoupling and breaking links&quot; and &quot;building walls and fortresses&quot;, even if the winds are high, the waves are strong, and the rain is coming, &quot;all suppression and containment will only stimulate the will and enthusiasm of the Chinese people.&quot; During the meeting at the Manor, President Xi Jinping firmly said: &quot;China&#39;s development and growth have endogenous logic, which cannot be stopped by external forces.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The endogenous logic here is rooted in the suffering and glory of the Chinese nation and nourishes it. to the majestic power of the Chinese people. Across the sea of ​​clouds, we look at each other with our hearts. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 05:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 为了亚太人民和子孙后代的共同繁荣]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20231119_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Sunday, November 19, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;San Francisco in November is sometimes sunny and sometimes drizzly. The Golden Gate Bridge is full of traffic, white sails are dotted on the blue sea, and gulls are flying. The cool and moist air carries the message of the Pacific sea breeze. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the invitation of US President Biden, President Xi Jinping went to San Francisco, the United States, from the 14th to the 17th to hold the China-US Presidential Meeting. He was also invited to attend the 30th APEC Leaders&#39; Informal Meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Departing from Beijing and flying across the vast Pacific Ocean, President Xi Jinping’s special plane successfully arrived in San Francisco after more than 10 hours of flight. California Governor Newsom, Treasury Secretary Yellen and other senior officials warmly welcomed him at the foot of the gangway. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The first time I came to the United States was to San Francisco, right here.” President Xi Jinping’s words were cordial. &quot;1985,&quot; Newsom added with a smile. Yellen once served as the president of the Federal Reserve Bank of San Francisco. This time she also warmly welcomed President Xi Jinping as a &quot;local&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This metropolis on the west coast of the United States has witnessed the century-old history of exchanges between the people of China and the United States, as well as the efforts of China and the United States to build a better world. This time it will witness a new milestone in the history of international relations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 1945, China and the United States jointly participated in the San Francisco Constitutional Convention and promoted the establishment of the United Nations. China was the first to sign the United Nations Charter. Looking back at the highlight moment of &quot;the last time San Francisco brought global leaders together,&quot; CBS reported that for San Francisco, this APEC meeting will be a rare &quot;opportunity of the century.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In four days, there were more than 10 bilateral and multilateral activities. Attracting worldwide attention, President Xi Jinping has intensively interacted with all parties, setting the course for China-US relations, drawing a blueprint for Asia-Pacific cooperation, and injecting strong confidence and impetus into regional and world peace, stability, development and prosperity. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The steps are dusty and dusty, but the magnanimity of the world is in mind. Through President Xi Jinping&#39;s &quot;San Francisco Time&quot;, the world listened to the sonorous footsteps of major-country diplomacy with Chinese characteristics in the new era, and witnessed a major Eastern country&#39;s dedication and responsibility to seek progress for mankind and unity for the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;(1)&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Shaping: &quot;What kind of Asia-Pacific should we bring to the middle of this century?&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/strong>; p>;&lt;p>;This is the 30th time that APEC leaders have gathered. At such a historical node, when we look back and look ahead, we can better understand the mighty tide of the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thirty years ago, shortly after the end of the Cold War, leaders in the Asia-Pacific region followed the trend of the times for peace and development and held the first informal meeting of APEC leaders. They unanimously agreed to transcend the old rules of group confrontation and zero-sum game. thinking, deepen regional economic cooperation and integration, and strive to jointly build a dynamic, harmonious and prosperous Asia-Pacific family. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the past 30 years, this mechanism has pushed the development and economic globalization of the Asia-Pacific into the fast lane, helping the Asia-Pacific become the center of world economic growth, the anchor of global development stability, and a highland for cooperation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What profound enlightenment does the extraordinary journey of Asia-Pacific cooperation bring to us? On the 16th, in a written speech delivered to the APEC Business Leaders Summit, President Xi Jinping shared his profound thoughts with the world -&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Openness and inclusiveness are the main theme of Asia-Pacific cooperation;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Common development is the overall goal of Asia-Pacific cooperation;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Seeking common ground while reserving differences is a good practice for Asia-Pacific cooperation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The language is incisive and contains philosophy. Draw wisdom and strength from history and let the light of thought illuminate the way forward. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Asia-Pacific cannot and should not be reduced to a battlefield of geopolitical games, let alone a ‘new cold war’ and camp confrontation.” “Only cooperation can development, non-cooperation is the biggest risk, and ‘decoupling and disconnection’ are &quot;Chain is not good for anyone&quot;, &quot;Adhere to open regionalism&quot;, &quot;Build an open Asia-Pacific economy with win-win cooperation&quot;, &quot;Promote digital, intelligent and green transformation and development&quot;...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has a strong voice China&#39;s position and China&#39;s plan of integrating knowledge and action will gather strength for the lasting stability, prosperity and development of the Asia-Pacific. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the press center of the conference, a stack of speech scripts was snatched away. After receiving them, reporters read them carefully and rushed to send out news. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The full text of the speech was published on the website of the San Francisco Observer on that day. The editor&#39;s note reads: We rarely publish the full text of political speeches, but President Xi Jinping&#39;s speech is extremely unusual. It contains information that is highly anticipated by the American business community, policymakers, and the world, and will be widely and deeply studied. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Thought-provoking”, “inspiring” and “pointing out the direction for the Asia-Pacific to work together to achieve common development and prosperity”... President Xi Jinping’s speech was highly praised by business people in the Asia-Pacific region. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The greatness of a great country lies in its broad mind, great structure and great responsibility. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since 2013, President Xi Jinping has attended or chaired all APEC leaders’ informal meetings and delivered important speeches, planning for regional cooperation, shaping the overall pattern, and planning a future for the common destiny of the Asia-Pacific people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From proposing to establish a &quot;consciousness of a community with a shared future in the Asia-Pacific&quot; to advocating the joint construction of an &quot;Asia-Pacific partnership of mutual trust, tolerance, cooperation and win-win&quot;, from describing the &quot;Asia-Pacific Dream&quot; to outlining &quot;all-round connectivity&quot; &quot;Blueprint&quot; to maintaining a smooth global supply chain and industrial chain...China&#39;s ideas and China&#39;s actions lead the Asia-Pacific ships to cut through the waves and keep moving forward. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Currently, the century-old changes in the world are accelerating, and the world economy is facing a variety of risks and challenges. As the engine of global economic growth, the Asia-Pacific shoulders greater responsibilities of the times. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;As leaders of the Asia-Pacific region, we must think deeply about what kind of Asia-Pacific we want to bring to the middle of this century? How to create the next &#39;golden thirty years&#39; of Asia-Pacific development? In this period How can we better play the role of APEC in the process?”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the 30th APEC Leaders’ Informal Meeting held on the 17th, President Xi Jinping delivered an important speech, laying the foundation for the new era facing the Asia-Pacific. Solve problems and promote Asia-Pacific cooperation to start again - &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Adhere to innovation-driven; adhere to open-oriented; adhere to green development; adhere to inclusive sharing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We should uphold the original intention of Asia-Pacific cooperation, respond responsibly to the call of the times, work together to respond to global challenges, fully implement Putrajaya’s vision, and build an open, dynamic, strong, and peaceful Asia-Pacific community. Achieve common prosperity for the people of the Asia-Pacific and future generations.&quot; President Xi Jinping&#39;s words won widespread approval from leaders of all participating economies. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;(2)&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Leader: &quot;This earth can accommodate China and the United States. The success of China and the United States is an opportunity for each other.&quot; &quot;&lt;/Strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Asia -Pacific Economic Cooperation Organization Leaders and the host guests held on the 16th and the host guests&#39; informal dialogue and work luncheon, with the issue of&quot; sustainable, climate and impartial energy transformation &quot;. During the gap between the meeting, the Sino -US dollar meeting held the previous day became the focus of discussion. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Congratulations!&quot; &quot;It&#39;s great!&quot; Seeing President Xi Jinping, many leaders came forward and congratulated the successful meeting of the China -US dollar. Chang Shu breathed. &quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On the 15th, the Florer Manor, Flower and Timber, President Xi Jinping with President Xi Jinping with President Xi Jinping with President Xi Jinping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The United States specifically stated that the first meeting of the China -US dollar was a separate invitation issued by President Bayeng to President Xi Jinping. Unlike the bilateral meeting arrangements during the informal meeting of the Asia -Pacific Economic Cooperation Organization. This is a Sino -US &quot;Summit&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At 11:15 am, when President Xi Jinping arrived by car, President Biden was waiting in front of the main building. Hand hands, group photos, and step by side into the talk hall. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;This earth can accommodate China and the United States. The success of China and the United States is the opportunity of each other.&quot; After the seat, President Xi Jinping opened Mingyi. At this meeting, the meeting was exactly one year and one day. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the past year, the United States has experienced serious &quot;action deficits&quot; in implementing Bali consensus, and even runs counter to the spirit advocated by consensus, leading to new difficulties in bilateral relations. In recent months, senior US government officials have visited China many times, and bilateral high -level interactions have increased significantly. The relationship between the two countries has stopped falling and stabilized and positive. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Mr. I and President and I are the helm of Sino -US relations. They are responsible for the people, the world, and history.&quot; Responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I always think that US -China relations are the most important bilateral relations in the world. The US -China conflict is not inevitable. A stable and developing China meets the interests of the United States and the world.&quot; President Bayeng said. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Establishing correct cognition together&quot;, &quot;common effective management and control&quot;, &quot;joint promotion of mutual benefit cooperation&quot;, &quot;joint responsibility for the big country&quot;, &quot;joint promotion of cultural exchanges together&quot; ... The stable development of Sino -US relations has five pillars. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On the basis of mutual respect and peacefulness, leaders of the two countries have discussed dialogue and cooperation in various fields, and have reached more than 20 consensus in the fields of political diplomacy, humanistic exchanges, global governance, and military security. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Meeting, luncheon, walking, and using the same pass throughout the process, the heads of state of the two countries talked solidly for 4 hours. When saying not to say, President Xi Jinping said: &quot;Believe our relationship will keep it.&quot; &quot;I agree.&quot; President Biden responded. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the meeting, the media captured such an instant- &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Before the luncheon, President Bayeng specifically showed a photo in President Xi Jinping. It was in 1985. Xi Jinping, the secretary of Ren Zhengding County Party Committee, took a photo in front of the Golden Gate Bridge. &quot;You haven&#39;t changed at all!&quot; President Biden said. There was a bright laugh at the scene. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; 38 years later, the fingers are waved. From the county party secretary to the leader of the great power, Xi Jinping always believed that the foundation of Sino -US relations was poured by the people, and the gate of Sino -US relations was opened by the people. The story of Sino -US relations was written by the people. The future of Sino -US relations is Created by the people. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On the night of the 15th, the center of San Francisco and the American friendly group jointly held a banquet to welcome President Xi Jinping. Flying Tigers, descendants of General Stiway, &quot;Friends of Guling&quot;, friends in Aiwa, Washington, ... about 400 new friends and friends gathered together, the scene was very enthusiastic. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;When I first visited the United States, I lived in the Davachek couple who lived in Aiwa. I still remember that the house number was No. 2911 Bonnie Street.&quot; The tenderness was moving. The people present at the scene of President Xi Jinping warmly applauded with nearly twenty times. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;The more difficult it is, the more you need to tighten the people of the people and enhance the communication of the people&#39;s hearts. More people need to stand up for Sino -US relations drums and calls.&quot; President Xi Jinping pointed out. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;President Xi Jinping, welcome you to visit the Jindibari Farm, and then open a tractor.&quot; Everyone at the scene &quot;... The American people responded enthusiastically, saying that they would continue to inherit and develop good and Chinese friendship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Pacific Ocean is large enough to accommodate the stream of the world; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Under the rudder of the heads of state of the two countries, the giant round of Sino -US relations crossed the reef beach and arrived in San Francisco from Bali. But San Francisco is not the end, but it should be a new starting point. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; (3) &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; responsibility: &quot;Next &#39;China&#39;, still China&quot; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On November 16, the Chinese delegation&#39;s delegation was endless and became a &quot;home&quot; of Chinese bilateral diplomacy during the multilateral international conference. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the dense and compact schedule, President Xi Jinping arranged time to hold a bilateral meeting with many foreign leaders who attended the relevant activities of the Asia -Pacific Economic Cooperation Leadership Leadership Leaders. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Some come from Latin America, which is thousands of miles away from China- &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Before talking about other topics, I will first take this opportunity to express your gratitude.&quot; Mexican President Lopez talked about a past. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;At our most difficult moment, China was the first country to help us.&quot; President Lopez was a little emotional. &quot;China has set up a bridge with an empty bridge, which has continued to send shortages to us. Medical supplies help us through the difficulties. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; The world has gone out of the new crown epidemic, but President Lopez still feels in the emergency helping China. Seeing President Xi Jinping, he couldn&#39;t wait to express gratitude. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;We may not find another planet for human survival in our lifetime.&quot; During the trip to San Francisco, this sentence that Chairman Xi Jinping said was thoughtful. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Although it is located in different continents and is far away, it is also a member of the Asia -Pacific family, the residents of the Earth Village, and a community of human destiny. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Some are the Pacific Island countries that are far away from China- &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;China is a great country, and always adheres to the equality of countries, and the Filial side admires the world leadership of President Xi Jinping.&quot; Lantuka, who met with Xi Jinping for the first time after taking office for the first time. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;China&#39;s development with the Pacific island nation is frank, without selfishness, and not targeting third parties.&quot; President Xi Jinping&#39;s words mean. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Although the national conditions are different, Prime Minister Landuka is still eagerly looking forward to seeking inspiration from the successful road of Chinese -style modernization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; He sincerely stated: &quot;President Xi Jinping&#39;s global development initiative, global security initiative, and global civilization initiative are conducive to maintaining and promoting the development and interests of global southern countries. Choose and take the road to modernization. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Some are friendly neighbors that look at the sea across the sea- &lt;/p>; &lt;p>;&quot; I still remember our meeting in Bangkok. During the informal meeting of the leaders of the Asia -Pacific Economic Cooperation Organization. &quot;Brunei Sultan Ha Sannal said that Brunei and China have a long history of friendship and China. High -quality co -construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Seeing old friends again today, I feel very kind.&quot; President Xi Jinping said that China attaches great importance to East Asian cooperation and is willing to work with ASEAN countries such as Brunei to promote regional economic integration and maintain the correct direction of East Asian cooperation. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Some are close neighbors with water with Chinese clothes — &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Seeing it again after a year. The positioning of the relationship between the two countries that comprehensively promote the relationship between the strategic and reciprocity is committed to the constructive and stable Sino -Japanese relations that meet the requirements of the new era. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; ... &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; No matter the size of the country, no matter where, everyone gathers together, and there is a common wish: jointly build a peaceful, stable, and prosperous Asia -Pacific family. The relationship and cooperation with China is very important. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The 20th China Communist Party held more than a year ago, opened a new journey of comprehensively promoting the construction of a strong country and a great cause of national rejuvenation with the modernization of Chinese -style modernization. What will China bring to the Asia Pacific and the world in the new journey? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, President Xi Jinping&#39;s first trip to the United States, told the vivid and wonderful Chinese story to the United States, Asia Pacific, and the world from different dimensions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Not long ago, we successfully held the 6th China International Import Expo, attracting more than 3,400 companies from 128 countries including the United States, and the largest 6 consecutive exhibition area in the United States.&quot; At the joint welcome banquet of friendly groups, President Xi Jinping talked about the expo that has just been successfully held to explain to the world with real numbers that &quot;more than 1.4 billion Chinese people&#39;s moving towards modernization is a huge opportunity for China to bring to the world.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Now, the global photovoltaic power generation capacity is nearly half in China. Dafeng realized carbon neutrality before 2060. We talk about it. &quot;Talking about the green development that the parties care about, President Xi Jinping depicts a beautiful vision of the harmonious coexistence of the future people and nature. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Last month, China successfully held the 3rd &#39;Belt and Road&#39; International Cooperation Summit Forum, forming 458 results. Chinese financial institutions set up 780 billion yuan &#39;Belt and Road&quot; project financing window. Chinese and foreign companies have reached a commercial cooperation agreement of $ 97.2 billion, which will promote the construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; high -quality development of the co -construction, injecting a strong motivation for global interconnection and promoting development and prosperity. &quot;Exchange with friends in the Asia -Pacific business community, President Xi Jinping has hoped to build a&quot; The bright future of the Belt and Road Initiative. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国坚持走和平发展道路，发展的根本目的是让中国人民过上好日子，不是要取代谁。”在旧金山，习近平主席深刻指出，“工作得更好，生活得Better, children grow up better, and they are the earnest wishes of more than 1.4 billion Chinese people. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Looking back on the 30 -year extraordinary journey. As a member of the Asia -Pacific family, China&#39;s development starts in the Asia Pacific. Thanks to the Asia -Pacific; China, which is facing the future, will continue to focus on the Asia -Pacific and benefit the Asia -Pacific. The next &quot;China&quot; will still be China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;I would like to send you the most enthusiastic invitations, I hope you can attend the informal meeting of leaders of the Asia -Pacific Economic Cooperation Organization in 2024 and have a state visit to Peru again.&quot; The San Francisco meeting has not ended. The host President Bolu Alt has acted in advance. When President Xi Jinping met with him, President Bolu Alt couldn&#39;t wait to invite President Xi Jinping. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Seeing a &quot;30 years of gold&quot;, starting from San Francisco, for the common prosperity of the Asia -Pacific people and descendants, for the peace and development of the world, for the better future for human beings, President Xi Jinping led China in the new era China. The journey is thousands of miles, and move forward. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; (Xinhua News Agency, San Francisco, November 18, &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; Participate in reporters: Yang Yijun, Sun Yi, Su Liang, warmth) &lt;/p>; &lt;!-/Enpcontent->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 05:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 坚守初心  团结合作  携手共促亚太高质量增长]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20231119_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;DIV>; Sunday, November 19, 2023 &lt;/div>; &lt;!-ENPCONTENT->; &lt;p>; Dear President Biden, &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; colleagues: &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; I am very happy Gathering everyone in the beautiful San Francisco. This is the 30th time that APEC leaders have gathered together, which is of special significance. Thank you to President Biden and the US government for making thoughtful arrangements for this meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Since the establishment of a regular meeting mechanism for leaders in the Asia -Pacific Economic Cooperation Organization, it has always been at the forefront of the global open development, which has effectively promoted regional trade and investment liberalization, economic and technological development, and material flow, and created worldwide attention. &quot;Asia -Pacific Miracle&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At present, the World Centennial Change has accelerated the evolution, and the world economy is facing a variety of risk challenges. As a global growth engine, Asia -Pacific shoulder a greater time responsibility. As leaders of the Asia-Pacific region, we must think deeply about what kind of Asia-Pacific we want to bring to the middle of this century. How to create the next &quot;golden thirty years&quot; of Asia-Pacific development? How can APEC better play its role in this process? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The ancient Chinese said: &quot;Where the Tao is, although there are millions of people going.&quot; We should adhere to the original intention of Asia -Pacific cooperation, respond to the call of the times responsibly, work together to deal with global challenges, and fully implement Btella Gariah&#39;s vision, building an open, vibrant, strong, and peaceful Asia -Pacific community, and realize the common prosperity of the Asia -Pacific people and descendants. Here, I would like to make some suggestions. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; First, insist on innovation -driven. Innovation is a powerful driving force for development. We must follow the development trend of science and technology, promote scientific and technological exchanges and cooperation with a more active attitude, and work together to create an open, fair, just and non-discriminatory scientific and technological development environment. It is necessary to accelerate digital transformation, narrow the digital divide, accelerate the implementation of the &quot;APEC Internet and Digital Economy Roadmap&quot;, support the application of new technologies such as big data, cloud computing, artificial intelligence, and quantum computing, and continuously shape new momentum and new advantages for the development of the Asia-Pacific. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China adheres to the innovation -driven development strategy, coordinated to promote digital industrialization and digitalization of industrial, and proposes proposal initiatives such as the Asia -Pacific Economic Co -Organization Digital Rural Construction, Enterprise Digital identity, and using digital technology to promote green low -carbon transformation. Develop and empower. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Second, persist in opening -up orientation. The experience of Asia-Pacific development tells us that if we are open, we will prosper, and if we are closed, we will decline. We must safeguard free and open trade and investment, support and strengthen the multilateral trading system with the World Trade Organization as its core, maintain the stability and smoothness of global industrial and supply chains, and oppose the politicization, weaponization and pan-security of economic and trade issues. We must unswervingly promote regional economic integration, accelerate the process of the Asia-Pacific Free Trade Area, fully implement the APEC Connectivity Blueprint, and share regional open development opportunities. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Recently, China has successfully held the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; international cooperation summit forum to inject new driving forces to promote global interconnection and build an open world economy. China adheres to the high-level implementation of the Regional Comprehensive Economic Partnership Agreement, actively aligns the high-standard economic and trade rules of the Comprehensive and Progressive Agreement for Trans-Pacific Partnership and the Digital Economy Partnership Agreement, actively promotes the process of joining the two agreements, and works with all parties to Together we draw a new picture of openness and development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Third, adhere to green development. In the face of increasingly severe challenges such as climate change and natural disasters, we must adhere to the harmonious coexistence of man and nature, accelerate the green and low-carbon transformation of the development model, coordinately promote carbon reduction, pollution reduction, green expansion and growth, and implement the &quot;Biological Cycle Green&quot; &quot;Economic Bangkok Goals&quot;, laying a solid foundation for Asia-Pacific growth. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China adheres to the road of ecological priority and green development, actively and steadily promote carbon peak carbon neutrality, and accelerate the green transformation of development methods. We propose APEC cooperation initiatives on green agriculture, sustainable cities, low-carbon energy transformation, and marine pollution prevention and control to promote joint efforts to build a clean and beautiful Asia-Pacific. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Fourth, insist on inclusive sharing. Currently, global development is facing severe challenges and the development gap is widening. I have said many times that true development is achieved when everyone develops together. We must fully implement the United Nations 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development, push development issues back to the center of the international agenda, deepen the alignment of development strategies, and jointly solve the global development deficit. All parties are welcome to actively participate in global development initiatives, deepen cooperation in poverty reduction, food security, industrialization, development financing and other fields, and build a global development community so that people of all countries can share the fruits of modernization. China will continue to support APEC in carrying out economic and technological cooperation and jointly make the Asia-Pacific development pie bigger. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; colleagues! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China is comprehensively promoting the construction of a strong country with Chinese -style modernization and a great cause of national rejuvenation. China adheres to the path of peaceful development. The fundamental purpose of development is to enable the Chinese people to live a good life, not to replace anyone. This year marks the 45th anniversary of China&#39;s reform and opening up. We will adhere to high-quality development, promote high-level opening up, and use Chinese-style modernization to provide new opportunities for promoting the modernization of countries around the world. I am willing to work with all my colleagues to promote Asia-Pacific cooperation to achieve more fruitful results and jointly create the next &quot;golden thirty years&quot; of Asia-Pacific! &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Thank you everyone. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; (Xinhua News Agency, San Francisco, November 17th) &lt;/p>; &lt;!-/Enpcontent->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 05:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 不断以中国新发展为世界带来新动力、新机遇]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20231119_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;DIV>; Sunday, November 19, 2023 &lt;/div>; &lt;!-ENPCONTENT->; &lt;p>; &quot;China has become synonymous with the best investment destination, the next &#39;China&#39;, or China,&quot; In the written speech delivered by the Organization of the Industrial and Commercial Leadership Summit, President Xi Jinping deeply elaborated the achievements and advantages of China&#39;s economy, and solemnly announced that China has unswervingly promoting high -quality development and unswervingly promoting high levels of public opening. Emphasizing that &quot;we have confidence and the ability to achieve long -term stable development, and continue to bring new motivations and opportunities for the world with the new development of China.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Climbing the risk challenge over the risk challenge, China&#39;s development has achieved historic achievements. Since the beginning of this year, in the face of the complex and severe international environment and the arduous and heavy tasks of domestic reform, development and stability, we have faced the difficulties and advanced, and the economy has continued to rise. Development is solidly advanced. Data show that the GDP in China in the first three quarters increased by 5.2%year -on -year, of which 4.9%in the third quarter. The two indicators were among the best in major economies. It is expected that China&#39;s contribution to global economic growth this year will reach one -third. Practice has fully proved that China has strong economic toughness, sufficient potential, and extensive room for virginity. The long -term good fundamentals will not change and will not change. China is still the largest growth engine in the world. Market opportunities. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; At present, the downward pressure of the world economy has increased, unstable, uncertain, and difficult to predict factors, and the economies of various countries face many challenges. Facing the complex external environment, the Chinese economy has held pressure, stabilized the scale, and improved its quality. China&#39;s development still has a good support foundation and many favorable conditions. President Xi Jinping profoundly pointed out: &quot;China has the advantages of the socialist market economy, the demand advantage of the large -scale market, the complete supply advantage of the industrial system, the advantages of a large number of high -quality workers and entrepreneurs, and the economic development has strong endogenous endogenous endogenous endogenous Dynamics, toughness, and potential. &quot;Facing the future, fully inspire the advantages and vitality of all aspects, we are completely confident, capable, and conditional to defeat various risks and challenges, promote the continuous movement of China&#39;s economic ships and waves. Development provides new opportunities for the world, and its own stable development has brought valuable certainty for uncertain world economy. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; China&#39;s development is inseparable from the world, and the development of the world also needs China. China&#39;s new development concepts of innovation, coordination, green, openness, and sharing are unswervingly promoted to high -quality development. The economic growth content is higher and the green has stronger. The results of shared development provide better institutional guarantees, and continuously cultivate new growth momentum and release greater development space. China has insisted on opening up the door to build, unswervingly promoting high -level opening to the outside world, and further expanding market access. It has announced that it has comprehensively canceled the restrictions on foreign investment in the manufacturing field. Regardless of how the international situation changes, China&#39;s determination to build a marketization, rule of law, and international business business will not change. As soon as it is equally, the policy of providing high -quality services for foreign investment will not change. It will continue to improve the protection mechanism of foreign investment rights and further reduce foreign businessmen to further reduce foreign businessmen The negative list of investment access, strive to break the barriers to restrict the flow of innovation elements, and deepen the reform of the digital economy. Facing the future, China&#39;s open door will only open and larger, bringing more market opportunities, growth opportunities, and cooperation opportunities to the world. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; President Xi Jinping emphasized: &quot;The Chinese economy overcome challenges and moves forward steadily, and achieves high -quality development. This is also an inevitable requirement for promoting Chinese -style modernization.&quot; The new journey of Weiye, we are committed to solidifying to make all the Chinese people move towards modernization together; we are committed to common prosperity, so that every Chinese person lives a better life; we are committed to comprehensive development, so that people&#39;s material and spiritual world is equally rich ; Committed to sustainable development, let people live in harmony with nature; commit to peaceful development and promote the construction of a community of human destiny. It should be seen that the starting point and end point of Chinese -style modernization is to allow more than 1.4 billion Chinese people to live a better life. For the world, this means a broader market and unprecedented cooperation opportunities. Strong motivation. Looking forward to the future, a China continuously moving towards modernization will definitely provide more opportunities for the world, inject stronger driving force into international cooperation, and make greater contributions to all human progress. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; China is not pursuing the modernization of its own body. It is willing to realize the world&#39;s modernization of peaceful development, mutually beneficial cooperation, and common prosperity with countries. Welcome to actively participate in the process of modernization of Chinese -style modernization and share the huge huge brought by China&#39;s high -quality development in China opportunity. Always stand on the correct side of history and stand on the side of human civilization, share the avenue of the world, and promote the establishment of a community of human destiny, which will definitely create a better future for mankind. &lt;/P>; &lt;!-/enpcontent->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 05:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - “在历史关头，我们共同作出了正确的选择”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20231119_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;DIV>; Sunday, November 19, 2023 &lt;/div>; &lt;!-ENPCONTENT->; &lt;p>; &quot;This is another separate invitation that is different from the 30th leader of the Asia-Pacific Organization Organization. The news of the &quot;Summit of the United States&quot; in the field. &quot;When President Xi Jinping went to the United States to attend the first meeting of the US dollar, the world set up a spotlight to define this long trip with&quot; hope &quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Beijing -San Francisco, nearly 10,000 kilometers across the vast Pacific Ocean. This is not flat. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; For decades, Sino -US relations have &quot;happened many things&quot; in the past year. As President Xi Jinping described, he walked to the mountains and watery, but he could always be dark. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Sino -US establishment diplomatic relations is a major event in the past 50 years. In the next 50 years, &quot;the most important thing in international relations is that China and the United States must find the right way to get along.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The way to get along with the two major economies of the world with different social systems and different development stages require wisdom, pattern, vision, and responsibility. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; China&#39;s attitude is consistent. President Xi Jinping&#39;s own industry passed a constructive attitude towards history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The 15th is the day when he arrived in San Francisco, and the day when Sino -US relations were entered. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; President Xi Jinping attended two events. A manor meeting; a welcome banquet jointly organized by American friendly groups. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The trend of Sino -US relations is on both sides of the long table of the manor meeting hall, and it is also a joint choice of more than 1.7 billion people in the Chinese and American people. President Xi Jinping said to President Biden: &quot;Mr. and I of China and I are the helm of Sino -US relations. They should be responsible for the people, the world, and history.&quot; With a heavy responsibility, we made a long -term strategic choice with the handshake of the Pacific. &quot;How many things have never been urgent; the world turns, and the time is forced.&quot; The &quot;only fight for the night&quot; when the trip to the ice breaks of China and the United States is not the time and potential facing Sino -US relations today? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Sino -US relations should be put in the world&#39;s century -old change to accelerate the evolution of this big background to think and plan.&quot; Today, in the era of chaos, the development of &quot;San Francisco Visual&quot;, &quot;bring to the people of the two countries, bring the people of the two countries Come to well -being and show the responsibility of human progress. &quot; For example, the other side of the ocean, let people in the storm see hope and peace. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Our descendants of our children and grandchildren said that at the historical juncture, we made the right choice together.&quot; President Xi Jinping&#39;s eyes, deep and firm. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Is it an opponent or a partner? &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &quot;This is the fundamental and the general problem&quot; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On the morning of the 15th, President Xi Jinping took the red flag car into Feifei Lori Manor. This is a century -old rural manor in the outskirts of San Francisco. The sky is high, the grass is leisure, and the rich rural scenery can be seen. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; President Biden waited at the gate of the meeting building. He walked down the steps and greeted Chinese guests from afar. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The San Francisco meeting was &quot;one year after day&quot; from the San Francisco meeting. Some people described the spiral decline of Sino -US relations some time ago as &quot;roller coaster&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In front of the red square wooden door, the two heads shook hands with a smile and walked into the meeting hall side by side, leaving the expectation to the camera. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The world is looking forward to the transfer of Sino -US relations, and the international community needs a stable Sino -US relations than ever. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the meeting hall, like the last Bali meeting, President Bayeng first talked about the interaction of the two heads: &quot;In the past ten years, we have spent a lot of time together.&quot; &lt;/ P>; &lt;p>; President Xi Jinping also felt the same: &quot;I also remembered that 12 years ago, you visited the United States, who was invited by Vice President of the United States at the time. At that time, the meeting was still vivid and emotional.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The head of the head of state is the most powerful chapter in the heavy historical book of the country&#39;s friendship. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In these years, the manor meeting, the Tai Tai Night talk, the White House autumn narrative, the West Lake long talk ... Every time the Chinese and American dollars meet every time, every deepest talk has become a historical monument for relations between the two countries. Long -term response. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Long -term dealings, China has formed a fundamental follow of the treatment of Sino -US relations: &quot;mutual respect, peaceful coexistence, and win -win cooperation.&quot; During the meeting, President Xi Jinping said with a long -term saying: &quot;This is not only the experience mentioned from the 50 -year -old Sino -US relations, but also the revelation of the conflict of the great power in history. P>; &quot;Those who have a big one can be small.&quot; This sentence from the ancient proverbs of Ouyang Xiu, the great Confucian Confucianism in the Northern Song Dynasty, contains oriental philosophy. President Xi Jinping has cited many times, which seems to be a window to observe China to deal with Sino -US relations. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;One is to strengthen the combination of grouping&quot; &quot;the other is to hold zero -sum thinking&quot;, President Xi Jinping pointed out: &quot;Two options represent two directions, which will determine the future of human future and the future of the earth&#39;s future. . &quot;The grand framework focuses on the strategic, global, and directional issues of Sino -US relations. The sight is from bilateral to the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This scene is depth of history. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 1972, the handshake of Chairman Mao Zedong and President Nixon melted the long -lasting ice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; More than 50 years later. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On this day, President Xi Jinping explained his &quot;always thinking&quot; question: &quot;How to make this giant wheel of Sino -US relations avoid the shallow beach of the reef, cross the windy waves, no partials, stagnate, collision without collision, no collision, no collision The first thing to answer is whether China and the United States are opponents or partners. This is a fundamental and general problem. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; The fundamental and total, exactly the&quot; trip to the avenue &quot; . &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the meeting, President Xi Jinping took out the problem solution: &quot;Establishing correct cognition&quot;, &quot;effective management and control&quot;, &quot;promoting mutual mutual cooperation&quot;, &quot;undertaking the responsibility of the great country&quot;, and &quot;promoting cultural exchanges&quot;. Each one is defined by &quot;common&quot;, which also brightens China&#39;s attitude: &quot;China is willing to be partners and friends with the United States.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; meeting, luncheon, and walk. It took more than 4 hours in the manor. Meeting tables, banquet halls, and slate trails, their topics are extensive and deeper. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The two sides talked about the Taiwan issue. This is also the most important and sensitive issue in Sino -US relations. President Xi Jinping directly pointed out the key: &quot;The United States should reflect the statement of not supporting &#39;Taiwan independence&#39; in specific actions, stop armed Taiwan, and support China peace and reunification. China will eventually be unified.&quot; From Bali to San Francisco, President Biden continued the promise of &quot;four unintentional&quot;. &quot;I would like to reiterate the five -point commitment made in the Bali meeting, that is, the United States does not seek a new cold war, does not seek to change the Chinese system, does not seek to oppose China through strengthening the alliance relationship, does not support &#39;Taiwan independence&#39;, and inadvertently conflict with China. . &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>;&quot; We insist on a Chinese policy, I will not change this. &quot;President Biden emphasized again at a press conference after the head of state. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;You can know the wind and waves, and the sea is flat.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; That night, when I saw the Governor of California, the governor of New Sen, President Xi Jinping talked about the meeting and talked about it. The manor meeting is frank and deeper: &quot;I have known President Biden for many years, so we have seen the interview issues straight.&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Do you lose and win a win -win cooperation? &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &quot;You can achieve each other, mutual benefit and win -win&quot; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Four seasons to compound, bred the upward power, buried huge change seeds . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当年，在起草中美关系破冰的象征“上海公报”时，其中的“贸易与交流”部分，并未引起美方代表基辛格多大兴趣：“我们纵然再努力，顶Most only account for a small share of our overall economy. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; At that time, they could not imagine that the&quot; marginal areas &quot;they defined will grow into a magnificent chapter that stimulates the world. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;China and the United States are the top two economies in the world, with a total economy of more than one -third of the world, the total population of nearly one -quarter, and bilateral trade accounts for about one -fifth of the world. The interests of the two sides are very close. &quot;President Xi Jinping recently used this set of data to clarify the broad foundation of the two countries&#39; cooperation and a win -win space. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Floreli Manor, President Xi Jinping couples to President Bayeng&#39;s cooperation blueprint: &quot;China and the United States have widespread common interests in many fields, including both traditional areas such as economy, trade, agriculture Wait for emerging areas. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; President Bayeng responded actively:&quot; The United States is willing to continue to develop economic and trade relations with China, strengthen cooperation in important areas such as climate change, anti -drug, and artificial intelligence. , Expand educational science and technology exchanges and personnel. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>;&quot; China and the United States are the opportunities for each other &quot;&quot; can achieve each other&#39;s achievements, mutual benefit and win -win &quot;. The cornerstone of development. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Before the United States friendly group jointly welcomed the banquet that night, President Xi Jinping met with the representatives of 30 or 40 American business community and shook hands with them one by one. Many people vividly describe the stories of their win -win cooperation with China in short language. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At the subsequent dinner, when President Xi Jinping talked about &quot;pulling the list of cooperation longer and making the cake of cooperation greater&quot;, applause was tide. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the era of globalization, the development of the two &quot;locomotives&quot; of the world economy is destined to have me and me. The leaders of the two countries have interacted around the &quot;Made in China&quot;. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Florer Manor, President Biden sent President Xi Jinping all the way to the car after the meeting. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;This car is so beautiful.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;Red Flag Car, Domestic.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Time returns to 2015. At that time, President Xi Jinping talked with Biden, then Vice President of the United States on the eve of the talks. Biden introduced his tie &quot;made in China.&quot; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;You should have a good quality of your tie. You wear it equivalent to advertising them. I wonder if they pay for advertising fees?&quot; President Xi Jinping said funnyly. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The field of cooperation is high and high in the field of cooperation. &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Looking at economic and trade, the bilateral trade volume is as high as US $ 760 billion, an increase of hundreds of times higher than the beginning of the diplomatic relations, accounting for 1/5 of the world; the two -way investment in China and the United States supports millions of employment in the two countries. Positions; Chadling, Sino -US trade saves hundreds of dollars for each American family ... &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Pacific West Coast, San Francisco&#39;s friendly city Shanghai, the Sixth Expo has just concluded. The participating American companies have become the highlights of the current Expo: the number of more than 200, the highest in previous. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Continue back. In March of this year, China Development High -level Forum attracted 67 leaders of foreign businessmen to attend, and a considerable part of them came from the United States. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Tesla, Microsoft, Apple, Intel, GM ... Since this year, the &quot;head&quot; of American companies has visited China intensively. The fine cross -ocean route just confirms the profound insights of President Xi Jinping during the meeting: &quot;In the current situation, the common interests of the two countries are not reduced, but more.&quot; Going to the direction; the general view of the general trend is powerful. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; On the one hand is the need for cooperation, win -win opportunities, and the risk of friction and the risk of confrontation, resulting in a significant sense of economic globalization. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; During the meeting, President Xi Jinping did not deny the problem between China and the United States: &quot;The United States has continuously adopted measures for China in terms of export control, investment review, and unilateral sanctions to seriously damage the legitimate interests of the Chinese side.&quot; &quot; It is hoped that the United States will take the concern of China seriously, take action, cancel unilateral sanctions, and provide Chinese enterprises with a fair, fair, and non -discriminated environment. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; Faced with this concern, President Bayeng stated his position:&quot; The US -China economy depends on each other. The United States is happy to see China&#39;s prosperity. It does not seek to suppress and curb the development of China, and does not seek decoupling with China. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; These dialogues and negotiations. The high wall of the judgment dispels the haze of Sino -US relations? &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The world is looking forward to. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; Is it Tiantian or Tongtong? &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &quot;I still remember the house number is No. 2911 Bonni Street&quot; &lt;/strong>; &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Fluriti Manor, before lunche Roll out an old photo from the mobile phone and ask President Xi Jinping with a smile: &quot;Do you know this young man?&quot; &lt;/P>; &lt;p>; When Xi Jinping, who was the secretary of the Zhengding County Party Committee in 1985, visited San Francisco, was Take a photo in front of the Golden Gate Bridge. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; That is also the first trip to the United States Xi Jinping. In the 38 years since then, there were one arc one after another on the Pacific Ocean. I have been to many American friends in China. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Kissinger, Bill Gates, Shumo, Newson ... Over the past year, American friends and guests have visited China. Ma Siyi, friendly people from all walks of life, chairman of the US -China Aviation Heritage Foundation and Flying Tigers, President and CEO of the Philadelphia Symphony Orchestra ... In the past year, President Xi Jinping has repeatedly trusted American friends with a lot of miles. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; Time is proved. The friendship formed, the roots are deep. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; On the evening of the 15th, President Xi Jinping squeezed out to meet old friends in the United States. Talk about memories, talk about the situation, talk about plans, do not reunite for a long time, and say endless things. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; After the meeting, the American friendly group jointly welcomed the banquet. President Xi Jinping boarded the podium, stood up, and applauded warmly, endless. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In the banquet speech, President Xi Jinping frequently mentioned his old friends. The speech entitled &quot;Gathering the Power of the Peoples of the two countries &amp; nbsp; &amp; nbsp; Promoting the China -US -friendly career&quot;, which tells the story of the people&#39;s friendly stories, and there are many of his own stories. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The opening of the Golden Gate Bridge opened. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;This morning, President Biden did not know where to go out, and showed it to me.&quot; President Xi Jinping talked about the episode of the head of state, with applause and laughter. one slice. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; V distinctive memory, warm little bit, deeply because of the blind date. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; &quot;When I first visited the United States, I lived in the Davachek couple who lived in Aiwa. I still remember that the house number was No. 2911 Bonnie Street.&quot; The applause brushed over the venue again. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; In 1985, the youth Xi Jinping led the Shijiazhuang corn delegation to come to the &quot;friendly province&quot; on the other side of the ocean. At that time, shortly after the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and the United States, the wishes of the two peoples had strong desires. Local newspapers call &quot;Chinese visitors&quot; as the super star of the town. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; This experience, President Xi Jinping was impressed: &quot;For me, they are the United States.&quot; For local residents, young Xi Jinping and his colleagues are China. The Chinese people&#39;s humility and friendship and friendliness quickly eliminated their doubts about China. This is the law of interaction: only to be intersecting to gain trust; only by emotional friendship, you can resonate. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; At this moment, Sara Landti, who is like snow, sat down on the stage and focused on listening. The youth Xi Jinping visited Maskatin and was in charge of reception. Every time President Xi Jinping sees her over the years, he will always talk about it for a while. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The Davac Brothers also came to the scene. As soon as Chairman Xi Jinping saw his elder brother Garui, who was studying at home, he said to him, &quot;I lived in your room at the time, remembering a sportswear and a golf. The next day, your mother made a rich breakfast. I still remember the name of the dish. &quot;&lt;/P>; &lt;p>; The past 38 years ago was like a few treasures. Being able to collect those years in the heart full of major events, only cherish and care for the friendship of far away. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; How thick ice and the tall courtyard wall will be dispelled by the heart. &lt;/p>; &lt;p>; The exchanges between the country and the country are not always smooth. China and the United States have also separated for 22 years. It is a common interest that allows China and the United States to surpass the differences. The wishes of the people will break the ice.从一场“小球转动大球”的比赛，到一份有历史分量的中美“上海公报”，再到如今，7600亿美元双边贸易和累计2600多亿美元双向投资，284对友好省州和友好城市关系，最多每周300多个航班和每年500多万人次的相互往来……这是全世界近1/4人口共同绘就的宏伟画卷。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“最近，飞虎队老兵、103岁高龄的莫耶和98岁高龄的麦克马伦来到中国，登上了长城，受到中国人民热烈欢迎。”习近平主席说到此处，将目光投向台下就坐的老兵，莫耶挥手致意。掌声响起，致敬并肩作战的峥嵘岁月。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;还有“鼓岭之友”的成员们，他们今天特意穿上了红色唐装、戴上红色领带，因为“在中国红色代表着喜庆”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近40分钟的演讲，座无虚席的宴会厅近二十次响起长时间热烈掌声。当然，还有笑声、赞叹声，有的老朋友听着听着又落下泪来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就在当天上午，中美元首达成共识，两国将推出更多便利人员往来、促进人文交流的措施。太平洋上将因此搭建起更多桥梁。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中美关系的根基由人民浇筑，大门由人民打开，故事由人民书写，未来由人民创造。 “正是善意友好的涓滴汇流，让宽广太平洋不再是天堑；正是人民的双向奔赴，让中美关系一次次从低谷重回正道。”习近平主席动情地说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两国人民的友好故事，还在书写。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;是挑战还是机遇？ &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“展现大国格局、拿出大国担当、发挥大国作用”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界对于中国这个“大块头”有着超乎寻常of curiosity. From one poor and two -in -largest developing countries and the world&#39;s second largest economy, China&#39;s growth rate and governance behind the governance of the country have paid attention to the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国之于世界，是挑战还是机遇？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;旧金山之行，是中国在世界讲台上的一次生动讲述。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;人们从习近平主席的丰富日程，不难读出何为“做好中国的事情，就是对世界最大的贡献”，何为“中国人民不仅希望自己过得好，也希望各国人民过得好”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个占世界人口近1/5的大国，创造了人类减贫史上的奇迹。晚宴演讲时，习近平主席分享了他的亲历。 8年时间让近1亿人摆脱贫困，堪称“彪炳史册的人间奇迹”。这一进程，“提前10年实现了联合国2030年可持续发展议程的减贫目标”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个占世界陆地面积1/15的大国，致力于永续发展。无论是《巴黎协定》的落实，还是“碳达峰碳中和”目标的践行，中国在行动。 “我们不说大话，我们说到做到”。雷鸣般的掌声，激荡着中国一次次“言必信，行必果”的回响。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一个昔日积贫积弱、百废待兴的国家，探索出了一条迥异于西方的中国式现代化道路，创造了人类文明新形态。这是“勇敢者的创造”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平主席向拜登总统、向美国人民深刻阐释了中国式现代化。它的五个特征，对应着团结奋斗、共同富裕、全面发展、永续发展、和平发展。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有国际问题观察者这样评析这段演讲：“从每一句话里都能发现中国的所思所想，发现中国的机遇。我们都知道，中国机遇也是世界的机遇。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;那么，发展起来的中国，于美国而言，是威胁吗？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“修昔底德陷阱”几乎已经被视为国际关系的“铁律”。时光流转到21世纪，中美关系成为新的焦点。宽广的地球有没有足够空间容纳中美两个大国？习近平主席就此多次强调：“世界上本无&#39;修昔底德陷阱&#39;，但大国之间一再发生战略误判，就可能自己给自己造成&#39;修昔底德陷阱&#39;。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;跨越太平洋，路在脚下。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“作为世界上最大的发展中国家和发达国家，中美要好好打交道。面对变乱交织的世界，中美更需要有宽广的胸怀，展现大国格局、拿出大国担当、发挥大国作用。”中国站在了历史正确的一边。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政治外交、人文交流、全球治理、军事安全……此次中美元首会晤，达成20多项共识，涉及全球治理秩序各个维度，为变乱交织的世界注入稳定性和正能量. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在气候变化、禁毒、人工智能等重要领域加强合作；就共同关心的巴以冲突等国际和地区问题交换意见……会晤桌前、宴会厅里，中美元首着眼的不仅是双边关系，也有地区和世界正待解决的棘手难题。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;解决人类社会面临的麻烦离不开大国合作。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;而合作的方式、路径以及诚意，决定着结果。习近平主席就此提出两点。一是“做表率”“向全球提供更多公共产品”；二是“双方提出的倡议要彼此开放，也可以协调对接，形成合力，造福世界”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;旧金山之行前夕，第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛刚刚成功举办。十年，沧海一粟，却创造了沧桑巨变。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中方提出的共建&#39;一带一路&#39;倡议以及全球发展倡议、全球安全倡议、全球文明倡议，始终面向各国开放，包括美国。中方也愿参与美国提出的多边合作倡议。”计利当计天下利，这是中国的襟怀。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;演讲时，有一处掌声格外持久，那是习近平主席分享心声时。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;忆起年轻时在陕北小村子下乡，他动情地说：“从那时到现在，半个世纪过去了，在人民中间让我觉得踏实，同人民在一起让我有力量。我将无我、不负人民，这就是我终生的信念。”会场又是一次热烈掌声。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;终生的信念，也是理解中国的逻辑起点。 “人民对美好生活的向往就是我们的奋斗目标，就是必须守住的人民的心。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;为了人民，也依靠人民。在会见友好人士时，习近平主席接见了著有《红星照耀中国》的埃德加·斯诺的后人亚当·福斯特。他说：“中国人民一直记着斯诺，是他最早向世界介绍了中国红军。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今天的世界对于中国的印象，一如这本书里所传递的，经历了长征洗礼愈挫愈勇，对前途满怀信念和向往。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“脱钩断链”“筑墙设垒”，纵使风高浪急、雨骤云屯，“一切打压和遏制只会激发中国人民的意志和热情”。庄园会晤时，习近平主席坚定地说：“中国的发展壮大有内生逻辑，是外部力量阻挡不了的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这里的内生逻辑，扎根于中华民族的苦难辉煌，滋养于中国人民的磅礴力量。云海万里，以心相望。 &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 05:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[03版要闻 - 为中美关系把舵，为亚太合作领航]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20231119_1-03.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月19日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;本报北京11月18日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;2023年11月14日至17日，应美国总统拜登邀请，国家主席习近平赴美国旧金山举行中美元首会晤，同时应邀出席亚太经合组织（APEC）第三十次领导人非正式会议。 At the end of the trip, Wang Yi, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Foreign Minister, briefed the accompanying reporters on the visit. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王毅说，当前，世界正经历百年未有之大变局，人类处于历史的转折点。 Where China-US relations go from here is of great concern to the people of both countries and to the international community. This year is also the 30th time that APEC leaders have gathered together. All parties are thinking deeply about where Asia-Pacific cooperation will go in the next 30 years. At this important juncture, President Xi Jinping flew across the Pacific and embarked on a trip to San Francisco. He held a meeting with President Biden to discuss the correct way for China and the United States to get along; interacted with all walks of life in the United States to gather consensus on friendly cooperation between the two countries; and attended the APEC leaders&#39; informal meeting to chart the direction of cooperation in the Asia-Pacific region. International public opinion generally believes that this visit is world-famous, fruitful and of far-reaching significance, adding stability to Sino-US relations, bringing new impetus to Asia-Pacific cooperation, injecting positive energy into the international and regional landscape, and demonstrating President Xi Jinping&#39;s far-sightedness and broad-mindedness. The leadership style of a great country in the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;b>;一、为新时期中美关系导航定向&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王毅说，今年年初以来，由于众所周知的原因，中美关系经历不少曲折，面临困难局面，这不符合两国人民利益和意愿。 With the joint efforts of both sides, Sino-US relations have recently stabilized and stabilized. In conjunction with the APEC meeting, President Biden issued a separate invitation to President Xi Jinping for a heads-of-state meeting. The United States specifically stated that this is a Sino-US &quot;summit&quot; and is different from the bilateral meeting arrangements during this APEC period. All walks of life in the United States and the international community are full of expectations for this, and generally hope that the two countries can &quot;return to Bali and lead to San Francisco.&quot; President Xi Jinping assessed the situation and accepted the invitation, once again promoting the stabilization and improvement of Sino-US relations at this historical juncture. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是习近平主席时隔6年访美，也是两国元首自去年11月巴厘岛会晤以来再次面对面会晤。 President Biden handpicked Fillori Estate as the venue for the meeting. In addition to the formal talks, President Biden hosted a luncheon for President Xi Jinping and invited him to take a walk on the estate. The meeting lasted 4 hours. In an atmosphere of candor and mutual respect, the two heads of state had a candid and in-depth exchange of views on strategic, overall and directional issues related to China-US relations, as well as major issues related to world peace and development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平主席深刻指出，中美两个大国不打交道是不行的，想改变对方是不切实际的，冲突对抗的后果是谁都不能承受的。 Whether China and the United States choose to strengthen unity and cooperation or provoke confrontation will determine the future of mankind and the future of the earth. The United States must seriously consider the fundamental question of whether China and the United States are partners or rivals, and make the right historical choice. President Xi Jinping pointed out that for this meeting in San Francisco, both sides should set up a new vision: first, to jointly establish a correct understanding and hope that the two countries can be partners, respect each other and coexist peacefully; second, to jointly and effectively manage differences, understand each other&#39;s bottom line of principles, and not Tossing, not provoking troubles, not crossing boundaries, communicating more, having more dialogues, and discussing more, and handling differences and accidents calmly; third, jointly promoting mutually beneficial cooperation and making full use of the restored or established relationships in the fields of diplomacy, economy, finance, commerce, agriculture, etc. mechanism to carry out cooperation in the fields of drug control, judicial law enforcement, artificial intelligence, science and technology; fourth, jointly shoulder the responsibilities of major powers, strengthen coordination and cooperation on international and regional issues, provide more public goods to the world, and coordinate and dock each other&#39;s initiatives; fifth, It is to jointly promote cultural exchanges and encourage and support more exchanges and communication between the two peoples. These &quot;five commonalities&quot; have laid five pillars for Sino-US relations and opened up the &quot;San Francisco Vision&quot; for the future. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平主席还重点就台湾问题和科技经贸问题阐明中方严正立场，强调美方应当将不支持“台独”的表态体现在具体行动上，停止武装台湾，支持中国和平统一；掷地有声地指出，打压中国科技就是剥夺中国人民的发展权利，中方不会答应，希望美方严肃对待中方关切，取消单边制裁，为中方企业提供公正非歧视的环境。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登总统重申了在巴厘岛会晤时向习近平主席作出的五点承诺，即：美国不寻求新冷战，不寻求改变中国体制，不寻求通过强化同盟关系反对中国，不支持“台湾独立”，无意同中国发生冲突。 President Biden said that conflict between the United States and China is not inevitable. A stable and developing China is in the interest of the United States and the world. The United States is happy to see China develop and prosper, and does not seek to suppress or contain China&#39;s development, nor does it seek to decouple from China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;经过双方共同努力，这次会晤取得20多项重要成果，包括响应国际社会的期待，建立人工智能政府间对话；在解除对中方有关机构制裁前提下，成立中美禁毒合作工作组，开展禁毒合作；在平等和尊重基础上恢复两军高层沟通和机制性对话；同意明年早些时候大幅增加直航航班；扩大教育、留学生、青年、文化、体育和工商界交流；欢迎启动中美“21世纪20年代强化气候行动工作组”，共同推动联合国气候变化迪拜大会（COP28）成功。 In particular, the two heads of state recognized the efforts made by the two teams to discuss the guiding principles of Sino-US relations and the consensus reached since the Bali meeting, and emphasized the need for mutual respect, peaceful coexistence, maintenance of communication, prevention of conflicts, and abide by the United Nations Charter. Cooperation in areas of common interests and responsible management of competitive factors in bilateral relations provide guidance for bringing Sino-US relations back on track. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国际舆论高度关注、积极评价，普遍认为元首之间面对面沟通至关重要，对稳定中美关系的作用无可替代，此次会晤展现了双方的积极意愿，取得重要成果，具有非凡意义，对于历经起伏的中美关系发挥了关键引领作用。 President Biden also tweeted five times, saying that this was the most positive and fruitful meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王毅说，中美元首旧金山会晤是中美关系史上的大事件，也是国际关系中的大事件，有利于推动中美关系朝着健康、稳定、可持续方向迈出pace. President Xi Jinping led the giant ship of China-US relations through the treacherous reefs and shoals from Bali to San Francisco, demonstrating the political responsibility and strategic courage of the leader of a major country. At the same time, we must be soberly aware that the development of Sino-US relations has never been smooth sailing. There are still many deep-seated and structural problems, and there are still many risks and challenges that need to be jointly addressed. San Francisco is not the end, but a new starting point. Whether China-U.S. relations can consolidate their positive momentum depends on whether the United States can keep its promises, work with China halfway, and truly implement the important consensus reached by the two heads of state. Next year marks the 45th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and the United States. Both sides should start from San Francisco and promote the continuous improvement and development of Sino-US relations. This is in line with the interests and aspirations of the two peoples and the expectations of the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;b>;二、汇聚两国人民力量&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王毅说，2015年，习近平主席在西雅图面向美国人民发表演讲，用朴实的话语、鲜活的故事拉近了两国人民的心，当时的热烈场面至今历历在目。 In recent years, the political atmosphere of Sino-US relations has undergone complex changes, and the COVID-19 epidemic has also blocked normal exchanges between the two peoples. Since the beginning of this year, new and old American dignitaries, business leaders, and people from the private sector have visited China one after another. President Xi Jinping has met with or sent letters to friendly people from the United States on many occasions and actively interacted with them. When President Xi Jinping recently met with California Governor Newsom, he pointed out that the hope of Sino-US relations lies in the people, the foundation lies in the people, the future lies in the youth, and the vitality lies in the localities. These four sentences are profound and enlightening, expressing the common aspirations of people from all walks of life in the two countries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此访期间，习近平主席应邀出席美国友好团体联合举办的欢迎宴会。 Leaders from all walks of life in the United States and important business leaders were present. Representatives from President Xi Jinping’s old landlord during his first visit to the United States, friends from Iowa who have continued friendship for 40 years, a 103-year-old veteran member of the Flying Tigers, descendants of General Stilwell, Guling, Washington State and other friendly people also came from the United States. People from all over the country rushed to meet in San Francisco. President Xi Jinping met with them cordially, recalled the past, and thanked them for adhering to the original intention of friendship between the Chinese and American peoples. The scene was very warm and touching. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平主席发表重要演讲，60多次提到“人民”这个词。 He emphasized that the foundation of Sino-US relations was laid by the people, the door was opened by the people, the stories were written by the people, and the future was created by the people; he stressed that although the two countries have different histories, cultures, social systems, and development paths, The people are kind, friendly, hard-working and pragmatic. It is the two-way commitment between the people that has brought Sino-US relations back to the right track from the trough time and time again. Once the door of Sino-US relations is opened, it will never be closed again. The more difficult times are, the more we need to tighten the bonds between people and enhance people-to-people communication, and the more we need more people to stand up and advocate for Sino-US relations. President Xi Jinping&#39;s sincere words and vivid stories deeply touched the hearts of the audience present and aroused strong resonance. More than 400 guests stood up twice and responded with nearly 20 long and warm applause. They all said that the United States and China are interdependent on each other and the people-to-people friendship is profound, which is the source of vitality for the long-term and stable development of U.S.-China relations. As two important major countries in the world, maintaining dialogue and cooperation between the United States and China is vital to both countries and the world. They will continue to work to promote mutual understanding between the two peoples and contribute to the improvement and development of U.S.-China relations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王毅说，从西雅图到旧金山，时隔8年，习近平主席同美国各界友好人士再次亲切互动，让我们深切感受到，中美友好的基础还在，交往的动力犹存，合作的前景可期。 No matter how the situation changes, the fundamental desire of the Chinese and American people for exchanges and cooperation will not change. The bright future of China-U.S. relations must rely on the people. President Xi Jinping&#39;s important speech will surely inspire the people of both countries to become more actively involved in the cause of Sino-US friendship and accumulate more positive energy for the stable and healthy development of Sino-US relations. This visit also reflects that attaching importance to love and justice is a traditional virtue of the Chinese nation and a warm foundation for China’s diplomacy. President Xi Jinping not only pays attention to enhancing the friendship between leaders, but also makes friends from all walks of life, giving China&#39;s major-country diplomacy a style of common sense, sincerity and amity. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;b>;三、弘扬亚太合作初心&lt;/b>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王毅说，APEC是亚太地区层级最高、领域最广、最具影响力的经济合作平台. Thirty years ago, the APEC Leaders’ Informal Meeting mechanism was launched in Seattle, USA, helping the Asia-Pacific become the center of world economic growth and the anchor of global development and stability. Thirty years later, President Xi Jinping revisited the original intention of the APEC mechanism on the west coast of the United States, and once again pointed out the direction and drew a blueprint for Asia-Pacific cooperation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平主席深刻总结了亚太合作历程的有益启示，指出开放包容是亚太合作的主旋律，共同发展是亚太合作的总目标，求同存异是亚太合作的好做法。 Focusing on how to create the next &quot;golden thirty years&quot; in the Asia-Pacific, President Xi Jinping used a grand historical vision to ask questions and prescribe prescriptions. He proposed that we should adhere to innovation-driven, open-oriented, green development, inclusive sharing, and high-quality development. Quality growth promotes the building of an Asia-Pacific community with a shared future, allowing people of all countries to share the fruits of modernization. These four &quot;persistences&quot; are in line with China&#39;s new development philosophy. They are all things that China is doing in a down-to-earth manner. They show that we are committed to better empowering the development of the Asia-Pacific with our own actions and working with all parties to promote high-quality growth in the Asia-Pacific. In response to certain countries&#39; blatant calls for division and confrontation and malicious suppression of other countries&#39; development, President Xi Jinping pointedly pointed out that development is the eternal theme of the Asia-Pacific region. Only cooperation can develop, non-cooperation is the biggest risk, and &quot;decoupling and breaking links&quot; does no good to anyone. The Asia-Pacific cannot and should not be reduced to a battlefield of geopolitical games, let alone engage in a &quot;new cold war&quot; and camp confrontation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平主席提出的一系列重大倡议主张顺应大势、合乎民心，对亚太合作和全球发展具有重要指导意义和实践价值，得到与会各方高度认同和积极响应。 The leaders&#39; declaration adopted at the meeting fully reflects China&#39;s ideas and propositions such as implementing Putrajaya&#39;s vision, building an Asia-Pacific community, building the Asia-Pacific Free Trade Area, inclusive and sustainable development, and connectivity. International public opinion believes that at the critical juncture of the 30th anniversary of the first APEC leaders&#39; meeting, the world can see which countries adhere to the original intention of Asia-Pacific cooperation, adhere to openness, inclusiveness, mutual benefit and win-win, and which countries violate the original intention, engage in geopolitical confrontation and &quot;decouple and break links&quot;. Clearly. No matter how the international situation changes, China will follow the historical trend, continue to promote an open economy and Asia-Pacific economic integration, and be committed to realizing the Asia-Pacific dream of common development, prosperity and progress. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;四、阐释中国道路理念&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王毅说，在世界经济复苏乏力、不确定因素增多的背景下，外界高度关注中国作为全球主要经济体的表现，普遍期待中国继续发挥全球增长“动力源”和“稳定器”作用。 During this visit, President Xi Jinping delivered a written speech to the APEC Business Leaders Summit, and comprehensively and in-depth introduced the essential connotation of Chinese-style modernization and its global significance to all walks of life in the United States and APEC participants on multiple occasions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平主席指出，中国式现代化是中国共产党领导的社会主义现代化。 Chinese-style modernization not only has the common characteristics of the modernization of all countries, but also has distinctive characteristics based on China&#39;s national conditions. President Xi Jinping emphasized that we are committed to uniting and working hard to enable more than 1.4 billion Chinese people to move towards modernization together; we are committed to common prosperity so that every Chinese can live a good life; we are committed to all-round development so that people&#39;s material and spiritual worlds are the same We are committed to sustainable development and the harmonious coexistence of people and nature; we are committed to peaceful development and promoting the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind. These five &quot;commitments&quot; explain the main characteristics of Chinese modernization in an easy-to-understand and simple way, allowing the outside world to further understand the mission and tasks of the Communist Party of China and China&#39;s development path. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平主席指出，中国经济持续回升向好，增速在全球主要经济体中保持领先，仍然是全球增长最大引擎，今年对全球经济增长的贡献将达到三分之一，发出中国经济光明论的最强音。 President Xi Jinping emphasized that China has the institutional advantages of a socialist market economy, the demand advantages of a very large market, the supply advantages of a complete industrial system, and the talent advantages of a large number of high-quality workers and entrepreneurs. He authoritatively discussed the inherent logic of China&#39;s economic growth. and strong resilience. President Xi Jinping used vivid examples to illustrate China&#39;s unswerving promotion of high-quality development and high-level opening-up, from the unprecedented grand occasion of hosting the 3rd &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum to the recent hosting of the 6th China International Import Expo. The prosperous scene depicts a dynamic picture in which China opens its doors to construction, and its economic growth is more valuable and greener. President Xi Jinping emphasized that no matter how the international situation changes, China&#39;s determination to create a market-oriented, rule-by-law, and international business environment will not change, and its policy of providing high-quality services to foreign investors without discrimination will not change. President Xi Jinping announced that China will host the second Global Digital Trade Expo. He also announced that China will further reduce the negative list for foreign investment access, fully guarantee the national treatment of foreign-invested enterprises, and promote the orderly and free flow of data in accordance with the law. President Xi Jinping&#39;s &quot;two unchanged&quot; statement and a series of major policy announcements were sonorous and powerful, sending a strong signal of China&#39;s high-level opening up to the outside world and boosting the confidence of all parties in continuing cooperation with China. U.S. Commerce Secretary Raimondo and business leaders have stated that the United States welcomes a stable and prosperous China. Economic and trade cooperation with China has created a large number of job opportunities for the United States. U.S. companies have a strong interest in the Chinese market and the United States is committed to developing with China. Long-term stable relationship. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;此访期间，习近平主席还同墨西哥总统洛佩斯、秘鲁总统博鲁阿尔特，斐济总理兰布卡、文莱苏丹哈桑纳尔举行友好双边会见，为未来关系发展提供战略指引。 President Xi Jinping also met with Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida at request. The leaders of the two countries reaffirmed their adherence to the principles and consensus of the four political documents between China and Japan, reaffirmed the positioning of bilateral relations in comprehensively promoting a strategic and mutually beneficial relationship, and committed to building a constructive and stable Sino-Japanese relationship that meets the requirements of the new era. These bilateral meetings, together with the meeting between the heads of state of China and the United States and attendance at the APEC meeting, have made important efforts to create a favorable external environment for promoting high-quality domestic development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;王毅最后说，此访是习近平外交思想的又一次成功实践，是习近平主席运筹大国关系的“大手笔”。 From the meeting between the heads of state of China and Russia in Moscow at the beginning of the year to the meeting of the heads of state of China and the United States in San Francisco at the end of the year, China has unremittingly promoted coordination and cooperation among major powers and promoted the establishment of a framework for major-country relations with overall stability and balanced development, fully demonstrating China&#39;s responsibility as a major power. This visit is also President Xi Jinping’s “final visit” to the multilateral summit he attended this year.从首届中国—中亚峰会到第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛，从金砖国家领导人约翰内斯堡会晤到旧金山APEC领导人非正式会议，中国主张和中国理念广得人心，中国建设性的大国The role is more prominent. This visit once again proves that no matter how the international situation changes, President Xi Jinping always guides China&#39;s diplomacy to overcome difficulties and move forward courageously with a lofty vision, strong determination, and outstanding wisdom, creating a proactive and favorable environment for realizing the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation. external environment and make more and greater contributions to the progressive cause of promoting world peace and development. The east wind blows the rain across the green hills. We must deeply study and understand Xi Jinping Thought on Diplomacy, and under the strong leadership of the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping at its core, and with the guidance of head-of-state diplomacy, we must continue to create a new situation in major-country diplomacy with Chinese characteristics. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 05:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[03版要闻 - 为了亚太人民和子孙后代的共同繁荣]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20231119_2-03.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月19日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;11月的旧金山，时而阳光明媚，时而细雨蒙蒙。 Golden Gate Bridge is like weaving, and the blue sea surface is a little bit, and the gulls are flying. In the cool and humid air, with the message of the Pacific sea breeze. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;应美国总统拜登邀请，国家主席习近平于14日至17日赴美国旧金山举行中美元首会晤，同时应邀出席亚太经合组织第三十次领导人非正式会议。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从北京出发，飞越浩瀚的太平洋，习近平主席乘坐的专机经过10多个小时飞行，顺利抵达旧金山。美国加利福尼亚州州长纽森、财政部长耶伦等高级官员在舷梯下热情迎接。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我第一次到美国就是到旧金山，就是这里。”习近平主席话语亲切。 &quot;1985.&quot; Newson added with a smile.耶伦曾担任过旧金山联邦储备银行行长，这次她也以“本地人”身份热情欢迎习近平主席的到来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这座美国西海岸大都会见证了中美两国人民百年交往的历史，也见证了中美建设美好世界的努力，这一次更将见证国际关系史上一座新的里程碑。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;1945年，中美共同参与发起旧金山制宪会议，推动建立了联合国，中国第一个在《联合国宪章》上签字。回顾“上次旧金山让全球领导人集聚一堂”的高光时刻，美国哥伦比亚广播公司报道说，对旧金山而言，此次亚太经合组织会议将是一次难得的“世纪机遇”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;四天时间里，10余场双多边活动。举世瞩目，习近平主席同各方密集互动，为中美关系引领航向，为亚太合作擘画蓝图，为地区和世界和平稳定、发展繁荣注入强大信心与动力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;风尘仆仆的脚步，胸怀天下的气度。透过习近平主席的“旧金山时间”，世界聆听新时代中国特色大国外交的铿锵足音，见证一个东方大国为人类谋进步、为世界谋大同的笃行与担当。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;（一）&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;塑造：“要把一个什么样的亚太带到本世纪中叶？”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这是亚太经合组织领导人第三十次聚首。在这样的历史节点，回首来路，眺望前方，更能感悟世界大潮的奔涌浩荡。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;30年前，冷战结束后不久，亚太地区领导人顺应和平和发展的时代潮流，召开了首次亚太经合组织领导人非正式会议，一致同意超越集团对抗、零和博弈的旧思维，深化区域经济合作和一体化，致力于共建一个活力、和谐、繁荣的亚太大家庭。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;30年来，这一机制推动亚太发展和经济全球化进入快车道，助力亚太成为世界经济增长中心、全球发展稳定之锚和合作高地。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚太合作的非凡历程带给我们怎样的深刻启示？ 16日，习近平主席在向亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会发表的书面演讲中，与世界分享他的深邃思考——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;开放包容是亚太合作的主旋律；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共同发展是亚太合作的总目标；&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;求同存异是亚太合作的好做法。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;语言精辟，蕴含哲理。从历史中汲取智慧与力量，让思想之光照亮前行方向。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“亚太不能也不应该沦为地缘博弈的角斗场，更不能搞&#39;新冷战&#39;和阵营对抗”“唯有合作才能发展，不合作是最大的风险，搞&#39;脱钩断链&#39;对谁都没好处”“坚持开放的区域主义”“打造合作共赢的开放型亚太经济”“推进数字化、智能化、绿色化转型发展”……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;掷地有声的中国立场，知行合一的中国方案，为亚太持久稳定、繁荣发展凝聚力量。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会议新闻中心内，一摞演讲稿被一抢而空，记者们拿到后仔细阅读，抢发快讯。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;演讲稿在当日的《旧金山观察家报》网站上全文刊载。编者按这样写道：我们很少全文刊登政治演说，但习近平主席的这份演讲稿极不寻常，包含着美国商界、决策者和全世界高度期待的信息，将被广泛深入研读。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“发人深思”“鼓舞人心”“为亚太携手实现共同发展繁荣指明了方向”……亚太地区工商界人士对习近平主席的演讲高度赞誉。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大国之大，在于胸襟大、格局大、担当大。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2013年以来，习近平主席出席或主持历次亚太经合组织领导人非正式会议并发表重要讲话，为区域合作谋划大手笔、塑造大格局，为亚太人民共同命运谋划未来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从提出树立“亚太命运共同体意识”，到倡导共建“互信、包容、合作、共赢的亚太伙伴关系”，从描绘“亚太梦想”，到勾画“全方位互联互通蓝图”，再到维护全球供应链产业链畅通……中国理念、中国行动，引领亚太航船劈波斩浪，不断前行。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当前，世界百年变局加速演进，世界经济面临多种风险挑战。作为全球经济增长引擎，亚太肩负更大的时代责任。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“作为亚太地区领导人，我们都要深入思考，要把一个什么样的亚太带到本世纪中叶？如何打造亚太发展的下一个&#39;黄金三十年&#39;？在这一进程中如何更好发挥亚太经合组织作用？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在17日举行的亚太经合组织第三十次领导人非正式会议上，习近平主席发表重要讲话，为亚太面临的新的时代之问破题，推动亚太合作再出发——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;坚持创新驱动；坚持开放导向；坚持绿色发展；坚持普惠共享。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们应该秉持亚太合作初心，负责任地回应时代呼唤，携手应对全球性挑战，全面落实布特拉加亚愿景，建设开放、活力、强韧、和平的亚太共同体，实现亚太人民和子孙后代的共同繁荣。”习近平主席的话赢得与会各经济体领导人广泛赞同。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;（二）&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;领航：“这个地球容得下中美两国。中美各自的成功是彼此的机遇。”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;16日举行的亚太经合组织领导人同东道主嘉宾非正式对话会暨工作午宴，以“可持续、气候和公正能源转型”为议题。在会议间隙，前一天举行的中美元首会晤成为各方谈论的焦点。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“祝贺您！”“太好啦！”见到习近平主席，多位领导人走上前来，就中美元首会晤成功举行表示祝贺，有人甚至感慨，会晤“让人长舒了一口气”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;15日，旧金山郊外的斐洛里庄园，花木葳蕤，习近平主席同拜登总统在这里举行会晤。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美方特别表示，中美元首会晤是拜登总统向习近平主席专门发出的单独邀请，不同于本次亚太经合组织领导人非正式会议期间的双边会见安排。这是一场中美“峰会”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上午11时15分许，习近平主席乘车抵达时，拜登总统在主楼门前迎候。握手、合影，并肩步入会谈厅。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这个地球容得下中美两国。中美各自的成功是彼此的机遇。”落座后，习近平主席开宗明义。此次会晤，距巴厘岛会晤正好一年零一天。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;过去一年里，美方在落实巴厘岛共识上出现严重“行动赤字”，甚至与共识倡导的精神背道而驰，导致双边关系出现新的困难。最近几个月，美国政府高官多次访华，双边高层互动明显增加，两国关系出现止跌企稳积极势头。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我和总统先生是中美关系的掌舵者，对人民、对世界、对历史都担负着沉甸甸的责任。”习近平主席话语有力，彰显负责任大国领袖的深邃思考和责任担当。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我始终认为，美中关系是世界上最重要的双边关系，美中冲突并非不可避免，一个稳定和发展的中国符合美国和世界的利益。”拜登总统说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“共同树立正确认知”“共同有效管控分歧”“共同推进互利合作”“共同承担大国责任”“共同促进人文交流”……习近平主席提出的“五个共同”为中美关系的稳定发展浇筑起五根支柱。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在相互尊重和平等互惠基础上，两国领导人探讨了各领域对话合作，在政治外交、人文交流、全球治理、军事安全等领域达成了20多项共识。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会晤、午宴、散步，全程使用同传，两国元首扎扎实实谈了4个小时。话别时，习近平主席说：“相信我们的关系将保持下去。”“我赞同。”拜登总统回应。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;会晤期间，媒体捕捉到这样一个瞬间——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;午宴前，拜登总统特地向习近平主席展示了手机里的一张照片，正是1985年时任正定县委书记习近平在金门大桥前的一张留影。 &quot;You haven&#39;t changed at all!&quot; President Biden said.现场顿时响起一阵爽朗的欢笑声。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;38年过去，弹指一挥间。从县委书记到大国领袖，习近平始终相信，中美关系的根基是由人民浇筑的，中美关系的大门是由人民打开的，中美关系的故事是由人民书写的，中美关系的未来是由人民创造的。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;15日当晚，旧金山市中心，美国友好团体联合举行宴会欢迎习近平主席。飞虎队老兵、史迪威将军的后人、“鼓岭之友”，艾奥瓦州、华盛顿州的友人……约400名新朋老友欢聚一堂，场面盛大热烈。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我第一次访问美国时，住在艾奥瓦州的德沃切克夫妇家中，我还记得门牌号是邦尼街2911号。”温情讲述令人动容。在场人士对习近平主席热情洋溢的演讲报以近二十次热烈掌声。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“越是困难的时候，越需要拉紧人民的纽带、增进人心的沟通，越需要更多的人站出来为中美关系鼓与呼。”习近平主席指出。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“习近平主席，欢迎您再来金伯利农场做客，再来开拖拉机”“您提到让大熊猫重返加州的事，我们愿意提供飞机把熊猫再接过来”“您讲的话打动现场每一个人”……美方人士热情回应，表示将继续传承和发展好美中友谊。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;太平洋足够大，容得下百舸争流；地球足够大，容得下中美各自和共同发展。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在两国元首领航把舵下，中美关系这艘巨轮穿越暗礁险滩，从巴厘岛抵达旧金山，殊为不易。但旧金山不是终点，而应该成为新的起点。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;（三）&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;担当：“下一个&#39;中国&#39;，还是中国”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; On November 16, the Chinese delegation&#39;s delegation was endless and became a &quot;home&quot; of Chinese bilateral diplomacy during the multilateral international conference. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在密集紧凑的日程中，习近平主席专门安排时间，同出席本次亚太经合组织领导人非正式会议相关活动的多位外国领导人举行双边会见。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有的来自与中国相距万里的拉美——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在谈及其他话题之前，我首先借此机会向您表示感谢。”首次同习近平主席会面，墨西哥总统洛佩斯讲起一段往事。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在我们最艰难的时刻，中国是最早向我们提供帮助的国家。”洛佩斯总统有些动情，“中国同我们架设起一座座空中桥梁，为我们源源不断送来紧缺医疗物资，帮助我们渡过难关。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;世界已经走出新冠疫情大流行，但洛佩斯总统仍对中国的紧急驰援感怀在心。见到习近平主席，他迫不及待表达感激之情。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在我们有生之年可能找不到另一个星球供人类生存了。”旧金山之行期间，习近平主席讲的这句话引人深思。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽地处不同大洲、相隔万里之遥，但同为亚太大家庭成员，同为地球村居民，同属人类命运共同体。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有的是与中国远隔重洋的太平洋岛国——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国是个伟大的国家，始终坚持大小国家一律平等，斐方敬佩习近平主席的世界领导力。”就任后首次同习近平主席会面的斐济总理兰布卡表示。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国发展同太平洋岛国关系坦坦荡荡，没有私心，不针对第三方。”习近平主席的话意味深长。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然国情不尽相同，但兰布卡总理仍热切期盼从中国式现代化的成功道路中寻求启迪。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他诚挚表示：“习近平主席提出的全球发展倡议、全球安全倡议、全球文明倡议，有利于维护和促进全球南方国家发展和利益。斐方期待同中方深化合作，助力斐济选择和走好通往现代化的道路。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有的是与中国隔海相望的友好邻邦——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我还记得我们在曼谷进行的会晤，当时也是在亚太经合组织领导人非正式会议期间。”文莱苏丹哈桑纳尔说，文莱同中国的友好交往源远流长，文方愿继续致力于加强经贸、农业、渔业、绿色能源等领域合作，积极推进高质量共建“一带一路”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“今天再次见到老朋友，感到十分亲切。”习近平主席表示，中方高度重视东亚合作，愿同文莱等东盟国家一道，推进区域经济一体化，维护东亚合作正确方向。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有的是与中国一衣带水的近邻——&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;时隔一年再次会见，习近平主席和日本首相岸田文雄重申恪守中日四个政治文件的原则和共识，重新确认全面推进战略互惠关系的两国关系定位，致力于构建契合新时代要求的建设性、稳定的中日关系。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无论国家大小，无论来自何方，大家相聚在一起，都有一个共同的心愿：共同建设一个和平、稳定、繁荣的亚太大家庭。而同中国的交往与合作，至关重要。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一年多前召开的中国共产党二十大，开启了以中国式现代化全面推进强国建设、民族复兴伟业的新征程。新征程上的中国，将给亚太、给世界带来什么？ &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;党的二十大之后习近平主席的首次美国之行，从不同的维度向美国、向亚太、向世界讲述着生动而精彩的中国故事。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“前不久，我们成功举办第六届中国国际进口博览会，吸引了来自包括美国在内128个国家的3400多家企业参展，美国连续6届展览面积最大。”在美国友好团体联合欢迎宴会上，习近平主席讲起刚刚成功举办的进博会，以实打实的数字向世界说明，“14亿多中国人民迈向现代化是中国带给世界的巨大机遇”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“现在，全球光伏发电装机容量接近一半在中国，全球新能源汽车一半以上行驶在中国，全球四分之一的新增绿化面积来自中国。我们力争2030年前实现碳达峰，2060年前实现碳中和。我们说到做到。”讲起各方都关心的绿色发展，习近平主席描绘了迈向未来人与自然和谐共生的美好愿景。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“上个月，中国成功举办第三届&#39;一带一路&#39;国际合作高峰论坛，形成了458项成果，中国金融机构成立7800亿元人民币的&#39;一带一路&#39;项目融资窗口，中外企业达成972亿美元的商业合作协议，这将推动共建&#39;一带一路&#39;高质量发展，为全球互联互通、促进发展繁荣注入强劲动力。”同亚太工商界朋友交流，习近平主席瞩望共建“一带一路”的光明未来。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国坚持走和平发展道路，发展的根本目的是让中国人民过上好日子，不是要取代谁。”在旧金山，习近平主席深刻指出，“工作得更好，生活得更好，孩子们成长得更好，是14亿多中国人民的殷切心愿。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;回首30年不凡历程，作为亚太大家庭的一员，中国的发展起步于亚太，得益于亚太；面向未来，踏上新征程的中国，将继续立足亚太、造福亚太。 The next &quot;China&quot; will still be China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我谨向您发出最热情的邀请，希望您拨冗出席2024年亚太经合组织领导人非正式会议，并对秘鲁再次进行国事访问。”旧金山会议尚未结束，明年亚太经合组织会议东道主秘鲁总统博鲁阿尔特已提前行动了。在习近平主席同其会见时，博鲁阿尔特总统就迫不及待地向习近平主席发出邀请。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;着眼下一个“黄金三十年”，从旧金山出发，为了亚太人民和子孙后代的共同繁荣，为了世界和平与发展，为了人类更加美好的未来，习近平主席引领新时代中国，征程万里，不辍前行。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（新华社旧金山11月18日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;参与记者：杨依军、孙奕、宿亮、温馨）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 05:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[04版要闻 - 建设开放、活力、强韧、和平的亚太共同体]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20231119_1-04.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月19日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;当地时间11月17日上午，亚太经合组织第三十次领导人非正式会议在美国旧金山莫斯科尼中心held.国家主席习近平出席会议并发表题为《坚守初心&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;团结合作&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;携手共促亚太高质量增长》的重要讲话，系统阐释推动亚太发展、加强亚太经合组织合作的中国方案，强调坚持创新驱动、坚持开放导向、坚持绿色发展、坚持普惠共享。接受本报记者采访的各界人士认为，在亚太发展的关键当口，习近平主席的重要讲话传递出团结合作、共促发展的坚定信念，为推动亚太合作行稳致远指明方向和路径，为建设开放、活力、强韧、和平的亚太共同体注入强劲动力。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“开放包容、合作共赢才是人间正道”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当前，世界百年变局加速演进，世界经济面临多种风险挑战，作为全球增长引擎，亚太肩负更大的时代责任。习近平主席在讲话中强调，我们应该秉持亚太合作初心，负责任地回应时代呼唤，携手应对全球性挑战，全面落实布特拉加亚愿景，建设开放、活力、强韧、和平的亚太共同体，实现亚太人民和子孙后代的共同繁荣。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;智利前驻华大使、安德烈斯·贝略大学拉美中国问题研究中心主任费尔南多·雷耶斯·马塔表示，在全球经济发展面临诸多挑战的当下，习近平主席提出了值得亚太各方乃至世界各国思考的重要命题。亚太各方应当携手并肩，一起把亚太地区打造成更具活力、开放、强劲的全球增长引擎。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“开放包容、合作共赢才是人间正道。亚太经合组织各成员之间的密切合作有助于推动亚太地区经济复苏和稳定增长。”泰国参议院外交委员会顾问阿颂西表示，当前，世界并不太平，全球经济发展面临许多不确定因素，亚太各方尤其应当保持团结，促进经济和社会发展方面的合作，以亚太地区的发展推动世界经济复苏。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国英菲尼瑞尔公司创始人兼首席执行官拜尔特·万克对习近平主席提出的构建亚太共同体目标深有感触。他说：“从太空俯视，地球这个蓝色星球是我们唯一赖以生存的家园。如果对这一事实有清醒的认知，就会意识到面对气候变化、可持续发展等人类共同挑战，亚太地区乃至全世界只有合作这一种选择，相互隔绝甚至彼此对立无助于人类的永续发展。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;澳大利亚澳中工商业委员会北领地分会主席、知名时政评论人士戴若·顾比表示，中国坚定推进亚太区域一体化，一直是推动亚太地区团结合作的重要力量。中国的倡议主张与亚太经合组织创建时的目标高度一致，为各方共同建设一个活力、和谐、繁荣的亚太大家庭作出重要贡献。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“习近平主席的重要讲话，让我们看到中国致力于维护地区和平稳定、促进亚太共同繁荣，将推动亚太各方携手建设亚太共同体，再创亚太合作新辉煌。”法国席勒研究所国际问题专家塞巴斯蒂安·佩里莫尼表示，过去几十年，亚太经济快速增长，得益于一个和平稳定的环境。亚太地区不能也不应成为地缘政治竞争的舞台，更不可陷入新冷战或阵营对抗的泥淖。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“亚太合作需要各方汇聚智慧、共同参与”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平主席在讲话中提出“坚持创新驱动”“坚持开放导向”“坚持绿色发展”“坚持普惠共享”四点建议，为全面落实布特拉加亚愿景，建设开放、活力、强韧、和平的亚太共同体指明了方向。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;普华永道会计师事务所中国及亚太区主席赵柏基认为，习近平主席的重要讲话令人鼓舞，四点建议具有前瞻性、战略性，意义重大。 “亚太合作需要各方汇聚智慧、共同参与，既要有顶层设计，也要注重落实，各方应努力推动亚太地区可持续发展，进而维护世界和平与发展。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国旧金山湾区委员会总裁、首席执行官吉姆·旺德曼表示，作为亚太地区两大重要经济体，美中两国肩负着推动亚太地区稳定发展的重任。两国应该加强合作，引领亚太地区继续成为世界经济发展的重要引擎。合作共赢是时代发展的潮流，也是美中关系应有的底色。中国正致力于高质量发展，美国也在着力发展经济，双方合作空间无限广阔，完全可以相互成就、互利共赢。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国西恩国际贸易咨询公司致力于为中小企业提供咨询服务，公司创始人安·休恩表示，如今越来越多的美国中小企业从与中国的贸易往来中受益。作为亚太地区最重要的经济体之一，中国扎实推进高质量发展和高水平对外开放，对亚太地区乃至全球经济发展贡献良多。亚太地区产业链供应链联系紧密，在全球经济复苏乏力的背景下，“中国主张加快推进亚太自由贸易区进程，有助于各方共享区域开放发展带来的机遇”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚太经合组织秘书处执行主任丽贝卡·玛丽亚表示，习近平主席强调坚持绿色发展，为世界打开了机遇之门，有助于推动亚太地区进一步探索经济复苏和包容性增长路径.从更广阔的视角看待数字化、减少碳排放和污染、保证能源安全和粮食安全等可持续发展议题，符合各方对亚太继续发挥引擎作用、引领世界经济增长的期待。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;墨西哥国家公共广播系统记者米格尔·阿尔扎特表示，中国人口规模巨大，在推进现代化建设中高度重视社会发展、人民生活水平提高，这种普惠共享的理念和实践为发展中国家作出了榜样。中国与包括墨西哥在内的亚太地区成员不断深化在基础设施等领域合作，为提升区域互联互通水平注入新活力，让各国人民可以共享现代化建设的成果。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“中国新发展为亚太及世界发展带来新机遇”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年以来，中国经济持续回升向好，增速在全球主要经济体中保持领先，高质量发展扎实推进。习近平主席在讲话中指出，今年是中国改革开放45周年，我们将坚持高质量发展，推进高水平对外开放，以中国式现代化为推动实现世界各国的现代化提供新机遇。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国新兴市场论坛首席执行官哈瑞尔达·考利表示，中国上个月成功举办第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛，共建“一带一路”倡议在推进亚太地区互联互通方面取得丰硕成果。共商共建共享原则契合亚太经合组织倡导的合作理念，有利于早日建成高水平的亚太自由贸易区。亚太经合组织中大多数成员属于发展中国家和新兴市场经济体，以中国为代表的发展中国家和新兴市场经济体在推进贸易和投资自由化便利化、推进区域经济一体化进程中发挥的作用越Come bigger. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;泰国泰中商务委员会主席邱威功表示，亚太地区经济发展深深受益于共建“一带一路”。如今，中老铁路开通运营已接近两年，印尼雅万高铁今年10月正式开通运营。相信随着中泰铁路加速建设，东盟国家和中国贸易、人员往来将进一步畅通，发展前景令人期待。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;秘鲁外贸旅游部部长马修斯表示，创新是发展的强大动力，中国加快实施创新驱动发展战略，对秘鲁等拉美国家来说意味着宝贵机遇。过去几十年，中国在科技领域取得长足进步。如今，中国是秘鲁主要贸易伙伴和投资来源国，中国出口秘鲁的产品中，新能源汽车等科技含量高的商品占比越来越大。中国积极推动科技交流合作，将创造更加良好的科技发展环境，持续为发展中国家经济社会发展增添新动能。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;马来西亚数字服务公司菲律宾分公司首席顾问保罗·马特尔表示，亚太各方应积极响应中国提出的全球发展倡议、全球安全倡议和全球文明倡议，携手应对各种全球性挑战，促进共同发展，增进全人类福祉。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;360集团创始人周鸿祎表示，作为亚太经济重要引擎，中国在推动世界经济复苏和增长中发挥了重要作用。中国是全球第二大经济体，积极发展高科技和创新产业，成为全球技术创新的重要推动力量。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德国拜耳集团执行副总裁马蒂亚斯·伯宁格表示，习近平主席的重要讲话展示了中国坚持对外开放的决心，有利于增强全球市场信心。 “世界经济发展一再证明，开放带来进步，封闭必然落后。45年来，中国不断扩大开放，不仅发展了自身，也为全球经济发展持续注入动力。中国市场拥有巨大机遇，中国新发展为亚太及世界发展带来新机遇。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（本报旧金山、曼谷、堪培拉、巴黎、北京11月18日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;记者陈一鸣、牟宗琮、任彦、陈尚文、张博岚、杨一、时元皓、李志伟、张梦旭、张朋辉、张矜若、陈效卫、尚凯元、万宇、孟祥麟）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 05:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[04版要闻 - 共同打造亚太下一个“黄金三十年”（和音）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/19/nw.D110000renmrb_20231119_2-04.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月19日星期日&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;过去几十年，亚太各方携手创造了举世瞩目的“亚太奇迹”。站在新的历史起点，各方应共同努力，推动亚太合作取得更多丰硕成果&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;世界百年变局加速演进，世界经济面临多种风险挑战。作为全球增长引擎，亚太肩负更大的时代责任。 What kind of Asia Pacific to bring to the middle of this century? How to create the next &quot;golden thirty years&quot; of Asia-Pacific development? How can APEC better play its role in this process?这是在历史发展的关键当口，亚太地区领导人要深入思考的问题。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“我们应该秉持亚太合作初心，负责任地回应时代呼唤，携手应对全球性挑战，全面落实布特拉加亚愿景，建设开放、活力、强韧、和平的亚太共同体，实现亚太人民和子孙后代的共同繁荣。”当地时间11月17日上午，习近平主席在美国旧金山出席亚太经合组织第三十次领导人非正式会议并发表重要讲话，提出“坚持创新驱动”“坚持开放导向”“坚持绿色发展”“坚持普惠共享”四点建议，为亚太发展指明方向。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;创新是发展的强大动力。只有积极推进创新，在新一轮科技革命和产业变革浪潮中抢抓机遇，亚太这个全球增长引擎才能更加强劲。亚太各方要顺应科技发展趋势，以更加积极姿态推动科技交流合作，携手打造开放、公平、公正、非歧视的科技发展环境。 It is necessary to accelerate digital transformation, narrow the digital divide, accelerate the implementation of the &quot;APEC Internet and Digital Economy Roadmap&quot;, support the application of new technologies such as big data, cloud computing, artificial intelligence, and quantum computing, and continuously shape new momentum and new advantages for the development of the Asia-Pacific.中国不仅自身在科技创新和数字经济发展方面走在世界前列，还积极倡导在亚太乃至世界范围内推进数字化转型，更好为亚太发展赋能，为地区长远发展打下更加坚实的基础。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;开放包容是人类繁荣进步的基本条件。亚太各方要维护自由开放的贸易投资，支持并加强以世界贸易组织为核心的多边贸易体制，维护全球产业链供应链稳定畅通，反对将经贸问题政治化、武器化、泛安全化。 We must unswervingly promote regional economic integration, accelerate the process of the Asia-Pacific Free Trade Area, fully implement the APEC Connectivity Blueprint, and share regional open development opportunities.中国成功举办第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛，坚持高水平实施《区域全面经济伙伴关系协定》，主动对接《全面与进步跨太平洋伙伴关系协定》和《数字经济伙伴关系协定》高标准经贸规则，积极推动加入两个协定进程，正是为了促进全球互联互通、构建开放型世界经济，同各方共绘开放发展新图景。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;绿色是亚太地区可持续发展的必然要求。当前，气候变化、自然灾害等挑战日益严峻。亚太各方要坚持人与自然和谐共生，加快推动发展方式绿色低碳转型，协同推进降碳、减污、扩绿、增长，落实好《生物循环绿色经济曼谷目标》，厚植亚太增长的绿色底色。 China adheres to the path of ecological priority and green development, actively and steadily promotes carbon peak and carbon neutrality, and accelerates the green transformation of its development model.中国提出亚太经合组织绿色农业、可持续城市、能源低碳转型、海洋污染防治等合作倡议，推动搭建亚太经合组织可持续能源中心等合作平台，参与实施墨西哥尤卡坦半岛齐拉姆红树林保护区等绿色发展项目，持续为共建清洁美丽的亚太贡献中国智慧、中国方案。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;大家一起发展才是真发展。只有坚持普惠共享，才能让发展成果更多更公平惠及各国人民。亚太各方要全面落实联合国2030年可持续发展议程，推动发展问题重回国际议程中心位置，深化发展战略对接，共同解决全球发展赤字。习近平主席提出全球发展倡议，为推动国际社会合力解决发展赤字作出了积极贡献。在此次会议上，习近平主席欢迎各方积极参与全球发展倡议，深化减贫、粮食安全、工业化、发展筹资等领域合作，构建全球发展共同体，让各国人民共享现代化建设成果，展现立己达人、胸怀天下的责任担当和使命情怀。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;万物得其本者生，百事得其道者成。过去几十年，亚太各方携手创造了举世瞩目的“亚太奇迹”。站在新的历史起点，各方应共同努力，推动亚太合作取得更多丰硕成果，共同打造亚太下一个“黄金三十年”。 &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sun, 19 Nov 2023 05:26:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>