<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平同委内瑞拉总统马杜罗会谈]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/14/nw.D110000renmrb_20230914_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, September 14, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-09/14/01/rmrb2023091401p34_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;The afternoon of September 13th , President Xi Jinping held talks at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing with Venezuelan President Maduro, who was in China for a state visit. This is a group photo of Xi Jinping and his wife Peng Liyuan with Maduro and his wife Flores before the talks. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Huang Jingwen&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot; center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-09/14/01/rmrb2023091401p33_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR >; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of September 13, President Xi Jinping held talks with Venezuelan President Maduro, who was in China for a state visit, at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing. Before the talks, Xi Jinping held a welcoming ceremony for Maduro in the square outside the east gate of the Great Hall of the People. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Liu Bin&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, September 13th&amp;nbsp ;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Liu Hua) On the afternoon of September 13, President Xi Jinping held talks at the Great Hall of the People with Venezuelan President Maduro, who was in China for a state visit. The two heads of state announced that they would upgrade China-Venezuela relations to an all-weather strategic partnership. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that China and Venezuela are good friends who trust each other and good partners for common development. In recent years, China and Venezuela have both gone through extraordinary development processes. The two sides have supported each other in the changing international situation and have forged an &quot;iron&quot; friendship. China has always viewed the development of relations with Venezuela from a strategic and long-term perspective, firmly supports Venezuela&#39;s efforts to safeguard national sovereignty, national dignity, and social stability, and firmly supports Venezuela&#39;s just cause of opposing external interference. The establishment of an all-weather strategic partnership between China and Venezuela is in line with the common expectations of the two peoples and conforms to the general trend of historical development. Both sides should promote China-Venezuela strategic cooperation to bear more fruits, bring more benefits to the people of the two countries, and inject more positive energy into world peace and development. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping introduced China&#39;s reform and opening up, especially the construction of special economic zones, and pointed out that reform and opening up is an important magic weapon for China to make great strides to catch up with the times, and is a key move to determine the destiny of contemporary China. China cherishes this process. The valuable experience gained will continue to push forward reform and opening up. No force can stop China&#39;s development and progress. China is willing to work with Venezuela to firmly support each other in exploring development paths that suit their national conditions, strengthen exchanges of experience in party and state governance, support Venezuela in establishing special economic zones, and is willing to share relevant experience with Venezuela to help Venezuela advance national construction. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that next year marks the 50th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and Venezuela, and both sides should celebrate it grandly. China is willing to intensify people-to-people and cultural exchanges with Venezuela, support the development of Chinese language teaching in Venezuela, run the Confucius Institute well, strengthen media exchanges, and tell the story of China-Venezuela friendship well. Both sides should conscientiously implement the results achieved at the 17th meeting of the China-Venezuela High-Level Mixed Committee and strengthen practical cooperation in various fields in the next stage. China is willing to expand imports of high-quality Venezuelan specialty products. Congratulations to Venezuela for becoming the first country in the Americas to join the international lunar scientific research station cooperation initiated by China. The two sides should cooperate closely in multilateral mechanisms such as the United Nations and the &quot;G77 and China&quot;, strengthen solidarity and cooperation with other developing countries, jointly safeguard the purposes and principles of the United Nations Charter, and safeguard the common interests of developing countries. China attaches great importance to the development of China-Latin America relations. Next year marks the 10th anniversary of the establishment of the China-CELAC Forum. China is willing to work with Venezuela and other regional countries to promote overall cooperation between China and Latin America and jointly build a community with a shared future for China and Latin America. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Maduro said that under the leadership of President Xi Jinping, China has become a great country committed to peace, development and welfare of all mankind, and an important engine for promoting a new multi-polar world. Everything I saw and heard during my visit to China fully demonstrated China&#39;s progress and strength. I would like to express my heartfelt congratulations to the Communist Party of China for its great achievements. Venezuela and China enjoy profound friendship and fruitful cooperation. Their relations can be regarded as a model for relations between countries in the global South. The Venezuelan people sincerely thank the Chinese government and people for their valuable support and assistance when Venezuela suffered from illegal unilateral sanctions and the multiple difficulties caused by the COVID-19 epidemic. It is precisely thanks to the help of our Chinese brothers that the Venezuelan people have withstood the test and made extraordinary achievements in the cause of national economic construction. The current development of Venezuela and China-Venezuela relations are at an important period. My state visit to China and my announcement together with President Xi Jinping to upgrade Venezuela-China relations to an all-weather strategic partnership are of historic significance and will surely open a new era for Venezuela-China relations. Venezuela is willing to learn from China&#39;s experience in building special economic zones and deepen practical cooperation between the two countries in agriculture, investment, education, tourism and other fields. Venezuela actively supports the joint construction of the “Belt and Road”, supports the global development initiative, global security initiative, and global civilization initiative proposed by President Xi Jinping, and is willing to work closely with China to communicate and collaborate within multilateral frameworks such as the United Nations and the BRICS mechanism to safeguard multilateralism and The legitimate interests of developing countries promote the building of a community with a shared future for mankind. Venezuela is willing to play an active role in promoting the further development of relations between CELAC and China. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;After the talks, the two heads of state jointly witnessed the signing of a number of bilateral cooperation documents in the fields of jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, economy and trade, education, tourism, science and technology, health, aerospace, civil aviation and other fields. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The two sides issued the &quot;Joint Statement between the People&#39;s Republic of China and the Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela on the Establishment of an All-Weather Strategic Partnership.&quot; &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Before the talks, Xi Jinping held a welcome ceremony for Maduro in the square outside the east gate of the Great Hall of the People. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;When Maduro arrived, soldiers of honor lined up to salute. The two heads of state ascended the reviewing stand, the military band played the national anthems of China and Venezuela, and a 21-gun salute was fired in Tiananmen Square. Accompanied by Xi Jinping, Maduro inspected the honor guard of the Chinese People&#39;s Liberation Army and watched the procession. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping’s wife Peng Liyuan and Maduro’s wife Flores accompanied him to the welcome ceremony. That night, Xi Jinping and Peng Liyuan held a welcome banquet for Maduro and Flores at the Golden Hall of the Great Hall of the People. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Wang Yi participated in the above activities. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 在党的旗帜下汇聚强军兴军强大力量（学思想 强党性 重实践 建新功）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/14/nw.D110000renmrb_20230914_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, September 14, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Consolidate the ideological foundation of being committed to the party and inspire the spiritual power of unity and forge ahead. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From mid-spring to early autumn, the military’s theme education on studying and implementing Xi Jinping’s new era of socialism with Chinese characteristics has been solidly carried out in the party committees of units above the military level throughout the military. The Central Military Commission regards the development of thematic education as a major matter related to the overall situation and pays close attention to it, resolutely implements the spirit of President Xi Jinping’s important speech and important instructions on thematic education, conscientiously implements the spirit of the all-party thematic education work conference, and convenes a work meeting to in-depth mobilize and deploy , implement strong leadership guidance. The military theme education leading group carefully organized and implemented the program, held multiple meetings to study and promote it, and strictly supervised and guided the entire process. Members of the Central Military Commission took the lead in collective learning, conducted in-depth investigations and studies, organized concentrated discussions, and set a powerful example for the troops. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The party committees of units above the military level immediately established a leading group and established a work coordination mechanism, firmly grasping the general requirements of &quot;learning ideas, strengthening party spirit, emphasizing practice, and building new achievements&quot;, and promoted the implementation of key measures in an integrated manner. , coordinate and grasp the educational practice activities of &quot;learning the thoughts of strengthening the army and making contributions to the cause of strengthening the army&quot;, and achieve tangible results in using learning to build the soul, using learning to increase wisdom, using learning to rectify the style, and using learning to promote cadres. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Build your soul through learning - deep study and careful understanding to lay a solid foundation of thought&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Only by true learning and true understanding can you be truly armed. There is no such thing as &quot;squeezing&quot; or &quot;drilling&quot; You can&#39;t learn the true scriptures with all your strength, and you can&#39;t understand the truth without spending the effort of &quot;reading the book a hundred times.&quot; The party committees of units above the military level focus on self-study and deepening, focus on loyalty training and internalization, and focus on applying what they learn and focusing on transformation. They study original books to understand the power of ideas, give party class guidance to temper strong party spirit, and conduct special seminars one after another. Strengthen self-confidence and self-awareness...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strong faith and belief. Adhere to reading the original works to learn the original text and understand the principles. Leading cadres take the lead in going to the branch to teach and promote learning. They read the required readings carefully and follow up the spirit of Chairman Xi’s latest important speeches and important instructions. Units at the military level and above organize more than 7 days of theoretical rotation training for all employees. Each member of the party committee team teaches special party classes, and the secretary of the Discipline Inspection Commission teaches party classes on integrity. They go to the red education base to learn on the spot, and carry out &quot;explaining morality, discipline, and argumentation through cases.&quot; &quot;Speaking of Responsibility&quot; warning education, the majority of party members and cadres have further built a solid foundation of faith, replenished spiritual calcium, and stabilized the rudder of thought by deepening theoretical study and accepting ideological baptism. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Form loyalty and character. Adhere to the implementation of the Chairman of the Military Commission Responsibility System as the highest political requirement to abide by and the highest political discipline to maintain, formulate and implement a study and education plan for the Chairman of the Military Commission Responsibility System, compile and distribute the &quot;Study Book for the Chairman of the Military Commission Responsibility System&quot;, and carry out study and education on the Chairman of the Military Commission Responsibility System in different categories, The main leaders gave the &quot;First Lesson&quot;. Party members and cadres understood the contemporary value and practice of the Chairman&#39;s Responsibility System of the Military Commission from the formation and development, connotation and unique advantages of the fundamental system, from the historic achievements and historic changes in the cause of strengthening the military. Weili always listens to Chairman Xi’s instructions, is responsible to Chairman Xi, and reassures Chairman Xi. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Harvest your feelings and take responsibility. Review President Xi&#39;s instructions and instructions, focus on major issues such as comprehensively strengthening party building in the military, comprehensively strengthening military training and preparations, comprehensively strengthening military governance, consolidating and improving the integrated national strategic system and capabilities, and use theoretical learning results to conduct special discussions and study ideas for improving work. Measures, with the urgency of &quot;not worrying at all times&quot; and the mission of handing in papers on time and returning to work as scheduled, strive to open up a new situation in the development of work and career. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;There is a soul in the heart and roots under the feet. Party committees and party members and cadres of units above the military level insist on the unity of learning, thinking and application, and the unity of knowledge, belief and action. They should ideologically rectify and consolidate the roots and cultivate talents, deeply understand the decisive significance of the &quot;two establishments&quot;, strengthen the &quot;four consciousnesses&quot; and strengthen the &quot;four consciousnesses&quot;. &quot;self-confidence&quot;, achieve &quot;two safeguards&quot;, implement the Chairman&#39;s responsibility system of the Military Commission, and ensure that theoretical study is integrated into the brain and heart. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Increase wisdom through learning - mastering and improving abilities&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Whether learning is effective depends on whether it is truly used to transform thoughts, update concepts, and provide guidance practice. Party committees and organs of units above the military level not only dig in to learn deeply, but also jump out to understand thoroughly, absorb the wisdom and strength of forging ahead, and transform it into scientific thinking methods to promote work. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Forge strong political abilities. In April this year, spring was in full bloom at the foot of the Red Mountain. A training class for major generals and above for military (police) officers to study and implement Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era was held as scheduled. Nearly a hundred senior cadres entered the National Defense University as ordinary students, highlighting political training Model participation in learning and training. The party committees of units above the military level rely on party committee theoretical study center group studies and cadre theoretical rotation training to strengthen ideological tempering, hold special democratic life meetings to strengthen political experience, and strengthen practical training in response to complex and severe struggle situations...continue to promote the normalization and institutionalization of political rectification training , and constantly improve political judgment, political understanding, and political execution. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Expand and improve thinking skills. How to promote the construction of new-quality combat forces in new domains, how to improve the effectiveness of military governance, and how to accelerate the transformation and upgrading of military training... Party committees of units above the military level use the worldview and methodology of &quot;six must persists&quot; and the military outlook of &quot;five persistences&quot; Carry out &quot;brainstorming&quot; and methodology to grasp the &quot;golden key&quot; to promote the construction and development of the army. In mid-June, an on-site basic training meeting of the entire army was held in Tianjin to accelerate the innovation of training models, establish the thinking concept that we must strengthen the &quot;chassis&quot; to grasp joint efforts, and promote the transformation and upgrading of basic training. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Strengthen the ability to plan and fight wars. If you want to win the war, you must know how to fight and plan the war. The party committees of units at or above the military level conscientiously implement the spirit of the party-building conference of the entire military, and examine and analyze shortcomings and weaknesses against the &quot;five capabilities&quot; of high-level party committees in preparing for war. Pay attention to making good use of the &quot;living teaching materials&quot; of actual warfare, and find the &quot;interface&quot; to improve the ability to prepare for war while studying the enemy&#39;s strengths, weaknesses, and changes. Refine and harden the party committee leadership’s ability indicators and responsibilities list for war preparation and war, promote the transformation of party committee discussions and training from principle guidance to precise pulse control, and truly make the party committee the “Chinese military account” for war preparation and war. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Facing the &quot;Loushanguan&quot; and &quot;Lazikou&quot; on the new journey, and facing the &quot;stumbling blocks&quot; in various fields and aspects of combat and military equipment, all departments and units have the courage to break the shackles of thinking and concepts and jump out. Under the constraints of rules and regulations, we use the party&#39;s innovative theory to transform the subjective world, enhance our ability to perform duties, guide and promote practice, and truly master the Marxist housekeeping skills. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Correcting the style through learning—seeking truth and being pragmatic and working hard to solve problems&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sit next to each other, chat heartily, and listen to the voices on the front line; establish a &quot;grassroots level&quot; &quot;If there is something to look forward to, the authorities will act quickly&quot; mechanism to promptly solve the &quot;head-scratching problems&quot; of officers and soldiers; from &quot;dissecting a problem&quot; to promoting &quot;solving a type of problem&quot;... one after another, seemingly ordinary little things, reflect the theme The great changes brought about by the pragmatic style of education. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Party committees of units at or above the military level adhere to the combination of goal orientation and problem orientation, and the integration of learning, inspection and reform. They find gaps in the party style requirements, investigate the root causes of the party spirit requirements, and clarify measures in accordance with the party discipline requirements. Changing work style and solving problems run through the entire process of thematic education, follow the party&#39;s mass line, avoid formalism and bureaucracy, and win praise from officers and soldiers with good work style and pragmatic actions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Face the problem head-on and conduct research. Make full use of the five-character formula of &quot;deep, practical, detailed, accurate, and effective&quot; to focus on key issues such as the party committee&#39;s leaders&#39; ability to prepare for war, strengthen war preparation and coordination, and improve the supply level of war personnel. When arriving at the outpost and entering the combat position, we looked at both &quot;high-rise buildings&quot; and &quot;shady alleys&quot;. We carried out extensive squatting, dissecting, and &quot;four-no-two-straight&quot; surveys, organized widespread research and exchanges on survey results, and helped solve a number of urgent needs for war preparations. , urgently needed for war and urgently awaited by officers and soldiers. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Reform hard and hard. Problem rectification and rectification is the key point, but also the difficulty. Methods such as surveys, studies, listening to opinions, analysis of typical cases to find out the root causes and cruxes, and exercises and trainings to review and examine shortcomings are widely used to comprehensively incorporate issues such as education and rectification of cadres, anti-corruption education for military cadres, and rectification and governance in key industries. Comprehensively and systematically investigate the underlying problems, and use a list of problems and a set of special rectification plans to promote rectification. Members of the party committee take the lead in tackling key problems, regularly &quot;posting bills&quot; and &quot;screening&quot;, promoting work implementation in solving each problem, and creating a new situation in army building. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dedicate yourself to solving problems. “Organize activities to warm the hearts of soldiers and relieve their worries”, “Carry out special actions to make full use of policies and stimulate vitality and motivation”, “Smooth regional cooperation channels for family services”... Party committees of units above the military level do their work with warmth and emotion. Help solve real-life problems. A list of practical projects has been generally established to promptly resolve doubts and concerns and respond to the urgent needs and concerns of officers and soldiers. Formulate rigid measures to reduce the &quot;five excesses&quot;, improve the normal mechanism for solving problems and help those in need, make great efforts to solve the difficulties of children&#39;s schooling, housing security, growth and success, and transform the &quot;demand list&quot; into a &quot;happy bill&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The results are obvious to all and the experience is real. Party committees and agencies of units above the military level work hard to solve real problems and to solve real problems. The majority of officers and soldiers can truly feel the pragmatism, integrity and frugality brought by thematic education. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Promoting learning to do things—taking responsibility to promote high-quality development&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The flood will not recede, and we will not recede!”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; During the critical period of &quot;seven down and eight up&quot; flood control, the people&#39;s army resolutely implemented Chairman Xi&#39;s important instructions, acted upon orders, charged forward, bravely shouldered heavy responsibilities, and rushed to the front line of flood control and disaster relief. It interpreted the mission of putting the people first with practical actions. Let the party flag fly high on the front line of flood prevention and disaster relief. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The power of theory can only be exerted through practice; the results of learning must be tested by practical results. Party committees of units at or above the military level adhere to the combination of education and practice, correct the orientation of work, enhance the motivation to work, and form a synergy of work, and transform the radiant loyalty, belief, political enthusiasm, and mission responsibility into truth-seeking, pragmatism, and hard work. of great power. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The smoke billows from the armored assault, the ship formations are sharpened with dark blue swords, and the fighter planes take off and soar into the sky... Training activities such as real-force confrontation exercises, cross-regional base training, mission training, and Chinese and foreign joint exercises and joint training are comprehensive The whole army is full of enthusiasm and enthusiasm to comprehensively strengthen troop training and preparations and accelerate the improvement of its ability to win. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From joint sea and air combat readiness patrols and joint exercises to maritime rights protection and border stability maintenance, the People&#39;s Army has carried out military struggles firmly and flexibly. It has withstood complex situations with firm will and quality, flexible strategies and powerful military operations. and severe struggle tests, the use of military power has achieved new developments and resolutely defended national sovereignty, security, and development interests. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The party committee has worked hard to build the grassroots, carried out help and guidance at different levels and categories to achieve &quot;one key opens a lock&quot;, and organized grassroots party organization secretaries to enter schools and classes to participate in centralized rotation training and regular cadres of leading agencies went to the front line to serve as soldiers in the company to review military conditions and experience the military spirit, and commended the entire army for implementing the goal of building a strong military. Model units and individual models set a typical example, and the entire army took more powerful measures to grasp the situation. Grassroots construction, leveraging grassroots troops to release new vitality. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ideological flag leads the way and we work hard towards the future. The entire army at all levels fully implements Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, deeply implements Xi Jinping Thought on Strengthening the Army, anchors the 100-year goal of the founding of the army, stimulates the spirit, gathers the strength for progress, and achieves the goal of the entire army in the new era. Unprecedented unity and unity under historical conditions, accelerating the improvement of the modernization level of the army, and resolutely completing various tasks assigned by the party and the people. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, September 13)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 推动京津冀协同发展不断迈上新台阶（高质量发展调研行）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/14/nw.D110000renmrb_20230914_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, September 14, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;On the shores of the Bohai Sea, development momentum is surging; in the land of Yanzhao, the east wind is blowing strong. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As one of the three important power sources leading the country’s high-quality development, Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei has significant geographical advantages. The coordinated development of Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei is advancing steadily in a broad time and space dimension; the cadres and masses of the three places are working hard to write a new chapter of high-quality development in the new era. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping has held three symposiums and personally planned, deployed and promoted the coordinated development of Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei to continuously reach new levels. In 2022, the total economic output of Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei will exceed 10 trillion yuan, delivering impressive results. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Practice has proven that the Party Central Committee’s development strategy for major regions such as Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei is in line with my country’s high-quality development needs in the new era and is an effective way to promote Chinese-style modernization.” On May 12 this year, General Secretary Xi Jinping made the final decision at the symposium on further promoting the coordinated development of Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking forward to the new journey, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: “Advance all work with a more energetic and promising spirit, promote the coordinated development of Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei to a new level, and strive to make Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei a Chinese-style A pioneer area and demonstration area for modernization.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Reducing the difference in potential energy and increasing the sum of kinetic energy&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For a period of time, &quot;Beijing cannot afford it and Tianjin cannot afford it. If you don’t have enough to eat, Hebei won’t have enough to eat.” How to break down the barriers of interest and eliminate administrative barriers, so as to truly turn the &quot;difference in potential energy&quot; of the development of Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei into the &quot;sum of kinetic energy&quot;? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In February 2014, General Secretary Xi Jinping presided over a symposium to listen to a special report on the coordinated development of Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei. As a result, the coordinated development of Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei has become a national strategy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Use &quot;sparse&quot; to &quot;advance&quot; and &quot;subtract&quot; to improve &quot;quality&quot;. The coordinated development of Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei has firmly grasped the &quot;narrow nose&quot; of relieving Beijing&#39;s non-capital functions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Today, the once bustling Beijing Zoo Wholesale Market has turned around and is accelerating to become a hub for the integrated development of the financial and technology industries. This change is the epitome of Beijing’s reduced development. Beijing has become the first megacity in the country to reduce development volume, and the functions of the capital have been continuously optimized and improved. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei is like the petals on a flower. The petals are different, but the petals are concentric. Collaborative innovation and industrial collaboration are the key supports and entities for the coordinated development of Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Every Tuesday, I will come back with the R&amp;D plan of the Beijing head office to complete the trial production and mass production of the product in Baodi.” Nan Xiaowei, product director of Tianjin Xinsong Intelligent Technology Co., Ltd. said that in recent years , Xinsong Intelligent moved the production line to Beijing-Tianjin Zhongguancun Science and Technology City, Baodi District, Tianjin. &quot;Beijing&#39;s technological innovation advantages and Tianjin&#39;s advanced manufacturing R&amp;D advantages are closely combined, allowing the company to enter the &#39;fast lane&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;At present, Beijing-Tianjin Zhongguancun Science and Technology City has initially formed four major industrial clusters: new generation information technology, high-end equipment manufacturing, new energy and new materials, biomedicine and medical equipment, and has formed an industrial chain synergy with Beijing Zhongguancun, gradually moving towards major projects in Beijing. The construction and evolution of parts supporting bases. Since the implementation of the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei coordinated development strategy, Tianjin has introduced more than 7,000 investment projects from Beijing enterprises, with funds in place exceeding 1.2 trillion yuan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At Hebei Lansheng Biotechnology Co., Ltd. in Jinzhou City, Hebei Province, staff are conducting remote control through the intelligent central control room. Not far away, the machines in the fully automated production workshop continue to operate, and batches of clethodim technical products are sold abroad from here. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Clethodim is a herbicide with a complex chemical structure and numerous production processes. &quot;Thanks to the in-depth advancement of the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei coordinated development strategy, the company cooperated with the Chinese Academy of Sciences in 2018 to effectively overcome technical problems and achieve continuous production through innovation. Sales revenue in the past three years totaled 1.9 billion yuan.&quot; Yuan Li, general manager of the company Just said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Implement special projects for the transformation of major scientific and technological achievements, accelerate the diffusion of common technological achievements in the industry, and encourage technology transfer institutions to provide services... In recent years, Hebei has taken the initiative to connect with the resources of Beijing and Tianjin, accelerate collaborative innovation, and continuously promote high-quality development . In 2022, Hebei will absorb a total of 40.3 billion yuan in technology contract transactions from Beijing and Tianjin, a year-on-year increase of nearly 14%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the sun and moon advance, the laws of the year are renewed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As collaborative innovation and industrial collaboration continue to accelerate, the flow of technology and capital in the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region has become increasingly frequent, and the exchanges of personnel and resources have become increasingly close. From 2013 to 2022, Beijing&#39;s technology contracts exported to Tianjin and Hebei increased from 3,176 to 5,881, and the transaction volume increased from 7.12 billion yuan to 35.69 billion yuan. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For more than nine years, the clarion call for the coordinated development of Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei has continued to sound, and the power of development has continued to gather. Beijing has gradually shifted from &quot;large and comprehensive&quot; to &quot;high-end, sophisticated&quot;, Tianjin has effectively consolidated &quot;development well&quot; with &quot;attraction&quot;, and Hebei has continued to use &quot;acquisition&quot; to achieve &quot;upgrade jump&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Building a new pattern through coordinated development&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Promoting high-quality development requires a &quot;national game of chess.&quot; It is necessary to plan a domain from the overall perspective and to serve the overall situation with one domain. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Based on an area of ​​216,000 square kilometers, sailing on the vast waves of the Bohai Sea. Whether looking at Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei from the perspective of domestic location or international latitude and longitude, its layout and atmosphere are extremely grand. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei Coordinated Development, as a pioneer and demonstration of regional coordinated development strategies, shoulders the historical mission of serving the construction of a new development pattern.&quot; said Zhang Gui, Secretary-General of the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei Coordinated Development Institute of Nankai University. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the shore of Bohai Bay, the whistle is melodious. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Green&quot; power supplies the landing gear, Beidou navigation and loading and unloading vehicles, and the &quot;Smart Zero Carbon&quot; terminal of Tianjin Port is a busy scene. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since its official operation in October 2021, the world&#39;s first &quot;smart zero-carbon&quot; terminal has handled more than 1.5 million containers, of which more than half of the cargo comes from Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“After the opening of the Bohai Rim branch line, we saved 20% of the cost and greatly improved the competitiveness of our products in the southern market.” said Sun Jian, deputy general manager of Hebei Zhengyuan Hydrogen Energy Technology Co., Ltd. , about 30% of their company&#39;s main products are transferred to Fujian and other places via Tianjin Port. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the &quot;maritime gateway&quot; of Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei, Tianjin Port has continued to make efforts in promoting regional high-quality development and serving to build a new development pattern in recent years. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At present, Tianjin Port has opened container trains to Pinggu, Beijing, built the Tianjin Port Group’s Xiongan New Area Service Center, and opened sea-rail intermodal trains to Xingtai, Gaoyi and other places in Hebei. In the past four years, the transportation volume of Tianjin Port’s Bohai Rim branch line has increased by more than 50% annually on average. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Open the aorta and unblock the microcirculation. With the accelerated formation of the &quot;Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei on Track&quot;, the total mileage of regional operational railways currently reaches 10,933 kilometers, and the 1 to 1.5-hour traffic circle of major cities in the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region has basically been formed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In global coordinates, the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region plays an important role in promoting high-quality development across the country and expanding external circulation.” Zhang Gui said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As an important hub port for the transportation of coal from the west to the east and the transportation of coal from the north to the south, Huanghua Port is connected with the &quot;One Belt and One Road&quot; initiative. The ships plying back and forth reflect not only the vitality of the Chinese market, but also the powerful charm of the “One Belt, One Road” initiative. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In May this year, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized during an inspection tour of the Huanghua Port Coal Port Area: “The port is an important support for economic development. I hope you will further develop scientifically and build Huanghua Port into a strategically important port. A multi-functional, comprehensive and modern port, it will make greater contributions to the coordinated development of Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei, the construction of Xiongan New Area, and the joint construction of the &#39;Belt and Road&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Currently, Huanghua Port has opened domestic and foreign trade routes 35, and joined the World Logistics Passport Plan, with navigation connections with more than 40 countries and regions and more than 200 ports at home and abroad.&quot; said Chu Lijun, deputy general manager of Hebei Cangzhou Port Group. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When the momentum rises, it never falls, and new trends emerge on the shores of the Bohai Bay. Every day at sunrise and sunset, cargo ships loaded with containers leave Huanghua Port and head towards Tianjin Port. From the opening of the &quot;daily sailing&quot; maritime express line between Tianjin Port and Huanghua Port, to more cooperation models and new routes emerging, in recent years, cooperation between the ports of Tianjin and Hebei has continued to advance in depth, and they have jointly created a Tianjin-based It is a world-class port group with Hebei Port as its core and Hebei Port as its two wings. The &quot;Maritime Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei&quot; transportation channel continues to become denser and expanded, like a microcosm, telling the story of Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei coordinated development and in-depth services to build a new development pattern. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Increase people’s well-being and promote common prosperity&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Achieving common prosperity for all people” is the essential requirement for Chinese-style modernization summarized in the report of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China one. Promoting the coordinated development of Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei will ultimately be reflected in improving people&#39;s well-being and promoting common prosperity. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: &quot;As socialism with Chinese characteristics enters a new era, the principal contradiction in our society has transformed into the contradiction between the people&#39;s growing needs for a better life and unbalanced and inadequate development.&quot;&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;The key points of regional coordinated development strategies such as the coordinated development of Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei are to solve the problem of unbalanced and inadequate development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;What to do? &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Maintain the strategic sobriety of &quot;collaboration&quot; and enhance the tactical initiative of &quot;seeking change&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Xiongan, on the west side of the Beijing-Xiongan Expressway, the Comprehensive Service Center in the Startup Zone with a total construction area of ​​approximately 3,332 square meters stands tall and tall. The architectural style of the Han and Tang Dynasties and the efficient and orderly docking work have effectively created Xiongan&#39;s &quot;golden business card&quot; to provide registration, land supply, approval, and construction services to Beijing&#39;s diversion targets. It is the service center&#39;s commitment and actions to make new residents willing to come, live stably, and live well. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Rongdong District, the Human Resources Service Industrial Park welcomes visitors from all directions in the early morning. The hall has specially opened the acceptance authority at the new district level and three counties, which can provide &quot;one-stop&quot; convenient services for enterprises entering the park and employment of talents, and effectively serve the needs of people&#39;s livelihood. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In today’s Xiongan, blueprints are drawn up as construction drawings, and great changes have given rise to new developments. The &quot;four horizontal and ten vertical&quot; backbone road network in the starting area is fully under construction, the underground city is taking shape at an accelerated pace, and &quot;Xiong&#39;an on the Cloud&quot; has been initially completed... A city of the people and a city of happiness based on the &quot;Millennium Plan&quot; is rising from the ground . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the implementation of the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei coordinated development strategy, in accordance with the cooperation agreement, Beijing has continuously promoted the sharing of high-quality basic education resources for primary and secondary schools with Hebei, and actively supported the new Beihai kindergarten in Xiongan New District in a &quot;turnkey&quot; manner. , Shijia Hutong Primary School, Beijing No. 4 Middle School, and Xuanwu Hospital, and continue to deepen cooperation in faculty, discipline construction, and achievement transformation among higher education institutions in the region. It is reported that in September this year, the kindergartens, primary schools, and middle schools in Xiongan New Area built with Beijing&#39;s aid welcomed the first batch of students. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Education is a people’s livelihood project, and it is also a people’s heart project. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I didn’t expect that I could receive such high-quality education in our county.” In Hebei, Xiao Ruizhen, a 2020 automotive operation and maintenance student at Tianjin Vocational University Wei County Branch, said. In 2020, the country&#39;s first cross-provincial and municipal &quot;five-year consistent&quot; talent training model was implemented at Tianjin Vocational University Wei County Branch. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, Tianjin has effectively taken advantage of the national modern vocational education reform and innovation demonstration zone, continuously delivered high-quality educational resources to Hebei, and built professional groups that meet the needs of industrial development in the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We will focus on the urgently needed majors and future industrial development directions in Hebei Province, especially Xiongan New Area, and jointly cultivate more high-quality technical and skilled talents.” said Li Li, director of the Vocational Education Division of the Tianjin Municipal Education Commission. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Support high-quality development with a high-quality ecological environment and accelerate the modernization of harmonious coexistence between man and nature.” On the banks of the Grand Canal in the sub-center of Beijing, the dynamic ecology, the culture immersed in the fragrance of books, and the booming economy all demonstrate the happy and beautiful life of the people in the sub-center of the city. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, three major livelihood construction projects, including the &quot;Cultural Granary&quot; Grand Theater, the &quot;Forest Book Garden&quot; Library, and the &quot;Canal Boat&quot; Museum in the city&#39;s sub-center, have entered the final sprint stage. &quot;Green&quot; building standards and &quot;colorful&quot; cultural heritage facilities continue to add color to the lives of residents in the &quot;prosperous&quot; sub-center. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The protection of ecological civilization, like the coordinated development of Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei, is not a matter of one region, a first-level responsibility, or a temporary achievement. It requires coordinated efforts, top-down efforts, and long-term efforts. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Xiaobazi Township, Fengning Manchu Autonomous County, Hebei, the former sand dunes have become an oasis. As the former source of sand in Beijing and Tianjin, Fengning has actively built a &quot;green barrier&quot; for sand prevention in Beijing and Tianjin in recent years by relying on key ecological projects such as the control of sandstorm sources in Beijing and Tianjin. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Use points to lead the way, and make progress together. High-quality development brings people’s livelihood and well-being. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under the coordinated management of Beijing, Tianjin and Hebei, the average concentration of PM2.5 in the region will drop by more than 63% in 2022 compared with 2013; the area of ​​desertified land in Hebei has decreased by 7.38 million acres compared with the data released in 1999. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Together, we will build &quot;a chain&quot; of industrial cooperation, jointly weave &quot;one network&quot; of internal and external connections, jointly build &quot;one forest&quot; of green protection, and jointly draw &quot;one picture&quot; of people&#39;s livelihood protection...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;Changes that flow deep in still waters often lie deep in the mighty rivers of the times. From planning coordinated development, to leading high-quality development, to demonstrating the construction of Chinese-style modernization, the advancing Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region is drawing a new picture of the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Our reporters Wang Haonan, Li Jiading, and Shao Yuzi participated in the reporting)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 赵乐际同阿联酋联邦国民议会议长萨格尔举行会谈]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/14/nw.D110000renmrb_20230914_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, September 14, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, September 13th&amp;nbsp; The church held talks with Al-Saqr, Speaker of the Federal National Assembly of the United Arab Emirates. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Zhao Leji said that under the strategic guidance of President Xi Jinping and President Mohammed, China-Arab political mutual trust has been continuously consolidated, pragmatic cooperation has continued to expand, people-to-people friendship has been further deepened, and bilateral relations have entered a new era of comprehensive, rapid and in-depth development. stage. Currently, the Chinese people are comprehensively promoting the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation through Chinese-style modernization, and the people of the UAE are making strides towards the goals set by the &quot;Our UAE 2031&quot; vision. China is willing to work with Afghanistan to push China-Afghanistan relations to a higher level and better benefit the two peoples. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Zhao Leji said that as a good friend, good partner, and good brother, China is willing to work with Afghanistan to jointly grasp the general direction of friendship between the two countries, intensify exchanges at all levels, and consolidate strategic mutual trust. Thanks to Afghanistan for its long-term and firm support on issues involving China&#39;s core interests and major concerns. We hope to deepen practical cooperation, steadily advance cooperation in traditional fields such as energy, investment, and infrastructure, and tap the potential for cooperation in emerging fields such as information technology. China and Arab countries share the same cultural spirit and hope to strengthen cooperation in culture, tourism, civil aviation and other fields to consolidate the public opinion foundation for China-Arab friendship. Congratulations to the UAE for becoming a member of the BRICS family. China supports Afghanistan in playing a greater role in international and regional affairs, and is willing to work with Afghanistan to practice true multilateralism and promote international fairness and justice. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Zhao Leji introduced the global development initiative, global security initiative and global civilization initiative proposed by President Xi Jinping, emphasizing that China is willing to work with Afghanistan to promote cooperation in the three major global initiatives and inject more positive energy into the turbulent world . &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Zhao Leji emphasized that exchanges between the legislative bodies of China and Afghanistan are an important part of the comprehensive strategic partnership between the two countries.中国全国人大愿继续加强同阿联酋联邦国民议会的友好合作，促进各层级友好交往，深化在依法治国、发展经济、改善民生等方面的经验交流，为共建“一带一路”及各领域务实合作提供法律保障，密切在各国议会联盟、亚洲议会大会等多边场合的协调配合。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;萨格尔表示，中国是值得信任的伙伴和朋友。阿联酋高兴地看到中国取得巨大发展成就。中国的发展将为世界其他国家带来更多机遇。明年是阿中建交40周年。阿联邦国民议会愿加强同中国全国人大的合作，深化立法等领域交流互鉴，为促进两国全面战略伙伴关系发展作出贡献。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;何维参加会谈。 &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 蔡奇会见越共中央政治局委员、越南公安部部长苏林]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/14/nw.D110000renmrb_20230914_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月14日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报北京9月13日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者王海林）中共中央政治局常委、中央书记处书记蔡奇13日在京会见越共中央政治局委员、越南公安部部长苏林。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;蔡奇表示，中越都是共产党领导的社会主义国家，具有共同理想信念和价值追求，我们愿同越方一道，共同落实两党最高领导人达成的重要共识，秉持“十六字”方针和“四好”精神，巩固传统友谊、加强战略沟通、增进政治互信、妥善管控分歧，推动新时代中越全面战略合作伙伴关系不断迈上新台阶。中越两国公安部要加强政治安全合作，联合严打跨国犯罪，深化网络安全合作，统筹好发展和安全，努力服务构建具有战略意义的中越命运共同体。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;苏林积极评价越中两党两国关系，表示愿与中方共同努力，不断加强越中各领域务实合作。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;中共中央书记处书记、公安部部长王小洪参加会见。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 丁薛祥在香港第八届“一带一路”高峰论坛开幕式上发表主旨演讲]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/14/nw.D110000renmrb_20230914_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月14日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;新华社北京9月13日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;中共中央政治局常委、国务院副总理丁薛祥13日以视频方式出席香港第八届“一带一路”高峰论坛开幕式，发表主旨演讲。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;丁薛祥指出，2013年秋天，习近平主席提出共建“一带一路”倡议。十年来，中国秉持共商共建共享原则，坚持开放、绿色、廉洁理念，努力实现高标准、可持续、惠民生目标，共建“一带一路”取得了丰硕成果。共建“一带一路”引领中国更高水平对外开放，促进各国共同发展共同繁荣，为构建人类命运共同体贡献了中国智慧、中国方案、中国力量，成为深受欢迎的国际公共产品和国际合作平台。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;丁薛祥表示，中央支持香港长期保持独特地位和优势，巩固国际金融、航运、贸易中心地位，维护自由开放规范的营商环境，保持普通法制度，拓展畅通便捷的国际联系，在共建“一带一路”中发挥更为重要的功能。希望香港深化区域合作，拓展经贸网络，与世界各地开展更加紧密的交流合作；完善金融服务，畅通融资渠道，更好满足“一带一路”建设多样化融资需求；聚焦专业服务，发挥人才优势，促进提升“一带一路”规则标准“软联通”水平；深化人文交流，促进民心相通，夯实共建“一带一路”民意基础。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;香港“一带一路”高峰论坛由香港特别行政区政府、香港贸易发展局共同主办，本届论坛的主题是“携手十载&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;共建共赢”。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 韩正会见阿联酋联邦国民议会议长]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/14/nw.D110000renmrb_20230914_7-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月14日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;新华社北京9月13日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;国家副主席韩正13日在京会见阿联酋联邦国民议会议长萨格尔。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;韩正表示，在习近平主席和穆罕默德总统战略引领下，中阿关系不断走深走实。中方愿同阿方一道，将两国元首重要共识落到实处，加强高层交往、增强战略互信，相互坚定支持、巩固政治友好，拓展务实合作、密切人文交流，促进集体合作、加强多边协作，不断丰富中阿全面战略伙伴关系内涵。祝贺阿联酋成为金砖大家庭成员。中方愿在推进中国式现代化进程中同阿方分享发展机遇，实现互利共赢。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;萨格尔表示，不断巩固阿中全面战略伙伴关系，是阿联酋坚定不移的政治意愿。感谢中国支持阿联酋加入金砖国家合作机制。明年是阿中建交40周年，愿不断增进双方在经贸、投资、立法、人文等各领域合作。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 中华人民共和国和委内瑞拉玻利瓦尔共和国关于建立全天候战略伙伴关系的联合声明]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/14/nw.D110000renmrb_20230914_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月14日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;一、应中华人民共和国主席习近平邀请，委内瑞拉玻利瓦尔共和国总统尼古拉斯·马杜罗·莫罗斯于2023年9月8日至14日对中华人民共和国第三次进行国事访问。访问期间，两国元首在热烈友好的气氛中举行会谈，就中委关系、两国各领域合作以及共同关心的国际和地区问题交换意见，达成广泛共识。中华人民共和国国务院总理李强、全国人民代表大会常务委员会委员长赵乐际分别同马杜罗总统会见。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;二、双方一致认为，自1974年6月28日建立外交关系以来，特别是自2014年7月21日两国建立全面战略伙伴关系以来，无论国际风云如何变幻，中委关系始终不惧风浪、坚如磐石，双边各领域合作取得丰硕成果。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;三、基于提升双边关系水平、进一步深化两国各领域合作的共同意愿，并考虑到当前国际和地区形势的深刻变化，双方一致决定将中委关系提升为全天候战略伙伴关系，进一步发挥元首外交的政治引领作用，拓展两国各领域务实合作，加强国际事务战略协作，增进两国人民福祉，共同推动构建人类命运共同体。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;四、委方再次热烈祝贺中国共产党第二十次全国代表大会和全国两会胜利召开，热烈祝贺习近平主席再次当选中国共产党中央委员会总书记和中华人民共和国主席，高度评价新时代十年中国取得的伟大成就，认为中国式现代化为人类实现现代化提供了新的选择。坚信在习近平总书记领导下，中国共产党和中国人民将在新时代中国特色社会主义事业中不断取得新的伟大成就。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;五、中方再次热烈祝贺委内瑞拉统一社会主义党第五次全国代表大会胜利召开，热烈祝贺马杜罗总统再次当选委统社党主席。尊重委内瑞拉人民选择符合本国国情的发展道路，支持委内瑞拉政府和人民为维护国家稳定、发展与和平所作的努力。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;六、中国和委内瑞拉是相互信赖的好朋友、共同发展的好伙伴、战略协作的好战友。双方重申在彼此核心利益问题上坚定相互支持。中方坚定支持委方，在解放者西蒙·玻利瓦尔遗志指引下，维护国家独立、主权、民族尊严、社会经济稳定和自决权。委方重申恪守一个中国原则的坚定立场，承认中华人民共和国政府是代表全中国的唯一合法政府，台湾是中国领土不可分割的一部分，坚定支持中国政府为实现国家统一所作的一切努力。双方一致同意坚决反对任何外部势力以任何借口干预本国内政，反对任何势力借台湾、涉港、涉疆、涉藏、南海、人权等问题干涉中国内政。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;七、双方认为有必要共同努力维护和平、发展、公平、正义、民主、自由的全人类共同价值，并承诺继续一道努力维护以国际法和国际关系基本准则为基础的国际秩序、以联合国和其宪章宗旨和原则为核心的国际体系，反对一切形式的霸权主义和强权政治，反对一切形式的单边主义，反对搞针对特定国家的阵营化和排他性小圈子。委方感谢中方参与“捍卫《联合国宪章》之友小组”，并承诺将继续与中方一道，致力于构建新型国际关系，深化拓展平等、开放、合作的全球伙伴关系，共同促进世界和平与发展，巩固多中心、多极化世界，携手推动构建人类命运共同体。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;八、委方热烈欢迎并坚定支持习近平主席提出的共建“一带一路”倡议。双方忆及在2018年9月签署的共建“一带一路”谅解备忘录，高度评价两国在共建“一带一路”框架下取得的丰硕成果，愿持续深化共建“一带一路”合作。双方愿在签署《中华人民共和国国家发展和改革委员会与委内瑞拉玻利瓦尔共和国经济财政和外贸部关于共同加快编制共建“一带一路”合作规划的谅解备忘录》的基础上，加快签署中委共建“一带一路”合作规划文件。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;九、委方高度赞赏并支持习近平主席提出的全球发展倡议、全球安全倡议、全球文明倡议。中方赞赏委方率先加入“全球发展倡议之友小组”。双方同意进一步加强在全球发展倡议、全球安全倡议、全球文明倡议框架内的合作，以实现更强大、更持续、更平衡的全球发展。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;十、双方一致认为，当前，世界之变、时代之变、历史之变正以前所未有的方式展开。中委同为发展中国家，在国际事务中拥有广泛共同利益和相近立场主张。双方积极评价两国在国际组织和多边机制中的战略协作，将在国际事务中继续坚定相互支持。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;十一、委方重申对加入金砖国家的兴趣，委作为可靠能源供应国、世界上最大石油和第四大天然气储量国，可为该机制能源议程作出重要贡献。中方欢迎委方加入金砖国家的积极意愿，支持委方为实现这一目标所作努力。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;十二、委方高度赞赏中方为支持全球南方国家发展、促进世界经济增长、创造经济治理新实践所作努力，愿加入新开发银行等金融机构和融资合作倡议。同样，委方也将继续支持人民币国际化。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;十三、双方一致认为，必须从本国实际出发，探索符合人民需求的民主和人权发展道路。反对任何国家滥用民主价值，借口维护民主、人权干涉主权国家内政，挑动世界分裂对抗，反对将人权问题政治化、工具化和双重标准，反对将自身意志和标准强加于别国。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;十四、非法强制单边制裁严重违反国家主权平等、不干涉内政等国际法基本原则，严重损害了委内瑞拉人民的生存权、发展权与和平权。中方坚定支持委内瑞拉人民捍卫国家主权、反对外部制裁的正义斗争，反对个别国家以任何借口对委实施非法强制单边制裁和所谓“长臂管辖”，反对任何政治霸凌行径，反对军事干涉或以武力相威胁。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;十五、双方一致认为，对话谈判是解决乌克兰危机的唯一可行出路，一切有利于和平解决危机的努力都应得到鼓励和支持。委方高度赞赏并坚定支持中方有关提议。双方呼吁更多国家为推动乌克兰危机政治解决发挥建设性作用。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;十六、双方高度评价于2023年9月13日召开的中国—委内瑞拉高级混合委员会第十七次会议。一致同意继续发挥高委会规划、指导、落实两国合作的机制性作用，深化双边各领域务实合作。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;十七、双方将继续推进和深化在能源、金融、经贸、投资、矿业、农业、基础设施、通信、数字经济等领域合作，坚持互利友好，造福两国人民。双方欢迎两国有关部门签署《关于进一步加强经济发展领域交流合作的谅解备忘录》、《关于促进产业投资与合作的谅解备忘录》、《关于开展可持续发展合作的谅解备忘录》、《关于加强数字经济合作的谅解备忘录》。委方高度评价中方在经济特区建设和脱贫攻坚等方面取得的巨大成就，中方愿支持委方经济特区建设。中方赞赏委方积极参与进博会、广交会和服贸会，支持委方企业更多参加在华举行的经贸展会。双方同意进一步发展双边贸易，丰富贸易商品种类。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;十八、经过共同努力，中委双方已完成《相互促进和保护投资协定》谈判。双方同意尽快完成协定签署和生效工作，尽早惠及双方投资者。委方重申欢迎中国企业和投资者扩大对委投资，充分发挥现有法律框架有利条件。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;十九、双方同意深化两国立法机构及下设各专门委员会、友好小组之间交往与合作，进一步加强立法和治国理政经验交流。同意加强两国地方交流合作，进一步深化业已建立的友好省州关系。同意推动更多地方省市发展友好关系。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;二十、双方同意进一步加强文化、教育交流，推动两国主流媒体和教育机构交流与合作，密切中委社会和文化联系。同意进一步为委来华留学生提供便利，欢迎两国有关部门续签教育交流执行计划，同意进一步便利两国人员往来、中文教育在委发展、扩大旅游交流。委方赞赏中方将委内瑞拉列入恢复出境团队旅游国家名单。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;二十一、双方忆及在“委星一号”通信卫星、“委遥一号”和“委遥二号”遥感卫星项目中取得的成就，同意进一步深化航天领域合作，在联合国外空委等平台加强协调，促进公正、合理的外空全球治理。中方欢迎委方加入国际月球科研站合作，双方高度赞赏关于航天领域合作的框架协定的签署，愿通力协作，共同推动通信和遥感卫星、月球与深空探测等领域合作项目进展，促进两国航天能力提升和国民经济发展。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;二十二、双方同意进一步加强航空领域合作，欢迎两国有关部门签署航空运输协定，鼓励两国航空公司根据市场原则适时开辟中委航线航班。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;二十三、双方注意到关于气候变化的共同关切，将根据共同但有区别的责任原则，推动《联合国气候变化框架公约》及其《巴黎协定》的全面有效实施，同意推动环保合作，应对气候变化和生物多样性流失。中方将加快推进援委水资源保护物资项目。双方欢迎亚马孙合作条约组织成员，以基于科学技术和保护该地区居民福祉为核心出发，制定保护亚马孙和该地区可持续发展的共同政策所作持续努力。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;二十四、委方衷心感谢中方在新冠疫情时期向委方提供的抗疫支持。中国疫苗、医疗物资和中方医疗队在委抗击新冠疫情中发挥了关键作用，为数百万委民众的生命得到拯救作出重要贡献。双方同意通过分享经验和技术，促进两国卫生健康合作。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;二十五、双方一致认为，数据安全攸关各国安全与经济社会发展，委方积极评价中方提出的《全球数据安全倡议》，愿推动制定全球数字治理规则。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;二十六、双方高度评价中拉论坛对推进中拉关系的重要作用。双方愿就中拉论坛事务加强沟通和协调，推动平等、互利、创新、开放、惠民的新时代中拉关系行稳致远。中方高度评价委方在拉美和加勒比地区事务以及促进中拉合作持续发展中所发挥的积极作用。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;二十七、双方支持拉美和加勒比地区为无核区，反对日本核污染水排海。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;二十八、双方一致同意举办系列活动，庆祝2024年中委建交50周年。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;二十九、两国元首对双方在此访期间签署的一系列成果文件表示满意。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;三十、双方认为，马杜罗总统此访取得圆满成功，对深化中委全天候战略伙伴关系、推动新时代中拉命运共同体具有重大意义。马杜罗总统衷心感谢习近平主席以及中国政府和人民在访问期间给予的热情友好接待，欢迎习近平主席适时对委进行国事访问。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;（新华社北京9月13日电）&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - “看到一条通往现代化的新道路”（外国政党政要和友好人士看中国式现代化）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/14/nw.D110000renmrb_20230914_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月14日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;“中国式现代化既植根于中华优秀传统文化，又具有突出的创新性，展现出传统与创新的有机结合。”尼泊尔共产党（联合社会主义）副总书记贾甘纳特·卡蒂瓦达在接受本报记者采访时表示，中国式现代化取得令人瞩目的理论和实践成就，必将深刻影响世界。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;卡蒂瓦达曾于2018年访问中国，走访了北京、天津、安徽等地。中国经济的快速发展、人民的热情好客、基础设施的先进完备，给他留下深刻印象。此后，卡蒂瓦达开始密切关注中国，并从中国的发展经验中深受启发：中国全面消除绝对贫困，实实在在提升了人民的生活水平；中国实现产业转型升级和现代科学技术快速发展，成为世界经济的稳定器、动力源；中国在反腐方面取得的成绩也值得学习借鉴。“取得这些成就的关键，在于中国共产党领导中国人民在五千多年中华文明深厚基础上开辟和发展中国特色社会主义，把马克思主义基本原理同中国具体实际、同中华优秀传统文化相结合。”卡蒂瓦达说。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;当前，尼泊尔仍有18.7%的人口生活在贫困线以下。“我们希望学习中国的脱贫经验。”卡蒂瓦达表示，尼泊尔已将消除贫困作为最优先事项，并推出一系列举措，如为贫困人口提供技能培训，以更公平地获得资源和就业机会等。“尼泊尔期待在减贫方面加强同中国交流与合作，让我们的减贫努力产生更好效果。”&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;在卡蒂瓦达看来，中国对现代化道路的探索实践具有深远的世界意义。“中国致力于走和平发展道路的现代化，为推动构建人类命运共同体不懈努力。”他说，中国推动国际贸易格局向多极化发展，坚定支持经济全球化和维护真正的多边主义，有效对冲了一些国家掀起的单边主义和保护主义逆潮。中国推动成立新开发银行、亚洲基础设施投资银行，有力增强了全球治理体系的代表性与民主性，为发展中国家特别是欠发达国家提供更多支持。“中国式现代化的成功实践，让各国民众看到一条通往现代化的新道路。”卡蒂瓦达感叹道，“广大发展中国家更是看到新希望，有了新选择。”&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;卡蒂瓦达深入研究中国提出的各项重大理念倡议，希望从中学习中国智慧。在他看来，全球发展倡议具有鲜明的中国经验底色，为全世界提出了新的发展理念；全球安全倡议主张通过对话协商化解国家间分歧矛盾，为国际和地区热点问题提供了更安全、更和平的解决方案；全球文明倡议倡导尊重世界文明多样性，推动文明交流互鉴，促进人类文明发展进步。“这些倡议展现了中国共产党的高瞻远瞩和天下情怀，体现了以人民为中心的发展思想，有利于引领世界朝着正确方向前进，对我们很有启发——人类作为命运共同体，应该为了共同的利益，通过共同行动应对共同面临的挑战。”卡蒂瓦达说。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;尼泊尔与中国山水相连。近年来，参与共建“一带一路”倡议为尼泊尔带来了实实在在的发展成果。今年年初，中方援建的尼泊尔博克拉国际机场正式投入使用，这是两国政府深化务实合作的重点项目。几十年前，中国援建的公路将博克拉与加德满都连接起来；如今，随着新机场投运，博克拉成为尼泊尔与众多国家联通的中心。空中交通设施的进一步完善，大大便利了尼泊尔对外经贸发展和人文交流合作，促进了当地旅游业发展。卡蒂瓦达相信，未来尼中双方还将不断推动更多惠及民生的合作项目落地开花。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;卡蒂瓦达认为，当今世界，多极化成为不可阻挡的时代潮流，而中国是世界多极化进程中的重要力量。“中国14亿多人口整体迈向现代化，这将重绘现代化的世界版图。”卡蒂瓦达相信，沿着中国式现代化道路，中国将更加繁荣富强，人民生活更加幸福安康，中国也将以自身发展更好造福世界。“尼泊尔共产党（联合社会主义）将坚持对马克思主义的信仰、对社会主义和共产主义的信念，努力走出一条适合自身特点的发展道路。”&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 中越公安部第八次合作打击犯罪部长级会议举行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/14/nw.D110000renmrb_20230914_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月14日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报北京9月13日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者张天培）中越公安部第八次合作打击犯罪部长级会议13日在京举行，中共中央书记处书记、公安部部长王小洪与越共中央政治局委员、越南公安部部长苏林共同主持。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;王小洪指出，习近平总书记与阮富仲总书记共同为新时代中越全面战略合作伙伴关系擘画了宏伟蓝图，为双方各领域合作提供了重要政治遵循。第七次会议以来，中越公安部在维护政治安全、追逃追赃、打击人口拐卖等多个领域亮点频现，圆满完成了各项重点合作任务。中方愿与越方共同落实两党最高领导人达成的重要共识，深化政治安全、网络安全合作，推进各层级交流合作，加强打击犯罪务实合作，强化多边框架下协调配合，提升执法能力建设水平，努力服务构建具有战略意义的中越命运共同体，为两国和本地区安全稳定作出新的更大贡献。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;苏林表示，越方愿加强两国执法高层交往，深化各领域执法合作，为各自国家发展营造安全稳定的社会环境。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;王小洪与苏林共同签署了中越打击跨境赌博合作谅解备忘录。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 赞比亚总统希奇莱马]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/14/nw.D110000renmrb_20230914_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月14日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20230914/1694636814702_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;希奇莱马总统&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;应国家主席习近平邀请，赞比亚共和国总统哈凯恩德·希奇莱马于9月10日至16日对中国进行国事访问。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;哈凯恩德·希奇莱马，男，61岁。2021年起担任赞比亚共和国总统。此次访问是希奇莱马总统就任以来首次访华。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;（新华社北京9月13日电）&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 14 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>