<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平出席亚太经合组织领导人同东道主嘉宾非正式对话会暨工作午宴]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/18/nw.D110000renmrb_20231118_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, November 18, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/18/01/rmrb2023111801p15_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;November 16, local time At noon, President Xi Jinping attended the informal dialogue and working luncheon between APEC leaders and host guests in San Francisco. &lt;BR/>;Photographed by Xinhua News Agency reporter Xie Huanchi&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Our newspaper, San Francisco, November 16 &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Jiang Yun, Mou Zongcong) At noon on November 16, local time, President Xi Jinping attended the informal dialogue and working luncheon between APEC leaders and host guests in San Francisco. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that sustainable development is the &quot;golden key&quot; to solve current global problems. In recent years, APEC has deeply implemented the Putrajaya Vision 2040 and vigorously implemented the &quot;Bangkok Goals for a Bio-Circular Green Economy&quot; to make positive contributions to global green and sustainable growth. Under the current circumstances, we must further build consensus, focus on action, and inject greater impetus into the cause of global sustainable development. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;First, accelerate the implementation of the United Nations 2030 Agenda for Sustainable Development. Put development firmly at the center of the global agenda and build a political consensus that everyone values ​​development and all countries seek cooperation. China has proposed a global development initiative and made active efforts to promote the international community to form synergy and solve the development deficit. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The second is to create a new path for green development transformation. Promote the transformation and upgrading of energy, industry, and transportation structures, coordinate the promotion of carbon reduction, pollution reduction, green expansion, and growth, coordinate the promotion of fair transformation of the labor force and high-quality employment, and build a global home where the economy and the environment advance in synergy. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The third is to gather global joint efforts to deal with climate change. Maintain the status of the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change as the main channel in global climate governance, adhere to the principle of common but differentiated responsibilities, and scientifically formulate climate goals based on their respective national conditions. Address the concerns of developing countries in terms of funding, capacity building and technology transfer, and promote the comprehensive and effective implementation of the Convention and the Paris Agreement. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that China will thoroughly implement the new development concept, promote the comprehensive green and low-carbon transformation of the economy and society, and continue to make China&#39;s contribution to the joint construction of a global home where man and nature coexist harmoniously. China promotes the green Belt and Road Initiative and will continue to deepen cooperation in green infrastructure, green energy, green transportation and other fields, and support developing countries in improving their capacity building through special funds for South-South cooperation in addressing climate change. China is willing to work together with all parties to make greater contributions to building a global development community and creating a clean and beautiful world! &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The meeting was hosted by US President Biden and the topic was &quot;Sustainable, Climate and Just Energy Transformation.&quot; &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Wang Yi attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平向亚太经合组织工商领导人峰会发表书面演讲]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/18/nw.D110000renmrb_20231118_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, November 18, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Our newspaper, San Francisco, November 16th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Chen Yiming and Shi Yuanhao) Local time on November 16th On the morning of the same day, President Xi Jinping delivered a written speech entitled &quot;Work together to meet challenges and write a new chapter in Asia-Pacific cooperation&quot; to the APEC Business Leaders Summit held in San Francisco. (See the second page for the full text of the speech)&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that 30 years ago, leaders of the Asia-Pacific region followed the trend of peace and development and held the first APEC Leaders’ Informal Meeting to promote the development and economy of the Asia-Pacific. Globalization has entered the fast lane, helping the Asia-Pacific become the center of world economic growth and the anchor of global development and stability. Over the past 30 years, we have adhered to open regionalism, openness and inclusiveness, learning from each other&#39;s strengths, sharing what we have, and focusing on development. We have created the &quot;APEC approach&quot; that is independent, voluntary, consensus-based, and step-by-step. The extraordinary journey of Asia-Pacific cooperation has given us many profound revelations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that the world has entered a new period of turbulence and change, and where Asia-Pacific cooperation will go in the next 30 years has become a question of the new era we are facing. We must uphold the original intention of APEC and promote Asia-Pacific cooperation to start again. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;We must jointly uphold the purposes and principles of the United Nations Charter, adhere to the way of country-to-country interaction of dialogue rather than confrontation, partnership rather than alliance, and maintain prosperity and stability in the Asia-Pacific. The Asia-Pacific cannot and should not be reduced to a battlefield of geopolitical games, let alone engage in a &quot;new cold war&quot; and camp confrontation. We must adhere to open regionalism, unswervingly advance the process of the Asia-Pacific Free Trade Area, promote economic interconnection and integration of various countries, and create an open Asia-Pacific economy with win-win cooperation. We must promote digital, intelligent, and green transformation and development, strengthen technological innovation and achievement transformation, promote the deep integration of the digital economy and the real economy, work together to improve global science and technology governance, and create an open, fair, just, and non-discriminatory science and technology development environment. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that since the beginning of this year, China&#39;s economy has continued to rebound and has made solid progress in high-quality development. China is still the largest engine of global growth. China has the institutional advantages of a socialist market economy and the demand advantages of a super-large market. , the supply advantage of a complete industrial system, the talent advantage of a large number of high-quality workers and entrepreneurs, and the economic development has strong endogenous power, resilience and potential. The fundamentals of China&#39;s long-term economic growth have not changed and will not change. We are confident and more capable of achieving long-term and stable development, and continue to bring new impetus and new opportunities to the world with China&#39;s new development. China insists on opening its doors for construction, unswervingly promotes high-level opening up to the outside world, and its determination to create a market-oriented, legal and international business environment will not change. China&#39;s policy of providing high-quality services to foreign investors without discrimination will not change. The starting point and goal of Chinese-style modernization is to enable more than 1.4 billion Chinese people to live a better life. This means a broader market and unprecedented cooperation opportunities for the world, and will also inject strong impetus into world modernization. We welcome the global business community to actively participate in the Chinese-style modernization process and share the huge opportunities brought by China&#39;s high-quality development! &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平会见墨西哥总统洛佩斯]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/18/nw.D110000renmrb_20231118_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, November 18, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231118/1700257449802_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the morning of November 16, local time, President Xi Jinping Xi Jinping met with Mexican President Lopez in San Francisco. &lt;BR/>;Photographed by Xinhua News Agency reporter Rao Aimin&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Our newspaper, San Francisco, November 16th&amp;nbsp ;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Ren Yan, Zhang Mengxu) On the morning of November 16, local time, President Xi Jinping met with Mexican President Lopez in San Francisco. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that the friendship between China and Mexico has gone through ups and downs and has become stronger with time. Last year, the two countries solemnly celebrated the 50th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations, and this year they celebrated the 10th anniversary of the establishment of a comprehensive strategic partnership. At present, the strategic nature, complementarity and mutual benefit of China-Mexico relations are constantly highlighted, and mutual understanding and support have become stronger on issues involving each other&#39;s core interests and major concerns. China attaches great importance to China-Mexico relations and is willing to work with Mexico to strengthen strategic alignment, tap cooperation potential, leverage complementary advantages, and push bilateral relations to a new level. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that China supports Mexico in independently pursuing a development path in line with its national conditions and is willing to strengthen exchanges with Mexico on state governance. The bilateral trade volume between China and Mexico has increased by more than 7,000 times compared with the time when diplomatic relations were established, and there are many highlights in cooperation in the fields of railways, automobiles, new energy, etc. The two sides should make good use of the inter-governmental working mechanism between the two countries, deepen cooperation in traditional areas such as infrastructure construction, expand cooperation in emerging industries such as finance and electric vehicles, and deepen cooperation in anti-drug law enforcement. Both sides should actively support each other in organizing cultural performances, cultural exhibitions and other people-to-people and cultural exchange activities, intensify multilateral collaboration, firmly safeguard multilateralism and the democratization of international relations, and safeguard international fairness and justice and the legitimate rights and interests of developing countries. Next year marks the 10th anniversary of the establishment of the China-CELAC Forum. China is willing to work with Mexico to promote the stability and long-term development of China-Latin America relations in the new era. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping also once again expressed condolences for the recent hurricane disaster on the Pacific coast of Mexico, saying that China will provide strong assistance to Mexico in purchasing disaster relief materials. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;López said that both Mexico and China have splendid civilizations, and the people of the two countries know each other and love each other like brothers. When the COVID-19 epidemic was at its worst, China was the first to come to the aid and provided a large amount of valuable anti-epidemic materials to Mexico, helping Mexico tide over the difficulties. After Mexico suffered a severe hurricane disaster in the Pacific Ocean recently, China immediately expressed condolences and support, and Mexico expressed its gratitude for this. Mexico and China both safeguard their independence and resolutely oppose interference in other countries&#39; internal affairs. Mexico will, as always, adhere to friendly policies towards China, firmly support each other, facilitate investment and cooperation by Chinese companies in Mexico, deepen mutually beneficial cooperation in various fields, and deepen cooperation in combating drug production and trafficking. Mexico is willing to collaborate closely with China in multilateral affairs and actively promote Latin America-China relations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cai Qi, Wang Yi and others attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平会见秘鲁总统博鲁阿尔特]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/18/nw.D110000renmrb_20231118_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, November 18, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231118/1700257491890_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the morning of November 16, local time, President Xi Jinping Xi Jinping met with Peruvian President Boruarte in San Francisco. &lt;BR/>;Photographed by Xinhua News Agency reporter Ding Lin&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Our newspaper, San Francisco, November 16th&amp;nbsp ;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Zhang Penghui, Zhang Bolan) On the morning of November 16, local time, President Xi Jinping met with Peruvian President Boruarte in San Francisco. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that since the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and Peru more than half a century ago, the two countries have understood and supported each other on issues involving each other&#39;s core interests and major concerns, and bilateral cooperation has developed steadily, especially in the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. It has promoted the development and revitalization of their respective countries and brought benefits to the people of the two countries. This year marks the 10th anniversary of the establishment of a comprehensive strategic partnership between China and Peru. Both sides should deepen political mutual trust, strengthen strategic communication, firmly support each other in taking a development path that suits their national conditions, strengthen the docking of development strategies, strengthen cooperation in traditional fields such as economy, trade, energy and minerals, cultivate new growth poles of cooperation in digital economy, green development and other areas, and promote The joint construction of the “Belt and Road” will achieve more results. China is willing to import more high-quality agricultural products with Peruvian characteristics and encourages Chinese enterprises to participate in the construction of major Peruvian projects in accordance with market-oriented principles. China and Peru both have splendid civilizations and profound cultures. The two sides should strengthen cooperation in education, culture, tourism, science and technology, youth exchanges and other areas, and become an example of exchanges and mutual learning between different civilizations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that under the new situation, developing China-Peru relations well not only conforms to the common interests of the two countries, but is also of great significance to building an open world economy. China supports Peru in hosting the 2024 APEC Economic Leaders&#39; Meeting and is willing to communicate closely and coordinate with Peru to promote new results in APEC cooperation and make new contributions to promoting economic recovery and long-term development in the Asia-Pacific region and promoting the building of an Asia-Pacific community with a shared future. China is willing to work with Peru to promote the continuous development of China-Latin America relations in the new era. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Boruarte said that both Peru and China are countries with ancient civilizations and have a long history of friendly exchanges between their peoples. Since the two countries established a comprehensive strategic partnership 10 years ago, the two sides have adhered to mutual respect and support. Peru is committed to deepening relations with China and hopes to better leverage the cooperation mechanism between the two countries, continuously improve the level of comprehensive strategic cooperation, and deepen practical cooperation in green economy and other fields. Secret recipe adheres to the one-China principle and actively participates in the joint construction of the “Belt and Road”. Peru will take over the rotating chairmanship of APEC next year and looks forward to working with China to promote inclusive and sustainable growth in the Asia-Pacific region and promote the development of Latin America-China relations. Peru is willing to strengthen multilateral cooperation with China. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cai Qi, Wang Yi and others attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平会见文莱苏丹哈桑纳尔]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/18/nw.D110000renmrb_20231118_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, November 18, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231118/1700257484873_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of November 16, local time, President Xi Jinping Xi Jinping met with Brunei Sultan Hassanal in San Francisco. &lt;BR/>;Photographed by Xinhua News Agency reporter Yao Dawei&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Our newspaper, San Francisco, November 16th&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;(Reporters Ren Yan, Wang Xiangyu) On the afternoon of November 16, local time, President Xi Jinping met with Brunei Sultan Hassanal in San Francisco. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that China and Brunei are friendly neighbors across the sea and good partners who trust and support each other. Over the past 30 years since the establishment of diplomatic relations, the two countries have continuously deepened political mutual trust, actively aligned development strategies, achieved fruitful results in practical cooperation in various fields, and maintained good cooperation in international and regional affairs. They have set an example of equal treatment, mutual benefit and win-win between large and small countries, and have set a good example for both countries. It has made positive contributions to regional peace, stability, development and prosperity. This year marks the fifth anniversary of the establishment of strategic partnership between China and Brunei. China is willing to work with Brunei to jointly build the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; with high quality, promote the continuous new development of bilateral relations, and bring more benefits to the people of the two countries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping emphasized that China supports Brunei in taking a development path that suits its own national conditions, welcomes Brunei to expand exports of high-quality products to China, encourages more Chinese companies to invest in Brunei, and expand food security, digital economy, We should carry out pragmatic cooperation in green development and other fields, and carry out people-to-people and cultural exchanges in education, culture, tourism, health and local areas. Both sides should work together to promote positive progress in joint maritime development and jointly safeguard peace and stability in the South China Sea. China attaches great importance to East Asia cooperation and is willing to work with Brunei and other ASEAN countries to promote regional economic integration and maintain the correct direction of East Asia cooperation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hassanal congratulated China on the successful hosting of the Hangzhou Asian Games not long ago, saying that Brunei and China have a long history of friendly exchanges, relations between the two countries have maintained good development, and exchanges and cooperation in various fields are progressing smoothly. Brunei has always firmly adhered to the one-China policy. Brunei attaches great importance to developing relations with China and is willing to continue to strengthen cooperation in the fields of economy, trade, agriculture, fishery, green energy and other fields, deepen people-to-people and cultural exchanges, and actively promote high-quality joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. Brunei is willing to continue to strengthen cooperation with China within the ASEAN framework, and looks forward to reaching the &quot;South China Sea Code of Conduct&quot; at an early date and working together to build the South China Sea into a sea of ​​peace and friendship and promote regional peace and security. Brunei is willing to communicate closely with China on regional issues such as the Palestinian-Israeli conflict. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cai Qi, Wang Yi and others attended the meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 同心协力  共迎挑战  谱写亚太合作新篇章]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/18/nw.D110000renmrb_20231118_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, November 18, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Dear representatives of the business community,&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ladies, gentlemen, friends:&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;I am very pleased to be invited to attend the APEC Business Leaders Summit. I visited San Francisco many years ago and was deeply impressed by the openness, tolerance and innovation of this beautiful city. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;30 years ago, faced with the world, history, and era questions of &quot;where will mankind go&quot; after the end of the Cold War, leaders in the Asia-Pacific region followed the trend of the times for peace and development and held a At the first informal meeting of APEC leaders, they unanimously agreed to transcend the old thinking of group confrontation and zero-sum game, deepen regional economic cooperation and integration, and commit to building a dynamic, harmonious, and prosperous Asia-Pacific family. This major decision has pushed the development and economic globalization of the Asia-Pacific into the fast lane, helping the Asia-Pacific become the center of world economic growth, the anchor of global development and stability, and a highland for cooperation. The extraordinary journey of Asia-Pacific cooperation has given us many profound revelations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Openness and inclusiveness are the main theme of Asia-Pacific cooperation. The development of the Asia-Pacific relies on openness and inclusiveness, learning from each other&#39;s strengths, and mutual exchange of needs, rather than confrontation, beggar-thy-neighbor, and &quot;small courtyards with high walls.&quot; We uphold open regionalism, jointly formulated the Bogor Goals and Putrajaya Vision, promote trade and investment liberalization and facilitation, and enhance the level of regional economic integration. In the past 30 years, the average tariff level in the Asia-Pacific region has dropped from 17% to 5%, contributing 70% to world economic growth. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Common development is the overall goal of Asia-Pacific cooperation. Development is the eternal theme in the Asia-Pacific region. We have always focused on development, continuously deepened economic and technological cooperation, and enhanced the independent development capabilities of developing members. We have jointly created the &quot;APEC Way&quot; that is independent, voluntary, consensus-based and step-by-step, and respects the development rights of all members. In the past 30 years, per capita income in the Asia-Pacific region has more than quadrupled, and one billion people have been successfully lifted out of poverty, making important contributions to human progress and global sustainable development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——Seeking common ground while reserving differences is a good practice for Asia-Pacific cooperation. Economies in the Asia-Pacific region have different histories, cultures, and development stages. To promote cooperation in the Asia-Pacific region, we cannot require uniformity and can only pursue common ground while reserving differences. Over the past 30 years, we have properly responded to major challenges such as the Asian financial crisis and the international financial crisis, and maintained the good momentum of economic development in the Asia-Pacific. We have relied on seeking the general trend and taking the overall situation into consideration, promoting the spirit of partnership in harmony but diversity, and working together with one heart and another, and constantly bringing together diverse members Sexuality is transformed into a driving force for cooperation, complementing each other&#39;s advantages and making progress together. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ladies, gentlemen, friends! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The world has entered a new period of turbulence and change. The world economic growth momentum is insufficient, and instability, uncertainty, and unpredictable factors are increasing. Where Asia-Pacific cooperation will go in the next 30 years has become a question of the new era we are facing. &quot;Everything is born when it is in its proper place, and everything becomes successful when it is in its proper way.&quot; We must uphold the original intention of APEC, keep in mind the mission entrusted to us by history, and promote Asia-Pacific cooperation to start again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;San Francisco is the signing place of the United Nations Charter, which embodies the good wishes of people of all countries for world peace. Peace is hard-won, but development has a long way to go. We must jointly uphold the purposes and principles of the United Nations Charter, adhere to the way of country-to-country interaction of dialogue rather than confrontation, partnership rather than alliance, and maintain prosperity and stability in the Asia-Pacific. The Asia-Pacific cannot and should not be reduced to a battlefield of geopolitical games, let alone engage in a &quot;new cold war&quot; and camp confrontation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The history of prosperity and development in the Asia-Pacific shows that only cooperation can lead to development, while non-cooperation is the biggest risk. &quot;Decoupling and breaking links&quot; is of no benefit to anyone. We must adhere to open regionalism, unswervingly advance the process of the Asia-Pacific Free Trade Area, respect economic laws, give full play to our respective comparative advantages, promote economic interconnection and integration among countries, strengthen the connection between relevant regional economic and trade agreements and development strategies, and create an open and win-win cooperation Asia Pacific Economy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Faced with a new wave of technological revolution and industrial transformation, we must take a long-term view, seize opportunities, ride on the momentum, promote digital, intelligent, and green transformation and development, and jointly strengthen technological innovation and achievement transformation, Promote the deep integration of the digital economy and the real economy. We must work together to improve global science and technology governance, strengthen the support of scientific and technological innovation for green digital transformation and sustainable development, and create an open, fair, just and non-discriminatory science and technology development environment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ten years ago, I proposed the concept of building a community with a shared future for mankind. The Putrajaya Vision formulated by APEC clearly proposes the establishment of an Asia-Pacific community by 2040, pointing out the direction for Asia-Pacific cooperation. In recent years, in response to urgent global needs, I have proposed the Global Development Initiative, the Global Security Initiative, and the Global Civilization Initiative, aiming to promote all parties to work together to respond to various global challenges, promote common global development, and enhance the well-being of all mankind. China is willing to work with all parties in the Asia-Pacific to promote the implementation of these initiatives and jointly build a world of lasting peace, universal security, common prosperity, openness, inclusiveness, cleanness and beauty. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ladies, gentlemen, friends! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the beginning of this year, China&#39;s economy has continued to rebound and improve. Its growth rate has maintained a leading position among the world&#39;s major economies, and high-quality development has been solidly advanced. China remains the world&#39;s largest growth engine and will contribute one-third of global economic growth this year. As friends from the business community have said, China has become synonymous with the best investment destination. The next &quot;China&quot; will still be China. Friends from the business community from all over the world are welcome to continue to invest in China and deepen their cultivation in China! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has the institutional advantages of a socialist market economy, the demand advantages of a very large-scale market, the supply advantages of a complete industrial system, and the talent advantages of a large number of high-quality workers and entrepreneurs. It has strong internal resources for economic development. Vitality, resilience, potential. In the past, China has made historic achievements while constantly overcoming risks and challenges. Now, China&#39;s economy is highly resilient, has sufficient potential, and has broad room for maneuver. Its long-term positive fundamentals have not changed and will not change. We are confident and more capable of achieving long-term and stable development, and continue to bring new impetus and new opportunities to the world with China&#39;s new development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China has thoroughly implemented the new development concepts of innovation, coordination, green, openness and sharing, and unswervingly promoted high-quality development. The economic growth has a higher gold content and a stronger green color. In recent years, China&#39;s exports of new energy vehicles, lithium batteries, and photovoltaic products have grown rapidly, and the upcoming national voluntary greenhouse gas emission reduction trading market will create huge green market opportunities. We will accelerate the construction of a modern industrial system, provide better institutional guarantees for all types of business entities to share development results, continue to cultivate new growth momentum, and release greater development space. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We insist on opening the door for construction, unswervingly promote high-level opening up to the outside world, further expand market access, and have announced the complete lifting of restrictions on foreign investment access in the manufacturing sector. The sixth China International Import Expo was successfully held recently, and the second Global Digital Trade Expo will be held later this month to further expand opening up and share development opportunities and dividends with other countries. China is implementing the Regional Comprehensive Economic Partnership Agreement with high quality, actively aligning the high-standard economic and trade rules of the Comprehensive and Progressive Agreement for Trans-Pacific Partnership and the Digital Economy Partnership Agreement, actively promoting the process of joining the two agreements, and expanding its global exposure high-standard free trade zone network. This year marks the 10th anniversary of my proposing the Belt and Road Initiative. Last month, China successfully held the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum, resulting in 458 results. Chinese financial institutions established a 780 billion yuan &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; project financing window, and Chinese and foreign companies reached US$97.2 billion in business deals. The cooperation agreement will promote the high-quality development of the Belt and Road Initiative and inject strong impetus into global connectivity and promote development and prosperity. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;No matter how the international situation changes, China&#39;s determination to create a market-oriented, legalized and international business environment will not change, and its policy of providing high-quality services to foreign investors without discrimination will not change. We will continue to improve the protection mechanism for foreign investment rights and interests, further reduce the negative list for foreign investment access, comprehensively guarantee the national treatment of foreign-invested enterprises, and continue to strengthen the protection of intellectual property rights. We will work hard to break down barriers that restrict the flow of innovation factors, deepen reforms in the digital economy, and promote the orderly and free flow of data in accordance with the law. At the same time, we will launch more &quot;heart-warming&quot; measures, optimize the policies for foreigners coming to China, staying and staying in China, and strive to clear up the barriers for people to use financial, medical, Internet payment and other services in China, and provide more opportunities for foreign business friends to invest and establish businesses in China. Good protection. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;I would like to emphasize that the Chinese economy has overcome challenges, moved forward steadily, and achieved high-quality development, which is also an inevitable requirement for promoting Chinese-style modernization. The starting point and goal of Chinese-style modernization is to enable the more than 1.4 billion Chinese people to live a better life. For the world, this means a broader market and unprecedented cooperation opportunities, and will also inject powerful impetus into world modernization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ladies, gentlemen, friends! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Asia-Pacific business community has always been a trendsetter in Asia-Pacific cooperation and global development. I hope that everyone will carry forward the innovative spirit of &quot;dare to be the first in the world&quot; and make greater contributions to building an open Asia-Pacific economy and assisting the development of the world economy. We welcome the global business community to actively participate in the Chinese-style modernization process and share the huge opportunities brought by China&#39;s high-quality development! &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thank you everyone. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Xinhua News Agency, San Francisco, November 16)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href =&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 习近平会见斐济总理兰布卡]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/18/nw.D110000renmrb_20231118_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, November 18, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231118/1700257503078_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the morning of November 16, local time, President Xi Jinping Xi Jinping met with Fiji Prime Minister Lambuka in San Francisco. &lt;BR/>;Photographed by Xinhua News Agency reporter Rao Aimin&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Our newspaper, San Francisco, November 16th&amp;nbsp ;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Li Zhiwei, Song Shuang) On the morning of November 16, local time, President Xi Jinping met with Fiji Prime Minister Lambuka in San Francisco. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that Fiji was the first Pacific island country to establish diplomatic relations with New China. A few days ago, it celebrated the 48th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and Fiji. China regards Fiji as a good friend and good partner and supports Fiji in choosing its own development path and achieving national development and revitalization. China is willing to work with Fiji to consolidate political mutual trust, expand practical cooperation, deepen people-to-people and cultural exchanges, and promote the continuous development of China-Fiji comprehensive strategic partnership. The one-China principle is the political foundation for the healthy and stable development of China-Fiji relations. It is hoped that Fiji will continue to provide China with firm support on issues concerning China&#39;s core interests and major concerns. China will also continue to support Fiji in safeguarding national sovereignty, security and territorial integrity. China is willing to strengthen cooperation with Fiji in jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, implement global development initiatives, promote cooperation in infrastructure, agriculture, forestry, fishery, new energy and other fields, and assist Fiji&#39;s economic and social development. China is willing to expand imports of Fijian specialty products, support Chinese enterprises to invest in Fiji, and encourage more tourists to travel to Fiji. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that China develops relations with Pacific island countries in an open and honest manner, has no selfish motives, and does not target third parties. China&#39;s policy on Pacific island countries fully respects the sovereignty and independence of island countries, attaches no political conditions, and does not write empty promises. China and Pacific island countries are both developing countries and should strengthen mutual assistance within the framework of South-South cooperation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Lambuka said that since the establishment of diplomatic relations between Fiji and China, relations between the two countries have continued to develop strongly. China has provided Fiji and other Pacific island countries with a lot of help, for which Fiji is deeply grateful. Fiji insists on adhering to the one-China principle. The global development initiative, global security initiative, and global civilization initiative proposed by President Xi Jinping are conducive to safeguarding and promoting the development and interests of countries in the global South. Fiji looks forward to deepening cooperation with China to help Fiji choose and take the path to modernization. China is a great country that always adheres to the principle that all countries, big or small, are equal. Fiji admires President Xi Jinping&#39;s world leadership. I believe that China will play a more important role in international affairs in the future, and Fiji-China relations will get better and better. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cai Qi, Wang Yi and others attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 习近平会见日本首相岸田文雄]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/18/nw.D110000renmrb_20231118_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, November 18, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231118/1700257510097_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of November 16, local time, President Xi Jinping Xi Jinping met with Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida in San Francisco. &lt;BR/>;Photographed by Xinhua News Agency reporter Wang Ye&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Our newspaper, San Francisco, November 16th&amp;nbsp ;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Mou Zongcong, Chen Shangwen) On the afternoon of November 16, local time, President Xi Jinping met with Japanese Prime Minister Fumio Kishida in San Francisco. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The leaders of the two countries reaffirmed their adherence to the principles and consensus of the four political documents between China and Japan, reaffirmed the positioning of bilateral relations in comprehensively promoting strategic and mutually beneficial relations, and committed to building a constructive and stable relationship that meets the requirements of the new era. Sino-Japanese relations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that this year marks the 45th anniversary of the signing of the Treaty of Peace and Friendship between China and Japan. The treaty established the general direction of peace, friendship, and cooperation between China and Japan in legal form and became a milestone in the history of bilateral relations. Over the past 45 years, under the guidance of the four political documents between China and Japan, including the treaty, the relations between the two countries have experienced ups and downs, but have generally maintained a momentum of development, brought benefits to the people of the two countries, and played a role in promoting regional peace, development, and prosperity. positive effects. The current international situation is intertwined with chaos and risks and challenges emerge one after another. Peaceful coexistence, ever-lasting friendship, mutually beneficial cooperation and common development between China and Japan are in line with the fundamental interests of the two peoples. At present, China-Japan relations are in a critical period of inheriting the past and ushering in the future. Both sides should follow the trend of the times, grasp the right direction, adhere to the spirit of &quot;taking history as a mirror and open up the future&quot;, maintain the original intention of normalizing diplomatic relations, view each other&#39;s development objectively and rationally, and establish positive, friendly and mutual recognition. We need to constructively manage conflicts and differences, and embody the political consensus of &quot;each other as a cooperative partner and not a threat to each other&quot; into specific policies and practical actions. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that major principled issues such as history and Taiwan are related to the political foundation of bilateral relations. Japan must abide by its faith and ensure that the foundation of Sino-Japanese relations is not damaged or shaken. The economic interests of China and Japan are deeply intertwined with the industrial and supply chains, and it will not benefit anyone to engage in &quot;small courtyards and high walls&quot; and &quot;decoupling and disconnection&quot;. China is promoting high-quality development and high-level opening up, which will bring unprecedented opportunities to countries around the world, including Japan. Both sides should deepen cooperation, achieve mutual success, effectively safeguard the global free trade system, and achieve a higher level of mutual benefit and win-win results. The two countries should base themselves on a higher position, uphold a broader vision, carry forward Asian values ​​with peace, cooperation, tolerance and integration as the core, practice true multilateralism, promote open regionalism, promote the process of regional integration, and jointly respond to Global challenges. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that the discharge of Japan’s Fukushima nuclear contaminated water into the sea is related to the health of all mankind, the global marine environment, and international public interests. Japan should take seriously the legitimate concerns at home and abroad and properly handle them in a responsible and constructive manner. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Kishida Fumio said that on the important occasion of the 45th anniversary of the signing of the Japan-China Treaty of Peace and Friendship, the people of the two countries deeply recall the efforts made by the older generation leaders of the two countries in a wide range of fields to promote the development of Japan-China friendly relations. . The international community is currently at a historic turning point. Japan hopes to focus on the future, strengthen high-level communication and dialogue with China, increase positive factors in bilateral relations, and adhere to peaceful coexistence. Japan has no intention of &quot;decoupling&quot; from China and hopes to continue to promote people-to-people and cultural exchanges and deepen practical cooperation in various fields such as digital economy, green development, finance, medical care and elderly care. Japan will continue to be committed to the path of peaceful development and adhere to the Japan-China Joint Statement on handling the Taiwan issue without any change. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Both sides spoke positively of the newly established Sino-Japanese export control dialogue mechanism, agreed to maintain dialogue and communication at all levels, hold a new round of Sino-Japanese high-level economic dialogue and Sino-Japanese high-level people-to-people and cultural exchange consultation mechanism meetings at an appropriate time, and discuss international issues. Maintain communication and coordination on regional affairs and jointly address global challenges such as climate change. Both sides agreed to find a suitable way to resolve the issue of discharge of Fukushima nuclear-contaminated water into the sea through consultation and negotiation in a constructive manner. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The two sides also exchanged views on international and regional issues of common concern. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cai Qi, Wang Yi and others attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 秉持初心，牢记使命，推动亚太合作再出发]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/18/nw.D110000renmrb_20231118_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, November 18, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;“We must uphold the original intention of APEC, keep in mind the mission given to us by history, and promote Asia-Pacific cooperation to start again.” President Xi Jinping said to He delivered a written speech at the APEC Business Leaders’ Summit held in San Francisco, profoundly summarizing the history and inspiration of Asia-Pacific cooperation, and in-depth expounding China’s propositions on deepening Asia-Pacific cooperation and promoting regional and world economic growth, in order to write a new chapter in Asia-Pacific cooperation and build a better future. The world has been infused with strong positive energy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;30 years ago, faced with the world, history, and era questions of &quot;where will mankind go&quot; after the end of the Cold War, the first APEC leaders&#39; informal meeting agreed to transcend The old thinking of group confrontation and zero-sum game has deepened regional economic cooperation and integration, and is committed to building a dynamic, harmonious and prosperous Asia-Pacific family. Asia-Pacific development and economic globalization have since entered the fast lane. In the past 30 years, the average tariff level in the Asia-Pacific region has dropped from 17% to 5%, contributing 70% to world economic growth; the per capita income in the Asia-Pacific region has more than quadrupled, and one billion people have been successfully lifted out of poverty, which has contributed to human progress and the global economy. It has made important contributions to sustainable development; properly responded to major challenges such as the Asian financial crisis and the international financial crisis, and maintained the good momentum of economic development in the Asia-Pacific. The extraordinary journey of Asia-Pacific cooperation has profound implications: openness and inclusiveness are the main theme of Asia-Pacific cooperation, common development is the overall goal of Asia-Pacific cooperation, and seeking common ground while reserving differences is a good practice for Asia-Pacific cooperation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping emphasized: &quot;Where Asia-Pacific cooperation will go in the next 30 years has become a question of the new era we are facing.&quot; In today&#39;s world, changes are intertwined, changes over the past century are accelerating, and the world has entered a new period of turbulence and change. , the world economic growth momentum is insufficient, and instability, uncertainty, and unpredictable factors are increasing. As the world&#39;s economic growth center, the anchor of global development and stability, and the highland of cooperation, the Asia-Pacific is an important engine of world economic growth. By adhering to the original aspiration of APEC, looking for the general trend and taking into account the overall situation, carrying forward the spirit of partnership of harmony but diversity and working together, adhering to openness and inclusiveness, common development, seeking common ground while reserving differences, and always moving in the right direction, we will surely be able to continue to benefit the people of the region and contribute to world peace. Inject more Asia-Pacific power into development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Everything is born when it is in its proper place, and everything becomes successful when it is in its proper way.” President Xi Jinping proposed “adhere to dialogue rather than confrontation, partnership rather than alliance as a way of country-to-country exchanges” and “adhere to an open regional Doctrine, unswervingly advancing the process of the Asia-Pacific Free Trade Area&quot; and &quot;promoting digital, intelligent, and green transformation and development&quot; and other views have drawn a blueprint, clarified the focus, and pointed out the path for promoting Asia-Pacific cooperation to start again. We must deeply realize that peace is hard-won and development has a long way to go. The Asia-Pacific cannot and should not be reduced to a battlefield of geopolitical games, let alone a &quot;new Cold War&quot; and camp confrontation. The history of prosperity and development in the Asia-Pacific shows that only cooperation can lead to development, and non-cooperation is the biggest risk. Facing a new wave of scientific and technological revolution and industrial transformation, we must take a long-term view, seize opportunities, and ride on the momentum. From a new starting point, we must jointly uphold the purposes and principles of the United Nations Charter, adhere to the way of state-to-state exchanges, and maintain prosperity and stability in the Asia-Pacific; we must give full play to our respective comparative advantages, promote economic interconnection and integration among countries, and build an open Asia-Pacific economy with win-win cooperation; Jointly strengthen technological innovation and achievement transformation, promote the deep integration of the digital economy and the real economy, strengthen the support of technological innovation for green digital transformation and sustainable development, and create an open, fair, just and non-discriminatory technological development environment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We are in an era full of challenges and changes, but also an era full of hope. All countries in the world are on a ship with a common destiny. Only by strengthening unity and cooperation can we jointly face challenges, overcome difficulties, and create a better future for mankind. Ten years ago, President Xi Jinping put forward the concept of promoting the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind, gathering the greatest common denominator for building a better world, and became a clear banner that leads the trend of the times and the direction of human progress. Looking into the future, China is willing to work with all parties in the Asia-Pacific to promote the implementation of the Global Development Initiative, the Global Security Initiative, and the Global Civilization Initiative, work together to respond to various global challenges, promote common global development, enhance the well-being of all mankind, and jointly build lasting peace and universal security. , common prosperity, openness and inclusiveness, a clean and beautiful world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China’s development has benefited from the Asia-Pacific, and it has also used its own development to give back to and benefit the Asia-Pacific. Today, the Chinese people are comprehensively promoting the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation with Chinese-style modernization, which means a broader market and unprecedented cooperation opportunities for the world. If all parties adhere to their original aspirations, keep their mission in mind, and work together to achieve world modernization of peaceful development, mutually beneficial cooperation, and common prosperity, they will surely make more contributions to the stability and prosperity of the Asia-Pacific and make strides forward on the road to building a community with a shared future for mankind. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 习近平会见文莱苏丹哈桑纳尔]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/18/nw.D110000renmrb_20231118_5-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, November 18, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231118/1700257484873_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of November 16, local time, President Xi Jinping Xi Jinping met with Brunei Sultan Hassanal in San Francisco. &lt;BR/>;Photographed by Xinhua News Agency reporter Yao Dawei&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Our newspaper, San Francisco, November 16th&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;(Reporters Ren Yan, Wang Xiangyu) On the afternoon of November 16, local time, President Xi Jinping met with Brunei Sultan Hassanal in San Francisco. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that China and Brunei are friendly neighbors across the sea and good partners who trust and support each other. Over the past 30 years since the establishment of diplomatic relations, the two countries have continuously deepened political mutual trust, actively aligned development strategies, achieved fruitful results in practical cooperation in various fields, and maintained good cooperation in international and regional affairs. They have set an example of equal treatment, mutual benefit and win-win between large and small countries, and have set a good example for both countries. It has made positive contributions to regional peace, stability, development and prosperity. This year marks the fifth anniversary of the establishment of strategic partnership between China and Brunei. China is willing to work with Brunei to jointly build the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; with high quality, promote the continuous new development of bilateral relations, and bring more benefits to the people of the two countries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping emphasized that China supports Brunei in taking a development path that suits its own national conditions, welcomes Brunei to expand exports of high-quality products to China, encourages more Chinese companies to invest in Brunei, and expand food security, digital economy, We should carry out pragmatic cooperation in green development and other fields, and carry out people-to-people and cultural exchanges in education, culture, tourism, health and local areas. Both sides should work together to promote positive progress in joint maritime development and jointly safeguard peace and stability in the South China Sea. China attaches great importance to East Asia cooperation and is willing to work with Brunei and other ASEAN countries to promote regional economic integration and maintain the correct direction of East Asia cooperation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hassanal congratulated China on the successful hosting of the Hangzhou Asian Games not long ago, saying that Brunei and China have a long history of friendly exchanges, relations between the two countries have maintained good development, and exchanges and cooperation in various fields are progressing smoothly. Brunei has always firmly adhered to the one-China policy. Brunei attaches great importance to developing relations with China and is willing to continue to strengthen cooperation in the fields of economy, trade, agriculture, fishery, green energy and other fields, deepen people-to-people and cultural exchanges, and actively promote high-quality joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;. Brunei is willing to continue to strengthen cooperation with China within the ASEAN framework, and looks forward to reaching the &quot;South China Sea Code of Conduct&quot; at an early date and working together to build the South China Sea into a sea of ​​peace and friendship and promote regional peace and security. Brunei is willing to communicate closely with China on regional issues such as the Palestinian-Israeli conflict. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Cai Qi, Wang Yi and others attended the meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[03版要闻 - 共享中国高质量发展带来的巨大机遇]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/18/nw.D110000renmrb_20231118_1-03.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Saturday, November 18, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;On the morning of November 16, local time, President Xi Jinping delivered a speech titled The written speech &quot;Working together to meet challenges and write a new chapter in Asia-Pacific cooperation&quot; pointed out that we must uphold the original intention of APEC, keep in mind the mission given to us by history, and promote Asia-Pacific cooperation to start again. People from all walks of life interviewed by this newspaper said that China&#39;s propositions and actions on Asia-Pacific cooperation play an important role in promoting regional development and prosperity, demonstrating China&#39;s unswerving efforts to build an Asia-Pacific community with a shared future and its responsibility as a major country in the Asia-Pacific with its own high-quality development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&quot;In Asia-Pacific economic cooperation, China has always played a &#39;propeller&#39; role&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Openness and inclusiveness are the main theme of Asia-Pacific cooperation&quot; &quot;Common development&quot; &quot;Is the overall goal of Asia-Pacific cooperation&quot; and &quot;Seeking common ground while reserving differences is a good practice for Asia-Pacific cooperation.&quot; President Xi Jinping&#39;s profound summary of the extraordinary history of Asia-Pacific cooperation inspired people to have new and in-depth thinking about Asia-Pacific cooperation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Antonio Basilio, Executive Director of the Secretariat of the APEC Business Advisory Council and Chairman of the Philippine National Committee for Pacific Economic Cooperation, participated in the APEC Business Leaders Summit held in Bangkok last year and in San Francisco this time. He told this reporter: &quot;President Xi Jinping&#39;s written speech was rich in content and attracted much attention. In Asia-Pacific economic cooperation, China has always played a &#39;propeller&#39; role, which is conducive to promoting the sustainable development and prosperity of the Asia-Pacific. China is the overwhelming majority in the Asia-Pacific region The largest trading partner of most economies, China’s economy is highly resilient, has great potential, and is full of vitality, and plays a decisive role in the economic development of the Asia-Pacific.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Openness, inclusiveness, common development, and seeking common ground while reserving differences are the core values ​​of the Asia-Pacific economy. Valuable experience in achieving successful cooperation.&quot; Luciano Paredes, manager of the Public Affairs Department of the Peruvian Foreign Trade Association, said that at a time when global geopolitics is tense and economic recovery is weak, President Xi Jinping&#39;s written speech called for the promotion of harmony in diversity and unity in unity. The spirit of partnership is crucial to promoting world economic recovery. The Asia-Pacific cannot and should not be reduced to a battlefield of geopolitical games. This is not beneficial to any country. It is of great significance for China to promote the joint efforts of all parties to build an Asia-Pacific community with a shared future. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ren Hongbin, President of the China Council for the Promotion of International Trade, said that President Xi Jinping’s written speech explained China’s proposition of building an open Asia-Pacific economy with win-win cooperation, which fully reflects China’s determination to promote high-level opening up and promote economic integration in the Asia-Pacific region. and promote the healthy development of economic globalization. The China Council for the Promotion of International Trade immediately organized a delegation of Chinese entrepreneurs to study President Xi Jinping’s written speech, especially his ardent hopes for the business community. Everyone expressed that they will actively play the role of China&#39;s business community and contribute to promoting the economic development and prosperity of the Asia-Pacific and the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“President Xi Jinping’s written speech systematically summarized the profound enlightenment of Asia-Pacific cooperation in the past 30 years, and pointed out the direction for promoting Asia-Pacific cooperation in the next 30 years.” Ge Haijiao, chairman of the Bank of China, said that finance is the modern economy The core is an important force in promoting regional and even global economic cooperation. Bank of China has been deeply involved in the Asia-Pacific for a long time, constantly expanding the depth and breadth of financial services, and actively promoting multilateral and bilateral economic and trade exchanges and mutually beneficial cooperation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“Only through unity and cooperation can we achieve real development and maintain regional prosperity and stability”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Ten years ago, I proposed the idea of ​​building a community with a shared future for mankind. Concept. The Putrajaya Vision formulated by APEC clearly proposes the establishment of an Asia-Pacific community in 2040, pointing out the direction for Asia-Pacific cooperation. In recent years, in response to urgent global needs, I have proposed global development initiatives, global security initiatives, and global civilization The initiative aims to promote all parties to work together to respond to various global challenges, promote common global development, and enhance the well-being of all mankind.&quot; President Xi Jinping pointed out that China is willing to work with all parties in the Asia-Pacific to promote the implementation of these initiatives and jointly build lasting peace and universal security. , common prosperity, openness and inclusiveness, a clean and beautiful world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Antonio Bermudez, a senior Colombian media person, told this reporter that President Xi Jinping’s written speech on “unswervingly promoting high-quality development” and “unswervingly promoting high-level opening up” are very important. People are impressed. He said that the Asia-Pacific region is the most dynamic growth belt of the global economy. China continues to promote high-level opening up and promotes high-quality joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; with all parties. Latin American countries have further deepened cooperation with China to achieve mutual benefit and win-win results. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jonjoel Gupta, CEO of American Renaissance Analysis Company, said: &quot;History and reality have repeatedly proven that only unity and cooperation can achieve real development and maintain regional prosperity and stability. China is the driving force behind world economic growth. As an important engine, China will unswervingly expand its opening up and allow companies from all over the world to share development opportunities.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Zhenguo, founder and president of LONGi Green Energy, said in President Xi Jinping&#39;s written speech that China&#39;s &quot;economic growth is more valuable. The color is higher and the green color is thicker.&quot; I feel deeply. He said that green development is one of the important topics of this APEC meeting. Under the current dual global energy and climate crises, China actively implements new development concepts and continuously promotes green development, which has more prominent significance. Chinese new energy companies reduce costs and increase efficiency through technological innovation, making important contributions to global energy transformation and sustainable human development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The Asia-Pacific is the region with the most growth vitality and development potential in the world. China’s proposals such as building an Asia-Pacific community with a shared future are in line with the expectations of all parties.” Chen Zhuomian, vice chairman of the Thailand Institute of Trade, said that in the past 10 years, China’s proposals Cooperation projects under the Belt and Road Initiative are spread all over the world and benefit the world. Cooperation between China and all parties in infrastructure, scientific and technological innovation and other areas is booming, bringing more development hope to all parties, especially developing countries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“China is willing to share opportunities with all parties and seek common development as a major country”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the beginning of this year, China’s economy has continued to rebound and is growing at a rate of Maintaining a leading position among the world&#39;s major economies and solidly advancing high-quality development. President Xi Jinping pointed out that we are confident and more capable of achieving long-term stable development and continue to bring new impetus and new opportunities to the world with China&#39;s new development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“President Xi Jinping’s written speech sent a clear and unambiguous signal: China will unswervingly expand its opening up to the outside world and continue to share China’s development opportunities with the Asia-Pacific and the world.” Co-founder and global director of Ambo Corporation President and CEO Peter Ho said, &quot;The Chinese propositions and measures put forward by President Xi Jinping have enhanced our confidence in expanding investment in the Chinese market.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Over the past 30 years, APEC has become an important economic cooperation platform in the Asia-Pacific region. , plays an important role in supporting the multilateral trading system and promoting the construction of an open Asia-Pacific economy. China actively advocates unity and cooperation in the Asia-Pacific region, and uses its own development to give back to and benefit the Asia-Pacific.&quot; said Susana Serra, President of Chile&#39;s Bosch Compliance Review Company , Chinese-style modernization is people-centered, emphasizes the path of peaceful development, and the harmonious coexistence of man and nature, providing useful reference for the development of countries in Latin America. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;President Xi Jinping pointed out in his written speech that we should take a long-term view, seize opportunities, ride on the momentum, and promote digital, intelligent, and green transformation and development. This further strengthens our confidence in green development.&quot; China Energy Song Hailiang, Secretary of the Party Committee and Chairman of the Construction Group Co., Ltd., said that China Energy Construction will give full play to its advantages in the integration of the entire industry chain in the green and low-carbon field, fully integrate into the new pattern of global green and low-carbon cooperation, and actively promote the green &quot;Belt and Road&quot; construction . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“President Xi Jinping’s written speech once again demonstrated to the world that China is willing to share opportunities and seek common development with all parties and its responsibility as a major country, and reflects China’s practical actions to promote the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind.” Chinese Academy of Sciences Bangkok Innovation Cooperation Jiang Biao, former director of the center, said that in recent years, China has further optimized its economic structure, accelerated the implementation of innovation-driven development strategies, and promoted industries to move toward mid- to high-end, bringing more development opportunities to all parties in the Asia-Pacific region. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;George Zogopoulos, head of the Europe-China Project at the International Center for European Studies, said that China adheres to peaceful development and openness and inclusiveness, which is conducive to maintaining the stability and smoothness of industrial and supply chains in the Asia-Pacific region and promoting the development of the Asia-Pacific region. economic recovery and achieve long-term prosperity and stability in the Asia-Pacific region. &quot;All parties actively participate in the Chinese-style modernization process and will share the huge opportunities brought by China&#39;s high-quality development.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(This newspaper, San Francisco, Rome, and Beijing, November 17th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Reporters Zhang Bolan, Mou Zongcong, Ren Yan, Chen Yiming, Li Zhiwei, Zhang Mengxu, Zhang Penghui, Chen Shangwen, Yang Yi, Shi Yuanhao, Xie Yahong, Zhao Yipu, People&#39;s Daily reporter Deng Wei also contributed to this article)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-- >;</description><pubDate> Sat, 18 Nov 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>