<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 审议《关于二十届中央第一轮巡视情况的综合报告》]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/28/nw.D110000renmrb_20230928_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, September 28, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;■&amp;nbsp;The Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core attaches great importance to inspection work and regards inspections as promoting the party’s self-revolution and We will comprehensively and strictly manage the party&#39;s strategic institutional arrangements and make a series of major decisions and arrangements. The first round of inspections of the 20th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China adhered to integrity and innovation, promoted the concreteness, precision and normalization of political supervision, and released a clear signal that comprehensive and strict governance of the party is always on the road, and the party&#39;s self-revolution is always on the road. Practice has proved that inspections are an effective way to discover and promote the solution of problems, and we must continue to make efforts and advance in depth&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■&amp;nbsp;From the perspective of inspections, party building in the fields of state-owned enterprises, finance, and sports must be strictly governed in an all-round way. The party has been strengthened and various tasks have achieved new results, but there are still some problems. It is necessary to pass on the strict tone, strict measures, and strict atmosphere to the end, urge the inspected party organizations, especially the main responsible comrades, to take on their responsibilities, carry out rectifications strictly and practically, and implement the inspection rectification and learning in the new era of Xi Jinping Integrate the theme education of socialism with Chinese characteristics, deeply understand the decisive significance of &quot;two establishments&quot;, and resolutely achieve &quot;two maintenances&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■&amp;nbsp;We must take inspections and rectifications as an opportunity to further strengthen the party&#39;s Provide comprehensive leadership and urge the inspected party organizations to improve their political standing, conscientiously fulfill the responsibilities and missions assigned by the Party Central Committee, continuously enhance the core functions and core competitiveness of state-owned enterprises, consolidate the important material and political foundations of socialism with Chinese characteristics, and expand financial enterprises Serve the real economy and national strategic efforts, promote high-quality development&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, September 27th The Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee held a meeting on September 27th to review the &quot;About Comprehensive report on the first round of inspections of the 20th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China. Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, presided over the meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The meeting held that the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core attaches great importance to inspection work, regards inspections as a strategic institutional arrangement to promote the Party’s self-revolution and comprehensively and strictly govern the Party, and has made a series of major decisions and arrangements. The first round of inspections of the 20th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China adhered to integrity and innovation, promoted the concreteness, precision and normalization of political supervision, and released a clear signal that comprehensive and strict governance of the party is always on the road, and the party&#39;s self-revolution is always on the road. Practice has proved that inspections are an effective way to discover and promote solutions to problems, and we must continue to make efforts and advance in depth. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The meeting pointed out that from the inspection, party building and comprehensive and strict party governance in the fields of state-owned enterprises, finance, and sports have been strengthened, and new results have been achieved in various tasks, but there are also some problems. It is necessary to pass on the strict tone, strict measures, and strict atmosphere to the end, urge the inspected party organizations, especially the main responsible comrades, to take on their responsibilities, carry out rectifications strictly and practically, and implement the inspection rectification and learning in the new era of Xi Jinping The education on the theme of socialism with Chinese characteristics should be combined to deeply understand the decisive significance of the “two establishments” and resolutely achieve the “two maintenances”. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The meeting emphasized that inspections and rectifications should be taken as an opportunity to further strengthen the party’s overall leadership, urge the inspected party organizations to improve their political positions, conscientiously fulfill the responsibilities and missions assigned by the Party Central Committee, and continuously enhance the core functions and functions of state-owned enterprises. Core competitiveness, consolidating the important material and political foundations of socialism with Chinese characteristics, increasing the efforts of financial enterprises to serve the real economy and national strategies, and promoting high-quality development. It is necessary to coordinate development and security, establish bottom-line thinking and extreme thinking, take effective measures to prevent and resolve major risks, and firmly maintain the bottom line of safety. It is necessary to promote the in-depth development of comprehensive and strict party governance, tighten the responsibilities of the party committee (party group) secretary as the first responsible person, the members of the leadership team with &quot;one post and two responsibilities&quot;, and the supervision responsibilities of the discipline inspection and supervision agencies, and highlight the strengthening of the &quot;top leaders&quot; at all levels. We will strengthen the supervision of corruption in state-owned enterprises and the financial sector, in-depth rectification of the &quot;four styles&quot;, deepen the use of cases to promote reform and treatment, and promote the integrated promotion of those who do not dare to corrupt, those who cannot corrupt, and those who do not want to corrupt. It is necessary to conscientiously implement the party&#39;s organizational line in the new era and strengthen the construction of leadership teams, cadres and talent teams, and grassroots party organizations. It is necessary to make full use of the inspection results, deepen reforms, improve systems, promote source control, and promote treatment of both symptoms and root causes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Other matters were also considered at the meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 积极参与世界贸易组织改革 提高驾驭高水平对外开放能力]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/28/nw.D110000renmrb_20230928_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, September 28, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;■&amp;nbsp;The World Trade Organization is an important pillar of multilateralism and an important stage for global economic governance. Necessary reform of the World Trade Organization is a general consensus and a general trend. We must deeply understand the importance and urgency of participating in the reform of the World Trade Organization from the perspective of better coordinating the overall domestic and international situations, and better coordinating development and security, and fully participate in the World Trade Organization with a more active historical responsibility and creative spirit reform and adjustment of international economic and trade rules, and promote in-depth reform and high-quality development with high-level opening up&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■&amp;nbsp;Accession to the World Trade Organization is a milestone in my country&#39;s opening up to the outside world. In just over 20 years, my country&#39;s total trade in goods has increased 11 times, becoming the world&#39;s largest trade country in goods and a major trading partner of more than 140 countries and regions, contributing nearly 30% to global economic growth annually. my country&#39;s relationship with the World Trade Organization has undergone historic changes. It has gradually grown from a passive recipient and active adapter of international economic and trade rules to an important participant. Facts have shown that my country&#39;s entry into the World Trade Organization has not only accelerated its own development, but also benefited the world. This major decision is completely correct&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■&amp;nbsp;To participate in the reform of the World Trade Organization, we must firmly maintain the World Trade Organization as the core the authority and effectiveness of the multilateral trading system, and actively promote the restoration of the normal operation of the World Trade Organization’s dispute settlement mechanism. We must stand firmly on the right side of history, adhere to the general direction of economic globalization, unequivocally advocate free trade and true multilateralism, oppose unilateralism and protectionism, oppose the politicization, weaponization, and pan-security of economic and trade issues, and promote the construction of openness world economy. We must uphold the concept of a community with a shared future for mankind and improve and refine China’s plan for comprehensive and in-depth participation in the reform of the World Trade Organization. Resolutely safeguard the legitimate rights and interests of the vast number of developing countries, including my country&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■&amp;nbsp;Promoting reform and development through opening up is an important magic weapon for my country&#39;s modernization drive to continuously achieve new achievements. This year marks the 45th anniversary of reform and opening up. We must continue to do a good job in reforming ourselves, not only expanding the door to opening up, but also stabilizing the path of reform. We must be more proactive in aligning with high-standard international economic and trade rules, steadily expand institutional opening up such as rules, regulations, management, and standards, accelerate the creation of new highlands for opening up, build a new higher-level open economic system, and accelerate the construction of a new development pattern. It is necessary to actively create a market-oriented, legal and international first-class business environment, and take the opportunity to promote the accession to the Comprehensive and Progressive Agreement for Trans-Pacific Partnership and the Digital Economy Partnership Agreement to further stimulate import potential, relax market access, Promote the in-depth development of multilateral and bilateral cooperation and enhance the attraction of foreign investment. It is necessary to accelerate the construction of a strong trading country, upgrade goods trade, innovate service trade, develop digital trade, take digital greening as the direction, further enhance the status of the international division of labor, and move towards the mid-to-high end of the global value chain. At the same time, we must pay attention to maintaining national economic security&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■&amp;nbsp;We must develop excellent skills in controlling high-level opening up. Daxing investigates and studies, summarizes and makes good use of my country’s successful experience in opening up and development, strengthens strategic, systematic and forward-looking planning for opening up work, and accurately understands new situations and new issues in the field of international economic and trade, so as to be aware of it and have strategies at hand , take powerful actions. Improve the ability to use international rules to safeguard my country&#39;s development rights and interests, and accelerate the creation of a high-level professional opening-up team with strong politics, high skills, and excellent work styles. Coordinate opening and security, maintain security, promote rights and interests in the struggle, seek cooperation and strive for win-win results&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, September 27th On the afternoon of September 27, the eighth collective study session on WTO rules and WTO reform was held. Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, emphasized when presiding over the study that the World Trade Organization is an important pillar of multilateralism and an important stage for global economic governance. Necessary reform of the World Trade Organization is a general consensus and a general trend. We must deeply understand the importance and urgency of participating in the reform of the World Trade Organization from the perspective of better coordinating the overall domestic and international situations, and better coordinating development and security, and fully participate in the World Trade Organization with a more active historical responsibility and creative spirit Reform and adjustment of international economic and trade rules, and promote in-depth reform and high-quality development with high-level opening up. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Gu Xueming, director and researcher of the Research Institute of the Ministry of Commerce, explained this issue and put forward work suggestions. Comrades from the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee listened carefully to the explanation and held discussions. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping delivered an important speech after listening to the explanation and discussion. He pointed out that joining the World Trade Organization is a milestone in my country&#39;s opening up. In just over 20 years, my country&#39;s total trade in goods has increased 11 times, becoming the world&#39;s largest trade country in goods and a major trading partner of more than 140 countries and regions, contributing nearly 30% to global economic growth annually. my country&#39;s relationship with the World Trade Organization has undergone historic changes. It has gradually grown from a passive recipient and active adapter of international economic and trade rules to an important participant. Facts have shown that my country&#39;s entry into the World Trade Organization has not only accelerated its own development, but also benefited the world. This major decision is completely correct. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that to participate in the reform of the World Trade Organization, we must firmly safeguard the authority and effectiveness of the multilateral trading system with the World Trade Organization as the core, and actively promote the restoration of the normal operation of the World Trade Organization&#39;s dispute settlement mechanism. We must stand firmly on the right side of history, adhere to the general direction of economic globalization, unequivocally advocate free trade and true multilateralism, oppose unilateralism and protectionism, oppose the politicization, weaponization, and pan-security of economic and trade issues, and promote the construction of openness world economy. We must uphold the concept of a community with a shared future for mankind and improve and refine China’s plan for comprehensive and in-depth participation in the reform of the World Trade Organization. We will resolutely safeguard the legitimate rights and interests of developing countries, including my country. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that promoting reform and development through opening up is an important magic weapon for my country&#39;s modernization drive to continuously achieve new achievements. This year marks the 45th anniversary of reform and opening up. We must continue to do a good job in reforming ourselves, not only expanding the door to opening up, but also stabilizing the path of reform. We must be more proactive in aligning with high-standard international economic and trade rules, steadily expand institutional opening up such as rules, regulations, management, and standards, accelerate the creation of new highlands for opening up, build a new higher-level open economic system, and accelerate the construction of a new development pattern. It is necessary to actively create a market-oriented, legal and international first-class business environment, and take the opportunity to promote the accession to the Comprehensive and Progressive Agreement for Trans-Pacific Partnership and the Digital Economy Partnership Agreement to further stimulate import potential, relax market access, Promote the in-depth development of multilateral and bilateral cooperation and enhance the attraction of foreign investment. It is necessary to accelerate the construction of a strong trading country, upgrade goods trade, innovate service trade, develop digital trade, take digital greening as the direction, further enhance the status of the international division of labor, and move towards the mid-to-high end of the global value chain. At the same time, we must pay attention to maintaining national economic security. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized the need to develop excellent skills in controlling high-level opening up. Daxing investigates and studies, summarizes and makes good use of my country&#39;s successful experience in opening up and development, strengthens strategic, systematic and forward-looking planning for opening up work, and accurately understands new situations and new issues in the field of international economic and trade, so as to be aware of it and have strategies at hand , take powerful actions. Improve the ability to use international rules to safeguard my country&#39;s development rights and interests, and accelerate the creation of a high-level professional opening-up team with strong politics, high skills, and excellent work styles. We should coordinate openness and security, maintain security, promote rights and interests in the struggle, and seek cooperation and strive for win-win results. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - “一定要放低身段来干这件事”（微观察·习近平总书记浙江之行）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/28/nw.D110000renmrb_20230928_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, September 28, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;These words, in terms of Zhejiang, which is building a common prosperity demonstration zone, are aimed at both the &quot;Chinese-style modernization&quot; &quot;Forerunner&quot; is also China on the new journey of building a strong country and rejuvenating the nation:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The mission here is to actively explore the high-quality development and construction of a common prosperity demonstration area, and strive to form a model that can be used for reference and can be used for reference. Experience and practices that can be promoted and replicated. But it is not about engaging in welfarism, &#39;raising lazy people&#39;, and going to the public canteens of the past. That will not work.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the Zhejiang Provincial Party Committee and Provincial Government Work Report Meeting At this point, General Secretary Xi Jinping reminded: &quot;We must seek truth from facts, work step by step, and work steadily. We must not have the idea of ​​​​being unconventional, enjoying great achievements, &#39;releasing satellites&#39;, or showing off. That will mess up our common prosperity. We must do it.&quot; Lower your body and do it.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lower your body and do it realistically. The key is to do it. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent times, we have traveled to the Guangdong-Hong Kong-Macao Greater Bay Area, Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei, the Yangtze River Delta, and the Northeast region to seek the connection point between Chinese-style modernization and the actual conditions of various places and the starting point for coordinated advancement. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Practice is the key word. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Party Central Committee has high hopes for Zhejiang, emphasizing that &quot;some forward-looking and forefront countries should consider Zhejiang&quot; and hopes that Zhejiang will &quot;always be practical, at the forefront, and bravely at the forefront.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Practical work&quot; is placed at the top of the positioning of Zhejiang. When he was working in Zhejiang, Comrade Xi Jinping added these four words in front of the Party Central Committee&#39;s request for Zhejiang to &quot;be at the forefront&quot; and believed that it was the way to achieve the goal. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ancients said: &quot;Don&#39;t listen to lies, don&#39;t listen to charlatanism, don&#39;t use famous names, and don&#39;t create falsehoods.&quot; During that period, Comrade Xi Jinping spent 10 months traveling to 11 cities in the province, 69 counties, &quot;going out early and returning late, like guerrillas&quot;, proposed the &quot;Eight-Eight Strategy&quot; based on in-depth research and designated the second year of the strategy as the &quot;Year of Implementation&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;I believe in action.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Zhijiang News&quot; has many articles about hard work, such as &quot;Grassing without doing anything is equal to wasting&quot;, such as &quot;Grassing without doing anything is equal to nothing&quot;, such as &quot;Grasp Implementation is like hammering a nail&quot;, and another example is &quot;implementation can produce results&quot;. To lower one&#39;s body means to grasp things in a down-to-earth manner, and to do things in a down-to-earth manner, without talking about things in vain. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the years, we have chosen to be consistent in our choices, whether to rush forward impetuously and push back what we have to encourage others, or to act within our capabilities and do our best, from striving for a well-off society to promoting common prosperity. As early as the 10th meeting of the 19th Central Financial and Economic Committee in 2021, when studying &quot;common prosperity&quot;, General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out the direction: &quot;We must coordinate needs and possibilities, and base the protection and improvement of people&#39;s livelihood on economic development and financial sustainability. On the basis of the above, do not aim too high, exaggerate your appetite, and make promises that cannot be fulfilled.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lowering your stature implies respect for the rules. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping once said: &quot;Leaders must have standards. Where does the level come from? The level comes from the understanding and grasp of objective laws, and the regular things are contained in the practice of the broad masses of the people. .&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This time in Zhejiang, General Secretary Xi Jinping visited Yiwu International Trade City. Many people remember his innovations in Yiwu&#39;s institutional mechanisms: &quot;Children who grow up quickly must be given big clothes.&quot; During this period, we not only grasped the law of China&#39;s county economic transformation, but also grasped the development law of reform and opening up. Now we are promoting the start of a new growth cycle under the &quot;dual cycle&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“There must be a law for everything, and then it can be done.” Respecting the laws is the basic essence of mastering the scientific method. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chinese-style modernization is an unprecedented and pioneering undertaking. How to promote common prosperity, which is one of the characteristics? Adopt the method of pilot exploration and throwing stones to ask for directions, then promote it when it is stable, and accumulate small wins into big wins. Today, Zhejiang is taking the lead in promoting common prosperity, &quot;crossing the river by feeling for the stones is by feeling for the rules.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It not only deploys the task of &quot;crossing the river&quot;, but also guides the solution of &quot;bridge&quot; and &quot;ship&quot; problems. Reducing oneself and being cautious are prerequisites for accurately recognizing changes, responding scientifically, and actively seeking change. To promote the &quot;double carbon&quot; work, General Secretary Xi Jinping has repeatedly warned that &quot;you cannot throw away the food you are eating first&quot; and cannot stop coal and reduce carbon emissions through campaigns. The development of emerging industries does not mean a one-size-fits-all approach, and we cannot abandon traditional industries. When he visited Zhejiang this time, the General Secretary emphasized: &quot;When grasping the digital economy and virtual economy, we must not forget that the real economy is the foundation.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Prudence lies in fearing the small, and wisdom lies in managing the big.” Keeping your body low and taking steps step by step is “caution”, and grasping the rules and piercing the clouds and mist is “wisdom.” With &quot;caution&quot; and &quot;wisdom&quot; working in harmony, you can be calm and calm, have insight into the current situation, and make a journey of thousands of miles in the midst of turmoil. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Some colleagues recalled that year: Faced with the pain of transformation in Zhejiang’s development, there was once a voice that “the ‘Zhejiang Model’ has reached the end of its road.” “Secretary Xi was very calm and pointed out clearly in several meetings that Zhejiang The problems we are facing now are all problems in development, and their root cause is the extensive growth model.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Lowering your stature is rooted in the concept of political achievements. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“After the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, various regions have been very motivated to pursue development. We must establish a correct view of political performance and prevent impulsiveness in political performance.” Recently, seeing the signs of “impulsiveness”, the General Secretary has repeatedly Reminder: &quot;We must always insist on basing ourselves on reality and making scientific decisions, insist on taking a long-term view, lay a solid foundation, and persist in doing practical things and striving for practical results.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Only by having a clear understanding of &quot;manifest achievements&quot; and &quot;potential achievements&quot; can we be more optimistic. Keep your body low, keep your perspective level, work hard and work hard. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past 20 years, Zhejiang has successfully solved the &quot;growing pains&quot; through the persistent implementation of the &quot;Eight-Eight Strategy&quot;. During this inspection, General Secretary Xi Jinping summed up the inspiration of the &quot;88th Strategy&quot; and said: &quot;The reason why it is effective is that a blueprint has been drawn to the end and has been consistent for 20 years. If orders are changed day by day, any good measures will be just words on paper and will be in vain.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;New ideas and new strategies for governing the country contain the concept of political performance. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The &quot;Two Mountains Theory&quot; back then, the concept that clear waters and lush mountains are mountains of gold and silver, has become a consensus across the country today. &quot;We cannot follow the path of rushing to catch up, fishing for nothing, and focusing only on GDP.&quot; This view of political performance focuses on the sustainable development of the Chinese nation and has the foresight and foresight that &quot;success does not have to be mine.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At that time, Comrade Xi Jinping proposed the &quot;Yangtze River Delta Summit&quot; with the main leaders of provinces and cities participating in the &quot;Yangtze River Delta Summit&quot; based on the pattern of &quot;stepping out of Zhejiang and developing Zhejiang&quot;. The first summit was held in Hangzhou in 2005. &quot;Will it cause the hollowing out of Zhejiang&#39;s industries?&quot; Faced with the question, he proposed &quot;Yangtze River Delta integration&quot; at the meeting. Nearly 20 years have passed, and this idea has enriched Zhejiang and rejuvenated the Yangtze River Delta. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The foundation of the concept of political performance lies in the people. &quot;Consider serving the people and benefiting the people as the most important political achievements.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It’s like a “ten million project”. &quot;Ten million&quot; is not just a number, but a glimpse of countless villages, and a promise that &quot;not one can be left behind.&quot; There is no grandeur, but a steady accumulation year after year, moistening things silently. Peaches and plums, the next from Seikei. It has been 20 years since I visited Li Zucun in Yiwu this time. General Secretary Xi Jinping reminded me that &quot;no one can be missing for common prosperity.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 图片报道]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/28/nw.D110000renmrb_20230928_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, September 28, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20230928/1695844733086_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/ TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;The National Day is approaching, and the flower arrangements along Tiananmen Square and Chang&#39;an Street have been completed and met with the audience. They have attracted many citizens and tourists in recent days. . &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The giant flower basket in Tiananmen Square has a top height of 18 meters, with the festive flower basket as the main scene. For the first time, the festive harvest grains (rice, wheat, millet, yellow rice, soybeans) are selected in the basket, and combined with beautiful The symbolic flowers represent the abundance of flowers and abundant harvests. The picture shows a giant flower basket on Tiananmen Square on September 27. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Photographed by our reporter&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chen&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Bin&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 坚持立足实际、科学决策]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/28/nw.D110000renmrb_20230928_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, September 28, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;The key to comprehensively building a modern socialist country and comprehensively promoting the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation lies in the party and the key to people. During his recent inspection in Zhejiang, General Secretary Xi Jinping put forward clear requirements for upholding and strengthening the party&#39;s overall leadership, strengthening and improving party building, emphasizing &quot;establish a correct view of political performance, insist on being based on reality and scientific decision-making, persist in taking a long-term view, lay a solid foundation, and persist in We must be practical, strive for practical results, and prevent formalism and bureaucracy.” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When officials start a business, they must establish and practice a correct view of political performance, and effectively solve the problems of who to create performance for, what kind of performance to create, and how to create performance. At present, our country&#39;s development has entered a period when strategic opportunities and risks and challenges coexist, and uncertain and unpredictable factors are increasing. To turn the grand blueprint drawn up by the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China into a beautiful reality, it is urgent for leading cadres at all levels to overcome difficulties, take on responsibilities, and truly Work hard. Since the beginning of this year, General Secretary Xi Jinping has emphasized on many occasions the establishment of a correct view of political performance, pointing out that &quot;firmly establish a view of political performance that benefits the people, adhere to the people-centered development idea, and adhere to high-quality development&quot;, requiring &quot;rectification of formalism, bureaucracy and &quot;Placing doctrine in a more prominent position&quot; is precisely to promote the orientation of the majority of party members and cadres to correct their work, enhance their motivation, form a synergy of work, firmly establish and practice a correct view of political performance, continuously improve their ability to promote high-quality development, and serve the people capabilities, the ability to prevent and resolve risks, and forge ahead on a new journey and build a new era with enthusiasm. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Insisting that everything should be based on reality is the starting point and final point for us to think about problems, make decisions and do things. Acting according to rules and regulations are principles that party members and cadres must adhere to. Chinese-style modernization is the largest modernization in human history, and it is also the most difficult modernization. We can neither aim too high nor stick to the old ways. We must fully consider the issue of population base and the reality of the large differences in development levels between urban and rural areas in our country. Only by persisting in seeking truth from facts and being pragmatic can we advance the unprecedented pioneering cause step by step. It is necessary to plan careers and work based on reality, so that the proposed ideas, policies, and plans conform to the actual situation, objective laws, and scientific spirit, and implement the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee through creative work. We must overcome the urge to work hard and get ahead quickly, suppress the impetuous and impatient mentality such as eager for quick success and quick results, set unrealistic goals, do not engage in blind comparisons that are divorced from reality, and carry out modernization in a down-to-earth manner. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Scientific decision-making and creative responses are the fundamental ways to turn crises into opportunities. Improving the ability to solve practical problems is an urgent need to cope with complex situations and complete arduous tasks. To achieve scientific decision-making, we must first have a strategic vision, see far and think deeply, find out the strategic positioning in the overall situation of the country, be good at integrating the work of regions and departments into the overall chessboard of the party and the country&#39;s undertakings, and achieve both Win glory and add luster to the overall situation. Investigation and research are the basis for planning and the way to achieve success. Without investigation, there is no right to speak, let alone decision-making power. Investigation and research must be regarded as a basic skill, and we must go deep into the grassroots, the masses, and reality to truly understand the situation, pinpoint the problems, and propose practical countermeasures. It is necessary to carry out in-depth research and comprehensive analysis, listen to opinions from multiple parties, and consciously ask the people for their plans and needs, so that decisions can be consistent with the actual situation, and prevent decisions made on the head and rash actions on the chest. For important decision-making plans, especially important policies and measures involving the vital interests of the people, the opinions of the people must be widely listened to. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;During an inspection in Zhejiang, General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out: &quot;For more than 20 years, through the persistent implementation of the &#39;Eight-Eight Strategy&#39;, Zhejiang has transformed from a small resource province to a large economic province, from a &#39;high pressure&#39; environment to a The historic leap of building a beautiful Zhejiang and taking the lead in achieving a moderately prosperous society in all respects to achieving a high level of moderate prosperity in all respects has also set an example for the whole country.&quot; The successful practice of the &quot;Eight-Eight Strategy&quot; proves that insisting on being based on reality and scientific decision-making is the key to entrepreneurship. Basics and premises. We must unite more closely around the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core, persist in using Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era to arm our minds, guide practice, and promote work, firmly establish and practice a correct view of political performance, and use a new atmosphere and a new In order to achieve new results in promoting high-quality development, we will make achievements worthy of the times, history and the people on the new journey. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 十年经验弥足珍贵  未来前景催人奋进]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/28/nw.D110000renmrb_20230928_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, September 28, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;“On the new journey, we must deeply implement the free trade pilot zone improvement strategy based on a comprehensive summary of ten years of construction experience. We must be brave enough to be the pioneers who forge ahead and overcome difficulties, carry out exploration in wider areas and at a deeper level, and strive to build a higher-level free trade pilot zone.&quot;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;General Secretary Xi Jinping has recently made in-depth efforts to promote the free trade pilot zone. Important instructions were given for the construction of the free trade pilot zone, which fully affirmed the achievements and experience of the ten-year construction of the free trade pilot zone, pointed out the direction for building a higher-level free trade pilot zone, focused on deepening reform and opening up on the new journey, and triggered a wave of enthusiasm among the broad masses of cadres and the masses. Strong response. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;On September 29, 2013, China’s first free trade pilot zone, the China (Shanghai) Pilot Free Trade Zone, was unveiled and put into operation. Over the past ten years, the Party Central Committee has deployed and established 21 free trade pilot zones in six batches, forming an innovative development pattern of reform, opening up, covering the east, west, south, north, and middle, and coordinating the coastal, inland and border areas. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions highly summarize the remarkable achievements of the ten-year construction of my country’s free trade pilot zones, which makes people feel very excited and proud.” Yang Zhengwei, Director of the Department of Coordination of Free Trade Zone and Port Construction of the Ministry of Commerce He said that ten years of experience is extremely precious and the future prospects are inspiring. We must follow the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions, thoroughly implement the free trade pilot zone improvement strategy, and be the pioneers to forge ahead and overcome difficulties, in wider areas and Carry out deeper exploration and strive to build a higher-level free trade pilot zone. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized “the need to uphold the party’s overall leadership.” Everyone agreed that this is the fundamental political guarantee for the ten-year construction of the Pilot Free Trade Zone, and that the party&#39;s leadership must be adhered to throughout the entire process of the construction of the Pilot Free Trade Zone. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“The China Pilot Free Trade Zone is different from other free trade zones in the world, which is reflected in its adherence to the leadership of the Party and the socialist system with Chinese characteristics.” China World Trade Organization Research Institute, University of International Business and Economics Dean Tu Xinquan said that General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions reflect the Party Central Committee’s consistent guidance and promotion of the construction of the free trade pilot zone. Adhering to the leadership of the party can ensure the correct political direction of the construction of the free trade pilot zone, help mobilize the enthusiasm of all parties to participate in exploration, construction and reform and innovation, and properly handle the relationship between promoting institutional openness and strengthening risk prevention. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Institutional innovation is the core task of building a free trade pilot zone. Gu Jun, director of the Shanghai Municipal Development and Reform Commission, said that at the new starting point, the Shanghai Pilot Free Trade Zone will follow the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions, firmly grasp the core task of institutional innovation, and expand foreign investment market access and cross-border data management. Conduct greater stress tests in key areas such as , offshore RMB transactions, etc., to ensure that they are both liberalized and controlled, and to explore ways to promote China-style modernization. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions encourage us to base ourselves on our jobs, test the system for the country, seek development for the local area, and better stimulate the innovative vitality of business entities.” Work at the Construction Project Approval Department of the Administrative Approval Bureau of Guangzhou Nansha District He Teng, a staff member, said that it is necessary to take institutional reform and innovation as the starting point to promote the creation of a market-oriented, legal, international and first-class business environment with higher standards, greater intensity, and more practical measures. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions put forward higher requirements for the construction of free trade pilot zones to be more systematic, holistic and coordinated.” Cui Weijie, deputy director of the Institute of International Trade and Economic Cooperation of the Ministry of Commerce, said, As reform and opening up enters the &quot;deep water zone&quot;, each trade pilot zone must pay more attention to the integration and innovation of institutional systems in exploring wider areas and deeper levels, giving full play to the superposition effect of institutions. At the same time, from an overall and systemic perspective, break the constraints that restrict development. point of obstruction. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Currently, Suzhou Industrial Park, located in the Jiangsu Pilot Free Trade Zone, is promoting the mutual recognition pilot of special items risk assessment results integrated in the Yangtze River Delta. Jiang Xuesong, chief of the Comprehensive Business Section of the Suzhou Industrial Park Customs Office in Weiting, said that General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions have put forward new and higher requirements for front-line supervision personnel to strengthen policy implementation. &quot;We will continue to guide enterprises to make full use of customs clearance facilitation measures, strengthen cross-regional and cross-department policy coordination and linkage, so that business entities have a stronger sense of gain.&quot;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xiamen Area Management Committee of Fujian Pilot Free Trade Zone Dai Bin, Director of the Bureau of Finance and Financial Services, believes that General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions have pointed out the direction for the construction of the free trade pilot zone to plan the entire process and entire chain of industrial development and promote development to a greater extent. The Xiamen area of ​​the Fujian Pilot Free Trade Zone should base on its own resource endowments and advantages, accelerate cross-strait industrial integration and innovative development of the entire industry chain, and accelerate the cultivation of internationally competitive industrial clusters. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Chen Yangsheng, Vice President of Chia Tai Pharmaceutical (Qingdao) Co., Ltd., said that General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions will promote various fields to accelerate the deep integration of the industrial chain and the innovation chain and the collaborative innovation and development of upstream and downstream. Riding on the momentum of further promoting the construction of free trade pilot zones, the company has established strategic cooperative relationships with scientific research institutes and universities to accelerate the transformation of industry-university-research results. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Looking forward to the future, everyone unanimously expressed the need to be a pioneer in forging ahead and overcoming difficulties, so that the free trade pilot zone can better play a demonstration role. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“General Secretary Xi Jinping proposed to build a higher-level free trade pilot zone, and we are more confident.” CEO of Qinhe (Hainan) Intelligent Technology Co., Ltd., which settled in the Hainan Free Trade Port in March last year Zhao Jian said that the company has felt the continuous optimization of Hainan&#39;s business environment, and will seize the opportunities of free trade port construction to promote its own development in the future, and use more innovative momentum to assist the construction of Hainan free trade port. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions are a sincere entrustment and an important encouragement.” Yang Chunting, director of the Guangxi Pilot Free Trade Zone Work Office, said that the Guangxi Pilot Free Trade Zone is the only free trade pilot in the country that has both coastal and border areas. District, the new journey will focus on the coordinated development of border and port industrial parks, promote the formation of more leading and iconic institutional innovations, create a core area that serves domestic and international dual circulation, facilitate market operations, and a cross-border industrial chain and supply chain for ASEAN agglomeration area. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;(Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, September 27)&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 努力建设更高水平自贸试验区（权威发布）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/28/nw.D110000renmrb_20230928_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, September 28, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;This year marks the 10th anniversary of the construction of the China Pilot Free Trade Zone. On September 27, the State Council Information Office held a press conference. Relevant officials from the Ministry of Commerce, the Ministry of Transport, the General Administration of Customs, and the State Administration of Foreign Exchange introduced the 10th anniversary of the construction of the free trade pilot zone. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since 2013, in accordance with the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee and the State Council, our country has established 21 free trade pilot zones in 6 batches. Over the past 10 years, the Pilot Free Trade Zone has launched a large number of basic and pioneering reform and opening-up measures, formed many iconic and leading institutional innovations, and cultivated a number of internationally competitive industrial clusters. In 2022, with a land area of ​​less than 4‰, the 21 pilot free trade zones contributed 18.1% of the country&#39;s foreign investment and 17.9% of the import and export trade, which further increased to 18.4% and 18.6% in the first half of this year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The negative list for foreign investment access in the Pilot Free Trade Zone has been “cleared” in the manufacturing industry&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vice Minister of Commerce Sheng Qiuping said that over the past 10 years, Commerce The Ministry, together with relevant regions and departments, supports the respective pilot trade zones in fully promoting reform, opening up and innovation in relevant fields, exploring new ways and accumulating new experience for comprehensively deepening reform and expanding opening up. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Systematically promote institutional innovation. It has successively submitted to the Party Central Committee and the State Council to issue 28 free trade pilot zone construction plans and a number of high-quality policy documents, and has deployed a total of more than 3,400 reform pilot tasks, forming a relatively complete free trade pilot zone policy and institutional framework system. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Collaborate to promote the implementation of tasks. The Office of the Inter-Ministerial Joint Conference on the Work of the Pilot Free Trade Zone coordinated and promoted various localities and departments to better complete a series of major reform pilot tasks. The member units of the joint meeting have issued more than 700 documents supporting the construction of the pilot free trade zone, and support the pilot free trade zone in exploring key areas. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Copy and promote the reform pilot experience. Up to now, the national level has summarized and refined 7 batches of reform pilot experience and 4 batches of best practice cases based on the advanced experience formed by the exploration of free trade pilot zones, and replicated and promoted a total of 302 institutional innovation results nationwide, forming a sharing of reform dividends and openness results. A good situation for inclusiveness. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sheng Qiuping said that the negative list for foreign investment access in the Pilot Free Trade Zone has been &quot;cleared&quot; of the manufacturing industry, and the next step will be to focus on promoting the opening of the service industry. We will work with relevant departments to conduct in-depth research and promote the rational reduction of the negative list for foreign investment in the pilot free trade zones. At the same time, we will promote the introduction of a negative list for cross-border service trade and lead the country&#39;s continued expansion of opening up. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Introducing a large number of important basic reforms and high-level opening-up measures&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Being the first to implement the pre-establishment national treatment plus negative list management model for foreign investment, Be the first to establish a trade facilitation model with the &quot;single window&quot; as the core for international trade, be the first to promote the comprehensive opening of the service industry represented by the negative list management model of cross-border trade in services, be the first to implement government management reforms such as &quot;separating licenses from licenses&quot;, and be the first to explore free trade Account... Over the past 10 years, the Pilot Free Trade Zone has adhered to high-level openness as its guide, focused on exploring an institutional system that is connected with international economic and trade rules, systematically promoted reforms in line with market laws, and achieved a series of breakthrough and leading innovation results. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen Zhenchong, Director of the Free Trade Zone and Special Area Development Department of the General Administration of Customs, introduced that the Customs takes institutional innovation as the core and takes replicability and promotion as the basic requirements, and strives to create a high-level, high-energy platform for opening up to the outside world. The State Council has experienced 7 batches of reform pilots, with a total of 162 items, of which Customs contributed 62 items, accounting for 38.3%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Use institutional mechanisms to standardize innovation and enhance the “gold content” of innovation initiatives. Establish a customs supervision innovation system of &quot;1 standard + 3 procedures&quot;, form a &quot;two up, two down&quot; working mechanism, focus on benchmarking new rules, service new business formats, etc., and carry out innovation work. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Serve the country’s major regional strategies. The customs offices in the pilot free trade zones of each region actively carry out collaborative innovation. For example, Beijing, Tianjin, and Shijiazhuang, Hebei, that is, the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei customs innovated the &quot;Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei collaborative new model for risk prevention and control of imported medical devices without online verification&quot; to enhance the effectiveness of medical device entry verification and collaboratively improve the level of risk prevention and control. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Make reference to international high-standard economic and trade rules and create an institutional open highland. Actively research and propose 11 customs measures to be piloted in qualified free trade pilot zones and free trade ports to meet high international standards. These have been incorporated into several measures issued by the State Council. Some measures such as minor errors in certificates of origin have been issued by the customs and implemented. Effective. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;交通运输部水运局负责人易继勇介绍，交通运输部加强航运管理制度政策改革创新，下放管理权限，提高政务服务效率。指导相关自由贸易试验区建立特殊的国际船舶登记制度，优化办理程序。截至2023年7月，已有100艘船舶、905万载重吨在自贸试验区办理国际船舶登记。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国家外汇管理局外汇研究中心主任丁志杰介绍，2013年以来，国家外汇管理局在自贸试验区分6批先行先试24项外汇管理创新措施。相关措施有效提升经营主体外汇资金使用的自由与便利度，政策红利逐步显现。 2022年，自贸试验区跨境收支同比增长14.7%，比全国高出8.7个百分点。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;推动特色优势产业创新发展，不断培育壮大发展新动能&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据介绍，10年来，商务部会同有关地方和部门，积极推动自贸试验区特色优势产业创新发展，不断培育壮大发展新动能。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一是明确产业发展方向。支持各地因地制宜，开展差别化探索，促进特色产业集群高质量发展。二是推动产业集成创新。支持自贸试验区围绕产业发展全链条、企业发展全周期，开展系统集成改革，打通产业发展的难点堵点，锻造长板，补齐短板。三是优化产业发展环境。持续推动贸易、投资、金融、科技等领域改革创新，推动资本、技术、人才、数据等各类要素的自由便捷流动，促进创新链产业链深度对接，营造市场化、法治化、国际化的营商环境。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10年来，各自贸试验区主动加强协同创新，探索推进联动发展，放大改革综合效应，取得积极成效。北京、天津和河北自贸试验区建立京津冀联席会议制度，推出了153项政务服务“同事同标”事项，实行区域通办。广西自贸试验区打造西部地区最便捷的出海口，有效加强与西南、西北、中南骨干通道的衔接，服务西部大开发。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“商务部将与有关地方和部门一道，深入学习贯彻习近平总书记重要指示精神，坚持以高水平开放为引领、以制度创新为核心，统筹发展和安全，高标准对接国际经贸规则，深入推进制度型开放，加强改革整体谋划和系统集成，推动全产业链创新发展，更好发挥自贸试验区示范作用。”盛秋平说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 工业企业效益恢复向好态势明显]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/28/nw.D110000renmrb_20230928_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月28日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报北京9月27日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者刘志强）27日，国家统计局发布的工业企业利润数据显示：8月份，规上工业企业利润同比增长17.2%，自去年下半年以来，工业企业当月利润首次实现正增长。其中，工业品价格降幅连续2个月明显收窄，企业营收连续3个月下降后首次增长，带动工业企业利润由降转增，效益恢复向好态势明显。今年以来，工业企业利润降幅逐月收窄。 1至8月份，规上工业企业利润同比下降11.7%，降幅较1至7月份收窄3.8个百分点，回升明显加快。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;随着工业生产稳步回升，产销衔接状况好转，工业企业营收逐步改善。 1至8月份，全国规上工业企业营业收入同比下降0.3%，降幅较1至7月份收窄0.2个百分点。其中，8月份企业营业收入在连续3个月下降后首次实现增长，由7月份同比下降1.4%转为增长0.8%，为利润由降转增创造了有利条件。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;三大门类利润均有改善，七成以上行业利润回升。 1至8月份，采矿业利润同比下降20.5%，降幅较1至7月份收窄0.5个百分点；制造业利润下降13.7%，降幅收窄4.7个百分点；电力、热力、燃气及水生产和供应业利润增长40.4%，增速加快2.4个百分点。分行业看，在41个工业大类行业中，有30个行业利润增速加快，或降幅收窄、由降转增，行业改善面超七成。 &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 守护土壤健康  发展智慧农业]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/28/nw.D110000renmrb_20230928_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月28日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;第三十届中国杨凌农业高新科技成果博览会（以下简称“农高会”）9月23日在陕西杨凌落下帷幕。展会为期5天，103.35万人次现场参观，项目签约投资和交易金额达1112.77亿元。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“土壤健康与粮食安全”为今年农高会的重中之重。2023年全球土壤健康论坛于9月19日至20日举办，聚焦黑土、盐碱土、红壤、水稻土和黄土等重要土壤类型的保护和利用，凝聚国际共识，发布《2023全球土壤健康杨凌倡议》。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;南非农业、土地改革和农村发展部副部长卡帕说：“这是我第一次参加专门讨论土壤健康的国际论坛，与会国家能够共同关注这个议题，我很感动。”&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;今年12月5日将迎来第十个世界土壤日。据联合国粮农组织统计，全球已有1/3的土地因侵蚀、盐碱、酸化等问题出现不同程度退化，改善土壤健康迫在眉睫。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“中国愿与各方加强土壤健康领域合作，搭建合作平台，开展联合研发，密切人员交往，为保障全球粮食安全、应对气候变化、推动落实联合国2030年可持续发展议程作出积极贡献。”农业农村部部长唐仁健说。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;今年中央一号文件提出，加快农业农村大数据应用，推进智慧农业发展。本届农高会上，9000多项农业高新科技成果集中亮相，全方位展示了农业科技新理念、新成果、新装备、新应用、新模式。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;在未来农业智能装备专题展上，一台机器人进行番茄采摘，吸引参观者驻足。“智农番茄采摘机器人主要用于农业园区、标准化温室种植等场景，对采摘果实的3D空间位置可以进行毫米级识别。”北京中科原动力科技有限公司采摘机器人项目工程师海丹说，“参展期间，我们与陕西的农业企业达成合作，为更多智慧农场提供农业机器人产品和解决方案。”&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;在农业高新技术成果展北京展区，一款畜禽健康状况巡检机器人亮相。工作人员王艾萌介绍，通过机器人的前置摄像头，可以监控、记录和分析畜禽健康状况，收集温度、湿度等环境数据，“节省人工巡检80%以上的工作。”&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;本届农高会上，来自49个国家和地区的2000多家单位参展参会。乌兹别克斯坦是本届农高会主宾国，展出了鹰嘴豆、蜂蜜、果干等特色农产品以及民族手工艺品。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;在荷兰展区，现代种植产业链展览展示让人耳目一新。13家企业带来的农业高科技覆盖水果蔬菜花卉育种、智能温室设计建造、智慧农业设施设备、农业人工照明等现代种植产业链各个环节。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;在阿富汗展区，参观者停下脚步，欣赏沙姆斯从阿富汗带来的精美地毯。沙姆斯大学期间主修中文，如今在上海创办了公司。“去年我参加农高会，将中国的温室大棚引进阿富汗，非常受欢迎；今年我对机械采摘臂很感兴趣。”沙姆斯说。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;杨凌农高会创办30年来，已累计吸引70多个国家和地区的上万家涉农企业和科教单位参展，3300多万名客商和群众参展参会，参展项目及产品超过18万项，发布推出科技成果和专利1.26万余个，累计促成投资与交易额超过1万亿元。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;本届农高会首次走出国门，在位于乌兹别克斯坦的上合组织农业基地中国（陕西）商品交易中心设立展区，展示农业技术及特色农产品、农机装备等，实现以会为媒，推动中国农业扩大高水平对外开放。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - “一定要放低身段来干这件事”（微观察·习近平总书记浙江之行）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/28/nw.D110000renmrb_20230928_5-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月28日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;这番话，放在正在建设共同富裕示范区的浙江来讲，面向的既是“中国式现代化的先行者”，也是走在强国建设、民族复兴新征程上的中国：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这里勇担使命，就是在高质量发展建设共同富裕示范区上积极探索，努力形成可借鉴、可推广、可复制的经验做法。但也不是去搞福利主义、&#39;养懒汉&#39;，走向过去那种公共食堂，那不行。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在浙江省委和省政府工作汇报会上，习近平总书记讲到这里，提醒道：“要实事求是、步步为营、稳扎稳打，一定不要有标新立异、好大喜功、&#39;放卫星&#39;、作秀出彩的思想。那会把我们好端端的共同富裕搞砸了。一定要放低身段来干这件事。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;放低身段，落点在实，关键在干。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近段时间，赴粤港澳大湾区、京津冀，到长三角、东北地区，谋的是中国式现代化与各地实际的结合点、统筹推进的发轫点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;实干是关键词。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;党中央对浙江寄予厚望，强调“把一些前瞻的、前列的国家考虑放在浙江这个地方”，希望浙江“始终干在实处、走在前列、勇立潮头”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“干在实处”置于对浙江定位的首位。当年在浙江工作时，习近平同志在党中央给浙江的要求“走在前列”前面，加了这四个字，认为它是实现目标的途径所在。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;古人曰：“不受虚言，不听浮术，不采华名，不兴伪事。”那一时期，习近平同志用10个月时间跑了全省11个市、69个县，“早出晚归，就像游击队”，在深入调研的基础上提出“八八战略”，并把战略提出的第二年定为“狠抓落实年”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我是崇尚行动的。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《之江新语》有多篇文章讲实干，如《抓而不实，等于白抓》，如《抓落实如敲钉子》，再如《落实才能出成绩》。放低身段，形容的就是实实在在地抓，脚踏实地地做，不虚谈废务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些年，是急躁冒进、拔苗助长地干，还是量力而行、尽力而为地做，从奔小康到推进共同富裕，选择一以贯之。早在2021年十九届中央财经委员会第十次会议，研究“共同富裕”时，习近平总书记就指明了方向：“要统筹需要和可能，把保障和改善民生建立在经济发展和财力可持续的基础之上，不要好高骛远，吊高胃口，作兑现不了的承诺。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;放低身段，蕴含着对规律的尊重。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记曾经讲过：“领导要有水平，水平从哪里来？水平来自对客观规律的认识和掌握，而规律性的东西，正是蕴藏在广大群众的实践中。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次在浙江，习近平总书记去了一趟义乌国际商贸城。很多人都记得他当年对义乌体制机制的创新：“得给成长快的孩子换上一件大衣服”。这期间，既把握了中国县域经济转型规律，也抓住了改革开放的发展规律，现如今又在“双循环”下推动开启新的成长周期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“事必有法，然后可成。”尊重规律，正是掌握科学方法的基本要义。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;中国式现代化，一场前所未有的开创性事业。特征之一的共同富裕，如何推进？采取试点探索、投石问路的方法，稳当了再推广，积小胜为大胜。如今，浙江在推进共同富裕中先行示范，“摸着石头过河就是摸规律”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;既部署“过河”的任务，又指导解决“桥”和“船”的问题。放低身段、谨慎待之，是准确识变、科学应变、主动求变的先决条件。推进“双碳”工作，习近平总书记再三叮嘱“不能把手里吃饭的家伙先扔了”，不能运动式停煤降碳。抓新兴产业发展，不是搞一刀切、大呼隆，不能把传统产业扔了。这次到浙江，总书记就强调：“抓数字经济、虚拟经济，一定不要忘了实体经济是基础”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“慎在于畏小，智在于治大”，放低身段、步步为营是“慎”，把握规律、穿云拨雾为“智”。“慎”与“智”协奏，便能冷静从容、洞察时势，于风云激荡间而就万里之行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;有同事回忆当年：面对浙江发展的转型之痛，一度有声音认为“&#39;浙江模式&#39;穷途末路”了，“习书记非常冷静，在几次会议上都鲜明指出，浙江现在面临的问题都是发展中的问题，根子就是粗放型的增长方式”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;放低身段，根子在政绩观。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“党的二十大后各地谋发展、抓发展的劲头很足，要树立正确政绩观，防止政绩冲动。”近来，看到“冲动”这一苗头，总书记一再提醒：“要始终坚持立足实际、科学决策，坚持着眼长远、打牢基础，坚持干在实处、务求实效。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;清醒认识“显绩”与“潜绩”，才能放低身段、放平视角，真抓实干、埋头苦干。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;20年来，通过持之以恒实施“八八战略”，浙江成功破解了“成长的烦恼”。这次考察，习近平总书记总结“八八战略”的启示说：“之所以有成效，就是一张蓝图绘到底，一以贯之20年。朝令夕改，那任何好的举措都是纸上谈兵，都将付诸东流。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;治国理政的新理念、新方略，处处蕴含政绩观。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当年的“两山论”，绿水青山就是金山银山的理念，今天在全国已成共识。“不能走那种急就章、竭泽而渔、唯GDP的道路”，这一政绩观着眼于中华民族的永续发展，有“功成不必在我”的胸襟远见。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当年，习近平同志以“跳出浙江发展浙江”的格局，提议由省市主要负责同志参加“长三角峰会”，第一次峰会2005年在杭州召开。“会不会造成浙江的产业空心化？”面对疑问，他在会上提出“长三角一体化”。近20年过去了，这一思路润泽了浙江，也焕新了长三角。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政绩观的根本，在人民。“把为民办事、为民造福作为最重要的政绩”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;就像“千万工程”。“千万”不只是一个数字，而是无数乡村的掠影，是“一个都不能少”的承诺。没有轰轰烈烈，而是年复一年的厚积薄发、润物无声。桃李不言，下自成蹊。20年了，这次考察到义乌的李祖村看一看，习近平总书记叮嘱，“共同富裕一个都不能少”。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 图片报道]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/28/nw.D110000renmrb_20230928_6-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月28日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20230928/1695844533263_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;青海省海西蒙古族藏族自治州积极发展枸杞产业，枸杞种植总面积约45万亩，其中有机产品认证面积近13万亩，成为全国有机枸杞种植面积最大的地区。图为海西都兰县宗加镇诺木洪村群众在晾晒枸杞。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;本报记者&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;贺&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;勇摄&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 28 Sep 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>