<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平离京赴美国举行中美元首会晤 同时出席亚太经合组织第三十次领导人非正式会议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20231115_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 15, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 14th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;On the evening of November 14th, President Xi Jinping left Beijing by special plane , at the invitation of US President Biden, he went to San Francisco, the United States, to hold the China-US Presidential Meeting, and was also invited to attend the 30th APEC Leaders’ Informal Meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Accompanying Xi Jinping on his visit are: Cai Qi, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and director of the General Office of the CPC Central Committee, Wang Yi, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Minister of Foreign Affairs, and others. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平向2023两岸企业家峰会10周年年会致贺信]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20231115_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 15, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Congratulatory letter&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;On the occasion of the 10th anniversary of the Cross-Strait Entrepreneurs Summit, I would like to express my warm congratulations and extend my sincere greetings to all members and guests of the summit! &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The economies on both sides of the Taiwan Strait belong to the Chinese national economy, and the compatriots on both sides of the Taiwan Strait are a community with a shared future. The Cross-Strait Entrepreneurs Summit is an important platform for exchanges and cooperation between cross-Strait enterprises and business people. It has played an important role in promoting cross-Strait economic cooperation and deepening cross-Strait integrated development. It is hoped that the summit will broadly unite the business and industrial circles on both sides of the Taiwan Strait and make new contributions to strengthening the Chinese national economy, improving the well-being of compatriots, and promoting the great cause of the reunification of the motherland. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Achieving the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation will open up broad space for cross-Strait economic cooperation, and realizing the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation requires the joint efforts of compatriots on both sides of the Taiwan Strait. We will continue to work to promote cross-Strait economic exchanges and cooperation, deepen cross-Strait integrated development in all fields, improve systems and policies that enhance the well-being of Taiwan compatriots, and help Taiwan compatriots and Taiwanese enterprises integrate into the new development pattern and achieve high-quality development. We hope that entrepreneurs on both sides of the Taiwan Strait will uphold national justice, grasp the general trend of history, bravely shoulder the responsibilities of the times, jointly promote the peaceful development and integrated development of cross-Strait relations, and jointly create the great historical cause of motherland reunification and national rejuvenation! &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;November 14, 2023&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>; (Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 14) &amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 14th Congratulatory letter. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that the economies on both sides of the Taiwan Straits belong to the Chinese national economy, and the compatriots on both sides of the Taiwan Straits are a community of shared future. The Cross-Strait Entrepreneurs Summit is an important platform for exchanges and cooperation between cross-Strait enterprises and business people. It has played an important role in promoting cross-Strait economic cooperation and deepening cross-Strait integrated development. It is hoped that the summit will broadly unite the business and industrial circles on both sides of the Taiwan Strait and make new contributions to strengthening the Chinese national economy, improving the well-being of compatriots, and promoting the great cause of the reunification of the motherland. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that realizing the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation will open up broad space for cross-Strait economic cooperation, and that realizing the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation requires the joint efforts of compatriots on both sides of the Taiwan Straits. We will continue to work to promote cross-Strait economic exchanges and cooperation, deepen cross-Strait integrated development in all fields, improve systems and policies that enhance the well-being of Taiwan compatriots, and help Taiwan compatriots and Taiwanese enterprises integrate into the new development pattern and achieve high-quality development. It is hoped that entrepreneurs on both sides of the Taiwan Strait will uphold national justice, grasp the general trend of history, bravely shoulder the responsibilities of the times, jointly promote the peaceful development and integrated development of cross-Strait relations, and jointly create the great historical cause of motherland reunification and national rejuvenation. (The full text of the congratulatory letter will be issued separately)&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The 10th anniversary annual meeting of the 2023 Cross-Strait Entrepreneurs Summit, with the theme of &quot;Integrated Development and High-Quality Development in the New Pattern&quot;, opened in Nanjing, Jiangsu on the 14th. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 2023两岸企业家峰会10周年年会开幕式在南京举行]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20231115_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 15, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Nanjing, November 14th&amp;nbsp; Held in Nanjing. Wang Huning, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Chairman of the National Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference, attended the event, read out General Secretary Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter and delivered a speech. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Wang Huning said that General Secretary Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter clarified the consensus and truth that the economies on both sides of the Taiwan Strait belong to the Chinese national economy and that the compatriots on both sides of the Taiwan Strait are a community with a shared future. It declared its commitment to promoting cross-Strait economic exchanges and cooperation and deepening cross-Strait integration in all fields. The principled stance of developing and assisting Taiwanese compatriots and Taiwanese enterprises to integrate into the new development pattern and achieve high-quality development fully reflects the care and concern for the business circles, industrial and commercial circles on both sides of the Taiwan Strait, and the majority of Taiwanese compatriots and Taiwanese enterprises. We must follow the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter as a guide to make the Cross-Strait Entrepreneurs Summit better and better. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Wang Huning said that comprehensively building a modern socialist country and comprehensively promoting the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation with Chinese-style modernization provide great opportunities and broad space for Taiwan compatriots and Taiwanese enterprises to develop in the mainland. Mainland China was, is and will certainly be the best choice for Taiwanese compatriots and Taiwanese companies to invest and start businesses in the future. We actively comply with the common aspiration of compatriots on both sides of the Taiwan Strait to seek peace, development, exchanges, and cooperation. We always uphold the concept of &quot;one family on both sides of the Taiwan Strait,&quot; respect, care for, and benefit our compatriots in Taiwan. We strengthen cross-Strait economic cooperation, deepen cross-Strait integrated development, and strive to strengthen cross-Strait economic cooperation and deepen cross-Strait integrated development. Contribution to the Chinese nation’s economy. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Wang Huning said that the peaceful development of cross-Strait relations is most in line with the vital interests and common aspirations of compatriots on both sides of the Strait, and is most in line with the development trend of the times. We hope that compatriots on both sides of the Taiwan Strait will join hands to stand firmly on the right side of history, share national justice and the responsibilities of the times, firmly hold the future and destiny of both sides of the Taiwan Strait in our own Chinese hands, and seek peace for the Taiwan Strait, reunification for the country, and rejuvenation for the nation. . &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Liu Zhaoxuan, chairman of the Taiwan side of the summit, said in his speech that in the past ten years, the summit has built a platform for cross-strait industrial cooperation on the basis of the &quot;1992 Consensus&quot; and contributed to the peaceful development of cross-strait relations. The mainland is building a new development pattern, providing new opportunities for enterprises on both sides of the Taiwan Strait to join hands in high-quality development. It is hoped that both sides will actively promote the peaceful and integrated development of cross-Strait relations and jointly create a better vision. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Before the opening ceremony, Wang Huning met with business representatives from both sides of the Taiwan Strait. Wang Dongfeng, Guo Jinlong and Zhang Ping attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;While in Jiangsu Province, Wang Huning visited Nanjing University, Taihu Laboratory of Deep Sea Technology and Science, Wuxi Qingshan Senior High School, Nanjing Taiwan Youth Entrepreneurship College, Nanjing Yunjin Museum, Niushou Mountain Cultural Park, Jiulong Lake Discussion Study Room and Relevant enterprises visited members of the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference and officials of the Jiangsu Provincial Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference in Nanjing. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 形成推动高质量发展的强大动力（全面辩证长远看待当前经济形势·记者观察）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20231115_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 15, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;To look at the economic situation rationally and calmly, we must look at both &quot;absolute results&quot; and &quot;relative results.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The increase in some key economic indicators is obvious and tangible, which is the &quot;absolute achievement&quot; of China&#39;s economy. Taking the economic growth rate as an example, the GDP in the first three quarters increased by 5.2% year-on-year, of which the growth in the third quarter was 4.9%. Both indicators ranked among the best among major economies. The growth rate has brought about solid increments, and the overall economic recovery has become more obvious. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Relative performance&quot; cannot be ignored either. In some cases, we should seize the opportunity early and continue to resolve hidden risks. Some are making precise efforts to continuously solve the problem of unbalanced and inadequate development. These achievements are not necessarily reflected in the data, but they play an important role in the stability of the overall economic and social situation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The overall economic recovery is improving, high-quality development is solidly advanced, and people&#39;s lives continue to improve. This is the combined result of &quot;absolute performance&quot; and &quot;relative performance&quot;. Only by taking a comprehensive, dialectical and long-term view can we accurately grasp the positive factors in economic development and form a powerful driving force to promote high-quality development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking at quality, growth momentum will accelerate the conversion. More and more people are driving new energy vehicles. In the first ten months, my country&#39;s new energy vehicle production and sales increased by 33.9% and 37.8% year-on-year respectively. When the &quot;Twelfth Five-Year Plan for the Development of National Strategic Emerging Industries&quot; was released in 2012, the new energy vehicle industry was a relatively late start. By increasing policy incentives, conquering key technologies, and improving infrastructure, the new energy vehicle industry has transformed and become an unquestionable &quot;absolute achievement.&quot; Relevant research shows that for every 1 yuan of added value in the automobile manufacturing industry, it can drive 2.64 yuan in added value to upstream and downstream related industries, and new energy vehicles can drive even more industrial links. From a longer perspective, today&#39;s &quot;leading&quot; of new energy vehicles is not achieved overnight, but comes from more than 20 consecutive years of accumulation. Maintain strategic focus, be patient, stick to the bottom line, make up for weaknesses, and strengthen strengths. &quot;Relative results&quot; will eventually be exchanged for &quot;absolute results&quot; one after another. There are many such bright spots. New industries and products such as new generation information technology and high-end equipment manufacturing that have experienced similar development trajectories are now developing strongly and continuously opening up new space for economic development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking at vitality, progress has been made in structural adjustment. Since the beginning of this year, contact and aggregation service industries have maintained rapid growth. At the Hangzhou Asian Games, sports and culture blended together, and the wave of spectators brought a tourism boom. During the Mid-Autumn Festival and National Day holiday, the place is bustling with tourists. In the first three quarters, service retail sales increased by 18.9% year-on-year, and the proportion of residents&#39; per capita service consumption expenditure in residents&#39; per capita consumption expenditure increased by 2 percentage points year-on-year. The development of the service industry has become an important highlight in this year&#39;s economic growth. The service industry is the main channel for attracting employment and expanding investment. As favorable factors continue to accumulate, the &quot;new engine&quot; of the service industry will surely provide inexhaustible impetus for sustained and healthy economic development. From industrial structure to investment structure to major regional strategies, whether it is &quot;absolute&quot; growth in numbers or &quot;relative&quot; shortcomings that are gradually being made up, we have witnessed that economic development is becoming increasingly coordinated and optimized. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Looking at the potential, economic transformation and upgrading will continue to advance. Development requires long-term accounts, overall accounts, and comprehensive accounts. The “gold content” in the “report card” is reflected in the synergistic effect of green transformation and economic growth. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For example, in the first three quarters, the proportion of sections with excellent water quality increased by 0.8 percentage points year-on-year, and the &quot;three new&quot; products such as electric passenger vehicles, lithium-ion batteries, and solar cells continued to maintain rapid growth momentum. Carbon reduction, pollution reduction, green expansion, and growth are promoted in a coordinated manner, and green has become a distinctive background for high-quality development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;If we look at &quot;absolute performance&quot; and &quot;relative performance&quot; comprehensively, we can see long-term growth trends through short-term fluctuations. The fundamentals of my country&#39;s long-term economic growth have not changed and the development prospects are bright. With firm confidence and facing difficulties, we will be able to achieve high-quality development while overcoming risks and challenges. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A comprehensive view of &quot;absolute achievements&quot; and &quot;relative achievements&quot; is, in the final analysis, a concrete manifestation of the worldview and methodology of dialectical materialism and historical materialism, especially the persistence and application of Marxist standpoints, viewpoints and methods. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Adhere to bottom-line thinking and coordinate development and safety. &quot;Absolute achievements&quot; can move forward without the protection of &quot;relative achievements&quot;. To maintain the country&#39;s &quot;five major security&quot;, we must estimate the difficulties more fully, think more deeply about the risks, stabilize the overall situation, make overall coordination, implement classified policies, accurately dismantle bombs, and strive to prevent and resolve major risks, so as to ensure the smooth progress of socialist modernization. Advance. Take food security as an example. We feed ourselves, and this achievement is hard-won. During this year&#39;s summer harvest, the main production areas suffered from &quot;bad rain&quot;, and they harvested, dried and aired day and night, and the summer grains were harvested again. During the &quot;Three Autumn Periods&quot;, we provide precise early warning and strengthen field management to ensure a bumper crop of autumn crops. It is precisely because of &quot;always worrying&quot; and always tightening the string of food security that we can keep our jobs firmly in our hands. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Adhere to strategic thinking and coordinate the current and long-term. &quot;Absolute achievements&quot; and &quot;relative achievements&quot; test the concept of development as well as the concept of political performance. Before the storm, we must maintain a calm mind and focus on the present while focusing on the long term. Do more things that lay the foundation and benefit the long-term, and be willing to &quot;the predecessors plant trees, and the descendants can enjoy the shade.&quot; For example, we will increase efforts to protect people&#39;s livelihood, continue to strengthen basic assistance to needy groups, consolidate and expand the results of poverty alleviation, and solve the urgent, difficult and anxious problems of the people. Only by drawing a blueprint to the end and working one term after another can we accumulate latent achievements into manifest achievements and turn latent achievements into manifest achievements, further boost the economy and strive to promote high-quality development. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 确保供给安全  服务保障大局（高质量发展调研行）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20231115_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 15, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;In early winter, the weather is getting colder, but various places insist on paying equal attention to development and safety, and strive to promote high-quality development. In Heilongjiang, large-scale agricultural machinery carries out protective farming such as deep raking and straw mulching, covering the black soil with a layer of winter &quot;quilt&quot; that maintains nutrients and increases soil fertility; in Shaanxi, the protection of water sources in the middle line of the South-to-North Water Diversion Project is further advanced. The water quality of the Han River&#39;s outlet from Shaanxi has been stable and maintained at the national surface water level II standard; in Xinjiang, the scale of Xinjiang&#39;s coal exports has steadily increased, and more and more coal has been converted into electric energy to serve the development of various regions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: &quot;For a big country like ours, ensuring the supply of primary products is a major strategic issue. We must strengthen strategic planning and make early adjustments to ensure supply security.&quot;&lt;/p>; p>;&lt;p>;Implementing the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important instructions, the three provinces of Heilongjiang, Shaanxi, and Xinjiang are based on their own realities, proactively ensuring the supply security of food, energy resources, ecological products, etc., and making every effort to promote high-quality development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;We must always put ensuring national food security in the first place&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: “Food security is the ‘greatest concern of the country’” and “we must always put Ensuring national food security comes first.” &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the courage to shoulder the responsibility for food security, the three provinces strive to improve their comprehensive food production capabilities and accelerate the modernization of agriculture and rural areas. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The black soil is known as the &quot;giant panda in the cultivated land&quot;. In recent years, Heilongjiang has regarded protecting black soil and building fertile farmland as important measures to serve as the &quot;ballast stone&quot; for national food security. It has given priority to building black soil into high-standard farmland and effectively protected black soil. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the fields in the fourth management area of ​​Beidahuang Group Friendship Farm Co., Ltd., a special strip tillage machine rotary tilled a 50-centimeter-wide black soil strip on a 1.3-meter-wide ridge, and the straw was Push to cover large ridges on both sides. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“This not only retains the decomposed nutrients of the straw, but also plays a role in conserving water. Next year, no-till sowing can be done on the rotary-tilled black soil strips.” Agricultural Development Department of Youyi Farm Co., Ltd. Minister Tang Cao Jiazi introduced that this is a farming model experiment explored and carried out by the company in conjunction with the Northeast Institute of Geography and Agroecology, Chinese Academy of Sciences. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, Beidahuang Group has continued to cooperate with agricultural research institutions to implement the &quot;Black Soil Granary&quot; technology battle project, built a 20,000-acre demonstration area, and carried out 25 technologies such as three-dimensional monitoring and systematic protection of black soil in small watersheds. Research. Improvements in soil quality have helped Beidahuang Group increase its grain production capacity from 41.88 billion jins in 2017 to 45.13 billion jins in 2022. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Heilongjiang continues to promote the integrated improvement of high-standard farmland construction, erosion gully management, and farmland shelterbelt construction. So far, the province has completed a total of 125 million acres of straw returning to farmland and 33.81 million acres of protective farming area. It has implemented 50 demonstrations of precise and standardized loss-reducing pesticide application technology on 1,000 acres of farmland in 26 counties, and built new fertilizer technologies, new fertilizer products, There are 11 provincial-level demonstration areas for new fertilization equipment, and more than 4.61 million acres of aviation and chemical operation display areas and black soil organic conversion areas have been constructed. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Heiliangwan Village, Baojiadian Town, Manas County, Xinjiang, all tractors are equipped with satellite navigation driverless systems as well as new precision seeders, smart sprayers and other new equipment. Just operate the application on your mobile phone, and the electric valve can be remotely activated within 3 seconds, and water and fertilizer will quickly flow into the roots of the corn along the drip irrigation belt. &quot;This year, 450 acres of seed corn have been planted. One person can take care of the work in the field, and the yield is much higher than before.&quot; Villager Zhang Xinxin said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Shaanxi, various regions are working hard to seize Chinese seeds and ensure food security from the source. As a national-level seed production county, Huayin City, Shaanxi’s improved wheat varieties have been promoted nationwide. The best varieties are selected, agricultural technology services the whole process of planting, social services are delivered to the fields, and order purchase guarantees farmers&#39; income... A single grain of wheat seed is fully cared for here through the entire process of selection, planting, management and harvesting. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Shaanxi Yangling Agricultural High-tech Industry Demonstration Zone, scientific researchers have cultivated more than 1,100 new varieties. The &quot;Three-Year Action Plan for the Construction of Improved Crop Breeding Bases in Shaanxi Province&quot; issued this year proposes to consolidate the development of improved seed breeding areas and improve comprehensive seed production capabilities. It is expected that by the end of 2025, the four major crop seed breeding bases of wheat, corn, rape, and tomato will be built with 490,000 acres and above. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;We must do a good job in modern energy economy&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: “Energy security and security are related to the national economy and people’s livelihood, and cannot be ignored for a moment. &#39;The great country&#39;&quot; &quot;must do a good job in modern energy economy.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Adhering to bottom-line thinking, the three provinces have given full play to their own resources and industrial advantages, and actively made new contributions to securing energy &quot;jobs&quot; and strengthening energy security. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To secure the energy “job”, we need to protect the bottom line of energy consumption for people’s livelihood. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A few days ago, good news came from the Tarim Basin in Xinjiang: my country&#39;s first Wanmike exploration well, Shendi Take 1 Well, has been drilled to a depth of more than 8,000 meters and is advancing into deeper strata. As of October 30, Tarim Oilfield had completed oil and gas production of 27.74 million tons this year, a year-on-year increase of 380,000 tons. As the main gas source for my country&#39;s west-east gas pipeline and the primary gas source in southern Xinjiang, the Tarim Oilfield provides domestic gas guarantee for southern Xinjiang and 15 provinces, striving to ensure that &quot;there will never be a short supply or a day&#39;s supply interruption.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xinjiang is not only rich in oil and gas resources, but also ranks among the top in the country in terms of coal resource reserves, wind energy and solar energy resources. Since the launch of Xinjiang&#39;s external power transmission in 2010, as of the end of August this year, Xinjiang&#39;s cumulative external power transmission has exceeded 700 billion kilowatt-hours, covering 20 provinces. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To secure the energy “job”, we need to follow the path of green and low-carbon development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As a major coal production and supply province, Shaanxi’s level of intelligent construction of coal mines ranks among the top in the country. Artificial intelligence, industrial Internet of Things, cloud computing and other technologies are deeply integrated with coal development and utilization, transforming the coal industry from &quot;coal mining skills&quot; to &quot;intelligent coal mining&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the coal mining working face of Shaanxi Coal Caojiatan Mining Company located 330 meters underground in Yulin City, Shaanxi Province, the hobs of the intelligent fully mechanized mining working face with a super large mining height of 10 meters are flying, and &quot;black gold&quot; is flowing. The commissioning of this project has set many world records such as a total mining height of 10 meters, an installed power of 22,000 kilowatts, and a single-sided production capacity exceeding 20 million tons. &quot;From design to manufacturing, from chips to screws, they are all made in China,&quot; said Wang Rui, the company&#39;s chief engineer. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With just a click of the mouse on the intelligent monitoring center platform, you can control the huge &quot;underground dragon&quot;; the underground intelligent inspection robot shuttles back and forth, providing 360-degree real-time monitoring; and the big data cloud computing platform is used to realize monitoring. Three-dimensional monitoring of the mine environment... There is no coal in sight, and no one is needed to dig coal. Intelligent scenarios have been integrated into every aspect of coal production. As of the first half of this year, Shaanxi has built 117 intelligent coal mining working faces and 75 intelligent tunneling working faces. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To secure the energy “job”, we need to promote the development of new energy and clean energy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The clear blue sky stretches as far as the eye can see, dotted with white clouds. The neat rows of photovoltaic panels in front of us mark the integration of the new energy business of Daqing Oilfield into the main business and the overall acceleration of development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In July 2022, the Daqing Oilfield Xinghuo Water Surface Photovoltaic Demonstration Project was connected to the grid to generate electricity. The project construction area is 400,000 square meters, the installed capacity is 18.73 megawatts, the average annual power generation is 27.5 million kilowatt-hours, and the carbon dioxide emissions are reduced by 22,000 tons. Converted into thermal power generation with the same power generation capacity, it can save 8,400 tons of standard coal every year, reduce smoke emissions by about 84 tons, sulfur dioxide by about 134 tons, and nitrogen oxides by about 63.9 tons. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Vigorously cultivating new energy and new business formats, Daqing Oilfield strives to build a green industrial structure and a low-carbon energy supply system. During the &quot;14th Five-Year Plan&quot; period, Daqing Oilfield will build a green, low-carbon and sustainable development demonstration base, with the installed capacity of new energy reaching more than 2 million kilowatts and a clean energy replacement rate of more than 20%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Supporting high-quality development with a high-quality ecological environment&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: “Place the construction of a beautiful China in a prominent position in building a strong country and rejuvenating the nation. &quot;Support high-quality development with a high-quality ecological environment and accelerate the modernization of harmonious coexistence between man and nature.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Firmly establishing the concept of green development, the three provinces maintain the strategic determination to strengthen the construction of ecological civilization, solidly protect the ecological environment, and make every effort to build a strong ecological security barrier. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Keep the baseline and make good combos. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shaanxi insists on protecting the ecology of the Yellow River Basin as the baseline for planning development and promoting high-quality development, continues to strengthen the ecological protection and restoration of the Yellow River Basin, actively improves the normal and long-term protection system and mechanism of the Qinling Mountains, and takes multiple measures to improve The level of ecological civilization construction. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Enter Nangou Village, Ansai District, Yan&#39;an City. Relying on &quot;channel damming, Liangmao land preparation, and hillside greening&quot; to control water and soil erosion, Nangou Village has completed the transformation of &quot;Bald Maomao into a green sea, and the ditch is transformed into a green sea.&quot; The butterfly change of &quot;Daodaosaijiangnan&quot;. This is a microcosm of the control of soil and water loss in the Loess Plateau. In recent years, the average annual yellow sediment input in Shaanxi has reduced from 830 million tons to 268 million tons. The Loess Plateau has become the area with the greatest greening in the country. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the Qinling Mountains ecological environment protection information grid supervision platform, &quot;satellite eyes&quot; guard the Qinling Mountains around the clock. &quot;Even changes such as garbage accumulation can be accurately captured.&quot; Cheng Xiaoying, leader of the monitoring team of the supervision platform operation and maintenance center, said that the application of a variety of high-tech means has enabled Qinling protection to achieve &quot;seeing from the sky, checking online, and managing on the ground&quot; &quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Implement systematic governance and promote ecological restoration. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xinjiang is promoting the integrated protection and restoration project of mountains, rivers, forests, fields, lakes, grass and sand in the important source area of ​​the Tarim River (Aksu River Basin) in accordance with local conditions and time. Among them, the ecological restoration and desertification control project in the Aisiman area of ​​Aksu Prefecture has completed the restoration and treatment of a total area of ​​about 200,000 acres. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jogging or walking on Kekeya Road is a habit that Aksu citizen Saimati Gapar has developed in recent years. &quot;I have imagined the tree-lined Kokoya countless times, and now it has become a reality.&quot; As one of the builders of the Kokoya desert greening project, Saimaiti knows that the blue sky and green trees in front of him are hard-won. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After more than 30 years of continuous construction, the Aksu region has built an ecological security barrier 57 kilometers long and 46 kilometers wide on the northwest edge of the Taklimakan Desert. Today, the Kekeya Ecological Engineering Zone has afforestation of more than 1.2 million acres, and the forest coverage rate has increased from 8% in 1986 to 73% in 2020. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ecology itself is the economy, and protecting the ecology is developing productivity. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Establishing the concept that adding green is to increase advantages and protecting forests is to protect wealth, Heilongjiang Province actively broadens the path for transforming green waters and green mountains into mountains of gold and silver, turning the &quot;green treasure basin&quot; into more of a &quot;treasure basin.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Using agricultural facilities and idle resources around the forest, Longjiang Forest Industry Group focuses on building a high-end forest fruit and vegetable industry. Currently, it has built 1,040 standardized forest fruit and vegetable greenhouses and built a &quot;cold land dragon fruit&quot; demonstration base of 15,000 acres. , constructing 41,200 acres of forest orchards. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This year, Longjiang Forestry Group will focus on cultivating seedling bases. So far, there are 100 standardized nurseries in the entire forest area, with a total operating area of ​​20,600 acres and a nursery scale of more than 200 million plants. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“At the busiest time, I work from 5 a.m. to 5 p.m. every day.” Han Shouliang, the person in charge of the Chenjialiangzi Ginkgo Planting Demonstration Base of Longjiang Forestry Group Founder Forestry Bureau Co., Ltd. said that the Ginkgo Planting Demonstration Base established last year The 500-acre Ginkgo Industrial Planting Demonstration Base has achieved good economic benefits. “Now there is even more momentum for development!”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Our reporters Cui Jia, Li Yanan, Yuan Taoxiong, and Liu Mengdan)&lt;/p>;&lt; !--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 前三季度新设民营企业增长15.3%]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20231115_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 15, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Our newspaper, Beijing, November 14th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Lin Lili) A reporter from the National Market Supervision Bureau on the 14th The General Administration was informed that in the first three quarters, 7.065 million new private enterprises were established across the country, a year-on-year increase of 15.3%. As of the end of September, the number of registered private enterprises nationwide exceeded 52 million, and private enterprises accounted for 92.3% of the total number of enterprises. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The regional development of private enterprises is more balanced. In the first three quarters, private enterprises in the four major sectors of East, Central, West and Northeast all maintained a steady and positive development trend. There were 3.51 million new private enterprises established in the eastern region, a year-on-year increase of 12.6%; 1.766 million new private enterprises were established in the central region, an increase of 16% year-on-year; 1.49 million new private enterprises were established in the western region, an increase of 23.3% year-on-year; new private enterprises were established in the northeastern region There were 299,000 enterprises, a year-on-year increase of 7.4%. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The industrial structure of private enterprises is constantly optimized. In the first three quarters, the number of newly established private enterprises in the primary, secondary and tertiary industries was 284,000, 1.116 million and 5.665 million respectively, with the tertiary industry accounting for more than 80%. Relying on the advantages of a strong market, the people&#39;s livelihood industries that are closely related to people&#39;s lives continue to develop rapidly. The growth rates of newly established private enterprises in the &quot;accommodation and catering industry&quot;, &quot;leasing and business services industry&quot; and &quot;wholesale and retail industry&quot; reached 40.3%, 23.1% and 23.1% respectively. 17.4%. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 下足绣花功夫  创新社会治理]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20231115_7-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 15, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out: “To do a good job in urban work, we must first understand, respect and comply with the laws of urban development, and correct urban development. Guiding Thought &quot;&quot;To find a new path of social governance that conforms to the characteristics and laws of megacities is a major issue related to the development of Shanghai.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shanghai is a megacity with a permanent population of 25 million. It has a high degree of openness to the outside world, active economic activities, high urban population density, diverse interest demands, and diverse grassroots conflicts and disputes. Based on the characteristics of a megacity, Shanghai has adhered to and developed the &quot;Maple Bridge Experience&quot; in the new era in recent years. It has made great efforts in internationalization, legalization, refinement, and intelligence, and strived to improve the multi-dimensional prevention, mediation and resolution mechanism of social conflicts and disputes, and strive to resolve conflicts and disputes. It is resolved at the grassroots level and in the bud. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Solve the practical difficulties of the masses with refined management&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shanghai has a highly aging population, and installing residential elevators has become an urgent wish for many elderly people. Since 2020, the Shanghai Municipal Party Committee and Municipal Government have promoted the public support project and completed the installation of more than 4,000 elevators in three years. However, during the advancement process, the different demands of residents upstairs and downstairs caused some new conflicts and disputes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The key is to do mass work in depth and detail.” Ding Bojie, deputy secretary of the Political and Legal Committee of the Shanghai Municipal Party Committee, said that to uphold and develop the “Maple Bridge Experience” in the new era, we must firmly focus on doing mass work well. The main line is to clarify the complicated ownership relationships from a legal perspective and to calculate the accounts of people&#39;s hearts clearly from a rational point of view. Once the people understand and understand it, there will be no unsolvable knots. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Hongkou District Hydropower Community was built in the 1980s. After the installation of elevators was launched in 2021, there were some conflicts and disputes, and the elevator installation project encountered obstacles. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When soliciting opinions in the early stage, in accordance with the provisions of the Civil Code and other laws and regulations, construction can start when the proportion of agreed owners reaches the legal proportion. &quot;Even if the standards are met, conflicts will occur during the construction phase.&quot; Qiu Xiangqin, secretary of the Party branch of the hydropower residential area, said, &quot;When installing elevators, residents often call the police due to disputes.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March 2022, Hongkou The district issued relevant opinions on comprehensively promoting the operation mechanism for the investigation and resolution of conflicts and disputes, exploring the &quot;three-firm linkage&quot; of police stations, judicial offices, and law firms, and &quot;twisting together&quot; police officers, people&#39;s mediators, and lawyers. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The procedures for installing elevators are legal and compliant, and the construction team must not be hindered from entering the site. Even if they go to court, they will not get support.” Starting from 2022, we will receive more complaints about the installation of elevators in hydropower communities. In case of conflicts and disputes, the police, people&#39;s mediators, lawyers and residents meet together. After listening to the explanation of the law, many residents no longer objected blindly, but made demands. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Affect privacy? Install frosted glass to protect against privacy. Afraid of noise? Install double glazing for sound insulation. Can not move? The elevator company builds barrier-free passages for free... &quot;We coordinate and resolve the reasonable demands of residents one by one.&quot; Qiu Xiangqin said. Under the &quot;three-institution linkage&quot; mechanism, the elevator company, property owners committee, and residents&#39; autonomous group also participated to form a &quot;special team for adding elevators&quot; to visit more than 600 households with objections and collect and summarize the difficulties in installing elevators in each building. Formulate a &quot;one ladder, one plan&quot; to fully resolve residents&#39; demands. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Today, all residents of the 29 buildings in the hydropower community have completed the consultation process. After all elevators are installed, more than 1,800 residents will benefit. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Refined governance, for cross-regional, cross-department, and cross-industry conflicts, means adhering to source governance, systematic governance, making fists, and joint resolution, so that conflicts and disputes can be solved in the initial stage resolved at minimal cost. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In order to promote the acceptance and centralized handling of all types of disputes, Putuo District has transferred the resources and power to resolve conflicts to the grassroots. Dispute resolution centers have been established in 10 streets and towns in the region, and disputes are subdivided into four categories for &quot;graded diagnosis and treatment.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the establishment of the dispute resolution center in the streets and towns of Putuo District in 2022, it has accepted more than 21,000 conflicts and disputes, and the mediation success rate has reached 99.1%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Guiding foreign residents to integrate into social life with a sense of rules&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Jinfeng International Community is located in Hongqiao Business District, affiliated to Huacao Town, Minhang District, with 11 There are foreign-related communities and 4 international schools, with a permanent foreign population of 14,500 people from 76 countries and regions, accounting for 51.4% of the community’s permanent population. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The square dance is too loud, which affects our rest.” In July this year, Chinese and foreign residents of Vanke Hongjun Community in Jinfeng International Community complained constantly because of the noise caused by the square dance. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Residents have the right to rest quietly and the right to dance. In the process of mediating conflicts, we have to find a balance.” Song Yeping, secretary of the party branch of the residential area affiliated to Vanke Hongjun Community, said that for residents After complaining and soliciting opinions, everyone agreed that &quot;the balance lies in establishing rules that are agreed upon by all parties.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Soon, three decibel meters were erected around the square, and the residents agreed: the maximum volume of dancing music No more than 70 decibels. So, one side can continue dancing while the other side can be relatively quiet. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This is one of Huacao Town’s innovative practices in cultivating community life rules in response to residents’ strong awareness of rules and rights protection. In order to provide a platform for all parties in the community to establish rules and boundaries, and to use rules to reduce friction, Huacao Town has also cultivated and established the Jinfeng International Community Development Promotion Association, which includes 67 member units such as international schools and foreign-related enterprises. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In addition to neighborhood committees, the promotion association is a platform for foreign residents to express their opinions and consult on policies.” Meng Lu, secretary-general of the Jinfeng International Community Development Promotion Association, said, for example, garbage classification, foreign and Shanghai classification standards , methods, etc. are different. After understanding the confusion of foreign residents, we communicated with relevant departments to popularize my country&#39;s laws, regulations and classification methods to foreign residents in a targeted manner, avoiding conflicts and disputes caused by this. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As an international metropolis, there are many foreigners working, studying and living in Shanghai, and many foreign companies investing in Shanghai. &quot;Timely and effective resolution of conflicts and disputes between foreigners and between foreigners and Chinese residents is a question that an international metropolis must answer well in adhering to and developing the &#39;Maple Bridge Experience&#39; in the new era.&quot; Ding Bojie said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Shanghai International Tourism Resort, where Shanghai Disneyland is located, has received more than 113 million domestic and foreign tourists in the seven years since it opened. Zhang Zhiqun, captain of the Security Brigade of the International Tourism Resort Public Security Department of the Pudong Branch of the Shanghai Public Security Bureau, said that Disneyland has attracted a lot of attention, and a small quarrel may trigger heated discussions on social media. Discover and deal with it in time.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2020, the Shanghai International Tourism and Resorts Public Security Department built the &quot;Xiaodi Police Station&quot; in Disneyland, innovated the &quot;mobile mediation&quot; mechanism, and dispatched police and mediators every day. Members of the public should strengthen their on-duty duties in the park to realize that “wherever there are disputes, mediation will be done in advance.” Since the beginning of this year, 1,194 conflicts and disputes of various types have been successfully mediated here, with an effective mediation rate of 99%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Using intelligent means to unify the entrance to dispute resolution for the convenience of the public&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Resolve disputes in ‘one thing’, a ‘handheld supermarket’ that resolves disputes for you.” On the Shanghai &quot;One-stop Service&quot; platform, search for &quot;dispute resolution&quot; and select the corresponding module according to the type of dispute. You can then fill in the information and select the dispute resolution agency under the intelligent guidance of the platform... The online application takes less than 5 minutes, and you can also apply online You can check the &quot;process progress&quot; at any time on the platform. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In December 2022, &quot;Dispute Resolution &#39;One Thing&#39;&quot; was launched on various platforms of &quot;One Online Service&quot;, connecting with more than 6,700 dispute resolution agencies in the first batch, providing services including marriage and family, neighborhood, labor disputes, etc. More than 430 types of dispute resolution services. &quot;The resolution of conflicts and disputes in different fields has different professional needs, involving more than a dozen departments and nearly 10,000 dispute resolution agencies, and the parties may not understand them.&quot; Peng Sen, deputy director of the People&#39;s Participation and Rule of Law Promotion Department of the Shanghai Municipal Justice Bureau, said, If the entrances are not unified, it will make it inconvenient for people to apply, which is not conducive to the timely resolution of conflicts and disputes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In March this year, the Huangpu District People’s Mediation Committee for Medical-Patient Disputes received a dispute settlement application from the platform. The client, Xiao Xu, had double eyelid repair surgery at a medical institution, but the postoperative results were not satisfactory. After several communication difficulties, he submitted a dispute resolution application on his mobile phone. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“After receiving the application, I immediately contacted the parties and rushed to the hospital involved.” People’s mediator Feng Jianying has rich experience in the field of medical mediation. She organized face-to-face meetings between the two parties to explain the law from both medical and legal perspectives. Reasoning, guiding Xiao Xu to make rational appeals, telling the hospital that it needs to face up to its own responsibilities. After several rounds of mediation, both parties signed a mediation agreement, and the dispute was successfully resolved on the day of application. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Create a &#39;one thing&#39; platform for dispute resolution, realize intelligent matching and implementation of responsibilities through smart empowerment, and achieve &#39;full coverage, full coordination, full traces, and full supervision&#39; for dispute resolution.&quot; Zhang Yi, member of the Party Committee and Level 2 Inspector of the Shanghai Municipal Justice Bureau, said.今年1至8月，平台共接到市民群众解纷申请近1.7万件，受理纠纷约1.4万件，成功化解率达95%。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“坚持和发展新时代&#39;枫桥经验&#39;，需要更多接地气、有特色、真管用的基层实践。”丁伯婕说，上海鼓励各区因地制宜创新探索，最大程度将矛盾纠纷化解在基层、化解在萌芽状态，“希望通过更多的基层实践，努力走出一条符合超大城市特点和规律的社会治理新路子。”&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 渤海首个千亿方大气田Ⅰ期开发项目投产]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20231115_8-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月15日星期三&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231115/1699991901133_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;图为渤中19—6气田Ⅰ期开发项目。 &lt;BR/>;费振宇摄（人民视觉）&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报北京11月14日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者冉永平、丁怡婷）14日，渤海首个千亿方大气田——渤中19—6气田Ⅰ期开发项目投产，标志着我国海上深层复杂潜山油气藏开发迈入新阶段。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;渤中19—6气田位于渤海中部海域，区域平均水深约20米，目前已探明天然气地质储量超2000亿立方米、探明凝析油地质储量超2亿立方米，是我国东部第一个大型、整装的千亿方大气田。项目主要生产设施包括新建1座中心处理平台、3座无人井口平台和1座天然气处理终端，计划投产开发井65口，高峰日产油气超5000吨油当量。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;据悉，渤中19—6气田Ⅰ期开发项目完全由我国自主设计、建造、安装及生产运营，多项技术突破填补了国内海上油气田开发技术空白。项目65口生产井全部采用远程智能控制。作为国家天然气产供储销体系建设重点项目，渤中19—6气田的正式投产，将为渤海油田2025年实现上产4000万吨目标提供重要保障。 &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 高原小城牧“云”记（一线调研）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20231115_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月15日星期三&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231115/1699994938669_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;图为贵南县草原牧场风光。&lt;BR/>;贵南县委宣传部供图&lt;BR/>;数据来源：中央网信办、农业农村部等&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;今年中央一号文件提出，深入实施数字乡村发展行动，推动数字化应用场景研发推广。数字技术的广泛应用，推动着传统农业向智慧农业转型升级，也改变着农民衣、食、住、行，还带来公共服务、乡村治理的新变化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在青海，贵南县首批入选国家数字乡村试点。记者近日走进当地牧区，跟随一位牧民的脚步，看数字技术为乡村振兴带来的新机遇。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;——编&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;者&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;急弯陡坡，过了不知多少个；高山峻岭，翻了不知多少座。海拔一路攀升，直至3100米。崇山之中，到达了青海省贵南县过马营镇日安秀麻村的草场。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“一大早就看到微信群里有人说要卖牛。毛色发亮、两眼放光，我收的这5头牛不错！”说这话的人，声音听着老练，却是个穿着利落的年轻人，身材敦实、肤色黝黑。电子合同、手机转账，不到半小时，牦牛装车完毕。来不及擦拭裤腿上的泥点，他发动汽车继续奔忙，“得赶时间，72小时后，青海的牛肉要上江苏的餐桌。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;年轻人叫关却杰，90后，当地闻名的牧户。跟着他，记者深入高原牧区，看一个普通小城如何乘“云”驾“数”，奔往乡村振兴。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;数字养殖——&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;牛羊领到“身份证”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关却杰记事起，家里就养牛，故而他年纪不大，却是识牛的行家里手。凭着这份本事，2021年，他揣着6年攒下的20万元，辞职创业，干起牦牛收购、加工、出售的生意。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;青海是我国重要牧区，牦牛和藏羊存栏数分别占全国的34%和46%。贵南县的牛羊肉，洗净后加清水，无需繁复的调料，只一撮盐，味道就够鲜美。“但长期以来，&#39;质优价不优&#39;问题突出，需要以绿色现代农牧业发展需求为导向，向科技要动力、向创新要活力。”贵南县副县长赵学军说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2020年，中央网信办、农业农村部等7部门联合印发《关于开展国家数字乡村试点工作的通知》。贵南县作为青海首批入选试点地区之一，当年开始推广牦牛藏羊原产地可追溯平台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数字技术打通了贵南牛羊肉的生产、流通流程。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新出生的牛羊，由县畜牧兽医工作站逐个打上耳标，输入养殖信息，并在其成长过程中不断更新。当地23万余头牛、近100万只羊的信息可实时查询。“这就是牛羊的&#39;身份证&#39;，每头牛、每只羊都有独一无二的编号。”指向牛耳上3厘米见方的黄色耳标，关却杰解释道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;把牛卖给关却杰的是牧民齐军加。交易敲定前，他持编号信息在过马营镇兽医站完成出售前报备，“编号还跟牛羊保险绑定，能精准索赔。”交易完成后，牛被送至贵南县定点屠宰场，工作人员身穿防护服、手持小仪器，向牛耳轻巧一扫，核对信息、确保无误。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;待到牛肉在城里的超市上架，扫描包装上的二维码，养殖、运输等信息公开透明。“扫描二维码，说不定还能看见我的名字。”齐军加学会了新名词，“全过程追溯，消费者吃着放心，每斤肉能多卖十几元，这叫产品附加值！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;让牧民满意的，不止市场行情。2022年，贵南县建立了农牧业专业技术和实用人才信息库，牛羊有大小问题，牧民可随时以视频方式远程问诊。心无旁骛搞养殖，效率和效益双双提升。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;前不久，齐军加发现自家几头牦牛精神不振，好几天吃不下草料。要搁以前，他又要纠结，是赶紧跑上80多公里到县城看兽医，还是先观察几天情况再说。如今可不一样了，一个视频电话连线，贵南县畜牧兽医工作站站长王小红给出诊断：“草酸中毒，没什么大问题，下次喂草时加些小苏打。”果然，不到一周，牦牛情况好转。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;规模化养殖企业拥抱数字技术，动力更足。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;午后时分，走进青海老扎西有机农牧科技有限公司养殖基地，见不到一个工作人员。“我们在8个牛舍安装了16个监控摄像头，配备了温度传感器，坐在办公室就能看到牛群、牛舍状况，只有温度过高需要开窗通风时，才需要人员去现场。10个工作人员，看管1800多头牛绰绰有余。”基地负责人王世斌说，“牦牛在牧场上活动，通过耳标也能实时监控其定位和轨迹。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;数字电商——&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;牧区畅通“两条路”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从屠宰场回到公司，牛肉进一步被加工成肉眼、西冷、牛柳等9类产品。“精细化加工，精准对接市场需求，更能卖个好价钱。”关却杰正说着，门口响起鸣笛声，“快递员来了！”打包好的新鲜牛肉被搬上快递车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“最多一天能寄500多件，省内外都有。”关却杰的妻子项毛卓玛曾在城市生活7年多，如今在牧区，她感觉网上购物、寄送快递一样方便。“一件快递从上海到村里，只用了3天，还不收邮费，和城里没啥区别。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;农村电商，串起城乡。“畅通农产品上行和消费品下行渠道，要靠两条路，一条柏油路，一条信息路。”过马营镇镇长增太加表示。如今，青海所有乡镇已实现硬化路通达，所有行政村实现4G网络和光纤宽带双覆盖。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;基础设施建设短板补齐，关键还在应用。走在过马营镇主干道，圆通、中通、顺丰等9家快递公司的门脸依次排列。快递公司门口，收寄包裹井然有序；室内，电脑、扫描仪、快递架等一应俱全。这一切，得益于青海2015年启动的国家电子商务进农村综合示范工作，全省如今初步建成以县城为中心，辐射乡镇、村落的三级物流支撑体系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“2017年起，贵南县相继建成县级物流配送中心、6个乡镇快递服务站、77个村级服务点，快递网点行政村覆盖率达到100%。”贵南县发展和改革局局长索贝介绍，2012年，电商在当地还是稀罕物，到了2022年，贵南县农产品网络零售额已超过400万元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外部硬件升级，从业者的思维也要跟上。“酒香也怕巷子深，要变被动的等待式销售为主动的宣传推广式销售，打造自己的品牌，提升知名度和影响力。”关却杰最近忙着搭建公司的交易平台，一头连通收购，一头沟通销售，牧民登记牲畜信息更快捷，还可以通过电商平台对接市场需求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他还请朋友给公司设计了品牌标识，自学视频剪辑，通过短视频平台分享草原风光、产品信息，最火的一条视频播放量超过2万，吸引不少外地顾客留言购买。今年上半年，公司销售鲜牛肉、牛肉干等超过30万元，其中线上销售额达到16.7万元，占比超过55%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;依托对口支援机制，贵南县职业技术学校开办了电商直播培训班，请江苏的专业老师从直播间布置、直播软件使用、产品介绍技巧等方面进行授课，场场爆满。关却杰听完课，赶紧布置带货直播间，“要借助网络，把我们村的牛肉卖到更远的地方。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;数字政务——&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;村民告别“办事难”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关却杰的公司位于西久公路旁，这是进入贵南县城的必经之路，有些过路司机在这里乱扔矿泉水瓶、废纸，时间长了、垃圾成堆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关却杰打开“景秀森多”小程序，点击“百姓诉求”模块，上传照片和说明，没过多久，贵南县乡村数字信息化平台的工作人员便打来电话反馈说，将安排环卫工人来打扫。环卫工人整理完后，也会拍摄现场照片上传至后台，由专人审核，保证工作有效。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;开展国家数字乡村试点工作，贵南县首先思考的就是如何根据当地需求，以信息技术推进农业农村现代化。农牧区地广人稀，针对居住分散的群众“办事难”等情况，贵南县与中国联通青海省分公司合作，建设了乡村数字信息化平台。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;平台集成村级党务、政务、财务公开系统和缴费系统等，村民在手机上就能缴纳电费、宽带费，预约代办事项，还能了解最新村情及惠农补贴、养老金发放、劳动就业等信息……信息多跑路、村民少跑腿，乡村数字平台融入群众生活。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“农村信息基础设施的不断完善和数字乡村工程的扎实推进，将全面提升乡村治理能力和治理水平，促进社会运转效率提升，夯实乡村振兴基础。”中国联通青海省分公司党委书记、总经理童庆军介绍，截至2022年年底，公司助力253个乡镇、3853个行政村搭建了数字乡村平台，覆盖率达92.3%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“青海数字乡村建设要充分考虑农牧民实际情况和需求，让数字服务更有力度、有温度。”平台信息指挥中心主任旦正吉介绍，“&#39;百姓诉求&#39;模块支持语音、图片上传，更方便村民使用。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在贵南县这个高原小城，“互联网+”还便捷了就医服务。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;关却杰的父亲多科有高血压，2021年末在贵南县第二人民医院接受了远程会诊。之前看病，倘若去西宁，来回就得一天，人生路不熟，住宿、车费等花销也不小。“现在足不出镇，也能看上省城大医院的医生。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;多科定期复诊，不用带病历——县里实现人口数据、居民电子健康档案、电子病历等互联共享，各级医院互认互通，“都在&#39;云&#39;平台上存着呢，医生随时调用。”关却杰说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;数字管护——&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;巡护用上“千里眼”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;青海最大的价值在生态、最大的责任在生态、最大的潜力也在生态。地处黄河上游的贵南县，通过对天然草场进行区域划分，实施禁牧、休牧、轮牧等措施，同时实施节水灌溉、小流域治理、河道治理等工程，落实各级河渠库长177名、河渠库管护员238名，草原生态得到有效恢复。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，贵南县探索用数字技术保护生态的成果也越发显著。在沙沟乡，查纳村村级河长李海青例行巡视，注意到河中几束水草打着旋。他打开手机上的“河湖长通”软件，焦距拉近后拍照上传，“可能是违规采砂，河道不平容易产生漩涡。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“河湖长通”软件是贵南县对“智慧巡河”的新尝试。“河长巡河时，点开软件，系统会自动匹配巡河地图、河段等信息，还能显示时间、轨迹等。”贵南县县级总河长乔万玛才仁介绍。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没走多远，空中传来“嗡嗡”声，一架无人机在河道上盘旋。巡查人员盯着实时传回的画面，观察水体颜色、岸边建筑等。“无人机能更高效地拍摄记录大范围河面的情况。通过分析比对发现问题，大大提高了保护效率。”乔万玛才仁说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;不一会儿，李海青的电话响了。“您刚才上传的照片，我们实地看过了，没有发现采砂坑，是上游冲下来的石头挡了水流。”电话那头，管护员的话让李海青放心了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“参照巡河，我们向贵南县乡村数字信息化平台也提出建议，生态管护员巡护前打开定位功能，可以自动生成巡查路线。”乔万玛才仁说，“不久之后，草原生态管护也能用上无人机，结合监控布置，巡护有了&#39;千里眼&#39;，提高巡查效率，更好保护草场生态。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本期统筹：郭雪岩&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;版式设计：沈亦伶&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 确保供给安全  服务保障大局（高质量发展调研行）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20231115_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月15日星期三&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;初冬时节，天气渐冷，但各地坚持发展和安全并重、奋力推进高质量发展的场面火热。在黑龙江，大型农用机械开展深松耙地和秸秆覆盖等保护性耕作，为黑土地盖上一层保养分、增地力的过冬“棉被”；在陕西，南水北调中线工程水源地保护深入推进，汉江出陕断面水质稳定保持在国家地表水Ⅱ类标准；在新疆，疆煤外运规模稳步提升，越来越多的煤炭转化为电能服务各地发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记强调：“对我们这样一个大国来说，保障好初级产品供给是一个重大的战略性问题。必须加强战略谋划，及早作出调整，确保供给安全。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;贯彻落实习近平总书记重要指示精神，黑龙江、陕西、新疆三省份立足自身实际，积极主动确保粮食、能源资源、生态产品等供给安全，全力推进高质量发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;要始终把保障国家粮食安全摆在首位&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记强调：“粮食安全是&#39;国之大者&#39;”“要始终把保障国家粮食安全摆在首位”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;勇担粮食安全责任，三省份努力提高粮食综合生产能力，加快推进农业农村现代化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;黑土地被誉为“耕地中的大熊猫”。近年来，黑龙江把护黑土、建良田作为当好国家粮食安全“压舱石”的重要举措，优先把黑土地建成高标准农田，切实把黑土地保护好。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在北大荒集团友谊农场有限公司第四管理区的大田里，特制的条耕机在1.3米宽的大垄上旋耕出一条50厘米宽的黑土条带，将秸秆推移到两边覆盖大垄。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这样既保留住了秸秆腐化的养分，又起到涵养水分的作用，明年就可以在旋耕好的黑土条带上免耕播种。”友谊农场有限公司农业发展部部长唐曹甲子介绍，这是公司联手中国科学院东北地理与农业生态研究所探索开展的耕作模式实验。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，北大荒集团持续与农业科研机构合作实施“黑土粮仓”科技会战项目，建设了2万亩示范区，开展立体监测、小流域黑土地系统保护等25项技术研究。土壤质量的改善，助力北大荒集团粮食产能从2017年的418.8亿斤提高到2022年的451.3亿斤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;黑龙江持续推进高标准农田建设、侵蚀沟治理、农田防护林建设一体化提升。截至目前，全省共完成秸秆还田面积1.25亿亩、保护性耕作面积3381万亩，在26个县落实千亩农田精准规范减损施药技术示范50个，建设施肥新技术、肥料新产品、施肥新机具省级示范区11个，建设航化作业展示区、黑土地有机转化区等461万亩以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在新疆玛纳斯县包家店镇黑梁湾村，拖拉机全部配备卫星导航无人驾驶系统以及新式精量播种机、智能打药机等新型设备。只需操作手机上的应用程序，3秒内就能遥控启动电动阀门，水肥迅速顺着滴灌带流入玉米根部。“今年种了450亩制种玉米，地里的活一个人就能管过来，产量还比以前高不少。”村民张全新说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在陕西，各地努力攥牢中国种，从源头上保障粮食安全。作为国家级制种大县，陕西华阴市的小麦良种已推广全国。品种优中选优，农技服务种植全流程，社会化服务送到地头，订单收购保障农户收益……一粒小麦良种，在这里经历选、种、管、收全过程全方位呵护。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在陕西杨凌农业高新技术产业示范区，科研人员培育的新品种已达1100多个。今年出台的《陕西省农作物良种繁育基地建设三年行动方案》提出，巩固发展良种繁育面积，提高种子综合生产能力，预计到2025年底建成小麦、玉米、油菜、番茄四大作物良种繁育基地49万亩以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;要把现代能源经济这篇文章做好&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记强调：“能源保障和安全事关国计民生，是须臾不可忽视的&#39;国之大者&#39;”“要把现代能源经济这篇文章做好”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;坚守底线思维，三省份充分发挥自身资源和产业优势，积极为端牢能源“饭碗”、强化能源安全保障作出新贡献。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;端牢能源“饭碗”，需守住民生用能底线。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;日前，新疆塔里木盆地传来喜讯：我国首口万米科探井——深地塔科1井钻井深度已超过8000米，正在向更深地层挺进。截至10月30日，塔里木油田今年完成油气产量当量2774万吨，同比增长38万吨。作为我国西气东输的主力气源地和南疆首要气源地，塔里木油田为南疆地区和15个省份提供生活用气保障，力保“无一时短供，无一日断供”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新疆不仅油气资源丰富，煤炭资源储量、风能和太阳能资源蕴藏量也居全国前列。自2010年启动疆电外送以来，截至今年8月底，新疆累计外送电量超过7000亿千瓦时，覆盖20个省份。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;端牢能源“饭碗”，需走绿色低碳发展道路。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为煤炭生产供应大省，陕西的煤矿智能化建设水平居全国前列。人工智能、工业物联网、云计算等技术与煤炭开发利用深度融合，让煤炭行业从“会采煤”向“慧采煤”转变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在位于陕西榆林市地下330米的陕煤曹家滩矿业公司采煤工作面，10米超大采高智能综采工作面滚刀飞转，“乌金”如流。这一项目的投用，创造了一次采全高10米、装机功率2.2万千瓦、单面产能突破2000万吨等多个世界纪录。“从设计到制造，从芯片到螺丝钉，都是中国造。”公司总工程师王锐说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;只需在智能监控中心平台上轻点鼠标，就能操纵庞大的“地下长龙”；井下智能巡检机器人来回穿梭，360度实时监控；通过大数据云计算平台实现对矿山环境立体监测……采煤不见煤，挖煤不用人，智能化场景已融入煤炭生产的各个环节。截至今年上半年，陕西已建成117个智能化采煤工作面和75个智能化掘进工作面。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;端牢能源“饭碗”，需促进新能源和清洁能源发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;澄澈蓝天一望无际，朵朵白云点缀其间。眼前一排排整齐的光伏板，标志着大庆油田新能源业务并入主业，发展全面提速。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022年7月，大庆油田星火水面光伏示范工程并网发电。项目建设用地40万平方米、装机规模18.73兆瓦，年均发电2750万千瓦时、减排二氧化碳2.2万吨。折合成同等发电量的火力发电，每年可节约标准煤8400吨，减少烟尘排放量约84吨、二氧化硫约134吨、氮氧化物约63.9吨。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大力培育新能源新业态，大庆油田着力构建绿色产业结构和低碳能源供应体系。“十四五”期间，大庆油田将建成绿色低碳可持续发展示范基地，新能源装机规模达到200万千瓦以上，清洁能源替代率达到20%以上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;以高品质生态环境支撑高质量发展&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;习近平总书记强调：“把建设美丽中国摆在强国建设、民族复兴的突出位置”“以高品质生态环境支撑高质量发展，加快推进人与自然和谐共生的现代化”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;牢固树立绿色发展理念，三省份保持加强生态文明建设的战略定力，扎实抓好生态环境保护，全力筑牢生态安全屏障。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;守住基准线，打好组合拳。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;陕西坚持把保护黄河流域生态作为谋划发展、推动高质量发展的基准线，持续加强黄河流域生态保护修复，积极健全秦岭常态化长效化保护体制机制，多措并举提升生态文明建设水平。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;走进延安市安塞区南沟村，依靠“沟道打坝、梁峁整地、山坡绿化”治理水土流失，南沟村完成了“秃峁峁变绿海，沟道道赛江南”的蝶变。这是黄土高原地区水土流失治理的一个缩影，近年来，陕西年均入黄泥沙量由8.3亿吨减少到2.68亿吨，黄土高原成为全国增绿幅度最大的区域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在秦岭生态环境保护信息化网格化监管平台上，“卫星眼”全天候守护着秦岭。“即使是垃圾堆放这样的变化也能准确捕捉。”监管平台运行维护中心监测组组长成晓英介绍，多种高科技手段的应用，让秦岭保护实现了“天上看，网上查，地上管”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;实施系统治理，推进生态修复。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新疆因地因时制宜推进塔里木河重要源流区（阿克苏河流域）山水林田湖草沙一体化保护和修复工程。其中，阿克苏地区艾西曼区域生态修复及荒漠化治理工程已完成修复、治理总面积约20万亩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在柯柯牙路慢跑或散步，是阿克苏市民赛买提·加帕尔近年来养成的习惯。“无数次想象过绿树成荫的柯柯牙，如今成了现实。”作为柯柯牙荒漠绿化工程的建设者之一，赛买提深知眼前这蓝天绿树来之不易。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;历经30余年的持续建设，阿克苏地区在塔克拉玛干沙漠西北边缘筑起了一道长57公里、宽46公里的生态安全屏障。如今，柯柯牙生态工程区累计造林120余万亩，森林覆盖率由1986年的8%提高到2020年的73%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;生态本身就是经济，保护生态就是发展生产力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;树立增绿就是增优势、护林就是护财富的理念，黑龙江省积极拓宽绿水青山转化为金山银山的路径，让“绿宝盆”更多变为“聚宝盆”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;利用森林周边设施农业和闲置资源，龙江森工集团重点打造高端森林果蔬产业，目前已建成标准化森林果蔬大棚1040栋，建设“寒地龙果”示范基地1.5万亩，建设森林果树园4.12万亩。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年，龙江森工集团将培育苗木基地作为发力点。迄今，全林区标准化苗圃保有量已有100处，经营总面积达2.06万亩，育苗规模突破2亿株。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“最忙的时候，每天从早上5点干到下午5点。”龙江森工集团方正林业局有限公司陈家亮子银杏种植示范基地负责人韩守亮介绍，去年建立的500亩银杏产业种植示范基地取得了良好的经济效益，“如今发展劲头更足了！”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（本报记者崔佳、李亚楠、原韬雄、刘梦丹）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 提高数字乡村建设精准度（专家观点）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20231115_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月15日星期三&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;近年来，我国高度重视数字乡村建设。智能农机等智慧农业建设快速起步，农村电商等乡村数字经济新业态新模式不断涌现，“互联网+教育”等数字惠民服务扎实推进……数字乡村发展给乡村产业、人才、文化、生态和组织振兴带来新变化，为全面推进乡村振兴、建设农业强国、加快农业农村现代化持续提供新动能。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;今年发布的中国数字乡村发展报告显示，2021年全国数字乡村发展水平达到39.1%。整体来看，乡村数字化水平仍有很大提升空间，主要包括基础设施建设不足，部分农村地区的宽带网络、移动网络等信息通信基础设施建设相对滞后；信息化应用水平较低，高龄农民对数字化技术的应用和接受程度不高；人才缺乏，农村地区的人才储备不足。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;在推动数字乡村建设上，应提高政策精准性：加强基础设施建设，增加农村信息通信基础设施建设的投入；加强信息化应用培训，提高农民的数字素养和技术应用能力；培养数字化农村人才，提高数字乡村建设的质量和可持续发展水平。同时，提升乡村数字发展水平，不能盲目追求指标，例如在传统牧区、林区等人口稀少区域，数字乡村水平需对应基本生产生活要求，更好满足需要。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;基于现有农村发展实际，数字乡村建设大有可为，只要找准路径并顺应发展规律，数字乡村必定能为全面推进乡村振兴添砖加瓦。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;（作者为中国社会科学院农村发展研究所研究员，本报记者常钦采访整理）&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 15 Nov 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>