<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 推动长三角一体化发展取得新的重大突破  在中国式现代化中更好发挥引领示范作用]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-12/01/nw.D110000renmrb_20231201_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, December 01, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-12/01/01/rmrb2023120101p21_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the morning of November 30, Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, President of the State, and Chairman of the Central Military Commission, chaired a symposium on in-depth promotion of the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta in Shanghai and delivered an important speech. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Xie Huanchi&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;■ Deeply promote the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta , further enhance innovation capabilities, industrial competitiveness, and development levels, and take the lead in forming a new pattern of higher-level reform and opening up. This is of great significance to our country in building a new development pattern, promoting high-quality development, and comprehensively promoting the construction of a strong country and national rejuvenation with Chinese-style modernization. major. It is necessary to fully, accurately and comprehensively implement the new development concept, closely adhere to the two key words of integration and high quality, establish a global vision and strategic thinking, unswervingly deepen reforms, expand high-level opening up, coordinate scientific and technological innovation and industrial innovation, and coordinate Leading the way and promoting each other&#39;s strengths, coordinating hardware connectivity and mechanism coordination, coordinating ecological environmental protection and economic development, taking the lead in promoting common prosperity, actively exploring in building a modern civilization for the Chinese nation, and promoting the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta to achieve new and significant achievements Break through, be at the forefront of Chinese-style modernization, and better play the role of pioneering, leading demonstrations, and radiating and driving&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■ In the five years since the Yangtze River Delta integrated development strategy was proposed and implemented, a planning policy system has been formed and continuously The functions of perfect, strong and active growth poles have been continuously consolidated and improved, the establishment of a modern industrial system has been accelerated, major breakthroughs have been made in coordinated regional development, new steps have been taken in reform and opening up, joint protection and joint management of the ecological environment have been solidly advanced, and the overall strength and comprehensive competitiveness of the Yangtze River Delta region have been It continues to rank at the forefront of the country, and its role as an important window to demonstrate the superiority of the socialist system with Chinese characteristics and an important platform for China to participate in international competition and cooperation has become increasingly apparent, winning strategic initiative for building a new development pattern and promoting high-level opening up to the outside world. At the same time, we must also see that there are many deep-seated problems in the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta that need to be further solved. The quality, efficiency and radiating role of development still need to be improved. The integration of key areas and key regions still needs efforts. The level of division of labor and collaboration in the industrial chain and supply chain needs to be improved. The leading and leading role in establishing a national unified market needs to be further improved, reform and opening up needs to be further expanded in depth, and there are still many shortcomings in the governance and development of very large and megacities. Promoting the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta is a big article. We must persist in making progress while maintaining stability, take one job after another, and continue to write a new chapter in the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■The Yangtze River Delta region must strengthen technological innovation and industry Innovative cross-regional collaboration. Vigorously promote scientific and technological innovation, strengthen the in-depth integration of scientific and technological innovation and industrial innovation, spawn new industries, new business formats and new models, expand new development space, cultivate new development momentum, better link the Yangtze River Economic Belt and radiate the whole country&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■Yangtze River Economic Belt The triangular region must speed up the improvement of integrated development systems and mechanisms. Regional divisions and administrative barriers must be broken through institutional mechanisms to provide institutional guarantees for integrated development&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■The Yangtze River Delta region must actively promote high-level collaborative opening up. Promote high-level opening-up with an emphasis on institutional opening-up, strengthen mutual learning and replication of reform experience, and strive to become a powerful engine that smoothes my country&#39;s economic cycle and a strategic hub that connects domestic and international dual cycles&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; ■The Yangtze River Delta region must strengthen joint protection and management of the ecological environment. Strengthen the seamless connection of ecological protection red lines in three provinces and one city, promote the joint protection of important ecological barriers and ecological corridors, strengthen the comprehensive prevention and control of air, water, and soil pollution, carry out in-depth joint protection and joint treatment of cross-border water bodies, and strengthen regional policies for energy conservation, emission reduction, and carbon reduction. Collaborate to build a regional green manufacturing system&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■The Yangtze River Delta region must focus on improving its safe development capabilities. It is necessary to implement the overall national security concept, adhere to bottom-line thinking, coordinate development and security, focus on science and technology, industry, finance and other fields and major infrastructure related to national and regional security, strengthen risk prevention and control systems and capacity building, and consolidate the foundation for safe development. Foundation&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;■To further promote the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta, we must uphold and strengthen the party&#39;s overall leadership. It is necessary to give full play to the overall coordination function of the central leading group for coordinated regional development and adhere to the strategic leadership function of the planning outline. The three provinces and one city must conscientiously implement the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, strengthen organizational leadership and investigation and research, strengthen coordination and consultation and supervision and inspection, promote the resolution of major problems, promote the implementation of major reforms, and promote the implementation of key tasks. It is necessary to strengthen the construction of a team of high-quality professional cadres who are loyal, clean and responsible, and encourage cadres to boldly explore and take on their responsibilities. It is necessary to implement the second batch of thematic education, deepen the comprehensive and strict governance of the party, promote the integrated promotion of dare not, cannot, and do not want to corrupt, strengthen the political and organizational functions of party organizations at all levels, and implement strict discipline, practical style, and Honest ethics ensure that all work is implemented&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This newspaper, Shanghai, November 30th, Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, President of the State, and Chairman of the Central Military Commission On the morning of the 30th, he hosted a symposium in Shanghai to further promote the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta and delivered an important speech. He emphasized that further promoting the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta, further enhancing innovation capabilities, industrial competitiveness, and development capabilities, and taking the lead in forming a new pattern of higher-level reform and opening up, will be crucial for our country to build a new development pattern, promote high-quality development, and use Chinese-style modernization It is of great significance to comprehensively promote the construction of a strong country and the great cause of national rejuvenation. It is necessary to fully, accurately and comprehensively implement the new development concept, closely adhere to the two key words of integration and high quality, establish a global vision and strategic thinking, unswervingly deepen reforms, expand high-level opening up, coordinate scientific and technological innovation and industrial innovation, and coordinate Leading the way and promoting each other&#39;s strengths, coordinating hardware connectivity and mechanism coordination, coordinating ecological environmental protection and economic development, taking the lead in promoting common prosperity, actively exploring in building a modern civilization for the Chinese nation, and promoting the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta to achieve new and significant achievements Make breakthroughs, be at the forefront of Chinese-style modernization, and better play the role of pioneering, leading and demonstrating, and radiating and driving. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Qiang, Member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Premier of the State Council, and Cai Qi, Member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Director of the General Office of the CPC Central Committee, attended the symposium. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping specially held this symposium during his investigation in Shanghai. At the symposium, Director of the National Development and Reform Commission Zheng Shajie, Shanghai Municipal Party Committee Secretary Chen Jining, Jiangsu Provincial Party Committee Secretary Nobunaga Xing, Zhejiang Provincial Party Committee Secretary Yi Lianhong, and Anhui Provincial Party Committee Secretary Han Jun made speeches on promoting the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta. Report work status and put forward opinions and suggestions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After listening to everyone’s speeches, Xi Jinping delivered an important speech. He pointed out that in the five years since the Yangtze River Delta integrated development strategy was proposed and implemented, the planning policy system has been formed and continuously improved, the strong and active growth pole functions have been continuously consolidated and improved, the establishment of a modern industrial system has been accelerated, major breakthroughs have been made in coordinated regional development, and reform and opening up have taken great strides. With new steps, joint protection and joint governance of the ecological environment have been solidly advanced. The overall strength and comprehensive competitiveness of the Yangtze River Delta region continue to rank among the best in the country. It is an important window that demonstrates the superiority of the socialist system with Chinese characteristics and an important platform for my country to participate in international competition and cooperation. It shows that it has won strategic initiative to build a new development pattern and promote high-level opening up to the outside world. At the same time, we must also see that there are many deep-seated problems in the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta that need to be further solved. The quality, efficiency and radiating role of development still need to be improved. The integration of key areas and key regions still needs efforts. The level of division of labor and collaboration in the industrial chain and supply chain needs to be improved. The leading and leading role in establishing a national unified market needs to be further improved, reform and opening up needs to be further expanded in depth, and there are still many shortcomings in the governance and development of very large and megacities. Promoting the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta is a big article. We must persist in seeking progress while maintaining stability, work one term after another, and continue to write a new chapter in the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping emphasized that the Yangtze River Delta region should strengthen cross-regional collaboration in technological innovation and industrial innovation. Vigorously promote scientific and technological innovation, strengthen the in-depth integration of scientific and technological innovation and industrial innovation, spawn new industries, new business formats and new models, expand new development space, cultivate new development momentum, better connect the Yangtze River Economic Belt and radiate the whole country. It is necessary to integrate scientific and technological innovation forces and superior resources across regions and departments to achieve strong alliances and create a source of scientific and technological innovation. It is necessary to participate in international scientific and technological cooperation with more open thinking and measures to create a more globally competitive innovation ecosystem. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that the Yangtze River Delta region must speed up the improvement of integrated development systems and mechanisms. Regional divisions and administrative barriers must be broken through institutional mechanisms to provide institutional guarantees for integrated development. It is necessary to enhance the awareness of integration, adhere to the idea of ​​​​a game of chess, intensify the innovation of systems and mechanisms, achieve greater breakthroughs in key areas and regions, strengthen the systematic integration and coordination of various reform measures, and promote integration to a deeper level and wider areas. expand. It is necessary to gradually promote the connection of basic public service systems, policy coordination, and standard convergence, and promote the convenient sharing of public services in various fields in a classified manner. It is necessary to strengthen the cross-regional connection of various transportation network infrastructure standards and improve the level of infrastructure interconnection. It is necessary to accelerate the construction of the ecological green integrated development demonstration zone in the Yangtze River Delta, improve the land and space planning system of the demonstration zone, strengthen cross-regional coordination and organic connection of planning, land, and project construction, and accelerate the transition from regional project coordination to regional integration system innovation. It is necessary to promote cross-regional co-construction and sharing, orderly promote cross-regional transfer of industries and rational allocation of production factors, so that the Yangtze River Delta can truly become a regional development community. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping emphasized that the Yangtze River Delta region should actively promote high-level coordinated opening up. Promote high-level opening-up with a focus on institutional opening-up, strengthen mutual learning and replication of reform experiences, and strive to become a powerful engine that smoothes my country&#39;s economic cycle and a strategic hub that connects domestic and international dual cycles. It is necessary to speed up the construction of Shanghai&#39;s &quot;five centers&quot;, accelerate the comprehensive reform pilot of Pudong New Area, further enhance the radiation level of Hongqiao International Open Hub, vigorously implement the free trade pilot zone improvement strategy, and promote the Shanghai Free Trade Pilot Zone Lingang New Area to a higher level Open to the outside world. It is necessary to promote the deep integration of the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta and the joint construction of high-quality development of the &quot;Belt and Road Initiative&quot;, and promote the &quot;going out&quot; of the Yangtze River Delta&#39;s superior production capacity, high-quality equipment, applicable technologies and standards. We must take the lead in implementing policies and measures that encourage, support, and guide the healthy development of the private economy, further optimize the development environment for private enterprises, and promote the healthy and high-quality development of the private economy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that the Yangtze River Delta region must strengthen joint protection and management of the ecological environment. Strengthen the seamless connection of ecological protection red lines in three provinces and one city, promote the joint protection of important ecological barriers and ecological corridors, strengthen the comprehensive prevention and control of air, water, and soil pollution, carry out in-depth joint protection and joint treatment of cross-border water bodies, and strengthen regional policies for energy conservation, emission reduction, and carbon reduction. Collaborate to build a regional green manufacturing system. It is necessary to comprehensively promote cleaner production, promote energy conservation, carbon reduction and efficiency improvement in key areas and key industries, strengthen and improve green and low-carbon industries, establish and improve green industrial systems, and accelerate the formation of sustainable production and lifestyles. It is necessary to establish a cross-regional emission rights trading system and actively and steadily promote carbon peak and carbon neutrality. It is necessary to plan and build a new energy system and coordinate the promotion of mutual power supply between provinces and cities. It is necessary to continue to promote the &quot;ten-year fishing ban&quot; in the Yangtze River and strengthen joint law enforcement. It is necessary to improve the value realization mechanism of ecological products and broaden the path for transforming ecological advantages into economic advantages. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping emphasized that the Yangtze River Delta region must focus on improving its security development capabilities. It is necessary to implement the overall national security concept, adhere to bottom-line thinking, coordinate development and security, focus on science and technology, industry, finance and other fields and major infrastructure related to national and regional security, strengthen risk prevention and control systems and capacity building, and consolidate the foundation for safe development. Base. It is necessary to give full play to the advantages of the Yangtze River Delta&#39;s complete industrial system and strong supporting capabilities, implement chain strengthening and chain replenishment actions in important areas and key links related to the national economy and people&#39;s livelihood, strengthen industrial cooperation with the central and western regions, and strive to improve the resilience and safety level of the industrial and supply chains. . It is necessary to steadily expand institutional opening up in the financial sector, improve cross-border investment and financing facilitation, strengthen risk prevention and control throughout the process, and better safeguard national financial security. We must attach great importance to the security of external cooperation and guide the rational and orderly cross-border layout of industrial chains. We must adhere to the people&#39;s construction of people&#39;s cities, improve the level of modern urban governance, accelerate the construction of resilient cities, improve the urban safety prevention system, strengthen the basic urban operation guarantee system, and improve disaster prevention, reduction, and relief capabilities. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that to further promote the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta, we must uphold and strengthen the party&#39;s overall leadership. It is necessary to give full play to the overall coordination function of the central leading group for coordinated regional development and adhere to the strategic leadership function of the planning outline. The three provinces and one city must conscientiously implement the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, strengthen organizational leadership and investigation and research, strengthen coordination and consultation and supervision and inspection, promote the resolution of major problems, promote the implementation of major reforms, and promote the implementation of key tasks. It is necessary to strengthen the construction of a team of high-quality professional cadres who are loyal, clean and responsible, and encourage cadres to boldly explore and take on their responsibilities. It is necessary to implement the second batch of thematic education, deepen the comprehensive and strict governance of the party, promote the integrated promotion of dare not, cannot, and do not want to corrupt, strengthen the political and organizational functions of party organizations at all levels, and implement strict discipline, practical style, and Honest conduct ensures that all work is carried out. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Qiang said in his speech that it is necessary to conscientiously study, understand and thoroughly implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech, place the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta in the overall national development situation, position and think about it, and place it in leading the national high-tech development. We should lay out plans for quality development, give full play to the role of economic growth pole, development power source, and reform experimental field, and better support and serve Chinese-style modernization. It is necessary to further smooth the economic cycle, realize the rational flow and efficient allocation of resource factors, promote the construction of a unified national market, and guide the rational layout of industry and economy. It is necessary to proactively align with high-standard international economic and trade rules, expand institutional opening, create a high-level opening door to the outside world, and enhance the attraction of international commodities and resource elements. We should give full play to our advantages, highlight our characteristics, deepen cooperation, empower each other, turn each region&#39;s own advantages into regional advantages, and work together to enhance the overall effectiveness of regional development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Ganjie, He Lifeng, Wu Zhenglong, Mu Hong, and Jiang Xinzhi attended the symposium, as well as responsible comrades from relevant departments of central and state agencies, relevant localities, and relevant enterprises. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 切实加强耕地保护  抓好盐碱地综合改造利用]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-12/01/nw.D110000renmrb_20231201_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, December 01, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 30th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The 23rd issue of &quot;Qiushi&quot; published on December 1st The magazine will publish an important article by Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, President of the State, and Chairman of the Central Military Commission, &quot;Effectively Strengthen the Protection of Cultivated Land and Do a Good Job in the Comprehensive Transformation and Utilization of Saline-Alkali Lands.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The article emphasizes that we must deeply understand the importance and urgency of strengthening farmland protection. Food security is the &quot;biggest thing in a country&quot;, and cultivated land is the lifeblood of food production. Our party has always attached great importance to the protection of cultivated land. Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the Party Central Committee has implemented a series of hard measures to maintain the red line of cultivated land and initially curb the continued decline in the total amount of cultivated land. At the same time, we must be soberly aware that my country’s national situation of more people and less land has not changed, the problem of “non-agricultural” and “non-grain” cultivated land is still prominent, the basis for holding the red line of cultivated land is not yet solid, and there are still many unpaid debts in farmland water conservancy. In the new era and new journey, the task of protecting farmland has not eased, but has become more arduous. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The article puts forward the overall ideas and key measures to strengthen the protection of cultivated land. The article emphasizes that farmland protection is a systematic project. At present, it is necessary to highlight the important requirements of paying equal attention to quantity and quality, strict law enforcement, systematic promotion, and sustainable utilization. The article emphasizes that there must be several key practical measures to protect the lifeblood of cultivated land. The first is to consolidate the responsibility for protecting cultivated land. The new round of land spatial planning has clarified the tasks of protecting cultivated land and permanent basic farmland in various places and implemented them in detail. Provincial party committees and governments must firmly shoulder the responsibility to ensure that the red line of 1.8 billion acres of cultivated land will never be breached. The second is to make every effort to improve the quality of cultivated land. We will truly build 1.546 billion acres of permanent basic farmland into modern fertile farmland that is suitable for farming, guarantees yields despite droughts and floods, and has high and stable yields. Accelerate legislation on farmland quality protection, implement black soil protection projects, strengthen the management of degraded farmland such as acidification, and implement actions to improve farmland organic matter. The third is to reform and improve the system of balancing farmland occupation and compensation. All types of occupation of cultivated land will be unified into the balance management of occupation and compensation. Improve the quality inspection and acceptance system for supplementary cultivated land. The fourth is to mobilize the enthusiasm of farmers and local governments to protect cultivated land and grow grain. Improve the income guarantee mechanism for grain farmers. Develop various forms of agricultural operations on a moderate scale. We will improve the interest compensation mechanism in major grain-producing areas and form a joint effort to protect cultivated land in major grain-producing areas, main sales areas, and balanced production and marketing areas. Strengthen the management of abandoned land, find out the bottom line, and promote the use of abandoned land in categories. Fifth, actively develop various types of non-traditional farmland resources. Strengthen scientific research and development and production investment, explore effective development models, combine &quot;grain storage in the land&quot; with &quot;grain storage in technology&quot;, and use various non-traditional cultivated land resources for agricultural production. To protect farmland, we must strictly enforce the law, but we cannot &quot;pull the drawer&quot; back and forth indiscriminately. We must seek truth from facts, respect laws, protect the interests of farmers, strengthen publicity and interpretation, appropriately set aside a transition period, and promote it step by step. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The article pointed out that we must do a good job in the comprehensive transformation and utilization of saline-alkali land. The comprehensive transformation and utilization of saline-alkali land is an important aspect of farmland protection and improvement. There are many saline-alkali lands in our country, and the salinization trend of cultivated land in some areas is intensifying. It is of great significance to carry out comprehensive transformation and utilization of saline-alkali lands. It is necessary to fully tap the development and utilization potential of saline-alkali land, strengthen the transformation and upgrading of existing saline-alkali cultivated land, effectively curb the trend of salinization of cultivated land, steadily expand agricultural production space, improve comprehensive agricultural production capacity, and do a good job in saline-alkali land characteristic agriculture. Several tasks should be focused on: First, comprehensively understand the status of saline-alkali land resources and lay a solid foundation. The second is to do a good job in top-level design and study and prepare the overall plan and special implementation plan for the comprehensive utilization of saline-alkali land. The third is to implement classified policies and carry out saline-alkali farmland management and improvement in different regions. The fourth is to adhere to the overall planning of grain, economy and feeding, use saline-alkali land according to local conditions, and obtain food from various saline-alkali land resources. The fifth is to combine &quot;planting to suit the land&quot; with &quot;planting to the land&quot;, speed up the breeding of saline-alkali tolerant varieties, and vigorously promote effective practices in saline-alkali land management and improvement. The sixth is to formulate fiscal and financial policies to support the comprehensive utilization of saline-alkali lands and strengthen the guarantee of funds and other factors. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 取得新的重大突破  谱写新的发展篇章]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-12/01/nw.D110000renmrb_20231201_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, December 01, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;On November 30, General Secretary Xi Jinping chaired a symposium on further promoting the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta in Shanghai and delivered an important speech , to draw a new blueprint for the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta from an overall and strategic perspective. The majority of cadres and the masses expressed that they must follow General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech as a fundamental guide, implement the new development concept completely, accurately and comprehensively, work hard and make long-term achievements, and continue to write a new chapter in the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta in the new era and new journey. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Shouldering the historical mission&amp;nbsp;The new achievements in integrated development are inspiring&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In his speech, General Secretary Xi Jinping fully affirmed the proposal and implementation of the Yangtze River Delta integrated development strategy. Achievements achieved in the past 5 years of implementation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xiang Wei, deputy director of the Department of Regional Coordinated Development of the National Development and Reform Commission, said: “The remarkable results achieved in the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta are fundamentally due to General Secretary Xi Jinping’s leadership and the leadership of Xi Jinping’s Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era. Scientific guidance.&quot; Over the past five years, the National Development and Reform Commission and relevant localities and departments have closely followed the two keywords of integration and high quality to promote the formation and continuous improvement of a planning policy system for the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta, and the strong and active growth pole functions have continued Consolidate and improve. &quot;Next step, we must adhere to the strategic leadership function of the planning outline and promote the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta to achieve new and major breakthroughs.&quot; Xiang Wei said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the past five years, the scientific and technological innovation capabilities of the Yangtze River Delta region have continued to improve. &quot;General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s important speeches have emphasized technological innovation many times, inspiring us to accelerate the deep integration of the innovation chain and the industrial chain and the collaborative innovation and development of upstream and downstream.&quot; said Cao Dongqiang, chairman of Shanghai Dongjian Digital Energy Technology Group Co., Ltd. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The smooth flow of the industrial chain is inseparable from the smooth flow of the &quot;circulation chain&quot;. Wuhu Port in Anhui Province is known as the &quot;Gateway to Southern Anhui&quot; and is the frontier for Anhui&#39;s eastward integration into the Yangtze River Delta. Every day, ro-ro ships carrying new energy vehicles depart from here and go down the river to the Haitong Terminal in Shanghai Waigaoqiao Port Area. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“General Secretary Xi Jinping affirmed the Yangtze River Delta region’s acceleration of the establishment of a modern industrial system, which further strengthened our confidence in promoting the ecologically integrated development of the new energy vehicle industry in the Yangtze River Delta.” said Liu Wenfeng, deputy director of the Anhui Provincial Automobile Office , we will continue to optimize the complete and retail supporting facilities in accordance with the direction guided by the General Secretary, and accelerate the &quot;core-vehicle collaboration&quot; linkage in the Yangtze River Delta region. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Over the past five years, major breakthroughs have been made in the coordinated development of the Yangtze River Delta region. Among them, infrastructure interconnection is the most deeply felt by the masses. Qian Lili, who works in Minhang District, Shanghai, told reporters that it used to take several hours by long-distance bus to return to her hometown of Yancheng, Jiangsu Province, but now it only takes one and a half hours with high-speed rail. She deeply feels the travel convenience brought by transportation integration. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hui Xianbao, deputy director of the Jiangsu Provincial Department of Transportation, said that in recent years, Jiangsu has joined hands with other provinces and cities in the Yangtze River Delta to build the &quot;Yangtze River Delta on Track&quot;, and infrastructure interconnection has been continuously enhanced to further enhance cross-border transportation. personnel exchanges in the region. In the next step, in accordance with the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech, we must strengthen the cross-regional connection of various transportation network infrastructure standards and further improve the level of infrastructure interconnection. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;While affirming the achievements, the General Secretary also pointed out that there are many deep-seated problems in the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta that need to be further solved. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhou Shifeng, deputy director of the Zhejiang Provincial Development and Planning Institute, believes that the next step is to thoroughly study and implement the spirit of the General Secretary’s important speech, strengthen cross-regional top-level design in the three provinces and one city, and seek more detailed and practical measures, and continue to We will provide more leadership and demonstrations in deepening reform, expanding opening up, and promoting the comprehensive green transformation of regional development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Seizing strategic opportunities&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Coordinating planning to achieve new major breakthroughs&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized at this symposium that coordinating scientific and technological innovation and For industrial innovation, we need to coordinate leading efforts and promote each other&#39;s strengths, coordinate hardware connectivity and mechanism coordination, and coordinate ecological environmental protection and economic development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Luo Dajin, director of the Shanghai Municipal Science and Technology Commission, said that the &quot;four coordinations&quot; are organically unified and have clear goals, and they provide guidance and direction for jointly promoting the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta to achieve new major breakthroughs. &quot;In the fierce international competition, to open up new areas and new tracks for development and create new momentum and new advantages for development, we fundamentally need to rely on technological innovation.&quot; Luo Dajin said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Liu Yunjie, academician of the Chinese Academy of Engineering and director of the Purple Mountain Laboratory, said that the next step is to continue to create a source of scientific and technological innovation, provide high-level scientific and technological supplies, and support the integrated high-quality development of the Yangtze River Delta region. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Up to now, the Yangtze River Delta Science and Technology Resource Sharing Service Platform has gathered more than 3,000 service agencies of various types, and the Yangtze River Delta Science and Technology Innovation Voucher has been universally available in Shanghai and Zhejiang, as well as in some areas of Jiangsu and Anhui provinces. , this year, Suzhou and Nantong were newly included.&quot; He Jun, director of the Shanghai R&amp;D Public Service Platform Management Center, said that the cities in the Yangtze River Delta are both &quot;neighbors&quot; and &quot;teammates&quot;. In the future, we will follow the direction indicated by the General Secretary. Do both &quot;your own things&quot; and &quot;common things&quot; well. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To further promote the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta, we must coordinate ecological environmental protection and economic development to enhance development potential and stamina. On the map of the Yangtze River Delta, Xuancheng is located in the geographical center. It is the only prefecture-level city in Anhui that borders Zhejiang and Jiangsu at the same time. Its forest coverage rate is close to 60%. Yang Weiping, deputy director of Wanling Forest Farm in Xuanzhou District, Xuancheng City, Anhui Province, said that we will follow General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech as a fundamental guide, strengthen joint protection and joint governance of the ecological environment, jointly explore strategies to protect greenery, and practice green development. Tao, guard the same blue sky. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An important purpose of integration is to solve the problem of uneven regional development. The output of jackets in Sanmen County, Taizhou City, Zhejiang Province accounts for nearly 60% of the country&#39;s total output. &quot;The jacket industry is a labor-intensive industry that employs many people, especially low-income people to find employment at home and increase their income. The General Secretary emphasized that we should set a pioneering example in promoting common prosperity. We will continue to base ourselves on our own characteristics, give full play to our industrial advantages, and drive more The masses create wealth and increase income,&quot; said Lou Mingrong, the person in charge of Sanmen County Jacket &quot;Co-Wealth Workshop&quot;. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Strengthen institutional and mechanism innovation&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Build a regional development community&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out that to further promote the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta, we must adhere to the principle of peace and harmony. Strengthen the party&#39;s overall leadership. This makes us more determined to implement the key tasks deployed at this symposium under the leadership of the party.&quot; Yu Lizhong, secretary of the Hai&#39;an Municipal Party Committee in Nantong City, Jiangsu Province, said that since this year, Hai&#39;an has introduced the construction of Shanghai The implementation plan of the satellite city strives to create a place for the coordinated development of high-end industries in Shanghai, a key radiation place for scientific and technological resources, an important guarantee place for cold chain storage and transportation, and a place for public service integration and sharing. It will be integrated into southern Jiangsu in a wide range of areas, deeply integrated with Shanghai, and fully integrated into the Yangtze River Delta. In line with the overall development situation, we will make every effort to build a satellite city with two-way integration in the north wing of Shanghai. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To promote higher-quality integrated development in the Yangtze River Delta, we must deepen reforms, increase innovation in systems and institutional mechanisms, and achieve greater breakthroughs in key areas and regions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The General Secretary pointed out that regional divisions and administrative barriers must be broken through institutional mechanisms to provide institutional guarantees for integrated development. This points out the direction for us to deepen reform.” Vice President of Shanghai Academy of Social Sciences, Wang Zhen, executive deputy director of the Yangtze River Delta and Yangtze River Economic Belt Research Center, said that to implement the spirit of the General Secretary’s important speech, the three provinces and one city must further promote “breaking” and “building”, promote reform and opening up to further expand in depth, and complement the governance of super large cities. and development shortcomings, while promoting the free flow of talents, data and other elements across regions to avoid inefficient resource allocation and duplication of competition caused by administrative barriers. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Three provinces and one city are accelerating action to break down various barriers. In the Yangtze River Delta (Huzhou) Industrial Cooperation Zone, the leveling of more than 4,000 acres of industrial land has been accelerated, and two main roads with a total length of nearly 20 kilometers have been basically opened to traffic. In the future, the travel time between the cooperation zone and Anhui Guangde will be shortened from 45 minutes to 15 minutes. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The General Secretary pointed out that the Yangtze River Delta must truly become a regional development community. In recent years, Huzhou has firmly seized the strategic opportunity of the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta, focusing on cultivating new energy vehicles and key components, geographical information and other emerging industrial chains.&quot; Chen Hao, Secretary of the Huzhou Municipal Party Committee in Zhejiang Province, said that in the next step, Huzhou will give full play to its comparative advantages to promote a more reasonable division of labor in the Yangtze River Delta and form a synergy for regional high-quality development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To learn and understand General Secretary Xi Jinping’s requirements for the Yangtze River Delta region to actively promote high-level coordinated opening up, Zhu Bing, Director of the Department of Foreign Investment Management of the Ministry of Commerce, said that in the next step, the Ministry of Commerce will actively support relevant provinces in the Yangtze River Delta region. The city takes advantage of its location and industry advantages to take the lead in the pilot free trade zone and proactively connect with high-standard international economic and trade rules, conduct in-depth comprehensive pilot trials for the expansion of the opening up of the national service industry, promote innovation and upgrading of national economic development zones, and accelerate pilot projects for the innovative development of trade in services. , run the CIIE with high quality, steadily promote institutional opening up and promote the joint development of open platforms, and create a new highland for opening up with a higher level of opening up, a better business environment, and a stronger radiation effect. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The National Intelligent Speech Innovation Center is jointly launched by Anhui University of Science and Technology iFlytek and upstream and downstream key enterprises, universities and social capital in the industry. General Manager Wu Jiangzhao said that they will focus on researching a number of common technologies with high thresholds and urgent needs in the industry, such as industrial AI and AI chips, and strive to make the voice of China&#39;s artificial intelligence industry known internationally and implement the General Secretary&#39;s proposal of &quot;promoting the Yangtze River Delta.&quot; The requirements of &quot;going out&quot; with advantageous production capacity, high-quality equipment, applicable technology and standards have been implemented. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Promoting the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta is a big article. As General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out, we must persist in seeking progress while maintaining stability and work one term after another in order to continue to write a new chapter in the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gu Jun, deputy secretary-general of the Shanghai Municipal Government and director of the Yangtze River Delta Regional Cooperation Office, said that the general secretary’s important speech pointed out the way forward and provided fundamental guidance for us to further promote the integrated development of the Yangtze River Delta. Under the overall leadership of the Party and the overall coordination of the Central Leading Group for Coordinated Regional Development, we must persist in seeking progress while maintaining stability, closely adhere to the two key words of integration and high quality, further play the leading role of Shanghai, and coordinate with the three provinces of Jiangsu, Zhejiang and Anhui Each should leverage its strengths to truly make the Yangtze River Delta a regional development community, take the lead in Chinese-style modernization, and better play its role of pioneering pathfinding, leading demonstrations, and radiating and driving. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 30th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Xinhua News Agency reporter)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平向“声援巴勒斯坦人民国际日”纪念大会致贺电]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-12/01/nw.D110000renmrb_20231201_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, December 1, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 30th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;On November 29th, the United Nations held the &quot;International Day of Solidarity with the Palestinian People&quot; &quot;In commemoration of the conference, President Xi Jinping sent a congratulatory message to the conference. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that the Palestinian issue is the core of the Middle East issue and is related to international fairness and justice. The crux of the Palestinian-Israeli conflict lies in the Palestinian people&#39;s delay in realizing their legitimate national rights to establish an independent state. The painful lessons of the repeated cycles of Palestinian-Israeli conflicts fully demonstrate that only by adhering to the concept of common security can sustainable security be achieved. The international community must act urgently, and the United Nations Security Council should shoulder its responsibilities and make every effort to promote ceasefires and wars, protect civilians, and prevent humanitarian disasters. On this basis, the Palestinian-Israeli peace talks should be restarted as soon as possible and the Palestinian people&#39;s rights to statehood, survival and return should be realized as soon as possible. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping emphasized that China has always firmly supported the just cause of the Palestinian people to restore their legitimate national rights. The fundamental solution to the Palestinian issue lies in the establishment of an independent Palestinian state based on the 1967 borders, with East Jerusalem as its capital, and enjoying full sovereignty. The economic and livelihood needs of Palestine should be guaranteed, and the international community should increase development assistance and humanitarian assistance to Palestine. We must adhere to the correct direction of peace talks and convene a more authoritative international peace conference as soon as possible. China has proposed a global security initiative, advocates resolving differences and disputes between countries through dialogue and consultation, and supports all efforts that are conducive to the peaceful resolution of crises. China will continue to uphold fairness and justice on the Palestinian issue, actively promote peace and talks, and continue to provide humanitarian and development assistance to Palestine. As a permanent member of the United Nations Security Council, China will continue to work together with the international community to build international peace-promoting consensus and push the Palestinian issue back to the right track of the &quot;two-state solution&quot; to achieve a comprehensive, just and lasting solution at an early date. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平就亨利·基辛格逝世向美国总统拜登致唁电]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-12/01/nw.D110000renmrb_20231201_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, December 01, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 30th&amp;nbsp; ·Sent a message of condolences to US President Biden after Kissinger passed away. On behalf of the Chinese government and people, and in his own name, Xi Jinping expressed deep condolences for the death of Dr. Henry Kissinger and sincere condolences to his family. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping said in his message of condolences that Dr. Henry Kissinger was a world-renowned strategist and an old friend and good friend of the Chinese people. Half a century ago, with his outstanding strategic vision, he made historic contributions to the normalization of Sino-US relations, which not only benefited both countries but also changed the world. He regards promoting the development of Sino-US relations and enhancing the friendship between the two peoples as his lifelong pursuit. Kissinger&#39;s name will forever be associated with Sino-US relations. Dr. Kissinger will always be remembered and missed by the Chinese people. China is willing to work with the United States to pass on the cause of friendship between the Chinese and American peoples, promote the healthy and stable development of Sino-US relations, benefit the two peoples, and make due contributions to world peace and development. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 凝聚国际促和共识，推动巴勒斯坦问题早日得到全面、公正、持久解决]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-12/01/nw.D110000renmrb_20231201_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, December 01, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;On November 29, the United Nations held a commemorative conference for the &quot;International Day of Solidarity with the Palestinian People&quot;. President Xi Jinping sent a congratulatory message to the conference. International sources interviewed by our reporter said that President Xi Jinping has sent congratulatory messages to the United Nations commemorating the &quot;International Day of Solidarity with the Palestinian People&quot; for 10 consecutive years, and has repeatedly put forward Chinese initiatives to promote the settlement of the Palestinian issue, demonstrating China&#39;s responsibility as a responsible power. All parties should work together to build international consensus on peace promotion, push the Palestinian issue back to the right track of the &quot;two-state solution&quot;, and achieve a comprehensive, just and lasting solution at an early date. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; “Strong moral support for the Palestinian cause”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping emphasized that the fundamental way to solve the Palestinian issue lies in establishing a new border based on the 1967 borders. An independent Palestinian state with full sovereignty and East Jerusalem as its capital. The economic and livelihood needs of Palestine should be guaranteed, and the international community should increase development assistance and humanitarian assistance to Palestine. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;President Xi Jinping has sent congratulatory messages to the United Nations&#39; International Day of Solidarity with the Palestinian People&#39; commemoration conference on many occasions, expressing China&#39;s consistent firm position on the Palestinian issue.&quot; Member of the Political Bureau of the Palestinian Popular Struggle Front and Secretary of Relations with China Mohammed Alloush said that China always supports a comprehensive, fair and lasting solution to the Palestinian issue and supports the realization of the Palestinian people&#39;s rights to statehood, survival and return. &quot;China adheres to justice on the Palestinian issue, makes unremitting efforts to advance the peace process, and provides humanitarian assistance to improve the lives of the Palestinian people and develop the Palestinian economy. We highly appreciate this.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Egypt&#39;s Al-Ahram Newspaper Deputy Editor-in-Chief Sunuti said that President Xi Jinping’s congratulatory message demonstrates that China attaches great importance to the Palestinian issue and demonstrates China’s responsibility as a responsible major country. &quot;The Palestinian issue is the core of the Middle East issue and is related to international fairness and justice. The crux of the Palestinian-Israeli conflict lies in the Palestinian people&#39;s delay in realizing the legitimate national rights of an independent country. President Xi Jinping has put forward China&#39;s initiatives on promoting the settlement of the Palestinian issue on many occasions. This is It is a strong moral support for the Palestinian cause and also points out the direction and path for the international community to solve the Palestinian issue.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ferhat Asif, Director of the Institute of Peace and Diplomacy in Islamabad, Pakistan, said, The Palestinian-Israeli conflict is one of the current focuses of global attention, and resolving this issue is crucial to achieving peace, stability, cooperation and development in the Middle East. The road map proposed by President Xi Jinping in his congratulatory message to resolve the Palestinian-Israeli issue is pragmatic and feasible, meets the needs of the Palestinian people, and embodies international fairness and justice. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“China has never been absent in promoting the peaceful settlement of the Palestinian issue”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping pointed out that the international community must act urgently, and the United Nations Security Council should take practical responsibility. Take responsibility and make every effort to promote ceasefires and wars, protect civilian safety, and prevent humanitarian disasters. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hu Yishan, a senior researcher at the Singapore Institute of International Affairs, said that since the outbreak of the current round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict, China has actively promoted peace talks, promoted a ceasefire and an end to the war, provided emergency humanitarian assistance to the Gaza Strip, and will provide assistance to the Gaza Strip in accordance with the If the people need it, we will continue to provide material assistance. &quot;China, together with other countries, has made a lot of efforts to promote the solution of the Palestinian-Israeli issue and guided all parties to build consensus to the greatest extent, which reflects China&#39;s responsibility as a major country.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;As a permanent member of the United Nations Security Council, China has never been absent in promoting the peaceful settlement of the Palestinian issue.&quot; Mohammed Lieb, editor-in-chief of the Palestinian Jerusalem News, said that from calling for a ceasefire and an end to the war, to pushing all parties to abide by international humanitarian law obligations, to repeatedly emphasizing the Palestinian-Israeli issue The solution is to implement the &quot;two-state solution&quot;. China&#39;s logic for resolving the Palestinian-Israeli conflict is consistent, which is to safeguard humanity and peace, uphold fairness and justice, and is widely appreciated by all parties. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Alush said that China has always been an activist in promoting the peaceful coexistence between Palestine and Israel. At the special video summit of BRICS leaders on the Palestine-Israel issue held not long ago, President Xi Jinping put forward three proposals based on the current situation between Palestine and Israel. As the rotating president of the United Nations Security Council this month, China has always regarded the Palestinian-Israeli conflict as the most urgent issue. The Security Council passed Resolution 2712, taking the initial steps to promote a ceasefire. China also issued the &quot;China&#39;s Position Paper on the Resolution of the Palestinian-Israeli Conflict.&quot; These practices are welcomed by all walks of life in Palestine. He said that China is playing an increasingly important role in promoting the political settlement of the Palestinian issue. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; &quot;It has played a constructive role in maintaining peace and stability in the Middle East.&quot; &lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping pointed out, &quot;The painful lessons of the repeated cycles of Palestinian-Israeli conflicts have fully demonstrated that &quot;Only by adhering to the concept of common security can we achieve sustainable security.&quot; &quot;China has proposed a global security initiative, advocates resolving differences and disputes between countries through dialogue and consultation, and supports all efforts that are conducive to the peaceful resolution of crises.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Najra Azharuni, a senior researcher at the UAE Trend Research and Consulting Center, said that President Xi Jinping proposed a global security initiative, advocating mutual respect, peaceful coexistence, and win-win cooperation, and emphasized peaceful solutions through dialogue and consultation. differences and disputes between countries, which has contributed Chinese wisdom to solving security issues in the world today, and is of great significance to regional countries in achieving peace and stability. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“For a long time, China has played a constructive role in maintaining peace and stability in the Middle East.” Algerian Radio International reporter Mohamed Wail said that in March this year, under the mediation of China, Saudi Arabia and Iran The achievement of historic reconciliation has set an example for regional countries to resolve conflicts and differences through dialogue and consultation and achieve good-neighborly friendship. The Saudi-Iranian reconciliation has set off a wave of &quot;reconciliation&quot; in the Middle East, helping to de-escalate hot-spot issues such as Yemen, Syria and Libya. This is a vivid practice of implementing global security initiatives and promoting the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;China is unswervingly promoting world peace and stability, promoting multi-polar development of the world, and achieving common prosperity.&quot; Carlos·, British political commentator and co-editor of the &quot;Friends of Socialist China&quot; website Martinez said that in March this year, China facilitated the reconciliation between Saudi Arabia and Iran, demonstrating that it can play a valuable role in helping to resolve conflicts in the Middle East. In November, a joint delegation of foreign ministers from Arab and Islamic countries visited China. The delegation made China the first stop for international mediation, demonstrating the high degree of trust the international community has in China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Kofi Kouaku, a senior researcher at the Africa-China Research Center at the University of Johannesburg in South Africa, believes that China has not only stated its position and propositions on multiple occasions, but has also taken practical actions to promote regional peace and stability and facilitate the resumption of diplomatic relations between Saudi Arabia and Iran. , providing emergency humanitarian assistance to the Palestinian Gaza Strip, etc., are all tangible examples. &quot;As a permanent member of the United Nations Security Council, China has made great contributions to peace, stability and development in the Middle East. We look forward to an early comprehensive, just and lasting solution to the Palestinian issue with the joint efforts of all parties.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; (This newspaper’s Beijing, Dubai, Cairo, Islamabad, Bangkok, Algiers, London, and Johannesburg reports on November 30. Reporters Zhou Xi, Zhang Zhiwen, Ren Haoyu, Huang Peizhao, Cheng Shijie, Liu Hui, Hao Ruimin, and Xing Xue , Yan Yunming)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 中国是推进全球气候治理的行动派（和音）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-12/01/nw.D110000renmrb_20231201_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, December 1, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;As a responsible major developing country, China will actively respond to climate change as an inherent requirement to achieve its own sustainable development and provide Global climate governance has contributed wisdom and strength&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;On November 30, the 28th Conference of the Parties (COP28) of the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change opened in Dubai, United Arab Emirates. At this meeting, all parties will conduct a global inventory of the progress made in achieving the goals of the Paris Agreement for the first time, which is of important stage significance for the global climate governance process. The international community expects all parties to abide by the system, principles and goals of the UNFCCC system and send a positive signal to focus on action and strengthen cooperation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The theme of COP28 is &quot;Unity, Action, Implementation&quot;, which reflects the desire for unity and cooperation to deal with climate change. According to the latest report from the Secretariat of the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change, current climate action plans of various countries cannot achieve the goals of the Paris Agreement. UN Secretary-General António Guterres said that COP28 must be a place where countries can bridge the climate ambition gap, and developed countries must fulfill their financial commitments and rebuild trust. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;China is an activist in promoting global climate governance. Since the beginning of this year, China has maintained close communication with all parties to promote the success of COP28 and the full and effective implementation of the Paris Agreement. Not long ago, President Xi Jinping met with US President Biden in San Francisco. The two heads of state emphasized the importance of China and the United States accelerating efforts to respond to the climate crisis in the current critical decade, and welcomed the recent active discussions held by the climate envoys of the two countries, including: domestic emission reduction actions in the 2020s, jointly promoting the success of COP28, and launching the China-U.S. &quot;21 Strengthening the Climate Action Task Force in the 2020s&quot; to accelerate concrete climate action. World Meteorological Organization Secretary-General Taalas believes that this echoes the spirit of global cooperation and has a positive impact on the global response to the challenge of climate change. President Xi Jinping emphasized in a recent phone call with French President Macron that China is willing to work with France to send a strong signal to the outside world that China and France are working together to address climate change and promote the success of the United Nations Climate Change Conference in Dubai. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;As a responsible major developing country, China regards actively addressing climate change as an inherent requirement to achieve its own sustainable development, and has contributed wisdom and strength to global climate governance. Implement the national strategy to actively respond to climate change, announce the goal of carbon peak and carbon neutrality, build and complete the &quot;1+N&quot; policy system for carbon peak and carbon neutrality, promote the adjustment of industry, energy, and transportation structures, adopt energy conservation to improve energy efficiency, and establish and improve Market mechanisms, increasing forest carbon sinks... China insists on paying equal attention to mitigation and adaptation, and has made positive progress in responding to climate change. China&#39;s carbon emission intensity will drop by more than 51% in 2022 compared with 2005. &quot;China has made great contributions to the global response to climate change and is the global leader in the development of renewable energy.&quot; COP28 Chairman Sultan Al-Jaber said. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;China has carried out in-depth South-South cooperation on climate change, actively participated in the multilateral climate process, and demonstrated its responsibility as a major country. Recently, the Al Dhafra photovoltaic power station in the United Arab Emirates, contracted by a Chinese enterprise, was fully completed. It is currently the largest single photovoltaic power station in the world, providing electricity for 200,000 households and reducing carbon emissions by 2.4 million tons per year. As of September 2023, China has signed 48 memorandums of understanding on South-South cooperation on climate change with dozens of developing countries, cooperated in the construction of 4 low-carbon demonstration zones, carried out 75 climate change mitigation and adaptation projects, and provided services to more than 120 countries. Developing countries have trained more than 2,300 officials and technicians in the field of climate change. Promoting the implementation of the &quot;China-EU Green Action&quot;, building the China-EU Carbon Neutral Research Center, launching the China-France Carbon Neutral Center, and hosting the Global Sustainable Transportation Summit Forum... China has used practical actions to build consensus on global climate governance and boost the global response to climate change. Confidence. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Coping with climate change is a common cause for all mankind. All parties must always maintain the status of the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change as the main channel in global climate governance, adhere to the principles of fairness, common but differentiated responsibilities and respective capabilities, and fully and effectively implement the goals of the Paris Agreement. China will work with all parties to take the global stocktake as an opportunity to focus on implementation actions, strengthen support means, and promote the establishment of a global climate governance system that is fair, reasonable, cooperative and win-win. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 中方主持安理会巴以问题高级别会议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-12/01/nw.D110000renmrb_20231201_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, December 01, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper’s United Nations report on November 29&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Li Zhiwei) On November 29, local time, at the United Nations Under the initiative of China, the rotating president of the Security Council this month, the Security Council held a high-level meeting on the Palestinian-Israeli issue. The meeting was chaired by Wang Yi, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Foreign Minister, and attended by foreign ministers and high-level representatives from nearly 20 countries including Brazil, Palestine, Qatar, Jordan, Saudi Arabia, Egypt, Indonesia, Turkey, Slovenia, and Malaysia, as well as all members of the Security Council. . United Nations Secretary-General Guterres and United Nations Special Coordinator for the Middle East Peace Process Vineslan briefed the meeting on the situation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Wang Yi said that since the outbreak of the current round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict, China has been working hard to achieve peace and save lives. President Xi Jinping has repeatedly stated China&#39;s principled position on the current situation between Palestine and Israel, calling for an immediate ceasefire and war, preventing the expansion of the conflict, and ensuring the safety and smooth flow of humanitarian relief. He stressed that the fundamental way out is to implement the &quot;two-state solution&quot; and promote an early comprehensive, fair and comprehensive resolution of the Palestinian issue. Lasting solution. As the rotating president of the Security Council this month, China has always regarded the Palestinian-Israeli conflict as the most urgent issue. The Security Council passed Resolution 2712 this month, taking the initial steps to promote a ceasefire. Recently, the release of some detained persons and a ceasefire have been achieved. This shows that dialogue and negotiation are the best option to save lives and the fundamental way to resolve conflicts. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Wang Yi emphasized that the current round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict has caused the loss of a large number of innocent lives and unprecedented humanitarian disasters, and its spillover effects are still emerging. War tests conscience and justice, while peace calls for reason and wisdom. The international community must take more proactive actions to save lives and restore peace. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;We must promote a comprehensive and lasting ceasefire with the greatest sense of urgency. There are no safe zones under fire, there is no firewall in Gaza. China strongly hopes that the temporary ceasefire is not a pause before a new round of offensive, but the beginning of a further comprehensive and lasting ceasefire. A comprehensive and lasting ceasefire should become an overriding priority, and all parties should focus all their efforts on the common goal of quelling the war in Gaza. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;More pragmatic and powerful actions must be taken to protect civilians. Any violence and attacks against civilians are unacceptable, and any violation of international humanitarian law should be condemned. China reiterates its opposition to the collective punishment of the people of Gaza and the forced relocation of Palestinian civilians, and all detained persons should be released. Security Council Resolution 2712 must be fully implemented to clear obstacles for sufficient humanitarian supplies to enter and open up more relief channels to Gaza. The United Nations should play a greater role in supervising and coordinating humanitarian operations in Gaza. The Chinese government will provide a new batch of emergency humanitarian aid to the Gaza Strip. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;We must revitalize the political prospects of the &quot;two-state solution&quot; with firmer determination. Israel has long since established an independent state, and the Jewish people are no longer displaced. However, the Palestinian people&#39;s rights to statehood, survival, and return have long been ignored. This is the crux of the ongoing turmoil in the Palestinian-Israeli situation. Fairness and justice for the Palestinian issue is the &quot;two-state solution&quot; and is irreplaceable. Only when the &quot;two-state solution&quot; is truly and comprehensively implemented can peace in the Middle East be achieved, the two countries of Palestine and Israel peacefully coexist, and the Arab and Jewish nations develop together. China calls for intensifying international and regional diplomatic efforts, revitalizing the political prospects of the &quot;two-state solution&quot; and restarting direct negotiations between Palestine and Israel. China proposes to convene an international peace conference with a larger scale, greater scope and more effectiveness, and supports Palestine to become a full member of the United Nations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;We must push the Security Council to take responsible and meaningful actions. The Security Council must reflect its responsibility and responsibility on the major issues of war and peace, life and death, listen to the voices of the Arab and Islamic countries and the international community, and take further action in a timely manner. China submitted the &quot;China Position Paper on the Resolution of the Palestinian-Israeli Conflict,&quot; proposing that the international community should promote a comprehensive ceasefire and end the war, effectively protect civilians, ensure humanitarian relief, increase diplomatic mediation, and seek a political solution through the implementation of the &quot;two-state solution.&quot; Five working principles and priorities. We will continue to strengthen coordination with relevant parties, build consensus, and push the Security Council to shoulder its responsibilities, fulfill its responsibilities for peace, and speak out for justice. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;All parties appreciate China&#39;s initiative to hold a high-level meeting on the Palestinian-Israeli issue and believe that the meeting, held on the occasion of the &quot;International Day of Solidarity with the Palestinian People&quot;, is of great significance in promoting a ceasefire and war and easing the humanitarian crisis, and will help Brainstorm, build consensus, and form synergy. All parties generally support extending the temporary ceasefire until a permanent ceasefire is achieved, calling for the release of hostages, protection of civilians, increased humanitarian assistance, and ensuring smooth access to supplies. It is expected that the Security Council will effectively fulfill its responsibilities in maintaining international peace and security, play a greater role in easing tensions, restart the peace process at an early date, and ultimately achieve peaceful coexistence between Palestine and Israel. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;During the meeting, Wang Yi met with United Nations Secretary-General Guterres, Slovenia Deputy Prime Minister and Foreign Minister Fayon, Brazilian Foreign Minister Vieira, and Malaysian Foreign Minister Zambiri, and met collectively with Saudi Arabia and Egypt , Qatar, Turkey, Indonesia and other Arab and Islamic countries. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 外交部发布《中国关于解决巴以冲突的立场文件》]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-12/01/nw.D110000renmrb_20231201_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, December 01, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 30th&amp;nbsp; Position Paper on Conflict. The full text is as follows:&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The current round of Palestinian-Israeli conflict has caused a large number of civilian casualties and led to a serious humanitarian disaster, which has attracted great attention from the international community. President Xi Jinping has repeatedly stated China&#39;s principled position on the current situation between Palestine and Israel, emphasizing that an immediate ceasefire and war should be carried out, humanitarian relief channels should be ensured safe and smooth, and the conflict should be prevented from expanding. The fundamental way out is to implement the &quot;two-state solution&quot;, build international consensus on peace promotion, and promote The Palestinian issue should be resolved comprehensively, justly and lastingly at an early date. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;According to the United Nations Charter, the United Nations Security Council bears the primary responsibility for maintaining international peace and security and should play a positive and constructive role on the Palestinian-Israeli issue. In view of this, China puts forward the following suggestions: &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;1. A comprehensive ceasefire and an end to the war. The parties concerned must earnestly implement the relevant resolutions of the United Nations General Assembly and the Security Council and immediately implement a lasting and sustained humanitarian truce. On the basis of Resolution 2712, the Security Council should respond to the universal call of the international community and further clarify its demand for a comprehensive ceasefire and an end to the war, promote the de-escalation of the conflict, and achieve the goal of cooling down the situation as soon as possible. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;2. Effectively protect civilians. The Security Council resolution clearly requires all parties to abide by their obligations under international humanitarian law and protect civilians. It is necessary to stop all violent attacks against civilians and violations of international humanitarian law, and avoid attacks on civilian facilities. The Security Council should further send a clear signal, oppose the forced relocation of Palestinian civilians, prevent the displacement of Palestinian civilians, and call for the early release of all detained civilians and hostages. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;3. Ensure humanitarian relief. Relevant parties must, in accordance with the requirements of the Security Council resolutions, avoid depriving civilians in Gaza of supplies and services indispensable for their survival, establish humanitarian relief channels in Gaza and provide fast, safe, barrier-free and sustainable humanitarian access to prevent more incidents. A serious humanitarian disaster. The Security Council should encourage the international community to increase humanitarian assistance, improve the current humanitarian situation, support the coordination role of the United Nations and its Near East Relief and Works Agency for Palestine Refugees in the Near East in humanitarian relief, and promote the international community&#39;s preparation to support post-war reconstruction in Gaza. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;4. Increase diplomatic mediation. The Security Council must play its role of good offices and mediation as entrusted by the United Nations Charter, require the parties concerned to exercise restraint, prevent the expansion of conflicts, and maintain peace and stability in the Middle East. The Security Council should attach great importance to the role of regional countries and regional organizations, support the mediation efforts of the United Nations Secretary-General and the Secretariat, encourage countries that have influence on the parties concerned to uphold an objective and impartial stance, and jointly play a constructive role in promoting the cooling of the crisis. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;5. Seek political solution. According to relevant Security Council resolutions and relevant international consensus, the fundamental way to resolve the Palestinian issue is to implement the &quot;two-state solution&quot;, restore the legitimate rights of the Palestinian nation, and establish an independent Palestine with full sovereignty based on the 1967 borders, with East Jerusalem as its capital. country. The Security Council should promote the resumption of the &quot;two-state solution&quot;, convene a larger, more authoritative and more effective international peace conference as soon as possible under the leadership and organization of the United Nations, and formulate a specific timetable and road map for the implementation of the &quot;two-state solution&quot;. Promote a comprehensive, just and lasting solution to the Palestinian issue. Any arrangements for the future of Gaza must respect the will and independent choices of the Palestinian people and cannot be imposed on others. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 王毅将赴越南主持中越双边合作指导委员会第十五次会议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-12/01/nw.D110000renmrb_20231201_5-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, December 01, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, November 30th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Zhao Yipu) Foreign Ministry Spokesperson Wang Wenbin announced on the 30th: At the invitation of Vietnamese Deputy Prime Minister Chen Liuguang, Wang Yi, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Foreign Minister, will go to Vietnam from December 1 to 2 to chair the 15th meeting of the China-Vietnam Bilateral Cooperation Steering Committee. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 中国人民将铭记基辛格博士对中美关系投入的真挚感情和作出的重要贡献]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-12/01/nw.D110000renmrb_20231201_6-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, December 01, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, November 30th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Zhao Yipu) Foreign Ministry Spokesperson Wang Wenbin was in the case on the 30th He said at the press conference that the Chinese people will remember Dr. Kissinger’s sincere affection and important contribution to Sino-US relations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;On November 29, local time, former US Secretary of State Henry Kissinger passed away at the age of 100. Wang Wenbin said that Dr. Kissinger is an old friend and good friend of the Chinese people, and a pioneer and builder of Sino-US relations. &quot;He has long been concerned about and supported the development of Sino-US relations, and has visited China more than a hundred times, making historic contributions to promoting the normalization of Sino-US relations. The Chinese people will remember Dr. Kissinger&#39;s sincere feelings and important contributions to Sino-US relations. Contribution.&quot; Wang Wenbin said that Chinese President Xi Jinping has sent a message of condolences to US President Biden on the death of Dr. Kissinger, expressing his deep condolences for the death of Dr. Kissinger and condolences to his family. Prime Minister Li Qiang sent a message of condolence to Dr. Kissinger’s family. Wang Yi, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and director of the Office of the Central Foreign Affairs Commission, sent a message of condolence to US Secretary of State Antony Blinken. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Wang Wenbin said that Dr. Kissinger attached great importance to Sino-US relations during his lifetime and believed that Sino-US relations were crucial to the peace and prosperity of China, the United States and the world. China and the United States must inherit and carry forward Dr. Kissinger’s strategic vision, political courage, and diplomatic wisdom, adhere to the important consensus reached at the San Francisco meeting between the heads of state of China and the United States, adhere to mutual respect, peaceful coexistence, and win-win cooperation, and promote healthy and stable Sino-US relations. ,sustainable development. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 01 Dec 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>