<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 勇做开拓进取攻坚克难先锋 努力建设更高水平自贸试验区]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/27/nw.D110000renmrb_20230927_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, September 27, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, September 26&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, President of the State, and Chairman of the Central Military Commission, recently The important instructions on further promoting the construction of free trade pilot zones pointed out that the construction of free trade pilot zones is an important strategic measure of the Party Central Committee to promote reform and opening up in the new era. Over the past ten years, each pilot trade zone has implemented the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, emancipated the mind, kept integrity and innovated, launched a large number of basic and pioneering reform and opening-up measures, formed many iconic and leading institutional innovation achievements, and effectively played the role of reform and opening-up. Comprehensive test platform function. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that on the new journey, we must thoroughly implement the free trade pilot zone improvement strategy on the basis of a comprehensive summary of ten years of construction experience, bravely be a pioneer in forging ahead and overcoming difficulties, and be a pioneer in wider areas and Carry out deeper exploration and strive to build a higher-level free trade pilot zone. It is necessary to uphold the party&#39;s overall leadership, adhere to high-level openness as the guide and institutional innovation as the core, coordinate development and security, align with international economic and trade rules with high standards, further promote institutional openness, strengthen overall reform planning and system integration, and promote the entire industry The innovative development of the chain will enable the free trade pilot zone to better play a demonstration role. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;A symposium on the 10th anniversary of the construction of the Pilot Free Trade Zone was held in Beijing on September 26. He Lifeng, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Vice Premier of the State Council, conveyed Xi Jinping&#39;s important instructions and delivered a speech at the meeting, saying that he should conscientiously study and deeply understand the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s important instructions, comprehensively summarize the experience in the construction of the free trade pilot zone, and thoroughly implement the improvement of the free trade pilot zone. Strategy, continue to change concepts, strengthen safeguard measures, coordinate development and security, strive for new breakthroughs in institutional innovation, make new expansions in promoting openness, make new improvements in planning development, and strive to build a higher-level free trade pilot zone. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;At the symposium, the responsible comrades of the Ministry of Commerce reported on the ten-year construction of the free trade pilot zone. The responsible comrades of the Ministry of Finance, the People&#39;s Bank of China, the General Administration of Customs and Shanghai, Tianjin, Fujian, Liaoning, Sichuan and Guangxi Made a speech. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Relevant departments of the central and state agencies, and responsible comrades of the provinces, autonomous regions and municipalities where the 21 free trade pilot zones are located attended the symposium. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 构建新发展格局  推动高质量发展]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/27/nw.D110000renmrb_20230927_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, September 27, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;From September 20th to 21st, General Secretary Xi Jinping inspected Zhejiang and delivered an important speech. On September 24, on his way back to Beijing, General Secretary Xi Jinping inspected Zaozhuang, Shandong and delivered an important speech. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech aroused enthusiastic response among the cadres and the masses. Everyone expressed that they must conscientiously study, understand and thoroughly implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech, completely, accurately and comprehensively implement the new development concept, focus on building a new development pattern, promote high-quality development, focus on building a common prosperity demonstration area, and create a new era to comprehensively showcase China. It is an important window for the superiority of the socialist system with distinctive characteristics, adhere to a blueprint to draw it to the end, continue to promote the &quot;Eight-Eighth Strategy&quot; to be in-depth and practical, always work hard, be at the forefront, and be at the forefront, and strive to write a new era of Chinese-style modernization in Zhejiang Chapter. Build a good brand, improve quality, extend the industrial chain, enhance industrial market competitiveness and comprehensive benefits, and drive more folks to get rich together. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Being at the forefront of using scientific and technological innovation to create new advantages for development&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out that Zhejiang must be at the forefront of using scientific and technological innovation to create new advantages for development. At the forefront. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We must thoroughly implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech, continue to promote the construction of a high-level innovative province and a strong science and technology province, highlight the ‘main starting point’ of scientific and technological innovation leadership, and create a ‘big platform’ for strategic scientific and technological strength. , explore &quot;new paths&quot; for key technology research, strengthen the &quot;main force&quot; of corporate scientific and technological innovation, cultivate the &quot;reservoir&quot; of global scientific and technological talents, and enhance the &quot;driving force&quot; of scientific and technological system reform, in order to accelerate the realization of high-level scientific and technological self-reliance and build a strong scientific and technological country. Contribute to Zhejiang’s strength.” said Tong Guili, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group of Zhejiang Provincial Department of Science and Technology. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Min, deputy director of the Office of the Zhejiang Provincial Digital Economy Development Leading Group, said that Zhejiang will deepen the construction of the national digital economy innovation and development pilot zone, coordinate and promote key actions such as upgrading key digital core technologies and releasing the value of data elements, and strive to Create a number of strategic emerging industry clusters and digital industry clusters with international competitiveness. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;General Secretary Xi Jinping called for &#39;promoting the development of high-end, intelligent and green manufacturing&#39;. We must anchor the goal of building a global advanced manufacturing base and promote high-end manufacturing in key areas such as advanced manufacturing and the digital economy.&quot; Quality development, and continuously enhance the power and vitality to promote new industrialization.&quot; said Ye Jiansong, deputy director of the Zhejiang Provincial Department of Economy and Information Technology. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhu Zheng, director of the Hangzhou Comprehensive Bonded Zone Management Office, said: “We must follow the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech as a guide, persist in laying out the construction of industrial and supply chains from a global perspective, and improve communication platforms such as the Supply Chain Cooperation Forum. , build a bridge of supply chain cooperation, and continuously improve the resilience and security level of the industrial chain and supply chain.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;In recent years, we have cooperated with universities, scientific research institutes, etc. to build R&amp;D centers, constantly breaking through the Internet of Things, cloud Key technologies such as computing and big data will be used to create application scenarios such as smart parking and smart urban management. The next step is to accelerate the implementation and transformation of scientific and technological achievements and help upgrade urban management.&quot; Chief Technology Officer of Chengyun Technology (China) Co., Ltd. located in Hangzhou, Zhejiang Guan Yuqiang said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Set an example in promoting common prosperity&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized that Zhejiang should set an example in promoting common prosperity. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We must deepen the ‘Thousand Villages Demonstration, Ten Thousand Villages Improvement’ project, and accelerate the drawing of a new picture of ‘Thousand Villages Leading, Thousands of Villages Revitalizing, Whole Region Shared Wealth, and Urban and Rural Harmony’.” Director of the Zhejiang Provincial Department of Agriculture and Rural Affairs Wang Tonglin said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We must take narrowing the urban-rural gap, regional gap, and income gap as the main direction, further improve the urban-rural integrated development system and mechanism, continue to promote high-quality development of mountainous island counties (cities, districts), and solidly promote common prosperity. &quot; said Sun Zhejun, deputy director of the Office of the Leading Group for High-Quality Development and Construction of Common Prosperity Demonstration Zone in Zhejiang Province. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wu Weibin, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Director of the Zhejiang Provincial Department of Human Resources and Social Security, said that it is necessary to continuously promote the construction of a high-quality employment and entrepreneurship system, carry out special actions to stabilize enterprises, expand jobs and increase employment, and do a good job in employment assistance for key groups. , intensify efforts to deepen the reform of the income distribution system, and improve the multi-level social security system. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We must thoroughly implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech, adhere to and develop the Maple Bridge Experience in the new era, adhere to the party’s mass line, correctly handle contradictions among the people, and closely rely on the people , solve the problem at the grassroots level and nip it in the bud.&quot; Shen Zhijiang, member of the Standing Committee of the Shaoxing Municipal Party Committee and Secretary of the Zhuji Municipal Party Committee in Zhejiang Province, said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wei Zhongqiang, Executive Deputy Secretary of the Political and Legal Affairs Committee of the Zhejiang Provincial Party Committee, said that it is necessary to thoroughly implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech, coordinate and promote the construction of a safe Zhejiang and a rule of law Zhejiang, and strive to write a new chapter in the modernization of Zhejiang with Chinese style Provide strong protection. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Continue to write a new chapter in deepening reform and expanding opening up&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out that Zhejiang must continue to write a new chapter in deepening reform and expanding opening up. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech provided scientific guidance for Zhejiang to comprehensively deepen reforms in the new era.” Jin Xiaoming, executive deputy director of the Office of the Zhejiang Provincial Party Committee’s Comprehensive Deepening Reform Committee, said that Zhejiang will take reforms in key areas as a guide , adhere to “what the country needs, what Zhejiang can do, what the people want, and what the future wants”, promote institutional innovation in various fields, and strive to form more replicable and promoteable institutional innovation results. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ruan Ganghui, deputy mayor of Jinhua City, Zhejiang Province and director of the Jinyi Area Management Committee of China (Zhejiang) Pilot Free Trade Zone, said: &quot;We will give full play to the pilot free trade zone and Yiwu International Trade Comprehensive Reform Pilot Zone We will serve the whole country and take a global view to plan reforms, continuously improve the quality and level of trade and investment cooperation, and cultivate new advantages in foreign trade competition.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Implementing the important speech of General Secretary Xi Jinping spirit, we must proactively adapt to the trend of restructuring international economic and trade rules, continue to establish and improve systems such as the roundtable for foreign-invested enterprises, strengthen the cultivation of foreign trade entities, and increase the development of foreign trade markets.&quot; said Han Jie, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Director of the Zhejiang Provincial Department of Commerce. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Jian, member of the Standing Committee of the Jinhua Municipal Party Committee in Zhejiang Province and Secretary of the Yiwu Municipal Party Committee, said: “Keeping in mind General Secretary Xi Jinping’s instructions, Yiwu will continue to innovate methods and channels to utilize foreign investment, expand foreign trade, and strive to cultivate new formats and new models of digital trade. , promote the &quot;Yi-Xin-Europe&quot; freight train to increase efficiency and allow more Yiwu small commodities to break into the big market and become big industries.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Zhejiang will continue to encourage and support private enterprises to actively participate in the global industry The division of labor and resource allocation will make greater contributions to expanding domestic and international markets and smoothing the domestic and international dual circulation.&quot; said Zhang Shuming, deputy director of the Zhejiang Provincial Development and Reform Commission. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Actively explore in building the modern civilization of the Chinese nation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized that Zhejiang should actively explore in building the modern civilization of the Chinese nation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech has strengthened our confidence in protecting, inheriting and utilizing the Grand Canal culture.” Xu Jun, Secretary of the Yuecheng District Committee of Shaoxing City, Zhejiang Province, said that in recent years, the local government has improved and implemented Relevant provisions and regulations on the protection and management of the Grand Canal, establish and improve the Grand Canal Zhejiang Canal Heritage Protection List, and continue to innovate new forms and new mechanisms for protection, inheritance and utilization such as fine management, digital protection, and cultural tourism integration. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Keeping in mind General Secretary Xi Jinping’s instructions, we must further explore and protect the rich historical and cultural resources, speed up the construction of the Shaoxing section of the East Zhejiang Canal into a bright cultural belt, a green ecological belt, and a colorful tourism belt, and strive to make the ancient The Grand Canal has taken on a new look of the times.&quot; said the Secretary of the Shaoxing Municipal Party Committee, Zhejiang Province warmly. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Dong Fuquan, director of the Cultural Development and Reform Department of the Propaganda Department of the Zhejiang Provincial Party Committee, said that Zhejiang will adhere to the position of Chinese culture and actively develop new culture that reflects the requirements of the times and has the characteristics of the times. Zhejiang will adhere to the &quot;tracing the source&quot; and carry out Xi Jinping&#39;s Research and spread the thought of socialism with Chinese characteristics in the new era; adhere to the &quot;continuity of context&quot;, deeply explore cultural genes, and develop the modern form of Chinese civilization; adhere to the &quot;spiritual common wealth&quot;, continue to promote the standardization and equalization of urban and rural public cultural services, and allow cultural development The results will benefit all people more and more equitably; adhere to &quot;cultural exchanges&quot;, make good use of external communication windows to tell the story of Zhejiang and China, and continuously enhance the appeal of Chinese culture and the influence of Chinese civilization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, Shangcheng District, Hangzhou City, Zhejiang Province has created a number of characteristic neighborhoods and cultural tourism experience points by fully exploring and protecting thousands of years of human history and cultural heritage. Fan Weidong, member of the Standing Committee of the Shangcheng District Party Committee and Minister of the Propaganda Department, said: &quot;We will shoulder the new cultural mission in the new era and continue to prosper and develop cultural undertakings and cultural industries.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Uphold and strengthen the party&#39;s overall leadership , Strengthen and improve party building&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out that we must uphold and strengthen the party’s overall leadership and strengthen and improve party building. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized the establishment of a correct view of political performance, which further pointed out the way forward for our officers and entrepreneurship.&quot; Yang Weidong, member of the Standing Committee of the Huzhou Municipal Party Committee and Secretary of the Anji County Party Committee, Zhejiang Province, said that Anji County has deeply practiced the concept of &quot;lucid waters and lush mountains are golden mountains&quot; The Silver Mountain Concept promotes development to a higher level. &quot;We must draw a blueprint to the end, work one term after another, and strive to continuously transform &#39;green appearance&#39; into &#39;golden value&#39;.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhejiang Province Lang Wenrong, Secretary of the Party Leadership Group and Director of the Department of Ecology and Environment, said that to implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech, we must more consciously practice the people-centered development philosophy, make every effort to promote ecology to benefit and enrich the people, and firmly move towards green, low-carbon and high-energy development. Quality development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Guided by the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech, we must continue to strengthen the education, training and practical training of cadres, carry out the action of &#39;Adhere to the correct view of political achievements and build new achievements for the people&#39; throughout the province, and establish and improve A comprehensive assessment system that embodies the correct view of political performance, constantly improves cadre responsibility as an incentive and protection mechanism, and educates and guides party members and cadres to dare to venture, to be good at planning, and to be practical and practical.&quot; said Xie Zhiyuan, executive deputy director of the Organization Department of the Zhejiang Provincial Party Committee. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“It is necessary to combine the in-depth implementation of the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speeches with the in-depth development of thematic education, and strive to achieve results in learning to build souls, learning to increase wisdom, learning to rectify the style, and learning to promote cadres. Real results.&quot; He Huigang, deputy director of the Office of the Theme Education Leading Group of the Ningbo Municipal Party Committee, Zhejiang Province, said, &quot;Based on reality, we will deepen the implementation of &#39;tracing the origins of learning ideas to promote practice&#39; and &#39;big visits, big surveys, big services and big problem-solving&#39; Activities such as &#39;Visiting villages and communes in Lianzhen Street, visiting businesses and visiting people&#39; use steps to measure people&#39;s sentiments, listen to people&#39;s voices with true feelings, and use practical methods to solve people&#39;s concerns.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Enhance the competitiveness of the industrial market and Comprehensive benefits, driving more folks to get rich together&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of September 24, on the way back to Beijing, General Secretary Xi Jinping visited Zaozhuang City, Shandong Province for an inspection. The garden pomegranate germplasm resource bank inspected pomegranate tree species, learned about the local pomegranate planting history, germplasm resource collection and preservation, and industrial development. They also came to the pomegranate plantation to ask fellow villagers about this year&#39;s pomegranate planting, harvest and income situation. General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out that it is necessary to build a good brand, improve quality, extend the industrial chain, enhance industrial market competitiveness and comprehensive benefits, and drive more people to get rich together. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;My family has grown several varieties of pomegranates, which are resistant to frost damage and do not crack. The maturity period lasts from early September to late October, which can meet market demand at different stages.&quot; said Liu Yuan, a pomegranate grower in Yicheng District. , &quot;Fruit sales are good, income is rising, and life is as prosperous as pomegranate fruit. In the coming year, I will expand the planting area and continue to work hard!&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s important speech , we must continue to preserve and innovatively utilize pomegranate germplasm resources, develop deeply processed products such as pomegranate juice, pomegranate wine, pomegranate tea, and pomegranate honey, and continuously enrich products.&quot; said Li Zhiqiang, director of the Zaozhuang Pomegranate Research Institute. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The General Secretary pointed out that people&#39;s living standards are improving, the market demand for high-quality specialties is growing, and the pomegranate industry has development potential. This encourages us.&quot; Chen Guangliang, director of the Zaozhuang Municipal Agriculture and Rural Affairs Bureau, said that he will promote The pomegranate industry will be scaled up, standardized, specialized and branded, and a modern pomegranate deep processing industrial park will be built to drive more people to get rich together. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Our reporters Li Zhongwen, Jiang Nan, Gu Chun, Liu Junguo, Dou Hanyang, Dou Hao, Xiao Jiaxin)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 坚持好、发展好新时代“枫桥经验”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/27/nw.D110000renmrb_20230927_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, September 27, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;&quot;We must adhere to and develop the &#39;Maple Bridge Experience&#39; in the new era.&quot; Recently, General Secretary Xi Jinping visited Zhejiang during his inspection Come to Fengqiao Town, Zhuji City, the birthplace of the &quot;Fengqiao Experience&quot;, visit the Fengqiao Experience Exhibition Hall, and learn about the vivid practice of the &quot;Fengqiao Experience&quot; in the new era. He pointed out that &quot;adhere to the party&#39;s mass line, correctly handle contradictions among the people, and We must rely closely on the people to solve problems at the grassroots level and nip them in the bud.” &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Revitalized by persistence and carried forward by development, the &quot;Fengqiao Experience&quot; of &quot;relying on the masses to resolve conflicts on the spot&quot; created by the cadres and the masses in Fengqiao, Zhejiang in the 1960s has become a national comprehensive political and legal governance A flag for the battle line. This year marks the 60th anniversary of Comrade Mao Zedong’s instructions to study and promote the “Maple Bridge Experience” and the 20th anniversary of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s instructions to uphold and develop the “Maple Bridge Experience”. Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping has made important instructions on many occasions, emphasizing that &quot;Party committees and governments at all levels must fully understand the significance of the &#39;Maple Bridge Experience&#39;, carry forward fine styles, adapt to the requirements of the times, innovate mass work methods, and be good at using &quot;The rule of law thinking and method of solving conflicts and problems involving the vital interests of the people&quot; has given the &quot;Maple Bridge Experience&quot; a new era connotation, allowing it to play a greater role in serving the people and resolving conflicts. From improving the petition system to improving the comprehensive mechanism for the prevention, mediation and resolution of social conflicts and disputes in multiple ways; from the &quot;Three Zero&quot; work method of Mudan Community in Shenyang, Liaoning, to the &quot;Fengqiao&quot; dispute resolution work method of &quot;Overseas Chinese Township&quot; in Mingxi County, Fujian... &quot;Fengqiao&quot; &quot;Experience&quot; has been enriched and developed in the great practice of the new era, with more emphasis on the party&#39;s leadership, more emphasis on rule of law thinking, more emphasis on scientific and technological support, and more emphasis on social participation, showing a lasting charm. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Adhere to and implement the party&#39;s mass line, fully mobilize the masses, organize the masses, and rely on the masses to solve their own problems under the leadership of the party. The most prominent feature of the &quot;Maple Bridge Experience&quot; in the new era is to firmly Grasp the grassroots foundation and prevent and resolve conflicts and risks at the grassroots level to the greatest extent. The reason why the &quot;Maple Bridge Experience&quot; will always maintain its vitality and vitality lies in adhering to the fundamental principle of the party&#39;s leadership, adhering to the fundamental position of people-centeredness, adhering to the fundamental approach of comprehensive policy implementation, and establishing the fundamental concept of moving the gateway forward. , and consolidate the fundamental support of the grassroots foundation. The most important achievement and the most distinctive feature of the &quot;Maple Bridge Experience&quot; that has developed to this day is the integration of self-discipline and heterodiscipline, rigidity and flexibility, body and mind management, human power and technology. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Governing the country and ensuring peace and stability lies at the grassroots level. The 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China made arrangements for improving the social governance system and clearly stated that &quot;the Maple Bridge Experience in the new era must be upheld and developed at the grassroots level of society.&quot; Chinese-style modernization is a great and arduous undertaking. All the people must be mobilized to unite into &quot;a hard piece of steel&quot; under the banner of the Party. Great power. We must deeply realize that social stability is a prerequisite for a strong country. Only by adhering to and developing the &quot;Maple Bridge Experience&quot; in the new era, improving the mechanism for correctly handling contradictions among the people under the new situation, and promptly resolving problems at the grassroots level and nipping them in the bud, can we ensure that the people live and work in peace and contentment, the society is stable and orderly, and the country has long-term peace and stability. Write a new chapter in the two miracles of rapid economic development and long-term social stability, and create a stable, united, harmonious and stable social environment for promoting Chinese modernization. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;To uphold and develop the &quot;Maple Bridge Experience&quot; in the new era, we must implement the party&#39;s mass line, consciously integrate people-centered development ideas into all work, and accurately respond to the demands of the masses. Solve the difficulties and conflicts of the grassroots people in a timely manner. It is necessary to correctly handle conflicts among the people, strengthen and improve the work of people&#39;s petitions, unblock and standardize the channels for the expression of people&#39;s demands, coordination of interests, and protection of rights and interests, improve the grassroots governance platform with grid management, refined services, and information support, and improve urban and rural community governance. system, and continuously improve the ability to prevent and resolve conflicts among the people at their source. We must rely closely on the people, give full play to the role of grassroots party organizations as a fighting fortress and the leading role of party building, develop and strengthen mass prevention and control forces, promote the focus of social governance to move down to the grassroots, build a social governance system of joint construction, joint governance and shared benefits, and build a social governance system for everyone A social governance community where everyone has responsibilities, everyone fulfills their responsibilities, and everyone enjoys it. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Chinese-style modernization is the cause of hundreds of millions of people. The people are the main body of Chinese-style modernization and will always be the most solid support and the most powerful confidence. On the way forward, we must unite more closely around the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core, fully implement Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, uphold and develop the &quot;Maple Bridge Experience&quot; in the new era, and uphold the Party&#39;s mass line We will continue to improve the ability and level of people&#39;s work under the new situation, so that the results of social governance can benefit all people more and more equitably. We will surely be able to continue to turn the people&#39;s yearning for a better life into reality and promote Chinese-style modernization. In the process, we closely rely on the people to create new historical achievements. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 二十届中央第一轮巡视完成反馈]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/27/nw.D110000renmrb_20230927_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, September 27, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;This newspaper, Beijing, September 26th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Zhao Cheng) According to the deployment of the Party Central Committee, the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China The central government’s first round of inspection feedback work has been completed recently. Feedback from this round of inspections is carried out through a combination of centralized feedback and &quot;one-on-one&quot; feedback from the inspection team. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On September 19, the Central Inspection Leading Group held a centralized feedback meeting on the first round of inspections of the 20th Central Committee. The meeting conveyed and studied the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech when he listened to the Central Committee’s first round of inspection reports, informed the common problems discovered during the inspection, and made arrangements for rectification during the inspection. Liu Jinguo, secretary of the Central Secretariat and deputy leader of the Central Inspection Leading Group, attended the meeting and delivered a speech. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From September 20th to 22nd, 15 central inspection teams conducted &quot;one-on-one&quot; meetings with the party groups of 30 medium-sized enterprises, the party committees of 5 medium-sized financial enterprises, and the party groups of the State Sports General Administration during this round of inspections. feedback. According to the Central Inspection Work Arrangement, each Central Inspection Team notified the principals of the inspected party organizations of the outstanding problems discovered during the inspection, and reported the inspection situation to the leadership team. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Feedback pointed out that in recent years, centrally managed enterprises and financial enterprises have faced the complex and severe external environment and the impact of the epidemic. They have withstood the test and bravely shouldered heavy responsibilities. They have been successful in winning the battle against poverty and promoting high-level scientific and technological self-reliance. It has made important contributions in building a new development pattern, promoting high-quality development, coordinating epidemic prevention and control, and economic and social development, and has made new progress in building a sports power. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The feedback seriously pointed out the outstanding problems existing in the fields of state-owned enterprises, finance and sports. Some fail to implement the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, do not have a deep understanding of the responsibilities and missions they shoulder, and have gaps in their performance of duties; some do not coordinate development and safety, have weak risk awareness, and have insufficient prevention and control mechanisms; some implement party management The responsibility for party governance is not in place, the pressure transmission is decreasing layer by layer, the implementation of the strict tone is weak, the integrity risks of key positions such as &quot;top leaders&quot; are relatively prominent, the problem of &quot;depending on the enterprise to take advantage of the enterprise&quot; is common, the &quot;four styles&quot; problem is prominent, and it violates the eight central regulations Mental problems still occur; there are weak links in the construction of some leadership groups and cadre talent teams, and the political functions of grassroots party organizations need to be strengthened. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The feedback requires that the inspected units should thoroughly study Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, conscientiously study and implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech when he listened to the inspection report, and fully implement the deployment of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China. Uphold and strengthen the party&#39;s leadership, firmly establish and practice a correct view of political performance, completely, accurately and comprehensively implement the new development concept, adhere to functional positioning, focus on main responsibilities and main businesses, and promote high-quality development. It is necessary to resolutely implement the political responsibility to prevent and resolve major risks, establish bottom-line thinking and extreme thinking, comprehensively sort out and investigate hidden risks, plug leaks and fill gaps, resolve risks and recover losses, and effectively safeguard national interests. It is necessary to conscientiously implement the &quot;two responsibilities&quot; of comprehensively and strictly governing the party, strengthen the effectiveness of supervision of &quot;top leaders&quot;, intensify the investigation and handling of corruption cases, seriously correct the &quot;four styles&quot; problem, deepen the use of cases to promote reform, use cases to promote treatment, and integrate We dare not, cannot, or do not want to be corrupted. It is necessary to thoroughly implement the party&#39;s organizational line in the new era and effectively strengthen the construction of leadership teams, cadres and talent teams, and grassroots party organizations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Feedback emphasized that inspections and rectifications should be more serious and tough, and the strict tone, strict measures, and strict atmosphere should be passed on and carried out consistently. The inspected party organization must resolutely shoulder the political responsibility for rectification. The &quot;top leader&quot; is the first person responsible for rectification. Other members of the team must conscientiously perform &quot;one post, two responsibilities&quot;, strictly compare feedback opinions, and establish a problem list, task list, and responsibility list. Combining the problems found during the inspection with the theme education inspection issues and the problems that were not rectified in the last inspection, rectify the system and rectify the whole body, practice the &quot;two maintenances&quot; with practical actions, and reflect the loyalty and responsibility with the rectification results. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The feedback requires that the responsibilities of all parties for rectification should be consolidated and efforts should be made in the same direction to solve the problem. Discipline inspection and supervision agencies must strengthen daily supervision of rectification, focus on key issues, focus on specific people and specific matters, strengthen on-the-spot inspections, grasp the real situation, and seize examples of those who deal with perfunctory or false rectifications and seriously hold accountable them. The organizational department should strengthen research and guidance based on the inspection situation, and promote the solution of outstanding problems in the construction of leadership teams, cadres and talent teams, and grassroots party organizations. Relevant functional departments must comprehensively make full use of the inspection results, strengthen daily supervision of common and deep-seated problems reflected in the inspection, deepen reforms in key areas, optimize policy supply, and improve systems and mechanisms. Inspection agencies must strengthen overall coordination and supervision, establish and improve rectification work mechanisms, and report important situations to the Party Central Committee in a timely manner. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It is understood that the Central Inspection Team has also received clues about problems reported by some leading cadres, and has transferred them to the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and the National Supervisory Commission, the Organization Department of the Central Committee and other relevant parties for handling in accordance with relevant regulations. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 韩正会见美国前财长保尔森]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/27/nw.D110000renmrb_20230927_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, September 27, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, September 26&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;On September 26, Vice President Han Zheng met with the United States in Beijing Former Treasury Secretary Paulson. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Han Zheng said that China-US relations are the most important bilateral relations in the world today. As the largest developing country and the largest developed country, the two countries should strengthen mutually beneficial cooperation in various fields, jointly promote the recovery of the world economy and cope with the Global challenges. China has always viewed and handled Sino-U.S. relations in accordance with the three principles of mutual respect, peaceful coexistence, and win-win cooperation proposed by President Xi Jinping. We hope that the U.S. and China will meet each other halfway and jointly push Sino-U.S. relations back to a healthy and stable track. Since the beginning of this year, China&#39;s economy has maintained an upward trend. We will further optimize the economic structure, deepen reform and opening up, and achieve high-quality development. We welcome more American companies to invest in China and share development opportunities. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Paulson said that I have confidence in China&#39;s economic development prospects. U.S.-China relations have an important impact on the world. The two countries should maintain communication and dialogue, strengthen cultural exchanges and economic and trade cooperation, and jointly respond to global challenges such as climate change. We are willing to continue to play an active role in promoting the stable development of US-China relations. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 呼和浩特在筑牢生态安全屏障上求实效]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/27/nw.D110000renmrb_20230927_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, September 27, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;The water is gurgling, tourists are everywhere, cattle and sheep are flocking on the grassland, and Daqingshan is lush and lush with trees. In the golden autumn, when you walk into the Chilechuan National Grassland Nature Park located in the northern suburbs of Hohhot City, Inner Mongolia Autonomous Region, you will be greeted by surging green waves and the fragrance of grass. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;We all call it the &#39;city back garden&#39;. Whenever we have free time, we come here to stroll around and experience &#39;Cele River, under the Yin Mountain, the sky is like a dome, covering the surrounding fields...&#39;&quot; Hohhot citizen Liu Baoquan said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In June this year, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized during his inspection in Inner Mongolia that building a strong ecological security barrier in northern my country is the &quot;biggest country&quot; that Inner Mongolia must bear in mind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, Hohhot City has taken practical measures to seek practical results, focusing on greening improvement, water body management, and pollution control, and coordinating the comprehensive management of mountains, rivers, forests, farmlands, lakes, grass, and sand to create a livable environment with dense green and clear water. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chilechuan Grassland and Daqing Mountain are important ecological security barriers in the north of Hohhot City. However, due to factors such as drought and lack of rain, reclamation and quarrying in the past few years, the vegetation was once reduced and sand and gravel were everywhere. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“At that time, in the spring and autumn in Hohhot, the wind and sand were very strong, and I often brought dirt all over my body when I went home.” Liu Baoquan said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since 2012, Hohhot City has invested nearly 200 million yuan in ecological restoration of Chilechuan. Today, the average summer humidity of the Chilechuan National Grassland Nature Park is 67%, attracting many tourists to enjoy the pleasant ecological environment. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the same time, Hohhot City has implemented comprehensive ecological management and protection projects and ecological construction projects on the front slopes of Daqing Mountain. &quot;Every year during the tree-planting season, the barren hills are filled with afforestation teams.&quot; Liu Baoquan, 30, said that almost all Hohhot citizens of his age participated in afforestation activities in Daqingshan when they were students. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“So far, a total of 72,000 acres of green barren hills have been completed in the Daqingshan area, and the ecological protection construction area totals 118 square kilometers, building a beautiful green ecological barrier.” Yang, Director of the Ecological Environment Bureau of Hohhot City Introduced by Wu Ri Tu. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Entering the city from the Chilechuan National Grassland Natural Park, rows of trees, patches of grassland and other rich greenery come into view. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In recent years, Hohhot has vigorously implemented the construction of urban &quot;pocket parks&quot;. 310 new &quot;pocket parks&quot; will be built in 2022, and urban green space continues to increase. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As of now, the green coverage rate of Hohhot’s built-up areas has reached 43.21%, and the per capita park green space has reached 19.62 square meters. Standing on Daqing Mountain and looking around, the whole city is full of green. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the sun sets, the clear river water is covered with a golden coat, the flowers and plants on the shore are swaying in the wind, and the warm evening breeze carries the chirping of birds... Not long ago, on the banks of the Dahei River in southern Hohhot, a local The artist created a painting called &quot;Sunset on the Dahei River&quot;. Dahei River is a tributary of the Yellow River and an important water system in Hohhot City. “In recent years, fundamental changes have taken place here,” the painter said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In order to thoroughly control the water system, Hohhot City has implemented a special action to meet the emission standards of industrial pollution sources. As of now, all 45 water-related companies in the city have built first-level sewage treatment facilities, and 5 domestic sewage treatment plants in the city have been inspected. All have been implemented to improve standards and expand production capacity, and the quality of factory water has reached Grade A standards.&quot; Zhang Yongde, director of Hohhot Water Affairs Bureau, said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The environment is people’s livelihood, the green mountains are beautiful, and the blue sky is happiness.” The responsible comrade of the Hohhot Municipal Party Committee said, “We must continue to work hard on ‘building an important ecological security barrier in northern my country’ to make Hohhot Mountains more beautiful. Greener, greener water, and fresher air make it a beautiful city that is suitable for living, working, studying, raising, and traveling.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 前8月铁路完成固定资产投资4320亿元（新数据 新看点）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/27/nw.D110000renmrb_20230927_7-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, September 27, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-09/27/01/rmrb2023092701p38_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;Data source: China Railway Group &lt;BR/>;Drawing: Shen Yiling&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, September 26th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; (Reporter Li Xinping) The reporter recently learned from China State Railway Group Co., Ltd.: From January to August this year, the country’s railways completed fixed asset investment of 432 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 7.2%. This year, more than 3,000 kilometers of new railway lines are expected to be put into operation across the country, including 2,500 kilometers of high-speed railways, and the construction of a modern railway infrastructure system is accelerating. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Some projects have been fully completed and put into operation. The quality improvement project of the Qinghai-Tibet Railway from Xining to Golmud was completed, and the Fuxing EMU was put into operation for the first time; the Lanzhou-Xining High-speed Railway section was renovated, achieving a high-speed operation of 250 kilometers per hour; the Guinan High-speed Railway with a total length of 482 kilometers was put into operation. The maximum number of passengers arriving and departing from the station on a daily basis is 11,000. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Multiple railway projects are about to be put into operation. The Shanghai-Nanjing High-speed Railway along the Yangtze River, the Fuzhou-Xiamen High-speed Railway, and the Qingbaijiang-Zhenjiang Pass section of the Sichuan-Qinghai Railway have gradually entered the trial operation stage and are about to be put into operation; the Shandong Section of the Jizheng High-speed Railway, the Changjing-Huang High-speed Railway, and the Jinxing Intercity Railway have begun joint debugging Joint testing; the construction of several projects such as the Lijiang-Shangri-La section of the Yunnan-Tibet Railway, the Xuyong-Bijie Railway, and the Longyan-Wuping section of the Long-Long Railway are also nearing completion. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;A large number of projects under construction are being promoted solidly and effectively. The reconstruction of the original site of the Dali Railway Station has been fully started. The first over 10,000-meter tunnel of the Shenbai High-speed Railway has been successfully connected. The Ningxia section of the Baoyin High-speed Railway has officially entered the track laying stage. The preliminary construction of the Yi section of the Haiyi High-speed Railway has been completed. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;From January to August, the national railway shipped 2.575 billion tons of cargo, including 468 million tons of containers, a year-on-year increase of 7.4%. The vigorous development of multimodal transport has promoted the continuous optimization and adjustment of the transportation structure. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 图片报道]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/27/nw.D110000renmrb_20230927_8-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, September 27, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20230927/1695760774860_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/ TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;my country&#39;s first suspended aerial rail train, the &quot;Optics Valley Photon&quot; sky rail, opened for operation in the East Lake High-tech Zone in Wuhan, Hubei Province on September 26. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The train operates in fully automatic driverless mode, with a maximum operating speed of 60 kilometers per hour. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Fan Haotian&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Huang&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Photography Report (People’s Vision)&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 让可持续交通发展成果更好造福世界各国人民]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/27/nw.D110000renmrb_20230927_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, September 27, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;&quot;China is willing to work with all countries in the world to uphold the concept of extensive consultation, joint contribution and shared benefits, so that the results of sustainable transportation development can better benefit Peoples of the World”. On September 25, President Xi Jinping sent a congratulatory letter to the Global Sustainable Transportation Summit, which aroused strong resonance at home and abroad. Everyone said that President Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter clarified China’s clear position on promoting global transportation cooperation, providing new opportunities for the world with its own development, and making the results of sustainable transportation development better benefit people around the world. It brought together all parties’ mutually beneficial and win-win views. strength. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;&quot;The congratulatory letter summarizes the main characteristics of a sustainable transportation system from seven aspects: safety, convenience, efficiency, green, economy, inclusiveness, and resilience, and looks forward to a future where people can enjoy their travels and things can flow smoothly. The beautiful vision has greatly inspired the confidence of the majority of transportation service cadres and workers.&quot; Cai Tuanjie, Director of the Transportation Services Department of the Ministry of Transport, said that my country&#39;s modern comprehensive transportation system is becoming increasingly perfect, and the world&#39;s largest high-speed railway network and highway network have been built. and world-class port clusters, cross-sea bridges, airports, plateau railways and other major projects are vivid practices in the construction of a sustainable transportation system. Transportation has achieved leapfrog development, effectively promoted my country&#39;s industrial development and improved the quality of life of more than 1.4 billion Chinese people. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;现场聆听了习近平主席的贺信，吉尔吉斯斯坦副总理托罗巴耶夫对建设可持续交通体系是支撑服务经济社会高质量发展的重要举措感受深刻。托罗巴耶夫说：“交通领域是世界经济的关键环节之一。今年我们开通了从西安到比什凯克等多条航线，推动实现中吉乌铁路项目，实施大规模的交通物流项目。我相信吉尔吉斯斯坦会成为一个桥梁，更好连接中亚与中国。”&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“习近平主席强调的&#39;人享其行、物畅其流&#39;的美好愿景，是可持续交通体系发展的方向和目标，也是我们交通人努力为之奋斗的图景。”交通运输部规划研究院院长刘昕表示，未来将聚焦综合交通、空间规划、要素保障、融合发展、“双碳”战略、全球合作、机制保障等领域，提高规划的前瞻性和可操作性，为全球可持续交通发展提供更多助力。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;交通运输现代化是衡量国家现代化水平的重要标志。加快建设交通强国，推动可持续交通健康发展，既要着力探索符合国情的交通运输发展路径，也要加强国际合作，构建面向全球的运输网络。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“贺信指出，中国正在加快建设交通强国。现代化交通基础设施建设具有投资规模大、落地见效快、综合效益好、带动作用强等特点，这正是建设交通强国的应有之义。”中铁十四局雄商高铁项目负责人王永辉说，目前正在参与建设我国“八纵八横”高速铁路网的重要组成部分——雄商高铁，未来还要在加强革命老区、民族地区、边远地区、脱贫地区现代化交通基础设施建设方面下“硬功夫”，推进现代化交通基础设施网与运输服务网、信息网、能源网进一步融合发展。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“按照习近平主席贺信的要求，我们将继续坚持与世界相交、与时代相通，以便捷的交通推动经济融通、人文交流，使世界成为紧密相连的地球村。”南方航空物流股份有限公司董事长刘祖斌表示，南航将进一步践行央企责任担当，确保航空货运物流各环节高效运转，为服务以国内大循环为主体、国内国际双循环相互促进的新发展格局贡献力量。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“当前世界经济发展还面临严峻挑战，发挥交通作为经济发展&#39;先行官&#39;的作用，要致力于推动全球交通合作，以我国自身发展为世界提供新机遇。”中国远洋海运集团有限公司相关负责人说。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;可持续交通发展是未来交通领域的大势所趋。面向未来，大家表示，要坚持开放联动，推进互联互通，以可持续的交通推动可持续的发展，推进全球可持续交通深化合作、高质量发展。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“习近平主席贺信强调秉持共商共建共享理念。中老铁路的发展，就是推动我国与其他国家之间互联互通、互利共赢的生动实践。”中国铁路昆明局集团有限公司客运部主任赵寅说，要进一步提升开行品质，让中老铁路国际旅客列车实现“从通到畅、从畅到快、从快到好”的目标。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“中国的可持续交通发展理念，将为世界可持续交通发展注入新的活力，将会更好地造福于世界各国人民。”瑞典“一带一路”研究所副所长侯赛因·阿斯卡里表示，从希腊比雷埃夫斯港到黑山南北高速公路，从克罗地亚佩列沙茨大桥到匈塞铁路，处处都能体现利益共享、环境友好、更高效益，可持续交通领域的中国经验、中国智慧，将为欧洲乃至世界的互联互通作出更为巨大的贡献。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;（新华社北京9月26日电）&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 从两份榜单看民营经济新发展]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/27/nw.D110000renmrb_20230927_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月27日星期三&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;日前，2023中国民营企业500强（以下简称“民企500强”）榜单和2023中国企业500强（以下简称“企业500强”）榜单先后发布。不少专家学者和企业界人士表示，两份榜单彰显了民营经济的成长进步，也坚定了广大民营企业进一步发展壮大的信心。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;综合实力加强&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2023民企500强营收增长3.94%，2023企业500强中民企占244家&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从民企500强榜单来看，民营企业的营收规模、总体实力均实现增长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;入围门槛更高。2023民企500强入围门槛达275.78亿元，比上年增加12.11亿元。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;企业营收更高。2023民企500强营业收入总额39.83万亿元，增长3.94%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;规模实力更强。2023民企500强资产总额46.31万亿元，增长11.21%。有28家民营企业500强入围世界500强。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“党中央始终坚持&#39;两个毫不动摇&#39;&#39;三个没有变&#39;。纵观十几年来民企500强榜单入围门槛不断提升的历程以及企业排序的变化，在各类政策支持下，广大民营企业开拓创新、迎难而上，主动适应新形势、新情况、新变化，积极开拓新市场、新业态、新领域，在转型升级、结构优化、提质增效等方面，实现了新的飞跃与突破。”中央统战部副部长、全国工商联党组书记徐乐江表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;从企业500强榜单来看，近年来，入围的民营企业数量保持增长态势。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“2023企业500强中，民营企业数量为244家，比2013年增加了54家。”中国企业联合会副研究员高蕊告诉记者，这些年，国有企业和民营企业的上榜数量逐渐接近，不同所有制的数量结构趋于稳定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;发展质量提升&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;2023企业500强研发投入持续增加，研发强度创新高&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;创新是引领发展的第一动力，企业是科技创新的主体。近年来，广大民营企业根据国家战略需要和行业发展趋势，持续加大研发投入，开展关键核心技术攻关，在科技创新方面取得一项项成绩。这些可喜变化，同样体现在两份榜单上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;先看民企500强榜单。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科研投入更足。2023民企500强中，研发人员占员工总数超过3%的企业326家，超过10%的企业175家；研发经费投入强度超过3%的企业86家，超过10%的企业8家。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;创新作用凸显。2023民企500强中，414家企业的关键技术主要来源于自主开发与研制。九成以上企业从不同层面实施或计划实施数字化转型，近九成企业采取多种措施实施绿色低碳发展。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;再看企业500强榜单。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023企业500强研发投入持续增加，研发强度创下1.85%的新高，其中，民营企业扮演了重要角色——入围的民营企业共投入研发费用7036.34亿元，占比44.57%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;研发投入持之以恒，创新成果不断涌现。2023企业500强中的民营企业共申报专利总数69.52万项，比上年增长5.83%，其中申报发明专利34万项，比上年增长8.25%；在参与国际标准制定上，民营企业共申报参与了2420项，占比为48.48%。此外，2023中国大企业创新100强中，民营企业有56家，其中华为、中兴、美的等6家进入前10。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在国际化经营方面，民营企业也有着不俗表现，对外投资平稳发展，国际化指标稳中有进。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2023民企500强出口总额2763.64亿美元，比上年增加309.34亿美元，增幅为12.6%。2023中国跨国公司100大中，按照跨国指数排序位居前20名的企业中，有15家为民营企业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“民营企业在创新发展驱动、产业结构优化和国际化经营中都取得积极进展，这是民营企业不断提升发展质量、增强发展韧性、提高发展动力的体现。”高蕊表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;作用贡献增大&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;民企500强纳税总额占全国税收总额的7.51%，就业总数占全国就业人员总数的1.5%&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纳税总额达1.25万亿元，占全国税收总额的7.51%，有3家企业纳税额超过400亿元；就业总数1097.21万人，占全国就业人员总数的1.5%；358家企业参与乡村振兴，329家企业参与“万企兴万村”行动……纵观2023民企500强榜单，不少民营企业积极履行社会责任，在稳增长、促就业、惠民生等方面发挥了重要作用。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;国有企业是中国特色社会主义经济的“顶梁柱”，民营经济是推进中国式现代化的生力军。从两份榜单可以看出，国企民企竞争合作、优势互补、携手并进，为经济发展注入了强劲动力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;先看2023中国战略性新兴产业领军企业100强。其中，国有企业占49家，涉及9个领域，在高端装备制造领域具有显著优势。民营企业占51家，涉及7个领域，主要分布在新一代信息技术、新材料以及新能源等领域。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;再看2023中国服务业企业500强。国有企业在公共服务、基础服务领域具有优势，民营企业则在互联网服务、物流、供应链服务等领域更具活力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“中国企业500强的系列榜单中，国有企业和民营企业具有明显的行业属性，他们发挥各自优势，呈现各自发展特色，共同支撑中国经济的高质量发展。”高蕊表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;同时也要看到，受多重因素影响，民营企业部分经营指标出现波动。“经济发展从来就不是一帆风顺的，我国经济潜力足、韧性大、活力强，具有多方面优势和条件，长期向好的基本面不会改变。”中国企业联合会、中国企业家协会会长王忠禹表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在社会主义市场经济环境下，国有经济、民营经济各有优势、各具特色，如鸟之两翼、车之两轮，缺一不可。只有国有经济和民营经济相互协调、共同发展，中国经济才能走得稳、走得好、走得远。”国家发展改革委副主任丛亮表示，相信随着各项政策的落实，民营经济的发展活力和内生动力将进一步激发。&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 以可持续交通助力全球发展]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/27/nw.D110000renmrb_20230927_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年09月27日星期三&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;9月25日至26日，以“可持续交通：携手合作助力全球发展”为主题的全球可持续交通高峰论坛在北京举办。约1000名海内外嘉宾齐聚北京，共商可持续交通发展大计。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;交通运输部部长李小鹏表示，近年来，中国坚持与世界相交、与时代相通，努力推进全球交通合作，与世界各国共同书写了基础设施联通、贸易投资畅通、文明交融沟通的新篇章。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;——放眼国内，现代综合交通运输体系日趋完善。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;交通运输部公路局局长吴春耕介绍，目前我国具备条件的建制村实现了通硬化路、通客车、通邮路，农村地区行路难问题得到历史性解决，“普惠公平、便捷高效的农村公路网络，为推进农业农村现代化、促进共同富裕作出积极贡献”。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“我们依托5.4万个营业网点、42万个邮乐购站点和日均里程超过420万公里的农村邮路，架起了连接城乡、服务民生的桥梁和纽带，增强了公共服务的均衡性、可及性。”中国邮政集团董事长刘爱力表示。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;——放眼全球，交通运输对外开放合作不断深化。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“改革开放以来，我们以更大力度推进基础设施建设领域对外援助，促进广大发展中国家经济建设。”国家国际发展合作署国际合作司副司长李翊介绍，这些年，中国在基础设施领域以打造六廊六路、多国多港、互联互通大格局为重点，帮助广大发展中国家提升基础设施建设水平。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;为肯尼亚蒙内铁路项目培养属地施工技术人员超过4000人；柬埔寨金港高速项目采取“结对子、拜师傅”模式，将工作标准、工作技能等传递给新员工……中交集团副总经理陈重介绍，中交集团在“走出去”过程中，积极践行共商共建共享理念，为发展中国家培养交通人才队伍。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;——展望未来，数字时代互联互通将加快演进。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;国家铁路局局长费东斌介绍，近年来，数字技术与铁路业务融合发展水平加快提升，智能铁路技术体系、数据体系和标准体系初步构建，助力中国铁路迈入高质量发展。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;在雄安新区这座未来之城，数字道路、智慧交通走进现实。雄安新区特聘专家、数字办主任张强介绍，雄安新区将努力打造全数字化环境，希望成为未来交通新技术、新模式的协同创新集聚区。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;论坛期间，以“交通天下&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;创新引领”为主题的第十五届国际交通技术与设备展览会同步举办，来自14个国家的88家交通运输头部企业和机构参展。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“我们要把握数字化、网络化、智能化方向，提高数字技术基础研发能力，推动交通运输产业数字化，大力发展智慧交通和智慧物流。要打造开放、公平、公正、非歧视的科技发展环境，促进创新要素全球流动，携手推动交通运输科技创新。”李小鹏表示。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 27 Sep 2023 06:26:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>