<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 福建全面提升产业体系现代化水平]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/02/nw.D110000renmrb_20231102_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 2, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized: “It is necessary to make arrangements in advance in key areas and comprehensively improve the modernization level of the industrial system, while consolidating traditional advantageous industries. leading position and creating new competitive advantages.&quot; Based on high-quality development and accelerating the upgrading of the industrial system, the Fujian Provincial Party Committee deployed and implemented the action of &quot;striving for excellence through deep learning, daring to be the first, and striving for results through hard work&quot; to further strengthen policy supply and strengthen projects Schedule and create a first-class business environment, continue to promote the upgrading of the industrial chain, and cultivate new development momentum. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;There are many scaffoldings and cement mixers are rumbling... The construction of the first phase of the high-strength magnesium-aluminum alloy wheel project in Fuqing City, Fujian Province is progressing rapidly. At present, the workshop buildings have all been capped, and trial production is planned before the end of the year. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;&quot;Compared with traditional steel wheels, magnesium-aluminum alloy wheels are 50% lighter in weight, but their load-bearing capacity is significantly improved. They have wide application space in the new energy vehicle market. The total investment of the project is 3 billion yuan. After the completion of the first phase, It will have 12 internationally leading production lines with an annual output of 900,000 sets of wheels.&quot; said Weng Huajian, chairman of Fujian Fuxin Wheel Co., Ltd. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Represented by the Fuxin high-strength magnesium-aluminum alloy wheel project, Fujian is building a &quot;Fujian Industry 4.0 Digital Wheel Industry Demonstration Park&quot; in Fuqing City that integrates R&amp;D, production, sales and service. After the completion of the industrial park, the annual output value will reach 6 billion yuan, driving more than 10 upstream and downstream related enterprises and creating more than 1,000 new jobs. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In the first half of this year, Fujian’s 1,580 provincial key projects completed an investment of 412.3 billion yuan, accounting for 63.6% of the annual plan, with a progress of 13.6 percentage points, successfully achieving the &quot;double and half&quot; mission goal; this year, Fujian The Provincial Digital Office has selected and determined 191 annual key digital economy projects for the first time, and plans to achieve a digital economic added value of more than 2.9 trillion yuan this year. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Focusing on the digital economy, marine economy, green economy, cultural tourism economy and key industrial areas, Fujian strives to accelerate future industrial layout. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Tongxiang High-tech City, Torch High-tech Zone, Xiamen City, Tianma Optoelectronics’ 8.6th generation new display panel project site, the machinery continues to operate, and the main factory building has been fully capped, and production is expected to start in the second half of next year. &quot;This is Tianma&#39;s first high-generation production line specializing in the field of small and medium-sized displays. The project focuses on the three major application markets of vehicle display, IT display, and industrial product display.&quot; He Cunjin, secretary of the board of directors of Xiamen Tianma Optoelectronics Co., Ltd., introduced. Xiamen is actively cultivating and expanding strategic emerging industries such as new displays and integrated circuits, and accelerating the creation of a trillion-yuan electronic information industry cluster. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;To comprehensively improve the modernization level of the industrial system, this year’s work report of the Fujian Provincial Government proposed to accelerate the construction of a modern industrial system, cultivate and expand strategic emerging industries, transform and upgrade traditional advantageous industries; create a first-class business environment, and improve Industrial coordination mechanism. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The Fujian Provincial Development and Reform Commission has established a regular project research service mechanism, sending 10 research teams every quarter to nine cities and one district to carry out research services, understand the economic operations of various places, and coordinate to solve problems in project construction. problems and difficulties to promote the accelerated construction of the project. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;&quot;There are difficulties in project land approval. Can key projects be given key guarantees?&quot; Facing the research and service team that rushed to Ningde, Chen Qingke, president of Qingtuo Group, expressed the company&#39;s expectations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;New stainless steel materials are one of Ningde’s leading industries, and this year it plans to achieve an output value of more than 230 billion yuan. The China-Indonesia Ningde new material deep processing project undertaken by Qingtuo Group urgently needs to expand its production line, but it encountered difficulties in land use approval. &quot;We will report it immediately for coordination and continue to track the progress.&quot; A member of the research service team responded on the spot. Eleven days later, Qingtuo Group received the coordinated solution. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;“At present, the project has been included in the list of key land use guarantees. In the subsequent construction of the project, the relevant departments will also provide us with assistance.” Chen Qingke said. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In 2022, the number of national high-tech enterprises in Fujian will exceed 10,000 for the first time, with 349 national-level specialized and new &quot;little giant&quot; enterprises and 45 individual manufacturing champions. In the first three quarters of this year, the province&#39;s investment in reconstruction and technological transformation increased by 10.9% year-on-year, 7.9 percentage points higher than the province&#39;s investment; the added value of the province&#39;s large-scale equipment manufacturing industry increased by 3.3% year-on-year, driving the growth of the province&#39;s large-scale industrial added value 0.9 percentage points. The optimization of industrial structure and upgrading of industrial system have achieved remarkable results. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>; Focusing on building a modern industrial system, Fujian will strengthen precise investment promotion in the industrial chain and expand new increments in industrial development. This year, Fujian has identified 1,580 annual provincial key projects with an annual planned investment of 648 billion yuan. Recently, Fujian issued opinions on further strengthening investment promotion work, proposing to increase the attraction of investment projects with strong industrial correlation and significant agglomeration to form a new economic growth pole. Strive to achieve the leap from the &quot;CNC generation&quot; to the &quot;intelligent generation&quot; in the four leading industries of electronic information and digital industry, advanced equipment manufacturing, petrochemical industry, and modern textile and clothing by 2025. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 坚定不移走中国特色金融发展之路]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/02/nw.D110000renmrb_20231102_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 2, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Finance is the blood of the national economy and an important part of the country&#39;s core competitiveness. From October 30 to 31, the Central Financial Work Conference was held in Beijing. General Secretary Xi Jinping attended the meeting and delivered an important speech, summarizing the financial work since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, analyzing the situation facing high-quality financial development, and deploying financial work for the current and future periods. General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech is high-level, profound, and rich in connotation. It scientifically answers a series of major theoretical and practical issues in the development of the financial industry. It is an important part of Xi Jinping’s economic thought and an important guide to Marxist political economics on financial issues. The innovative results provide fundamental compliance and action guidelines for promoting high-quality financial development in the new era and new journey. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core has strengthened the overall leadership and overall planning of financial work based on the strategic overall situation, and promoted the development of the financial industry to achieve new and major achievements. Finance has played an important supporting role in promoting stable and healthy economic development, supporting the fight against poverty, and meeting the people&#39;s financial service needs. Important phased results have been achieved in the battle to prevent and resolve financial risks, important progress has been made in deepening financial reform and opening up, and the financial industry has comprehensively The strength is significantly enhanced. At present, my country&#39;s banking industry ranks first in the world in terms of asset size, second in the world in terms of stocks, bonds, and insurance, and ranks first in the world in terms of foreign exchange reserves. Under the centralized and unified leadership of the Party Central Committee, the financial system has strongly supported the overall economic and social development and made important contributions to building a moderately prosperous society in all respects as scheduled and achieving the first centenary goal. The new and major achievements in my country&#39;s financial reform and development are fundamentally due to the leadership and helm of General Secretary Xi Jinping and the scientific guidance of Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The direction determines the road, and the road determines the destiny. In the practice of leading financial work, the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core combines Marxist financial theory with the specific reality of contemporary China and with the excellent traditional Chinese culture, strives to grasp the laws of financial development in the new era, and continues to promote my country&#39;s financial industry Through practical innovation, theoretical innovation, and institutional innovation, we strive to open up a path for financial development with Chinese characteristics and have achieved important practical and theoretical results. This Central Financial Work Conference made a high-level summary: &quot;Adhere to the centralized and unified leadership of the Party Central Committee on financial work, adhere to the people-centered value orientation, adhere to the fundamental purpose of financial services to the real economy, and adhere to risk prevention and control as financial work. The eternal theme is to insist on promoting financial innovation and development on the track of marketization and rule of law, insisting on deepening financial supply-side structural reform, insisting on coordinating financial openness and security, and adhering to the general tone of the work of seeking progress while maintaining stability.&quot; These &quot;eight insistences&quot; are a further deepening of our party&#39;s understanding of the nature and development laws of finance, and must be carefully studied and understood and resolutely implemented. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;If finance is active, the economy is active; if finance is stable, the economy is stable. The path of financial development with Chinese characteristics that the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping at its core has been based on the realities of contemporary China has been hard-won. Practice has fully proved that this is an unprecedented innovative path. It not only follows the objective laws of modern financial development, but also has distinctive characteristics suitable for China&#39;s national conditions. It clarifies how to look at and do financial work. It has both a world view and a methodology, which constitutes A dialectically unified organic whole. On the new journey of building a strong country and rejuvenating the nation, we must adhere to the guidance of Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, continuously strengthen the &quot;four consciousnesses&quot;, strengthen the &quot;four self-confidences&quot;, achieve &quot;two safeguards&quot;, and improve Political judgment, political understanding, and political execution, a deep grasp of the laws of financial development, a deep grasp of the political and people-oriented nature of financial work, and unswervingly following the path of financial development with Chinese characteristics. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China drew up a grand blueprint for comprehensively promoting the construction of a strong country and national rejuvenation with Chinese-style modernization, and clarified the central tasks of the party in the new era and new journey, focusing on promoting high-quality development and building We have made major arrangements for establishing a high-level socialist market economic system. To maintain stable and healthy economic development, we must do a good job in finance. We must fully understand the important position and role of finance in economic development and social life, and use high-quality financial development to support the construction of a strong country and the great cause of national rejuvenation. We must unify our thoughts and actions with the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speeches and the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee, fully implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Party, accelerate the construction of a financial power, comprehensively strengthen financial supervision, improve the financial system, optimize financial services, prevent and resolve risks , unswervingly follow the path of financial development with Chinese characteristics, promote high-quality financial development in our country, and provide strong support for comprehensively promoting the construction of a strong country and national rejuvenation with Chinese-style modernization. All regions and departments, especially the financial system, must adhere to goal orientation and problem orientation, comprehensively strengthen the party&#39;s leadership over financial work, do a solid job in key tasks, and ensure the implementation of work arrangements. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The grand goals of building a strong country and rejuvenating the nation are inspiring, and financial development is related to the overall situation of Chinese modernization. Let us unite more closely around the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core, fully implement Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, firmly support the &quot;two establishments&quot;, resolutely achieve the &quot;two safeguards&quot;, and bear in mind &quot;the great nation&quot; &quot;, strengthen our mission, forge ahead, be truthful and pragmatic, solidly promote high-quality financial development along the path of financial development with Chinese characteristics, accelerate the construction of a financial power, and make new and greater contributions to the construction of a strong country and the great cause of national rejuvenation. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 全国政协十四届常委会第四次会议举行全体会议]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/02/nw.D110000renmrb_20231102_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 2, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 1st&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;The Fourth Meeting of the Standing Committee of the 14th CPPCC National Committee A plenary meeting was held on the afternoon of the 1st, and 13 members of the Standing Committee delivered speeches focusing on &quot;strengthening ecological environmental protection and promoting the construction of a beautiful China.&quot; Wang Huning, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Chairman of the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference, attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Member of the Standing Committee Che Jun suggested that we should thoroughly study, publicize and implement Xi Jinping’s thoughts on ecological civilization, do a good job in the performance of the CPPCC’s duties in the field of ecological civilization construction, and contribute to the construction of a beautiful China. Member of the Standing Committee Ruan Chengfa proposed to improve the legal system related to ecological civilization, enhance administrative law enforcement capabilities for environmental resource protection, and use the rule of law to promote the construction of ecological civilization. Standing Committee Member Shangyong suggested strengthening overall coordination and promoting systematic independent innovation of green technologies to provide strong scientific and technological driving force for green development and the construction of a beautiful China. Standing Committee Member Wang Jinnan proposed to strengthen collaborative management of new pollutants and focus on key core technologies to ensure public health and ecological environment safety. Standing Committee Member Wang Xiaodong suggested that we should focus on the planning and guidance of beautiful rural construction, strengthen the comprehensive management of the rural ecological environment, and strive to create a modern version of the &quot;Fuchun Mountain Dwelling Map&quot; with unique characteristics. Standing Committee Member Qian Keming suggested optimizing the supply of green products and services, building and improving green consumption systems and mechanisms, and promoting the formation of a green and low-carbon production and lifestyle. Standing Committee Member Lin Jianyue suggested that Hong Kong should leverage its advantages as an international financial center to promote the development of green finance in the Greater Bay Area, coordinate the construction of a &quot;Green Bay Area&quot; ecological and environmental governance system, and realize the connection between ecological and environmental planning, rules, and systems. However, Yan Zheng, a member of the Standing Committee, spoke on behalf of the Central Committee of the Peasants and Workers’ Party and suggested breaking through and optimizing the complementary development technology of wind, solar, water and storage, and establishing a technical system covering the full cycle of development and utilization, planning and design, operation and dispatch, and intelligent management, to promote the consumption of clean energy. Standing Committee Member He Zhimin made a speech on behalf of the Central Committee for the Advancement of Democracy and suggested coordinating and advancing desertification control work in the new era, strengthening planning cohesion and departmental coordination, promoting the revision of relevant laws, and improving the industrialized desertification control mechanism. Cao Weixing, a member of the Standing Committee of the China Democratic League, made a speech on behalf of the Central Committee of the China Democratic League, proposing to coordinately promote ecological environmental protection in the Yangtze River Basin, strengthen the management and restoration of key ecological reserves, and innovate the upstream and downstream ecological compensation mechanisms. Member of the Standing Committee Liu Tongde proposed to protect the ecology of the Qinghai-Tibet Plateau and build a national ecological civilization highland. Standing Committee Member Fu Zhiguan made a speech on behalf of the Central Committee of the Taiwan League and suggested that we establish and improve the value realization mechanism of ecological products and promote the ecological conservation area from &quot;greening&quot; to &quot;getting rich&quot;. Standing Committee Member Zhang Quan suggested that the carbon emission statistical accounting system should be improved and the transition from “dual control” of energy consumption to “dual control” of carbon emissions should be promoted in a scientific and orderly manner. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Leung Chun-ying, Vice Chairman of the National Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference, presided over the meeting. Shi Taifeng, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Vice Chairman of the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference, Hu Chunhua, Shen Yueyue, Wang Yong, Zhou Qiang, Ho Hau Wah, Battelle, Su Hui, Shao Hong, Gao Yunlong, Chen Wu, Mu Hong, Xian Hui, Wang Dongfeng, Jiang Zuojun , He Baoxiang, Wang Guangqian, Qin Boyong, Zhu Yongxin, and Yang Zhen attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 韩正会见加拿大前总理克雷蒂安]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/02/nw.D110000renmrb_20231102_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 2, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 1st&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;On November 1st, Vice President Han Zheng met with Canada in Beijing Former Prime Minister Chretien. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Han Zheng said that you are an old friend and good friend of the Chinese people. The ten years you served as Prime Minister were the &quot;golden decades&quot; of China-Canada relations. After leaving office, you continued to work for the cause of China-Canada friendship. China and Canada have established diplomatic relations for more than half a century. A healthy and stable China-Canada relationship is in the fundamental interests of both countries and peoples, and is also conducive to world peace and development. China and Canada are both major and influential countries and should strengthen coordination and cooperation to jointly address global challenges such as climate change. Reform and opening up is China&#39;s basic national policy. We will continue to unswervingly expand opening up to the outside world, accelerate the construction of a new development pattern, and welcome more Canadian companies to invest in China and share development opportunities. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Chretien said that Canada and China are natural partners, with highly complementary economies and huge potential for cooperation. We are willing to continue to contribute to promoting practical cooperation and friendly exchanges between the two countries and promote the long-term development of Canada-China relations. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 国务院印发《关于取消和调整一批罚款事项的决定》]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/02/nw.D110000renmrb_20231102_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 2, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 1st&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;In order to further optimize the business environment, the State Council recently issued the &quot;About Cancellation of and Adjustment of a Group of Fines Matters&quot; (hereinafter referred to as the &quot;Decision&quot;), canceling and adjusting 33 fines in the fields of industry, information technology, housing and urban-rural construction, among which 16 fines were canceled and 17 fines were adjusted. If fine matters are canceled, the relevant fine provisions in relevant administrative regulations and departmental rules will be temporarily suspended from the date of issuance of the &quot;Decision&quot;; if fines are adjusted, the relevant fine provisions in the revised relevant administrative regulations and departmental rules will be implemented. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The 16 fines canceled by the &quot;Decision&quot; include 2 from the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, 2 from the Ministry of Education, 5 from the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development, 3 from the People&#39;s Bank of China, and 1 from the National Forestry and Grassland Administration. , 1 State Post Bureau, 2 National Bureau of Disease Control and Prevention; 17 fines adjusted, including 1 Ministry of Industry and Information Technology, 1 Ministry of Emergency Management, 13 National Press and Publication Administration, and 2 National Bureau of Disease Control and Prevention. These fines are mainly concentrated in areas closely related to the production and life of enterprises and the people. The purpose of cancellation and adjustment is to effectively reduce the burden on enterprises and the people. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The cancellation and adjustment of fines involve a total of 7 administrative regulations and 6 departmental regulations. The &quot;Decision&quot; puts forward clear requirements for the legislative work after the cancellation and adjustment of fines. Relevant departments of the State Council must submit relevant administrative regulations modification plans to the State Council within 60 days from the date of issuance of the &quot;Decision&quot; and complete the modification and abolition of relevant departmental regulations. If departmental regulations need to be adjusted according to the revised administrative regulations, the modification and abolition must be completed within 60 days from the date of promulgation of the relevant administrative regulations. Considering that there is a 30-day period for soliciting opinions on the modification and abolition of departmental regulations, it is stipulated that if the modification or abolition of departmental regulations cannot be completed within the above period due to special reasons, it may be appropriately extended, but the extension period shall not exceed 30 days at most. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The &quot;Decision&quot; emphasizes that after the fines are cancelled, the relevant departments must study carefully in accordance with the law, strictly implement supervision responsibilities, focus on strengthening supervision during and after the event, improve supervision methods, standardize supervision procedures, and improve the scientific and scientific nature of supervision. Simplicity and precision further enhance regulatory efficiency and provide strong support for promoting high-quality development. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 图片报道]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/02/nw.D110000renmrb_20231102_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 02, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231102/1698868509160_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/ TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;In recent years, Qianxi City, Guizhou Province has adhered to ecological priority and green development, increased efforts to comprehensively improve the rural living environment, and promoted the rural ecological environment. Continue to improve and steadily improve the appearance of the village; continue to improve rural infrastructure, create high-quality rural tourism routes, actively promote the in-depth integrated development of agriculture, culture and tourism, promote employment and entrepreneurship of the rural labor force, and solidly promote rural revitalization. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The picture shows the rural roads, lakes and villages in the green Bai and Yi Township of Qianxi City. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Photographed by Zhou Xunchao (Image China)&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 前9月水利建设落实投资超万亿元（新数据 新看点）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/02/nw.D110000renmrb_20231102_7-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 02, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/02/01/rmrb2023110201p18_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;Data source: Ministry of Water Resources&lt; br>;Drawing: Cai Huawei&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;This newspaper, Beijing, November 1&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter (Li Xiaoqing) Reporter recently learned from the Ministry of Water Resources: From January to September this year, the implemented investment in water conservancy construction was 1.075 billion yuan, and the completed investment was 860.1 billion yuan, both setting high records for the same period in history. There were 24,900 new water conservancy projects of various types started across the country, a year-on-year increase of 12.9%; the total investment scale was 1.15 trillion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 8.9%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The number of water conservancy project starts has achieved significant growth. Among them, 35 major water conservancy projects have been started, including water supply from the Xiongan Main Canal in Hebei Province along the middle route of the South-to-North Water Diversion Project, water resource allocation in Guangxi around the Beibu Gulf, backbone water network projects in Jilin, and warm tide reduction river management in Beijing. National, regional and provincial water resources projects have also started construction. The construction of network engineering system was accelerated. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The role of water conservancy construction in attracting employment has become more prominent. From January to September, the construction of water conservancy projects created 2.212 million jobs, a year-on-year increase of 5.7%; wages were paid to 41.13 billion yuan, a year-on-year increase of 37.1%. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The construction of water conservancy projects has been accelerated across the board. The middle route of the South-to-North Water Diversion Diversion Project to divert the Yangtze River to the Han Dynasty and the second phase of the Huaihe River&#39;s entry into the sea has been accelerated. The main body of the Datangxia water conservancy project has been fully completed. Shaanxi has diverted the Han River to the Wei River, Gansu has diverted water from the Tao River in the second phase, and the resources have been allocated to Pingtan and the Minjiang River Estuary in Fujian. The project realizes water supply. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - “通过科技创新共同促进人类和平与发展事业”]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/02/nw.D110000renmrb_20231102_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 2, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Recently, President Xi Jinping replied to a letter from the famous Cuban scientist Pedele. Foreign scientists, scientific and technological workers, including Pedel, said in interviews with this reporter that President Xi Jinping cares about foreign scientists and scientific and technological workers and attaches great importance to international scientific and technological innovation cooperation. Under the framework of the Belt and Road Initiative, China and co-building countries will further promote international scientific and technological cooperation, which will open up new space for economic development and inject new impetus into the sustainable development of mankind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“Contribute to promoting the health of human society”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping pointed out in his reply to Pedele: “You have long been committed to promoting the health of our fellow Cubans. China&#39;s special friendly relations have actively promoted Sino-foreign research cooperation and achieved many breakthroughs. I congratulate you and the team you lead.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pedele told reporters: &quot;After receiving President Xi Jinping&#39;s reply letter, I was very excited and felt very warm after reading the content of the reply. President Xi Jinping took the time to reply to me despite his busy schedule, which is a great affirmation of the cooperation between Cuba and China in the field of brain science research.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pedele He is an academician of the Cuban Academy of Sciences. In 2015, he joined the University of Electronic Science and Technology of China in Chengdu, Sichuan full-time, teaching in the School of Life Sciences and Technology and engaged in brain information and brain-like intelligence research. In 2017, he won the Chinese Government Friendship Award. A few days ago, Pedele sent a letter to President Xi Jinping, introducing the results of the team he led in promoting brain science research and Cuba-China neurotechnology cooperation in China, expressing his willingness to continue to promote Cuba-China friendship and contribute to the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative to a greater global extent. Contribute to the implementation of the scope. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Talking about the original intention of writing to President Xi Jinping, Pedele said, &quot;I wanted to express my admiration for President Xi Jinping by writing this letter, and also show my determination to promote scientific and technological cooperation between Cuba and China.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pedele said that President Xi Jinping proposed the concept of building a community with a shared future for mankind, which pointed out the way forward for human development. The joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative is a major practice in building a community with a shared future for mankind. Currently, the School of Life Science and Technology of the University of Electronic Science and Technology of China is actively promoting the application and construction of the &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; joint laboratory, which will become an important platform to strengthen Cuba-China scientific and technological innovation cooperation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pedele strongly agreed with President Xi Jinping’s discussion of international scientific and technological cooperation and scientific and technological innovation in his reply letter. He said that President Xi Jinping emphasized the importance of international scientific and technological cooperation. This is the direction that scientists and scientific and technological workers need to work hard in the future, so that science and technology can serve mankind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping pointed out that the traditional friendship jointly created by the older generations of leaders of China and China has grown vigorously and continues to bear fruitful results. Since last year, the two sides have reached important consensus on working together to build a community with a shared future between China and Cuba. I sincerely hope that in the new era, China-Cuba cooperation in various fields, including science and technology, will continue to deepen and better benefit the two peoples. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The friendship between Cuba and China continues to develop, and the two sides cooperate in a wide range of areas.” Pedele said that now that China’s information technology is developing rapidly, Cuba and China can carry out more cooperation in this field. &quot;President Xi Jinping mentioned that we will jointly build a community with a shared future between China and Cuba. I feel deeply that I shoulder the heavy responsibility and will continue to work hard to promote cooperation in scientific and technological innovation between Cuba and China and contribute to the promotion of the health of human society.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;&quot;To The international scientific community has sent a positive message”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping’s reply letter also triggered a warm response from the international community. Many international people said in interviews with this reporter that international scientific and technological cooperation is a major trend. President Xi Jinping’s reply letter reflects the great importance he attaches to scientific and technological workers and is of great significance to promoting international scientific and technological innovation cooperation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;&#39;All countries need to jointly promote the cause of human peace and development through scientific and technological innovation.&#39; I very much agree with President Xi Jinping&#39;s statement. President Xi Jinping&#39;s reply letter sent a positive message to the international scientific community.&quot; Turkmenistan native Thapur, an international student and doctoral student majoring in energy and resource engineering at Peking University School of Engineering, is working on research related to carbon neutrality. He said that scientists from all countries should join hands to promote the development of human science and work hard to build a community with a shared future for mankind. Scientific and technological innovation in clean energy, environmental protection technology and other aspects will help countries achieve their emission reduction goals and promote global sustainable development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“President Xi Jinping’s attention and emphasis on international scientific and technological cooperation is encouraging.” Zemir Awan, the founding chairman of the Pakistan Global Silk Road Research Alliance, once served as the science and technology counselor of the Pakistani Embassy in China and participated in the promotion The two countries have done a lot of work in scientific and technological innovation cooperation, and deeply understand the importance of scientific and technological innovation cooperation to national development. He said that in the agricultural field, Pakistan and China have jointly carried out cross-breeding work on rice, wheat, rapeseed, cauliflower and other crops, and selected a number of crop varieties with high yield and good stress resistance suitable for planting in Pakistan, which has effectively promoted local development. Farmers increase their income and become rich. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Eugene Afant, chief engineer of the South African National Space Agency, said that human society currently faces many problems, which need to be solved through technological innovation and the cooperation of all countries. China is a powerful promoter of international scientific and technological cooperation. It has signed intergovernmental scientific and technological cooperation agreements with more than 80 co-building countries, including traditional fields such as food, medicine, and chemical industry, but also extending to cutting-edge fields such as aerospace technology and artificial intelligence. The scientific and technological innovation cooperation between South Africa and China is in the ascendant, and the results of the cooperation between the two countries will surely benefit both countries and even all mankind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Adam Rilski, a professor at the Institute of Materials Science and Engineering at the University of Technology in Lodz, Poland, has served as a judge on the Nuremberg International Inventions Exhibition Award Committee for 15 consecutive years. He said that at the Nuremberg International Invention Exhibition held recently, China was invited to be the guest country, and the projects it brought showed a very high level and won praise from many parties. Since 2003, Rilski has participated in academic exchanges in China many times and held lectures on scientific research cooperation and innovation cooperation. He has also facilitated academic exchanges between Tsinghua University and other institutions and the Technical University of Lodz in Poland. &quot;Science has no borders. The unity and cooperation of scientists will produce the effect of 1+1>;2. Countries should strengthen cooperation and exchanges in science and technology, so that scientific and technological innovation can open up a better future for mankind.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong >;&quot;China&#39;s Plan for Building a Better World&quot;&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This year marks the 10th anniversary of the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative. President Xi Jinping emphasized that over the past decade, China and co-building countries have accelerated scientific and technological exchanges and knowledge sharing, continuously optimized the innovation environment, gathered innovative resources, and accelerated scientific and technological innovation cooperation with remarkable results. International people expect the co-building countries to continue to strengthen cooperation in science and technology innovation, improve the well-being of the people in the co-building countries, and promote global development and prosperity. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Aymara Geddel, director of the Venezuelan China Research Center, has long been paying attention to the progress of scientific and technological cooperation between China and Latin America. He said that China&#39;s open attitude towards scientific and technological innovation cooperation has promoted Latin American and Chinese scientists to work hand in hand and achieve important cooperation results. This is reflected in the story of Cuban scientist Pedele. Over the past 10 years, Latin America and China&#39;s joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; has brought huge development opportunities to Latin America. From clean energy technology and UHV DC transmission technology to 5G communications, artificial intelligence, big data, cloud computing and other technological innovations, they are conducive to bridging the development gap between the north and the south and have become an important aspect of poverty reduction cooperation between Latin America and China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“‘One Belt, One Road’ is a road of cooperation, innovation, and China’s plan to build a better world.” Talal, the Egyptian chief designer of the China-aided Egypt-2 satellite project and an Egyptian aerospace scholar He said that international scientific and technological cooperation is an effective way to enhance connectivity among countries and respond to major global challenges. Satellite cooperation between Egypt and China provides information support for the development of Egypt&#39;s agriculture, water conservancy, meteorology and other fields, and is of great significance to Egypt&#39;s economic and social development and improvement of people&#39;s livelihood. At the same time, a large number of Egyptian engineers have become key talents in the aerospace field with the help of China. It is expected that Egypt and China will further deepen cooperation in the aerospace field under the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sapur noted that under the framework of jointly building the “Belt and Road”, Turkey and China have carried out extensive cooperation in the fields of information and communication technology, energy and other fields, promoting the development of Turkmenistan’s digital economy and energy interconnection. &quot;We look forward to deepening cooperation between the two parties in the fields of artificial intelligence, biotechnology, environmental protection technology, etc., strengthening the construction of scientific and technological innovation capabilities and the cultivation of scientific and technological talents, promoting the transformation and application of scientific and technological innovation results, and jointly promoting sustainable development.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Awan said that in recent years, Brazil and China have continued to make new progress in the field of scientific and technological innovation cooperation. Pakistan has introduced China&#39;s independently innovative high-voltage direct current transmission technology and established a power transmission artery connecting the north and the south. The Pakistan-China cross-border optical cable project has helped Pakistan improve the speed and stability of network connectivity. In the future, as cooperation in jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; continues to deepen, the two countries will continue to expand new cooperation space in the field of scientific and technological innovation and help Pakistan&#39;s modernization process. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Reporters from Beijing, Chengdu, Islamabad, Johannesburg, Berlin, Rio de Janeiro, Cairo, November 1st)&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Reporters Gong Ming, Bao Han, Song Haoxin, Cheng Shijie, Zou Song, Liu Zhonghua, Chen Yiming, Shen Xiaoxiao)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot; color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>; https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 笺暖情长]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/02/nw.D110000renmrb_20231102_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, November 2, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;“I like Chinese friends, Chinese culture and the modernity there!” Returned to Laos after a trip to China Student Peng Piwan told reporters, &quot;Thank you to Grandpa Xi for the invitation in the letter, which allows us to take the China-Laos Railway train to China!&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;I will study Chinese well, just like what I said in the letter to Grandpa Xi , to become an envoy of friendship between the two countries as soon as possible.&quot; Arifa Qin, a Bangladeshi girl whose name means &quot;China&quot;, has strengthened her life aspirations after coming to China to participate in the forum. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the third &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum on people-to-people bonds, the story of Pengpiwan Heqin&#39;s correspondence with President Xi Jinping moved many people present. Jian Nuan is in love, and these sincere interactions have changed their lives and inspired them to grow. After returning from China this time, the children had new wishes and plans. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“I want to go to China for the third or fourth time”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of October 18, as a student of the China-Laos Friendship Nongbing Village Primary School Representative, Pengpiwan stood on the podium of the people-to-people bond forum of the summit forum. In fluent Chinese, he fondly recalled to the guests the experience of exchanging letters with Grandpa Xi, and talked about the benefits of the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative to his school and hometown. changes brought about. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Clean and tidy new desks and new benches are here!&quot; &quot;Modern equipment and a new teaching building are here!&quot; &quot;Now that we have come to Beijing as we wished, it feels great!&quot; The little girl&#39;s speech It attracted warm applause from the audience. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Songma Phonsena, Vice Chairman of the Lao National Assembly who attended the forum, was deeply moved: &quot;To deepen the friendship between Laos and China and the &#39;One Belt, One Road&#39; cooperation, young people from the two countries need to travel frequently. Just like Xi Jinping As the Chairman said, the relationship between states lies in the closeness between the people, and the closeness between the peoples lies in the heart-to-heart connection.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2019, on the eve of going to China to participate in the second &quot;Belt and Road&quot; International Cooperation Summit Forum, including Pengpi Bay Teachers and students of Nongbing Village Primary School of China-Laos Friendship wrote to General Secretary Xi Jinping. The teachers and students wrote in the letter that the Chinese dream and the Laotian dream are connected through the &quot;One Belt, One Road&quot; initiative, and they hope to take the China-Laos railway to Beijing as soon as possible. In his reply letter, General Secretary Xi Jinping encouraged them to be the successors of China-Laos friendship and welcomed them to take the China-Laos railway to Beijing as soon as possible. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Take the China-Laos Railway to go to China” has become the expectation of these Laotian children. With the joint efforts of the two countries, the China-Laos Railway was successfully opened for operation on December 3, 2021. On October 14, Pengpi Bay came to China again on board the China-Laos Railway international passenger train launched this year. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Unlike the last time you took a plane, you can see China’s mountains, rivers, and cities up close by taking the high-speed rail.” Pengpiwan told reporters: “This time we went to Kunming, Beijing, Shanghai, In Chengdu, I saw the majestic Great Wall, the bustling Bund, the beautiful flower city, and the cute giant pandas.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;She said: &quot;I can&#39;t wait to share my experience in China with my parents. I hope they can also come and see China.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;This time we performed Laotian traditional dance and traditional musical instrument Lusheng together with our Chinese friends, and exchanged gifts.&quot; Speaking of expectations for the future , Pengpiwan said shyly with expectation, &quot;I still want to practice more Chinese. I also want to go to China for the third or fourth time, study abroad, and introduce China to more friends.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &quot;We feel the warmth of family.&quot; Pan Tong, the principal of Nongbing Village Primary School who accompanied him, said that during this trip to China, the Lao children felt the friendliness of the Chinese people and the openness and vitality of Chinese cities. &quot;We hope that the younger generation can interact with each other.&quot; Learn and help each other and contribute to the common progress of Laos and China.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;“Become a messenger of friendship between the two countries at an early date”&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After returning from China, Alifa Qin made his learning goals clearer. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2010, Qin’s mother was in critical condition due to dystocia. Chinese doctors who visited Bangladesh with the hospital ship “Peace Ark” successfully performed the operation under great pressure to protect the safety of the mother and daughter.沁的父亲感念中国医生的救命之恩，以孟加拉语的“中国”一词发音给孩子取名为“沁”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在给习近平主席的信中，沁表达了自己的感激之情和未来希望到中国学医的心愿，得到习近平主席的复信和鼓励。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沁对新华社记者表达了自己的激动之情：“我很感谢习爷爷给我复信，我也很感谢有这样的机会再来中国。”这次来华，除了北京，沁和家人还去了上海、杭州、安吉、正定等地，所到之处的绿水青山、闹市街巷，都给她留下了深刻印象。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在上海，我和父母一起俯瞰繁华的夜景；在杭州，我们和中国奥运冠军见面；在正定，参观塔元庄同福乡村振兴园时，我第一次了解到&#39;乡村振兴&#39;的概念……”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沁感言，此次中国之行进一步增进了她对中国的认知，“我会好好学习中文，像给习爷爷信里说的那样，早日成为两国友谊的使者。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沁的母亲杰娜特陪伴她来中国参加论坛。在现场，杰娜特听到了许多外方领导人和其他国家参会者分享的“一带一路”合作故事，“和我们的故事有很多相似之处”。 “帕德玛大桥铁路连接线、卡纳普里河底隧道，这些项目我们耳熟能详。对我们来说，共建&#39;一带一路&#39;合作带来改善生活的机遇。我们很幸运拥有这样的机遇。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“习近平主席和阿里法·沁通信的暖心故事，展现了中国领导人对发展两国人民友谊的重视。”孟加拉国教育部长迪普·穆妮说：“我们期待更多这样相互尊重和平等的人文交流，进一步巩固我们的友谊，为两国追寻共同发展、提升人民福祉提供强大动力。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;民心相通未来可期&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10年间，在习近平主席擘画和推动下，“一带一路”合作将加强同共建国家人民“心联通”作为重要基础，推动共建伙伴之间积极开展人文交流，广泛实施民生项目，携手应对风险挑战，全力打造合作平台，取得一系列实打实、沉甸甸的成就。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10月18日，在第三届“一带一路”国际合作高峰论坛开幕式上，习近平主席指出，提出“一带一路”倡议的初心，就是“借鉴古丝绸之路，以互联互通为主线，同各国加强政策沟通、设施联通、贸易畅通、资金融通、民心相通，为世界经济增长注入新动能，为全球发展开辟新空间，为国际经济合作打造新平台”。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“加强人与人的交流和联结，增进不同国家人民之间的理解和友谊，是共建&#39;一带一路&#39;倡议的重要内涵。”参加高峰论坛民心相通专题论坛的巴基斯坦青年学者明竺表示，自己将继续在中国的学习和研究，为促进“一带一路”人文交流合作贡献力量。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2021年8月，习近平总书记给包括明竺在内的“国际青年领袖对话”项目外籍青年代表回信，对他们积极到中国各地走访、深化对华了解表示赞赏，鼓励他们加强交流互鉴，为推动构建人类命运共同体贡献青春力量。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;明竺说，民心相通带来的温暖力量，将鼓励年青一代架起更多和平友善的桥梁，播撒更多团结合作的种子。 “习近平主席的复信和寄语对世界各地的年轻人产生了积极影响，他鼓励年轻人多走动、多往来，帮助他们增进对不同国家和文化的认识和了解，让他们未来能够共同探寻解决问题的答案，共同建设更加美好的未来。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;10年来，“一带一路”合作已经见证了一座座“友谊桥”跨海而生，一条条“幸福路”四通八达，更见证了无数心手相连、同心筑梦的故事：在华留学期间多次无偿捐献“熊猫血”的哈萨克斯坦小伙儿鲁斯兰，“和中国造的铁路一起成长”的肯尼亚历史上首批女性火车司机之一的康西莉亚，疫情期间同中国朋友守望相助、说出“我是外国人，但不是外人”肺腑之言的留学生马文轩，用仁心仁术书写大爱与担当的中国援外医疗队……&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为高峰论坛主要成果，包括“支持民间交往”在内的八项行动，为开启高质量共建“一带一路”新阶段注入强劲动能。 “一带一路”合作步入下一个“金色十年”，相信将有更多民心相通的动人情节写进亲历者、建设者的人生故事，写进中国携手世界共同发展的崭新篇章。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（新华社记者陈杉、张代蕾&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;参与记者：赵旭、孙楠、马淮钊、侠克、王普）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 王毅会见洪都拉斯外长雷纳]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/02/nw.D110000renmrb_20231102_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月02日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;新华社北京11月1日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;11月1日，中共中央政治局委员、外交部长王毅在北京会见洪都拉斯外长雷纳。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;王毅说，中方愿同洪方全面落实两国元首达成的重要共识，高质量共建“一带一路”，推动中洪关系取得更多实实在在的成果。欢迎洪都拉斯作为主宾国参加第六届中国国际进口博览会，祝洪方参展取得圆满成功，中方愿为洪特色产品输华创造更多机遇。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;雷纳表示，洪中关系起步虽晚，但前途光明。洪方坚定恪守一个中国原则，愿以明年作为拉共体轮值主席国为契机，推动拉中关系实现新的发展。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 希腊总理米佐塔基斯]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/02/nw.D110000renmrb_20231102_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月02日星期四&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231102/1698868732540_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;米佐塔基斯总理&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;应国务院总理李强邀请，希腊总理米佐塔基斯将于11月2日至3日对中国进行正式访问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;米佐塔基斯1968年3月生于希腊雅典，国际经济关系及工商管理学硕士。长期从政，连续5次当选希腊议会议员。2016年起担任希腊新民主党主席。2019年7月出任希腊总理，2023年6月连任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;米佐塔基斯已婚，有1子2女。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;（新华社电）&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 02 Nov 2023 05:26:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>