<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 提高政治站位强化政治担当提升政治能力落实政治责任 建设让党放心让人民满意的模范机关]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20230915_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, September 15, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;■&amp;nbsp;The Party Committee and the General Office of the Government occupy a particularly important position in the party and state governance system and shoulder important responsibilities and missions. Since the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the national party committees and government general offices have focused on the center and served the overall situation, effectively played the functions of overall coordination, staff assistance, supervision and inspection, and service guarantee, and solidly promoted the implementation of the Party Central Committee’s decisions and deployments, and have withstood the test of many wars. , and made important contributions to promoting the development of the cause of the party and the country&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;■&amp;nbsp;Embarking on a new journey, the party committee and the government general office should have new responsibilities, new actions, and a new atmosphere. We must improve our political standing, adhere to the guidance of the Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, keep in mind the &quot;greatest of the country&quot;, deepen the construction of political institutions, firmly safeguard the centralized and unified leadership of the Party Central Committee, and always adhere to the Party Central Committee ideologically, politically and in action. Highly consistent. It is necessary to strengthen political responsibility, focus on comprehensively implementing the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, strengthen overall coordination, supervision and inspection, form a strong synergy, refrain from formalism, and promote the implementation of the Party Central Committee&#39;s decisions and deployments. It is necessary to improve political capabilities, adhere to integrity and innovation, and better play the important role of party committees and government staff assistants. It is necessary to implement political responsibilities, unswervingly promote comprehensive and strict governance of the party, create a team of high-quality professional cadres who are loyal, clean and responsible, build model institutions that reassure the party and satisfy the people, and make new contributions to comprehensively promoting the construction of a strong country and the great cause of national rejuvenation. Greater contribution&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, September 14th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, President of the State, and Chairman of the Central Military Commission, recently made a The important instructions pointed out that the party committee and the government general office occupy a special and important position in the party and state governance system and shoulder important responsibilities and missions. Since the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the national party committees and government general offices have focused on the center and served the overall situation, effectively played the functions of overall coordination, staff assistance, supervision and inspection, and service guarantee, and solidly promoted the implementation of the Party Central Committee’s decisions and deployments, and have withstood the test of many wars. , and made important contributions to promoting the development of the cause of the party and the country. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping emphasized that when embarking on a new journey, the party committee and the government general office should take on new responsibilities, new actions, and a new atmosphere. We must improve our political standing, adhere to the guidance of the Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, keep in mind the &quot;greatest of the country&quot;, deepen the construction of political institutions, firmly safeguard the centralized and unified leadership of the Party Central Committee, and always adhere to the Party Central Committee ideologically, politically and in action. Highly consistent. It is necessary to strengthen political responsibility, focus on comprehensively implementing the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, strengthen overall coordination, supervision and inspection, form a strong synergy, refrain from formalism, and promote the implementation of the Party Central Committee&#39;s decisions and deployments. It is necessary to improve political capabilities, adhere to integrity and innovation, and better play the important role of party committees and government staff assistants. It is necessary to implement political responsibilities, unswervingly promote comprehensive and strict governance of the party, create a team of high-quality professional cadres who are loyal, clean and responsible, build model institutions that reassure the party and satisfy the people, and make new contributions to comprehensively promoting the construction of a strong country and the great cause of national rejuvenation. greater contribution. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The National Party Committee and Government Secretary-General Meeting was held in Beijing from September 13th to 14th. Cai Qi, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and director of the General Office of the CPC Central Committee, attended the meeting and conveyed Xi Jinping&#39;s important instructions and delivered a speech. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The meeting pointed out that the important instructions of General Secretary Xi Jinping fully affirmed the work of the Party Committee and the Government General Office since the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, and played a vital role in fully implementing the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China and further improving the work of the General Office. The ability level puts forward clear requirements, which are highly political, guiding and targeted, and points out the direction for the work of the general office on the new journey. We must study and understand it in depth and implement it conscientiously. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The meeting emphasized that General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speeches and instructions on the work of the General Office systematically answered a series of important political requirements, responsibilities, main tasks, work standards, and team building of the General Office in the new era. The problem is the fundamental basis for doing a good job in the &quot;three services&quot; in the new era and new journey. We must implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s important speeches and instructions into all aspects of the work of the General Office. It is necessary to further deeply understand the decisive significance of the &quot;two establishments&quot;, take the lead in achieving the &quot;two maintenances&quot;, closely follow the goals and tasks set by the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, strengthen political responsibility, effectively improve political control capabilities, and better fulfill the implementation goals Basic functions: fully promote the implementation of the Party Central Committee’s decision-making and deployment. It is necessary to adapt to the new situation and new tasks, comprehensively improve the level of &quot;three services&quot; work capabilities, focus on strengthening overall coordination, focus on being a good staff assistant, focus on ensuring the safe and smooth transmission of government orders, focus on building a strong confidentiality defense line, and focus on providing service guarantees. It is necessary to implement political responsibilities, strengthen the construction of the general office with higher standards, stricter requirements, and more practical measures, strive to be at the forefront of party and government organs at all levels, be a good &quot;vanguard&quot;, and build a construction that reassures the party and satisfies the people. model institution. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;State Councilor and Secretary-General of the State Council Wu Zhenglong made a concluding speech. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The meeting summarized and exchanged the work of the General Office since the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, conducted an in-depth analysis of the new tasks and new requirements faced by the General Office system, studied the key issues existing in the &quot;three services&quot; work, and discussed recent key tasks. specific deployment. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平向2023北京文化论坛致贺信]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20230915_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, September 15, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, September 14th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;On September 14th, President Xi Jinping addressed the 2023 Beijing Cultural Forum Send a congratulatory letter. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that the Chinese nation has a long and excellent traditional culture and has been open, inclusive and inclusive since ancient times. Chinese civilization has always appreciated mutual understanding and respect among different civilizations. Beijing has a long history and a long cultural heritage, which is a powerful testimony to the continuity, innovation, unity, inclusiveness and peace of Chinese civilization. China will make better use of Beijing&#39;s advantages as an ancient historical capital and a national cultural center, strengthen cultural exchanges with other parts of the world, jointly promote cultural prosperity and development, cultural heritage protection, exchanges and mutual learning among civilizations, implement global civilization initiatives, and contribute to the construction of a destiny for mankind. The community injects profound and lasting cultural power. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The 2023 Beijing Cultural Forum, with the annual theme of &quot;Inheriting Excellent Culture&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; Promoting Exchanges and Cooperation&quot;, is co-sponsored by the Propaganda Department of the CPC Central Committee, the Beijing Municipal Party Committee, and the Beijing Municipal People&#39;s Government. It opened in Beijing that day. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平向新加坡新任总统尚达曼致贺电]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20230915_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, September 15, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, September 14th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;On September 14th, President Xi Jinping called Tharman Shanmugaratnam, Congratulations on his assumption of office as President of Singapore. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that China and Singapore are friendly neighbors and important cooperative partners. With the joint efforts of both parties, China and New Zealand have joined hands to find a successful path of mutual learning and win-win cooperation, which not only effectively promotes their respective development and revitalization, but also serves as a model for cooperation among regional countries. This year, China-New Zealand relations have been upgraded to a comprehensive, high-quality, forward-looking partnership, charting the course for the high-level development of bilateral relations in the new era. I attach great importance to the development of China-New Zealand relations and am willing to establish a good working relationship with President Tharman Shanmugaratnam, lead China-New Zealand relations to a new level, promote better integration and mutual reinforcement of the modernization processes of the two countries, and bring more benefits to the two peoples. Make greater contributions to regional peace, prosperity and stability. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 李强赵乐际分别会见委内瑞拉总统马杜罗]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20230915_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, September 15, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, September 14th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;On the morning of September 14th, Premier Li Qiang of the State Council attended the Great Hall of the People Met with Venezuelan President Maduro who was in China for a state visit. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Li Qiang said that President Xi Jinping and Mr. President decided to upgrade China-Venezuela relations to an all-weather strategic partnership, which is an important milestone in the history of bilateral relations. In the face of the chaotic international situation, China and Venezuela should firmly work together to continuously deepen strategic coordination, properly handle risks and challenges, and better achieve win-win development. Next year will mark the 50th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and Venezuela. I believe that under the strategic guidance of the two heads of state and the joint efforts of both sides, China-Venezuela friendship and trust will be further enhanced and cooperation in various fields will reach a new level. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Li Qiang pointed out that China will continue to firmly support Venezuela in safeguarding national sovereignty and national dignity, safeguarding its legitimate and legitimate rights and interests, and firmly opposes external forces interfering in Venezuela&#39;s internal affairs under any pretext. China is willing to work with Venezuela to implement the Belt and Road Initiative, the Global Development Initiative, the Global Security Initiative, and the Global Civilization Initiative, strengthen the exchange of development experience, continue to make good use of the China-Venezuela high-level mixed committee mechanism, and deepen practical cooperation in various fields. Both sides should successfully organize a series of celebrations for the 50th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic relations between the two countries next year, continue to expand people-to-people and cultural exchanges, and better promote mutual understanding and mutual understanding between the two peoples. China is willing to work with Venezuela to intensify multilateral coordination and cooperation to promote the building of a community with a shared future for mankind. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Maduro said that China is committed to peaceful development, follows a development path in line with its national conditions, and has achieved world-renowned achievements. China&#39;s development benefits its own people and the world. The establishment of an all-weather strategic partnership between Venezuela and China is a milestone in cooperation between countries in the global South. Venezuela supports the major initiatives put forward by President Xi Jinping and is willing to strengthen cooperation with China in the fields of economy, trade, science and technology, agriculture, education, culture and other fields to open up a bright future for bilateral relations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, September 14th Zhao Leji, Chairman of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress, met with Venezuelan President Maduro in Beijing on the 14th. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Zhao Leji said that China-Venezuela relations have withstood the test of the vicissitudes of the international situation for half a century, and are not afraid of wind and rain and are as solid as a rock. Yesterday, President Xi Jinping and Mr. President jointly announced that China-Venezuela relations would be upgraded to an all-weather strategic partnership. This is a reflection of the high level of China-Venezuela strategic cooperation, meets the common expectations of the two peoples, and demonstrates our firm determination to work together to build a more just and reasonable international order. Zhao Leji introduced China&#39;s poverty alleviation and promotion of Chinese-style modernization, saying that the National People&#39;s Congress of China is willing to intensify exchanges with the National People&#39;s Congress of Venezuela at all levels and in all fields, carry out legislative experience exchanges, continue to consolidate the &quot;iron&quot; friendship between China and Venezuela, and better benefit the two countries. and the peoples of both countries. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Maduro said that this visit is fruitful and of historic significance. Venezuela is willing to work with China to implement the important consensus reached by the leaders of the two countries, strengthen high-level exchanges, deepen practical cooperation, and promote the strong development of the Venezuela-China all-weather strategic partnership. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xiao Jie attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 06:26:06 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 李强将出席第20届中国—东盟博览会和中国—东盟商务与投资峰会]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20230915_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, September 15, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, September 14th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Foreign Ministry Spokesperson Mao Ning announced on the 14th: Premier Li Qiang of the State Council will On September 17, he attended and delivered a speech at the opening ceremony of the 20th China-ASEAN Expo and China-ASEAN Business and Investment Summit held in Nanning, Guangxi. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Foreign leaders and senior officials such as Cambodian Prime Minister Hun Manai, Lao Prime Minister Sonxay, Malaysian Prime Minister Anwar, Vietnamese Prime Minister Pham Minh Zheng, Indonesian Vice President Ma&#39;ruf, Thai Deputy Prime Minister and Commerce Minister Putan, and ASEAN Secretary-General Gao Jinhong will attend the opening ceremony of this China-ASEAN Expo. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 蔡奇出席2023北京文化论坛开幕式并致辞]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20230915_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, September 15, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, September 14th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Zhang Shuo and Zheng Haiou) Morning of the 14th, 2023 The Beijing Cultural Forum opened in Beijing. Li Shulei, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and director of the Propaganda Department of the CPC Central Committee, read out a congratulatory letter from President Xi Jinping at the opening ceremony. Cai Qi, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and secretary of the Secretariat of the CPC Central Committee, attended the opening ceremony and delivered a speech. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cai Qi pointed out that President Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter profoundly illustrates the open, inclusive and inclusive cultural mind of the Chinese nation and the outstanding characteristics of Chinese civilization, and clearly declares that China will implement global civilization initiatives and strengthen cultural exchanges with other parts of the world. , firm determination and policy propositions to jointly promote cultural prosperity and development. We must use the spirit of the congratulatory letter as a guide to build the modern civilization of the Chinese nation at a higher level, conduct extensive exchanges and mutual learning among civilizations, and inject profound and lasting cultural power into the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cai Qi emphasized that we must persist in self-confidence and self-improvement, be guided by Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, conscientiously implement the fundamental requirements of &quot;two combinations&quot;, and unswervingly follow the path of socialist cultural development with Chinese characteristics, Vigorously promote China&#39;s excellent traditional culture, systematically protect historical and cultural heritage, give full play to the leading role of socialist core values, and cultivate the spiritual power to achieve national rejuvenation. We must adhere to the supremacy of the people, adhere to the unity of ideology and artistry, carry forward the main theme and advocate diversity, create and produce more fine masterpieces, prosper and develop cultural undertakings and cultural industries, and continuously enrich the people&#39;s spiritual world. We must persist in upholding integrity and innovation, not forgetting our roots, absorbing external influences, and facing the future, innovating closely with the theme of the times, innovating in solving practical problems, innovating in strengthening scientific and technological empowerment, and striving to stimulate the vitality of cultural development. We must adhere to openness and inclusiveness, promote mutual respect and harmonious coexistence among different civilizations, break down barriers to cultural exchanges with a broad mind that embraces all rivers, promote our own civilization to maintain strong vitality in exchanges and mutual learning with other civilizations, and carry out extensive exchanges and mutual learning among civilizations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cai Qi said that China will work with the international community to adhere to its own cultural position, promote the common values ​​of all mankind, and strive to create a new situation of people-to-people exchanges, cultural integration, and people-to-people bonds around the world. It is hoped that the Beijing Cultural Forum will achieve results and influence, and build a first-class platform to promote cultural exchanges and deepen mutual learning among civilizations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Yin Li, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Secretary of the Beijing Municipal Party Committee, attended the opening ceremony and delivered a speech. Tie Ning, Vice Chairman of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress and Chairman of the China Federation of Literary and Art Circles, attended the opening ceremony. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The 2023 Beijing Cultural Forum is co-sponsored by the Propaganda Department of the CPC Central Committee, the Beijing Municipal Party Committee, and the Beijing Municipal People’s Government. Heads of central and local publicity and cultural units, well-known experts, scholars, writers, artists and industry leaders, as well as international dignitaries and heads of international institutions in the cultural field attended the forum. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 丁薛祥出席中国—委内瑞拉高级混合委员会第十七次会议全体会议暨闭幕式并致辞]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20230915_7-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, September 15, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, September 14th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Qi Zhongxi) Member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Vice Premier of the State Council Ding Xuexiang and Venezuelan President Maduro attended the plenary session and closing ceremony of the 17th China-Venezuela High-Level Mixed Committee meeting in Beijing on the 13th and delivered speeches. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Ding Xuexiang said that China and Venezuela are good friends and good partners, and China has always viewed and developed China-Venezuela relations from a strategic and long-term perspective. Under the strategic guidance of President Xi Jinping and President Maduro, China-Venezuela relations have maintained steady and sound development and achieved a series of new major results. China and Venezuela are both developing countries, and their cooperation has a solid foundation, huge potential and broad prospects. It is hoped that both sides will implement the important consensus reached by the two heads of state, deepen political mutual trust, expand practical cooperation, promote people-to-people bonds, and push China-Venezuela relations to a new level to better benefit the two peoples. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Ding Xuexiang fully affirmed the important role played by the China-Venezuela High-level Committee in promoting the development of bilateral relations, and hoped that the High-level Committee would strengthen the planning and guidance of cooperation in various fields between the two countries and continuously improve the practical cooperation between the two countries. level and make new contributions to the development and deepening of China-Venezuela relations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Maduro said in his speech that Venezuela-China relations have withstood various tests and increasingly achieved fruitful results, and Venezuela-China cooperation has ushered in a new milestone. It is hoped that the high-level committee will continue to play its role, strengthen exchanges and cooperation between the two countries in various fields, and promote the continuous development of bilateral relations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Venezuela Vice President Rodriguez and China’s National Development and Reform Commission Director Zheng Shajie attended the meeting and made work reports respectively. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The China-Venezuela High-Level Committee is an important mechanism for the governments of China and Venezuela to communicate and coordinate cooperation in various fields. About 100 people in charge of relevant departments and units of the two countries attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 在探索海峡两岸融合发展新路上迈出更大步伐]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20230915_8-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, September 15, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;The peaceful development and integrated development of cross-Strait relations are an important way to peaceful reunification and a broad road for the benefit of compatriots on both sides of the Strait. They need to be united Compatriots on both sides of the Taiwan Strait work together to advance. Recently, the &quot;Opinions of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council on Supporting Fujian in Exploring a New Path for Cross-Strait Integrated Development and Building a Cross-Strait Integrated Development Demonstration Zone&quot; was released, which is of great significance for deepening the integrated development of various fields across the Taiwan Strait and promoting the process of the peaceful reunification of the motherland. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We are connected by blood and wish each other well. Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, we have upheld the concept of &quot;one family on both sides of the Taiwan Strait&quot; and focused on the well-being of compatriots on both sides of the Taiwan Strait, promoting the peaceful and integrated development of cross-Strait relations, improving systems and policies that promote cross-Strait exchanges and cooperation, and safeguarding the well-being of Taiwan compatriots, and continue to take the lead in cooperating with Compatriots in Taiwan share the development opportunities on the mainland and gather together the majestic force to move towards peaceful reunification. Cross-Strait exchanges and cooperation are becoming increasingly extensive, and interactions are becoming increasingly closer, bringing tangible benefits to compatriots on both sides of the Strait, especially Taiwan compatriots, which fully demonstrates that peace on both sides of the Strait benefits both sides, and cooperation is a win-win situation. The &quot;Opinions&quot; released this time adhere to the party&#39;s overall strategy for solving the Taiwan issue in the new era, highlight the promotion of integration through communication, benefits and affection, and strive to build a cross-strait integrated development demonstration zone in Fujian. It is a further push forward. Major measures to develop peaceful cross-Strait relations and deepen cross-Strait integrated development are conducive to giving full play to Fujian&#39;s unique role in the overall work on Taiwan, and are conducive to helping Taiwan compatriots and Taiwanese enterprises obtain more development opportunities, broader development space, and better participate in the mainland High-quality development and integration into the new development pattern. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out, “As long as it is conducive to improving the well-being of Taiwan compatriots, as long as it is conducive to promoting the peaceful development of cross-Strait relations, as long as it is conducive to safeguarding the overall interests of the Chinese nation, we will Try your best to do it well.&quot; The fundamental purpose of deepening cross-Strait integrated development is to enhance the family ties and well-being of compatriots on both sides of the Strait, promote industrial integration and spiritual harmony, and realize the common yearning for a better life by compatriots on both sides. It is necessary to implement the &quot;Opinions&quot;, give full play to Fujian&#39;s unique advantages and pioneering role in Taiwan&#39;s work, make good use of resources from all parties, and deepen integrated development; always respect, care for, and benefit Taiwan compatriots, improve the well-being of Taiwan compatriots, and enjoy equal treatment policy and system; adhere to a problem-oriented approach, highlight pioneering and piloting, expand authorization and empowerment, and continue to promote policy and institutional innovation; adhere to the easy before the difficult, step-by-step, continuous advancement, and long-term success, adapt to the times and local conditions, have good support conditions, and have outstanding advantages. The region will take the lead in pilot projects and lead from one point to another, guiding other regions to find their correct positioning and synergy, and strive to build the first home for Taiwanese compatriots and Taiwanese enterprises, promote the in-depth economic and trade integration of Fujian and Taiwan, promote the integrated development of Fujian, and deepen social and cultural exchanges between Fujian and Taiwan. Take greater steps forward in exploring the new path of integrated development across the Taiwan Strait. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The journey of the great road and the aspirations of the people are unstoppable. In his report to the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized that &quot;deepening cross-Strait integrated development in all fields, improving systems and policies that enhance the well-being of Taiwan compatriots, promoting cross-Strait joint promotion of Chinese culture, and promoting spiritual harmony among compatriots on both sides of the Strait.&quot; Smooth channels for exchanges between Taiwan compatriots. , Promote Taiwanese students to come to Fujian to study and study, encourage Taiwan compatriots to come to Fujian for employment, optimize the Taiwan-related business environment, deepen industrial cooperation, support Xiamen and Kinmen to accelerate integrated development, support Fuzhou and Matsu to deepen integrated development, and accelerate the opening and development of Pingtan Comprehensive Experimental Zone , Expand social and cultural exchanges and cooperation... Implementing the 21 specific measures proposed in the &quot;Opinions&quot; will definitely accelerate the construction of cross-strait integrated development demonstration zones, improve the resilience and safety level of cross-strait industrial and supply chains, and further promote the spiritual harmony of compatriots on both sides of the strait. . On the way forward, we must further deepen cross-Strait integrated development in the process of peaceful development of cross-Strait relations, intensify cross-Strait exchanges and cooperation, tighten the emotional ties and interests of compatriots, enhance compatriots on both sides of the strait&#39;s recognition of Chinese culture and the Chinese nation, and build a solid cross-Strait community with a shared future. awareness and lay a solid foundation for the peaceful reunification of the motherland. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Resolving the Taiwan issue and realizing the complete reunification of the motherland are the unswerving historical tasks of the Communist Party of China, the common aspiration of all Chinese people, and the inevitable requirement for realizing the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation. Facing the future, if compatriots on both sides of the Taiwan Strait jointly grasp the general trend of history, adhere to the righteousness of the nation, meet each other halfway, and advance hand in hand, jointly promote the peaceful development of cross-Strait relations and promote the great cause of reunification of the motherland, they will surely be able to jointly create the long-lasting well-being of the Chinese nation and share the great glory of national rejuvenation. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 图片报道]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20230915_9-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, September 15, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-09/15/01/rmrb2023091501p15_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/ TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Hebei Tangshan Port China Petroleum Tangshan LNG (liquefied natural gas) receiving station has been in operation for 10 years, and has transported natural gas to the Beijing-Tianjin-Hebei region. More than 50 billion cubic meters, providing a strong guarantee for economic and social development. The picture shows an LNG ship berthing at the pier of PetroChina Tangshan LNG Terminal on September 13. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Yang Shiyao&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 共同推动文化繁荣发展、文化遗产保护、文明交流互鉴]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20230915_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, September 15, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;On September 14, President Xi Jinping sent a congratulatory letter to the 2023 Beijing Cultural Forum, which triggered an enthusiastic response. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Everyone said that President Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter clearly declares China’s firm determination and policy propositions to implement the global civilization initiative, strengthen cultural exchanges with other parts of the world, and jointly promote cultural prosperity and development. The spirit of the congratulatory letter should be used as a guide, Build the modern civilization of the Chinese nation at a higher level, conduct extensive exchanges and mutual learning among civilizations, and inject profound and lasting cultural power into the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Strong cultural self-confidence, open a cultural mind, and build a modern civilization of the Chinese nation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping pointed out in his congratulatory letter that the Chinese nation has a long and excellent traditional culture. Since ancient times, we have had an open, inclusive and inclusive cultural mind. Chinese civilization has always appreciated mutual understanding and respect among different civilizations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“President Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter has further pointed out the way forward and provided a guide for action for us to further promote cultural inheritance and development and implement global civilization initiatives.” In recent years, Beijing has vigorously promoted the development of the capital’s culture, and cultural Facilities are constantly enriched, high-quality literary and artistic creations are frequently produced, innovation and development are strong, and services that benefit the people continue to improve. Mo Gaoyi, member of the Standing Committee of the Beijing Municipal Party Committee and Minister of the Publicity Department, said that it is Beijing&#39;s important mission to further promote the construction of a national cultural center. &quot;Facing the future, Beijing will actively fulfill its functions as a capital, give full play to its resource advantages, and strive to promote cultural prosperity and build a cultural power.&quot; , and be at the forefront in the new journey of building a modern civilization of the Chinese nation.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;President Xi Jinping&#39;s congratulatory letter profoundly illustrates the open, inclusive and inclusive cultural mind of the Chinese nation and the outstanding characteristics of Chinese civilization.&quot; Beijing Municipality Dongcheng District Party Committee Secretary Sun Xinjun said that Dongcheng District, as the core carrying area of ​​the national cultural center and a key area for the protection of historical and cultural cities, should be guided by the spirit of President Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter to protect cultural heritage, maintain cultural determination, open up a cultural mind, and carry forward cultural Responsibility, promote the harmonious coexistence of historical context and urban development, the effective connection between history and culture and modern life, and the deep integration of cultural inheritance and exchanges and mutual learning, so that China’s excellent traditional culture can continue to shine in the new era. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“From the cultural program &quot;Encountering Civilizations&quot; and other film and television works that have won enthusiastic responses at home and abroad, to the increasingly in-depth exchanges in the fields of books, drama, archaeology, etc., the cultural picture of exchanges and mutual learning between Chinese and foreign civilizations is becoming more and more beautiful. .&quot; Yang Chenghu, deputy dean of the School of Art and Media at Beijing Normal University, said that we must respect all civilizations, treat each other as equals, learn from each other, and be inclusive. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“I was encouraged and excited after listening to President Xi Jinping’s congratulatory message live.” Bai Qun, president of the Beijing Yanjing Eight Arts Association and director of the Beijing Yanjing Eight Arts Museum, said, “Yenjing Eight Arts Museum &quot;Bajue&quot; has held more than 600 theme cultural activities based on the platform, and has also visited Canada, Russia, the United States and other countries. &quot;We will continue to protect and inherit traditional skills well, and use enthusiasm, wisdom and sweat to promote exchanges and mutual learning among civilizations.&quot; Contribute more.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Geng Yu, a researcher at the Fujian Academy of Social Sciences, said that workers in philosophy and social sciences must focus on major issues that combine the basic principles of Marxism with China&#39;s specific reality and with China&#39;s excellent traditional culture , and strive to put forward ideas, propositions, and plans that reflect China’s position, Chinese wisdom, and Chinese values. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Build a first-class platform to promote cultural exchanges and deepen mutual learning among civilizations&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping pointed out in his congratulatory letter that Beijing has a long history and a long cultural context. A powerful testimony to the continuity, innovation, unity, inclusiveness and peace of civilization. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“President Xi Jinping expounded on the importance of jointly promoting cultural prosperity and development, cultural heritage protection, and exchanges and mutual learning among civilizations from the perspective of building a community with a shared future for mankind, and put forward specific requirements for Beijing’s work.” Beijing Municipal Administration of Cultural Heritage Party Secretary and Director Chen Mingjie said that Beijing’s cultural relics system will thoroughly study and implement the spirit of President Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter, highlighting value exploration, systematic protection, activation and utilization, public participation, exchanges and mutual learning, in order to build a first-class platform for promoting cultural exchanges and deepening mutual learning among civilizations. Contribute to the platform. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Cultural relics are witnesses of Beijing’s long history.” Fu Meng, deputy director of the Conservation Department of the Capital Museum, said that disaster prevention, mitigation and preventive protection of cultural relics must be done in an all-round way to reduce damage and disease to cultural relics. Risk, &quot;We must also do a good job in the living inheritance of cultural relics and promote the creative transformation and innovative development of China&#39;s excellent traditional culture.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“President Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter deeply encourages us front-line archaeological practitioners!” Shang Heng, deputy research librarian of the Beijing Institute of Archeology (Beijing Institute of Cultural Heritage), said that we must do our jobs well. work, fulfilling its mission, and striving to provide material evidence for the study of the &quot;source of the city&quot; and &quot;the source of the capital&quot; in Beijing through archaeological surveys, exploration and excavations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Cultural heritage is a vivid carrier that tells the story of Beijing and China. In recent years, Beijing has made a lot of active explorations in cultural heritage protection and digital activation, and the projects being promoted can effectively promote the development of civilization. exchanges and mutual learning.&quot; said He Yan, chairman of the Digital Heritage Professional Committee of the China Association for the Protection of Monuments and Sites. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“We must keep in mind the earnest instructions in President Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter, carry out research activities, take ‘big ideological and political courses’, deepen the work of the Red Memorial Hall, and make more detailed and practical contributions to the development of the capital’s cultural undertakings. Great force.&quot; said Yang Jiayi, member of the Beijing Municipal Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference and director of the Memorial Hall of the Early Revolutionary Activities of the Communist Party of China in Beijing. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Jinke, member of the Standing Committee of the Beijing Shijingshan District Committee and Minister of the Publicity Department, said that Shijingshan District should further promote cultural construction, strengthen cultural relic protection and neighborhood improvement, and promote natural landscapes, ancient villages, industrial sites, red marks, and cultural creativity. The integrated development of other characteristic resources will show the unique natural beauty and cultural heritage of Shijingshan to the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Inject profound and lasting cultural power into promoting the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping pointed out in his congratulatory letter that China will make better use of Beijing as an ancient historical capital and The advantages of the National Cultural Center are to strengthen cultural exchanges with other parts of the world, jointly promote cultural prosperity and development, cultural heritage protection, exchanges and mutual learning among civilizations, implement global civilization initiatives, and inject profound and lasting cultural power into the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Currently, my country has a total of 43 projects included in the UNESCO Intangible Cultural Heritage List and Register, ranking first in the world.&quot; Honorary member of the Chinese Academy of Social Sciences and expert on national intangible cultural heritage protection Liu Kuili, deputy chairman of the committee, said that it is necessary to explain and introduce to the world more excellent culture with Chinese characteristics, embodying the Chinese spirit, and containing Chinese wisdom, so that the &quot;living&quot; intangible cultural heritage can tell the stories of China&#39;s excellent traditional culture and promote Chinese culture to be better. head to the World. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the past 16 years since the establishment of the National Center for the Performing Arts, the National Center for the Performing Arts has created 102 masterpieces that reflect national characteristics and themes of the times, and has established connections with more than 400 international art institutions in more than 100 countries.” National Center for the Performing Arts Chairman Wang Ning said that the National Center for the Performing Arts will resolutely implement the spirit of President Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter, take meeting the people’s spiritual and cultural needs as the starting point and goal, and continue to build a normative, in-depth, and normalized communication platform. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen Ning, Party Secretary of the Beijing Federation of Literary and Art Circles, said that in recent years, the Beijing Federation of Literary and Art Circles has leveraged its advantages in literary and artistic resources and invited music, art and other domestic and foreign artists to collaborate in creating works. “We will further deepen cooperation and promote international The society showcases Beijing&#39;s literary and artistic achievements and helps create a credible, lovely and respectable image of China.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;We share creation and culture around the world through high-quality drama works. Congratulatory letter from President Xi Jinping , has strengthened our drama workers’ confidence and determination to adhere to inclusiveness and openness, and promote exchanges and mutual learning between Chinese drama and world drama. In the future, we must work hard to create more masterpieces.&quot; Yanghua Drama Artistic Director and Director Wang Keran said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Traditional music collides with Western music, classical dance merges with hip-hop, ancient intangible cultural heritage and international fashion brands absorb the nutrients of innovative development from each other... The interaction of human civilizations weaves a colorful and gorgeous picture.” Wu Zhinan, a researcher at the Shanghai Academy of Social Sciences, said, &quot;We must work with the international community to adhere to our own cultural stance, promote the common values ​​of all mankind, and strive to create a new situation of people-to-people exchanges, cultural integration, and people-to-people bonds around the world.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;( Our reporters Zhang Shuo, Wang Haonan, Wang Jue, Shi Fang, Zheng Haiou, Pan Junqiang)&lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 优化分类管理格局  提高科学管理效能 建设堪当民族复兴重任的高素质公务员队伍]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-09/15/nw.D110000renmrb_20230915_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Friday, September 15, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Recently, the General Office of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China issued the newly revised &quot;Regulations on the Management of Professional and Technical Civil Servants&quot; and &quot;Regulations on the Management of Administrative Law Enforcement Civil Servants&quot; ” (hereinafter referred to as the two “Provisions”). On the occasion of the public release of the two &quot;Regulations&quot;, the person in charge of the Organization Department of the Central Committee answered reporters&#39; questions on relevant revisions and implementation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Q: What is the background and significance of this revision of the two &quot;Regulations&quot;? &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Answer: General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized in the report of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China that to comprehensively build a modern socialist country, we must have a team of cadres who are politically strong, adapt to the requirements of the new era, and have the ability to lead modernization. The civil service team is an important part of the party&#39;s cadre team and the backbone of comprehensively building a modern socialist country and comprehensively promoting the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation. The Civil Servant Law stipulates that civil servants are divided into categories such as comprehensive management, professional and technical, and administrative law enforcement. Comprehensive management civil servants are civil servants who are engaged in planning, organization, decision-making, command, supervision, and internal management of agencies. Professional and technical civil servants are civil servants who specialize in professional and technical work and provide technical support and guarantee for agencies to perform their duties. Administrative and law enforcement civil servants Civil servants are civil servants who directly perform law enforcement duties to administrative counterparts in accordance with laws and regulations. In July 2016, the General Office of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the General Office of the State Council issued the &quot;Regulations on the Management of Professional and Technical Civil Servants (Trial)&quot; and the &quot;Regulations on the Management of Administrative and Law Enforcement Civil Servants (Trial)&quot;, establishing two types of civil servant job sequences and Management System. The Civil Service Law revised in 2018 stipulates the implementation of a parallel system of civil servant positions and ranks, and adjusts non-leadership positions into ranks. In 2019, the General Office of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China issued the &quot;Concurrent Regulations on Civil Servant Positions and Ranks&quot;, which mainly stipulates the management of the rank establishment and management of comprehensive management civil servants. In conjunction with the implementation of the parallel system of civil servant positions and ranks, the Organization Department of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China has formulated supporting documents such as the rank establishment and management of professional and technical civil servants and administrative law enforcement civil servants, adjusted the job sequence of the two types of civil servants into a rank sequence, and guided localities and departments to classify civil servants in the comprehensive management category. Professional and technical civil servants and administrative law enforcement civil servants were created, and a classified management pattern for civil servants was initially formed, which played a positive role in stimulating the vitality of the team and improving governance efficiency. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Since the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, General Secretary Xi Jinping has made a series of important expositions on cadre work, talent work, and the construction of high-quality legal work teams, providing guidance for improving the management system of professional and technical and administrative law enforcement civil servants. Fundamentally followed. In order to implement the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speeches and important instructions, adapt to new tasks and new requirements, and formulate plans in accordance with the regulations within the Central Party Committee, the Organization Department of the Central Committee has launched two revisions of the Regulations. The newly revised two &quot;Regulations&quot; deeply implement Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, especially General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s important thoughts on party building, implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China and the Second Plenary Session of the 20th Central Committee, and embody the party&#39;s management of cadres. , the principle of party management of talents and deepening the reform of the administrative law enforcement system and other requirements, absorbing the latest provisions of relevant laws and intra-party regulations, in order to improve the civil service system with Chinese characteristics, improve the scientific level of civil servant management, and build a high-quality civil servant team worthy of the important task of national rejuvenation. of great significance. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Q: What are the overall considerations for revising the two Regulations? &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Answer: On the basis of maintaining the basic stability of the original regulatory framework, the two &quot;Regulations&quot; revised this time added 11 new items and deleted 3 items. The revision work generally focuses on the following points: First, Adhere to the correct political direction.加强党对公务员队伍的集中统一领导，始终把政治建设摆在首位，突出政治标准，强化政治要求，引导专业技术类、行政执法类公务员坚定拥护“两个确立”、坚决做到“两个维护”。二是突出问题导向。根据近年来地方和部门在推进分类改革中遇到的共性问题，特别是针对两类公务员职位设置、交流转任、考录培训、监督约束等有关重点难点问题，进一步明确相应的政策规定。三是注重系统衔接。在公务员法、公务员职务与职级并行规定等制度框架内，建立与综合管理类公务员总体保持对应衔接的专业技术类、行政执法类公务员职级序列，推动分类管理制度系统集成。四是坚持从严管理和激励保障并重。结合两类公务员履职特点，完善权力监督制约机制，引导专业技术类公务员恪守职业道德和学术诚信，培养优良专业素养、专业作风，促进行政执法类公务员强化法治意识、为民观念，做到严格规范公正文明执法。在职级升降、考核奖励、工资待遇等方面完善相关政策，引导两类公务员树立和践行正确政绩观，敢于担当、积极作为。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;问：两个《规定》在加强两类公务员政治建设上主要作了哪些规定？ &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;答：公务员的第一属性是政治属性，德才兼备，方堪重任。修订过程中，坚持把政治标准和政治要求制度化、具体化，落实到两类公务员管理的各个环节。一是在总则中，鲜明提出坚持以习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想为指导，贯彻新时代党的建设总要求和新时代党的组织路线，落实新时代好干部标准，坚持党管干部、党管人才原则，建设忠诚干净担当的高素质专业化公务员队伍；要求两类公务员应当忠于宪法，模范遵守、自觉维护宪法和法律，自觉接受党的领导，具有良好的政治素质和道德品行。二是在录用晋升方面，明确把政治素质作为考录测查的首要内容、作为职级晋升的首要条件，要求机关必须把政治标准放在首位，考准考实拟晋升职级人选的政治素质。三是在培训方面，提出将政治素质以及职业道德、廉洁自律等方面列入培训内容。四是在管理监督方面，规定对有政治能力不过硬，缺乏应有的政治判断力、政治领悟力、政治执行力，在涉及党的领导等重大原则问题上立场不坚定、态度暧昧等情形的，应当对职务职级进行调整；对有公开发表存在严重政治问题言论、对党不忠诚不老实、表里不一、阳奉阴违等违反政治纪律行为的，依规依纪依法予以严肃处理等。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;问：两个《规定》在推进两类公务员专业化建设方面作了哪些规定？ &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;答：在强国建设、民族复兴的新征程上，党和国家事业各项工作专业化、专门化、精细化程度越来越高，对公务员专业能力、专业素养提出了更高要求。贯彻落实习近平总书记关于建设高素质专业化干部队伍等重要指示批示精神，两个《规定》在加强两类公务员专业化建设方面，主要作了以下规定：一是突出专业要求。结合职位特点和队伍实际，在提出共性管理要求的同时，对专业技术类公务员管理强调“业内认可，分类评价”，明确专业技术类公务员任职应当具备相应的专业技术任职资格，对行政执法类公务员管理强调“群众公认，提高执法效能”，要求行政执法类公务员应当强化行政执法能力，提高执法执行力和公信力。二是优化职位设置。根据两类公务员的工作性质和岗位特点，明确专业技术类公务员职位主要在市地级以上机关设置，行政执法类公务员职位主要在市地级以下机关设置；从服务党和国家重大战略、重大工程、重大项目等引进高层次急需人才要求出发，明确县级以上机关可设置专业技术类公务员特设职位，其中突破规格、职数限额设置的职级，职数单独管理。三是完善分类考录、考核、培训政策。在分类考录方面，明确录用专业技术类公务员应当重点测查专业技术基础知识和运用专业技术处理实际问题的能力，可以对有关专业知识、专业技能进行测查；录用行政执法类公务员应当重点测查法律素养和法律执行等能力，可以对有关心理素质、体能等进行测评。在分类考核方面，明确要有针对性地设置考核内容和指标，采取体现职位特点的考核方法。在分类培训方面，明确对专业技术类公务员要强化专业知识和专业技能等培训，对行政执法类公务员要强化法律、法规和执法技能、文明执法、应急处突能力等培训。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;此外，为引导专业技术类公务员专注专业发展、提高创新能力，国家鼓励专业技术类公务员在工作中进行发明创造，对取得显著经济效益或者社会效益的给予奖励。符合条件的专业技术类公务员，经批准可以参加中央和地方各级重大人才工程、科技奖励和科研项目评选，纳入人才服务保障体系，作出杰出贡献的还可纳入院士参评、国务院和地方政府特殊津贴评定等范围。为促进人才顺畅流动，明确专业技术类公务员的专业技术任职资格，与企事业单位专业技术人才职称可以按照规定进行互认转换。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;问：两个《规定》在从严管理监督干部方面作了哪些具体规定？ &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;答：党的二十大报告提出，全面从严治党永远在路上，党的自我革命永远在路上。两个《规定》落实全面从严治党战略部署，坚持全的要求、严的基调、治的理念，进一步完善相关措施：一是压实主体责任。要求机关应当落实从严管理干部要求，严明政治纪律和政治规矩，加强对两类公务员全方位管理和经常性监督。对行政执法类公务员还要求机关完善行政执法程序，强化行政执法监督机制，严格落实行政执法责任制和责任追究制度。二是突出管理监督重点。专业技术类公务员在履行职责中有弄虚作假、滥用职权、玩忽职守、徇私舞弊等违纪违法行为的，行政执法类公务员在履行职责中有态度恶劣粗暴造成不良后果或者影响、故意刁难或者吃拿卡要、徇私枉法、打击报复行政相对人等违纪违法行为以及违反机关的决定和命令的，要按照有关规定严肃追究责任。三是强化权力监督和风险防范。坚持全链条从严管理，与公务员转任、回避、辞去公职等规定有机衔接。比如，明确行政执法类公务员在行政许可、行政处罚等同一职位工作满10年的应当转任。比如，明确两类公务员辞去公职或者退休的，应当遵守从业限制规定，原所在机关和有关部门应当按照规定加强对其离职从业行为的管理监督，切实防范政商“旋转门”风险。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;问：最后，请您谈谈下一步对贯彻落实两个《规定》有什么具体部署和要求？ &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;答：制度的生命力在于执行。各地区和有关部门要把贯彻落实两个《规定》作为在新时代新征程上加强和改进公务员工作、建设堪当民族复兴重任的高素质公务员队伍的重要任务来抓，切实把公务员制度优势转化为治理效能。一是加强政策宣传和解读。中央组织部将组织开展专题培训、做好政策阐释解读，各地区和有关部门要采取多种方式组织学习、搞好培训，引导广大公务员和公务员管理工作者原原本本学习两个《规定》，同学习公务员法及配套法规、干部选拔任用和管理监督等相关法规制度贯通起来，准确把握精神要义和实践要求，提高政策执行能力。二是抓好组织实施。各地区和有关部门要以修订颁布两个《规定》为契机，统一思想认识，认真谋划部署，加大工作力度。要服务党和国家事业发展，优化公务员分类管理格局，注重面向世界科技前沿、面向经济主战场、面向国家重大需求、面向人民生命健康，科学设置专业技术类公务员职位；落实深化行政执法体制改革、推进基层治理现代化要求，将改革到位、具备条件的综合执法队伍及时纳入行政执法类公务员管理。要统筹做好分类考录、分类考核、分类培训等工作，充分发挥分类管理整体效能。三是加强跟踪问效。中央组织部将加强工作指导，及时总结推广好的经验做法，适时开展实施情况调研评估。各地区和有关部门要加强沟通协调，形成工作合力，及时解决实施中出现的问题，推动两个《规定》落地落实、取得实效，努力打造创新能力强、专业素养高的专业技术类公务员队伍和法治意识强、执法能力水平高的行政执法类公务员队伍。 &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Fri, 15 Sep 2023 06:26:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>