<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平同哥伦比亚总统佩特罗会谈]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/26/nw.D110000renmrb_20231026_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 26, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-10/26/01/rmrb2023102601p18_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;October 25 In the afternoon, President Xi Jinping held talks at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing with President Petro Petro of Colombia, who was in China for a state visit. Before the talks, Xi Jinping held a welcome ceremony for Petro in the North Hall of the Great Hall of the People. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Huang Jingwen&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot; center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-10/26/01/rmrb2023102601p17_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR >; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of October 25, President Xi Jinping held talks with Colombian President Petro, who was in China for a state visit, at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing. Before the talks, Xi Jinping held a welcome ceremony for Petro in the North Hall of the Great Hall of the People. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Ding Haitao&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 25th&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;(Reporter Liu Hua) On the afternoon of October 25, President Xi Jinping held talks at the Great Hall of the People with Colombian President Petro, who was in China for a state visit. The two heads of state announced that they would upgrade China-Colombia relations to a strategic partnership. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping pointed out that since the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and Colombia 43 years ago, the relations between the two countries have withstood the test of international vicissitudes and have always maintained a good momentum of development. The two sides understand and support each other on issues involving each other&#39;s core interests and major concerns, cooperation in various fields has been solidly advanced, and people-to-people friendship has become increasingly popular. The establishment of a strategic partnership between China and Colombia is the result of long-term efforts from all walks of life in the two countries. It is also a reflection of mutual trust and natural cooperation between the two sides. It needs to be cherished and continuously enriched and developed by both sides. China is willing to work with Colombia to promote the China-Colombia strategic partnership to better benefit the two peoples and inject positive energy into world peace and development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping profoundly elaborated on the essential connotation of Chinese-style modernization. Xi Jinping emphasized that China supports Colombia in independently exploring a development path that suits its national conditions and supports the Colombian peace process. It hopes that Colombia will achieve comprehensive, lasting and sustainable peace at an early date. It believes that China&#39;s high-quality development and modernization process will bring benefits to countries around the world, including Colombia. to develop new opportunities. China-Colombia relations are based on equality, mutual benefit and win-win results. Colombia is welcome to join the “Belt and Road” family at an early date and achieve common development and prosperity. The two sides should make good use of the Joint Economic and Trade Committee mechanism, optimize the bilateral trade structure, and strengthen cooperation in information communications, digital economy and other fields. China encourages more high-quality products with Colombian characteristics to enter the Chinese market. Colombia is welcome to join the global clean energy partnership initiative proposed by China and share green development opportunities. The two sides should strengthen people-to-people and cultural exchanges such as Chinese language teaching, mutual visits of art groups, and tourism, and strengthen bilateral law enforcement cooperation in areas such as drug control and combating transnational crimes. It is hoped that Colombia will ensure the safety of Chinese citizens, enterprises, and institutions in Colombia. China and Colombia are both developing countries. The two sides should strengthen communication and coordination in international affairs and safeguard the common interests of developing countries and international fairness and justice. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Xi Jinping congratulated Colombia on taking over the rotating presidency of the Community of Latin American and Caribbean States in 2025. He pointed out that China attaches great importance to the development of China-Latin America relations and is willing to support the integration process of Latin America and the Caribbean as always. The 10th anniversary of the establishment of the Latin American and Caribbean Forum is an opportunity to promote the stability and long-term development of China-Latin America relations in the new era. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Petro said that he was very happy to visit China again after many years. Today&#39;s China and the world have undergone tremendous changes, and the theory and practice of China&#39;s revolution and construction have important enlightenment significance. Colombia attaches great importance to the “Belt and Road” initiative proposed by President Xi Jinping. After Colombia and China established a strategic partnership, Colombia is willing to align its regional advantages and development strategies with the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; initiative, strengthen cooperation in infrastructure, clean energy and other fields, welcome Chinese enterprises to invest in Colombia, and promote a more balanced development of bilateral trade relations. , which will help Colombia advance the domestic peace process and achieve the peace, stability and job growth that the people desire, and will also enhance regional and world connectivity. Colombia is willing to maintain communication with China on the situation between Palestine and Israel and other issues, and strive to find a solution to end the war and de-escalate the situation as soon as possible. Colombia welcomes the global development initiative, global security initiative and global civilization initiative proposed by President Xi Jinping, and is willing to strengthen communication and cooperation with China within multilateral mechanisms. Colombia supports the construction of the Latin American and Caribbean Forum and is willing to take advantage of the opportunity of assuming the rotating presidency of the Latin American and Caribbean Community in 2025 to actively promote the continuous development of Latin American and Chinese relations. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After the talks, the two heads of state jointly witnessed the signing of a number of bilateral cooperation documents on industrial investment, trade, digital economy, green development, agriculture, science and technology, education, culture, inspection and quarantine and other fields. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two sides issued the &quot;Joint Statement between the People&#39;s Republic of China and the Republic of Colombia on the Establishment of Strategic Partnership.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Before the talks, Xi Jinping held a welcoming ceremony for Petro in the North Hall of the Great Hall of the People. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A 21-gun salute was fired in Tiananmen Square, and soldiers lined up to pay tribute. The two heads of state ascended the reviewing stand, and the military band played the national anthems of China and Colombia. Accompanied by Xi Jinping, Petro reviewed the honor guard of the Chinese People&#39;s Liberation Army and watched the procession. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That night, Xi Jinping held a welcome banquet for Petro at the Golden Hall of the Great Hall of the People. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Yi participated in the above activities. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平致电祝贺诺沃亚当选厄瓜多尔总统]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/26/nw.D110000renmrb_20231026_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 26, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 25th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;On October 24th, President Xi Jinping called Daniel Novo Asia, congratulations on his election as President of the Republic of Ecuador. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that Ecuador is an important country in Latin America. Since the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and Ecuador 43 years ago, the two countries have maintained close high-level exchanges, continuously deepened political mutual trust, achieved fruitful results in cooperation in various fields, and enjoyed deep-rooted traditional friendship in the hearts of the people. I attach great importance to the development of China-Ecuador relations and am willing to work with President-elect Novoa to continuously enrich the connotation of China-Ecuador comprehensive strategic partnership and better benefit the two peoples. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平向美中关系全国委员会年度颁奖晚宴致贺信]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/26/nw.D110000renmrb_20231026_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 26, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 25th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;On October 25th, President Xi Jinping addressed the nation on U.S.-China relations Congratulatory letter from the committee’s annual awards dinner. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping expressed his appreciation to the National Committee on U.S.-China Relations for its active commitment to promoting exchanges and cooperation in various fields between China and the United States, and congratulated Dr. Kissinger on winning the award. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that as two world powers, whether China and the United States can establish a correct way to get along is crucial to world peace and development and the future and destiny of mankind. China is willing to adhere to the three principles of mutual respect, peaceful coexistence, and win-win cooperation to promote mutually beneficial cooperation with the United States, properly manage differences, and work together to respond to global challenges, achieve mutual success and common prosperity, and benefit both countries and the world. It is hoped that the National Committee on U.S.-China Relations and friends from all walks of life will continue to care and support Sino-U.S. relations and play a constructive role in promoting the healthy and stable development of bilateral relations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;On the same day, US President Biden also sent a congratulatory letter to the National Committee on U.S.-China Relations annual awards dinner. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 习近平会见美国加利福尼亚州州长纽森]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/26/nw.D110000renmrb_20231026_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 26, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-10/26/01/rmrb2023102601p21_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the afternoon of October 25, President Xi Jinping met with California Governor Newsom of the United States at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Huang Jingwen&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 25th&amp;nbsp ;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Liu Hua) On the afternoon of October 25, President Xi Jinping met with California Governor Newsom of the United States at the Great Hall of the People. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping pointed out that China and the United States are the top two economies in the world, with a total economic output exceeding one-third of the world, a total population accounting for nearly a quarter of the world, and bilateral trade accounting for about one-fifth of the world. First, the interests of both parties are closely intertwined. Sino-US relations have developed to this day, and the results have been hard-won and deserve to be cherished. China&#39;s policy toward the United States has always been to adhere to mutual respect, peaceful coexistence, and win-win cooperation. China will continue to work in this direction and hopes that the United States will work with China in the same direction. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xi Jinping happily recalled his visit to California and introduced China&#39;s green transformation and related local development. Xi Jinping pointed out that to develop Sino-US relations well, it is necessary to pool the strength of all parties. The foundation of Sino-US relations lies in the people, hope lies in the people, the future lies in the youth, and vitality lies in the localities. I attach great importance to and support exchanges from all walks of life and local cooperation between China and the United States. I hope your visit will enhance mutual understanding between the two sides and play a positive role in expanding cooperation between China and California and promoting the healthy and stable development of Sino-US relations. China and the United States have huge potential for cooperation in areas such as green development and addressing climate change. The two sides can definitely strengthen cooperation in this area and make it a new highlight in the development of Sino-US relations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Newsom said that China has made extraordinary achievements in development over the past few decades, especially its achievements in the field of new energy in recent years. There is no relationship between any other country in the world that is more important than the relationship between the United States and China. The relationship between the United States and China is related to the future of the United States and the happiness of the people. Local exchanges are an important part of U.S.-China relations. Historically, the Chinese have made important contributions to the construction of California, and California has always been an important gateway for the United States to cooperate with China. I agree with President Xi Jinping’s principles that should be followed in developing U.S.-China relations, and I am willing to follow the same spirit to promote California to strengthen exchanges and exchanges with China and to intensify cooperation in areas such as climate change and new energy. California is willing to be China&#39;s long-term, stable and strong partner. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Wang Yi attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 李强会见吉尔吉斯斯坦总统扎帕罗夫]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/26/nw.D110000renmrb_20231026_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 26, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-10/26/01/rmrb2023102601p14_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;October 25th local time In the morning, Premier Li Qiang met with President Zhaparov of Kyrgyzstan in Bishkek. &lt;BR/>;Photographed by Xinhua News Agency reporter Wang Ye&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Bishkek of this newspaper on October 25 (Reporter Wang Di) On the morning of October 25, local time, Premier Li Qiang met with President Zhaparov of Kyrgyzstan in Bishkek. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Qiang said that Kyrgyzstan is an important neighbor of China. In May this year, President Xi Jinping and Mr. President elevated China-Kyrgyzstan relations to a comprehensive strategic partnership for a new era, and jointly announced the establishment of a China-Kyrgyzstan community with a shared future of good neighborliness, friendship, and shared prosperity. This is a milestone in the history of bilateral relations and provides a solid foundation for the development of bilateral relations and cooperation. further pointed out the direction. China is willing to work with Kyrgyzstan to fully implement the important consensus reached by the two heads of state, promote bilateral cooperation in all fields to achieve new and greater development, and build a China-Kyrgyzstan community with a shared future that is stronger, more dynamic and more effective, and better benefits the two peoples. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Li Qiang pointed out that China is willing to deepen political mutual trust with Kyrgyzstan and always firmly support each other on major issues involving each other&#39;s core interests. Further align development strategies, deepen the integration of economic interests, and continuously improve the quality and efficiency of cooperation between the two countries. With high-quality joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; as the main line, we will further leverage the complementary advantages of industries, expand the scope and scale of economic and trade cooperation, maintain the stability of the industrial and supply chains, create a three-dimensional and diversified interconnection pattern, and start the construction of the China-Kyrgyzstan-Uzbekistan railway as soon as possible. Strengthen people-to-people and cultural exchanges in tourism, local areas, women, youth and other areas to promote mutual understanding among the people. Continue to strengthen counter-terrorism cooperation and jointly maintain a safe and stable development environment. China is willing to strengthen communication and coordination with Kyrgyzstan in regional and international affairs, step up the implementation of the outcomes of the China-Central Asia Summit, work closely with the United Nations, the Shanghai Cooperation Organization and other multilateral mechanisms, and safeguard the common interests of developing countries and international fairness and justice. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhaparov said that in May this year, President Xi Jinping and I reached important consensus on developing the comprehensive strategic partnership between the two countries in the new era and building a community of shared future between Kyrgyzstan and China. Kyrgyzstan-China relations maintain a strong momentum of development. Kyrgyzstan unswervingly supports China on issues involving China&#39;s core interests. Kyrgyzstan is willing to maintain close exchanges with China at all levels, consolidate good-neighborly friendship, promote the joint construction of the &quot;Belt and Road&quot;, and expand cooperation in economy, trade, connectivity, people-to-people and cultural exchanges and other fields. Kyrgyzstan is willing to deepen cooperation with China within the framework of China-Central Asia and the Shanghai Cooperation Organization, jointly combat the &quot;three evil forces&quot;, effectively respond to traditional and non-traditional security challenges, and promote regional security and development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wu Zhenglong attended the meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 赵乐际会见哥伦比亚总统佩特罗]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/26/nw.D110000renmrb_20231026_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 26, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 25th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chairman of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress Zhao Leji met with Colombia in Beijing on the 25th President Petro. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Zhao Leji said that since the establishment of diplomatic relations between China and Colombia, no matter how the international situation changes, the relations between the two countries have always been developing steadily. China has always insisted on viewing bilateral relations from a strategic and long-term perspective, and is willing to work with Colombia to promote the sustained and in-depth development of bilateral relations. The National People&#39;s Congress of China is willing to work with the Colombian Congress to implement the important consensus reached by the two heads of state, deepen friendly exchanges at all levels, strengthen exchanges of experience in state governance, and provide legal guarantee for the development of bilateral relations and promotion of practical cooperation. China is willing to strengthen cooperation with Colombia in international affairs and firmly safeguard the common interests of developing countries. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Petro said that Colombia and China have profound traditional friendship and the cooperation between the two countries is highly complementary. Colombia is willing to deepen cooperation with China in various fields and create a new future for the development of bilateral relations. Colombia highly agrees with China&#39;s series of important initiatives and concepts and is willing to join hands with China to jointly address global challenges such as climate change. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cai Dafeng attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 王沪宁会见纪念中国佛教协会成立70周年座谈会代表]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/26/nw.D110000renmrb_20231026_7-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 26, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;Our newspaper, Beijing, October 25th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Zhang Shuo) Seminar to commemorate the 70th anniversary of the founding of the Chinese Buddhist Association The meeting was held in Beijing on the 25th. Wang Huning, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Chairman of the National Committee of the Chinese People&#39;s Political Consultative Conference, met with members of the leadership team of the Buddhist Association of China and took a group photo with all representatives. Wang Huning congratulated the Buddhist Association of China on its 70th anniversary and extended sincere greetings to Buddhist figures and religious believers across the country. He said that the Chinese Buddhist community should thoroughly study and implement Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era and the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, deeply understand the decisive significance of the &quot;two establishments&quot;, and thoroughly understand General Secretary Xi Jinping&#39;s important exposition on religious work. , unite and guide Buddhists and religious believers to contribute to the realization of the Chinese dream of the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Huning said that since its establishment 70 years ago, the Chinese Buddhist Association has held high the banner of patriotism and socialism, firmly supported the leadership of the Communist Party of China and our country’s socialist system, firmly listened to and followed the Party, and firmly walked in line with socialism. We have followed a path that is compatible with society, actively participated in socialist modernization, and contributed wisdom and strength to the country&#39;s prosperity and national rejuvenation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Wang Huning said that on the new journey of comprehensively building a modern socialist country, the Chinese Buddhist community must adhere to ideological and political guidance in the right direction, firmly grasp the requirements of the times for united struggle, and guide Buddhists and religious believers to inherit and Carry forward the fine tradition of patriotism, continuously enhance the identification with the great motherland, the Chinese nation, Chinese culture, the Communist Party of China, and socialism with Chinese characteristics, and build a strong sense of community for the Chinese nation. It is necessary to further promote the Sinicization of Buddhism in my country and consciously integrate the core socialist values ​​​​and the excellent traditional Chinese culture into the teachings and thoughts. It is necessary to adhere to comprehensive and strict governance of education, and guide teaching staff to abide by laws, regulations, and precepts, and to act with integrity and integrity. Efforts should be made to strengthen talent training and build a team of teaching staff who are politically reliable, religiously accomplished, morally able to convince the public, and effective in critical situations. It is necessary to actively promote friendly exchanges of Buddhism with foreign countries and tell Chinese religious stories well. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Shi Taifeng, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and director of the United Front Work Department of the CPC Central Committee, attended the meeting. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 丁薛祥出席国家数据局揭牌仪式]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/26/nw.D110000renmrb_20231026_8-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 26, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 25th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Qi Zhongxi, Yan Fujing) National Data Administration on the 25th It was officially listed in Beijing in the morning. Ding Xuexiang, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Vice Premier of the State Council, attended the ceremony and unveiled the nameplate. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Ding Xuexiang emphasized that the establishment of the National Data Bureau is a major decision made by the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core from an overall and strategic perspective. It is necessary to follow the guidance of Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, thoroughly implement the decisions and arrangements of the Party Central Committee and the State Council on data work, coordinate and promote the planning and construction of Digital China, digital economy, and digital society, coordinate and promote the construction of data infrastructure systems, and coordinate data Resources are integrated, shared, developed and utilized to fully empower economic and social development. It is necessary to coordinate development and security, give full play to the role of data as a basic resource and an innovation engine, continue to make the digital economy stronger, better, and larger, and promote the deep integration of the digital economy and the real economy, so as to build a new development pattern, build a modern economic system, and build a national Provide strong support for new competitive advantages. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Members of the leadership team of the National Data Administration and all members of the preparatory team, as well as responsible comrades from relevant departments such as the Central Cyberspace Administration of China, the National Development and Reform Commission, and the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology attended the ceremony. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 韩正会见美国加利福尼亚州州长纽森]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/26/nw.D110000renmrb_20231026_9-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 26, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 25th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Vice President Han Zheng met with the Governor of California in Beijing on the 25th Newsom. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Han Zheng said that Sino-US relations are the most important bilateral relations in the world today. Despite some ups and downs, cooperation has always been the mainstream. Recently, Sino-U.S. relations have shown signs of stabilizing. The Chinese and U.S. governments, all sectors of society, and local governments should strengthen communication, exchanges, and cooperation to jointly promote the healthy and stable development of Sino-U.S. relations. The cooperation between Shanghai and other places and California is a model for local exchanges between China and the United States, with huge potential for future development. It is hoped that Governor Newsom&#39;s visit will inject positive energy into promoting exchanges and cooperation between the two sides and improving and developing Sino-US relations. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Newsom said that China’s development achievements, especially in the field of new energy, are amazing. U.S.-China cooperation is not a zero-sum game. California has maintained good cooperation with China for a long time. I am willing to use this visit to further promote closer exchanges and cooperation between California and China in the fields of economy, trade, climate change, and people-to-people and cultural exchanges, so as to bring more benefits to the people of both sides. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 开创工商联事业发展新局面 注入民营经济高质量发展新动能]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/26/nw.D110000renmrb_20231026_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 26, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;&quot;Unite the vast number of private economic people more closely around the party and continue to create a new situation in the development of the Federation of Industry and Commerce.&quot; On October 24, General Secretary Xi Jinping sent a congratulatory letter to the 70th anniversary of the establishment of the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce. He affirmed the important contributions made by the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce and clarified the significance, direction, theme, and tasks of the work of the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce. It is of great significance to the majority of private economic people. Putting forward earnest hopes and clear requirements provides fundamental guidance for doing a good job in the work of the Federation of Industry and Commerce in the new era and promoting the healthy development of the private economy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter deeply inspired and excited the officials and workers of the Federation of Industry and Commerce system, and made the majority of private economic people feel deeply concerned and concerned. Everyone said that they will be guided by the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter, keep in mind the instructions, bravely shoulder the mission, concentrate on development, and promote the cause of the Federation of Industry and Commerce to achieve new and greater achievements on the new journey of building a strong country and national rejuvenation. Open up a broader space for the high-quality development of the private economy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The work of the Federation of Industry and Commerce is an important part of the party’s united front work and economic work&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Federation of Industry and Commerce is a people’s organization and chamber of commerce organization led by the party. The joint cause is an important part of the cause of the party and the country. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The affirmation of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter to the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce is a great encouragement to us.” After studying the congratulatory letter carefully, Hu Linhui, director of the Research Office of the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce, said: “We will keep in mind the instructions to further strengthen The party&#39;s leadership over the private economy and the cohesion of private economic professionals are our own responsibility, and we should play a good role as a bridge and assistant to write a new chapter in the united front work of the private economy.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Shangdong, former deputy inspector of the General Office of the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce I read General Secretary Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter repeatedly and was deeply moved: “As General Secretary Xi Jinping said in his congratulatory letter, over the past 70 years, the Federation of Industry and Commerce has always adhered to the party’s leadership. The Federation of Industry and Commerce will firmly grasp the central tasks of the party and the country in the new era and new journey, and continue to Strengthen the ideological and political guidance for the majority of private economic people, and play a role in building a strong country and rejuvenating the nation.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Zhang Xinghai, chairman of the Chongqing Federation of Industry and Commerce and chairman of Thalys Automobile, said: &quot;I will incorporate the spirit of the congratulatory letter into In practical work, we must publicize and implement the party and the country&#39;s policies, laws and regulations to promote the healthy development of the private economy, and continue to promote Chongqing&#39;s practice of high-quality development of private enterprises.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The chamber of commerce affiliated to the Federation of Industry and Commerce is a private economy An important organizational basis for united front work. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter gave Li Meng, president of the Beijing Young Entrepreneurs Chamber of Commerce, a clearer understanding of the future work direction: “As a young entrepreneur in the new era, I will keep in mind the General Secretary’s instructions and solidly promote my own construction. , continue to deepen the reform of chambers of commerce, promote the work of the Federation of Industry and Commerce, consolidate the ideological foundation of young entrepreneurs, and build consensus for progress.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Unite the majority of private economic professionals more closely around the party&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>; strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“General Secretary Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter made me more aware of the importance of ‘strengthening ideological and political leadership’.” Xiang Qitao, deputy director of the United Front Work Department of the Zoucheng Committee of Shandong Province and secretary of the Party Leadership Group of the Municipal Federation of Industry and Commerce, said , in recent years they have given full play to the guiding role of the Federation of Industry and Commerce in the ideological and political construction of private economic professionals, promoting party building and industry co-construction and mutual promotion. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“In the next step, we will continue to work hard on innovating party-building work methods in the private economic field and further gather the power of private entrepreneurs.” Xiang Qitao said. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From General Secretary Xi Jinping’s important speech when he visited the members of the Democratic National Construction Association and the Joint Industry and Commerce Committee who attended the first session of the 14th National Committee of the Chinese People’s Political Consultative Conference and participated in the joint group meeting, to this congratulatory letter, we will promote the healthy development of the non-public economy &quot;Two health&quot; and the healthy growth of people in the non-public economy are always key words. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Chen Jin, deputy director of the United Front Work Department of the Fuzhou Municipal Committee and Party Secretary of the Fuzhou Federation of Industry and Commerce, said that the Fuzhou Federation of Industry and Commerce will keep in mind the requirements of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter, carry forward the ideological essence of the “3820” strategic project, and unite and lead the private sector Entrepreneurs inherit the spirit of Fujian businessmen and carry forward the enterprising spirit of &quot;dare to be the first in the world and love to work hard to win&quot;, continue to focus on the theme of promoting &quot;two health&quot;, and give full play to the service and guidance role of the Federation of Industry and Commerce in the reform and development of private enterprises. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“General Secretary Xi Jinping once again emphasized the ‘two health’ in his congratulatory letter, making our future work more targeted.” According to Dong Limin, chairman of the Tianjin Binhai New Area Federation of Industry and Commerce, creating a good business environment is the key to promoting An important part of the high-quality development of private enterprises. &quot;In the next step, we will continue to focus on hot topics such as corporate financing and rights protection, and strive to create a business-friendly, fair and transparent business environment to attract more companies to settle down.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Learning from Xi Jinping for the first time In a congratulatory letter from the General Secretary, Chen Zhilie, Chairman of the Guangdong Federation of Industry and Commerce and Chairman of the Board of Directors of EVOC High-Tech Holdings Group, thought deeply about how to better and solidly promote the high-quality development of the private economy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As private entrepreneurs in the new era, we should focus on our main business, continue to innovate and seek development.” Chen Zhilie said that he would take serving the country with industry as his own responsibility and strive to be a self-reliant and self-reliant company with high-level science and technology. Vanguard, unite and lead Guangdong private entrepreneurs to work hard and continue to create new competitive advantages through high-quality development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“General Secretary Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter makes the cadres and workers of the grassroots Federation of Industry and Commerce feel warmer.” Sang Yao, Chairman of the Federation of Industry and Commerce of Wujin District, Changzhou City, Jiangsu Province, said that they will further strengthen the unity of private enterprises and the party committee and government Based on the ideological foundation of peers, we will continue to provide accurate and efficient enterprise-benefiting services around the hot needs of private enterprises such as government-enterprise exchanges, management optimization, and collaborative innovation, and guide the majority of private economic professionals to unite more closely around the party and write a chapter for Chinese-style modernization. Jiangsu Chapter has made new achievements again. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>; &lt;strong>;Contribute the power of private enterprises to the construction of a strong country and national rejuvenation&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;General Secretary Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter to the vast number of private economic people expressed his hope that Chint Group Chairman Nan Cunhui Confidence is further strengthened: “We must vigorously promote the entrepreneurial spirit, continuously enhance the sense of responsibility and mission for entrepreneurship, innovation, and creation, be the vanguard and forerunner in the practice of green, low-carbon, and high-quality development, and promote the new Chinese-style modernization. Demonstrate new achievements of the private economy during the journey.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;High-quality development puts forward higher requirements for the development of the private economy, and practicing new development concepts is what the development of private enterprises should mean. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“General Secretary Xi Jinping hopes that the majority of private economic people will effectively implement the new development concept, which is a request and expectation for us.” Jiang Zhixiang, Secretary General of the Internet of Things Committee of the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce and Chairman of the Board of Directors of Share Communications Group Co., Ltd. said In the future, we will accelerate the research and development and transformation of digital common technologies, better support the construction of digital ecology and the digital transformation of thousands of industries, strive to be a pioneer in implementing new development concepts, a practitioner of innovation and entrepreneurship, and continuously enhance the reputation of &quot;Made in China&quot; Spend. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;To get rich, think about the source, and to get rich, think about progress. More and more private economic figures are in tune with the development of the times and demonstrate their responsibility in fulfilling social responsibilities. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In his congratulatory letter, General Secretary Xi Jinping emphasized &quot;striving to be a model of patriotism, dedication, law-abiding management, entrepreneurship and innovation, and repaying society.&quot; Yan Qi, the rotating chairman of the Catering Industry Committee of the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce and chairman of Taoranju Group, felt particularly real. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Private enterprises have developed under the leadership of the Party. We will keep in mind the requirements of the General Secretary’s congratulatory letter, adhere to the people-centered approach, and shoulder the mission of private enterprises to promote common prosperity.” Yan Qi said that we will continue to Actively participate in actions such as &quot;Thousands of Enterprises Prosper Tens of Thousands of Villages&quot;, and in practice be rich but responsible, rich and righteous, and rich but loving. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;After 70 years of hard work and setting off again, Zhou Haijiang, director of the Publicity and Education Committee of the All-China Federation of Industry and Commerce and chairman of the board of directors of Hongdou Group Co., Ltd., is full of longing: &quot;Chinese-style modernization is the modernization of common prosperity for all people, and private enterprises have an unshirkable responsibility. It is also an important force in promoting common prosperity. We will transform the spirit of General Secretary Xi Jinping’s congratulatory letter into the motivation to move forward, integrate enterprise development into the development process of the party and the country, and with the courage to stick to the main business and strengthen the industry, we will build a strong country and Make new and greater contributions on the new journey of national rejuvenation.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, October 25th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Reporters Fan Sixiang, Sun Shaolong, Ren Qinqin, Zhang Xinyi, Wang Haoming, Wang Jinghuai)&lt; /p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 为传承和弘扬爱国主义精神提供法治保障]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-10/26/nw.D110000renmrb_20231026_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Thursday, October 26, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Patriotism is the core of the Chinese national spirit, the national heart and the national soul of the Chinese nation. The spirit of patriotism is deeply rooted in the hearts of the Chinese nation, inspiring generations of Chinese people to strive for self-improvement and unremitting efforts for the development and prosperity of the motherland. On October 24, the Patriotic Education Law passed by the Sixth Session of the Standing Committee of the 14th National People&#39;s Congress will come into effect on January 1 next year. The Patriotism Education Law is formulated in accordance with the Constitution to strengthen patriotic education in the new era, provide legal guarantee for inheriting and carrying forward the spirit of patriotism, and gather the powerful force to comprehensively build a modern socialist country and comprehensively promote the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The Communist Party of China is the most determined promoter and practitioner of the spirit of patriotism. For more than 100 years, the practice of the Communist Party of China in leading the people to unite and struggle is a great practice of patriotism and has written a glorious chapter of the patriotism of the Chinese nation. Since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core has held high the banner of patriotism, united and led the entire Party and people of all ethnic groups to adhere to the path of socialism with Chinese characteristics, strengthen the &quot;four self-confidences&quot;, and build the Chinese spirit, Chinese values, and The power of China provides common spiritual support and strong spiritual power for realizing the Chinese dream of the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation. Practice has fully proved that patriotism is a powerful spiritual driving force that inspires the Chinese people to safeguard national independence and dignity and forge ahead bravely in the historical torrent. It is a powerful engine that drives the ship of the Chinese nation to ride the wind and waves and move forward bravely. The Chinese nation has unleashed overwhelming historical power and a magnificent banner to overcome all difficulties and obstacles on the road ahead. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The comprehensive construction of a modern socialist country embodies the long-cherished wishes and expectations of the Chinese nation. Today, our country has gone from poverty to moderate prosperity in all respects, and has embarked on a new journey to comprehensively promote the construction of a strong country and national rejuvenation with Chinese-style modernization. This is a great achievement achieved by the hard work of the people of all ethnic groups in the country united and led by the Communist Party of China. The 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China drew up a grand blueprint for comprehensively promoting the construction of a powerful country and national rejuvenation with Chinese-style modernization, and pointed out a broad road for comprehensively building a modern and powerful socialist country and realizing the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation. If we always hold high the banner of patriotism, vigorously carry forward the spirit of patriotism, gather strong synergy to realize the Chinese dream, and march forward bravely along the only correct path of building a strong country and rejuvenating the nation, we will surely be able to firmly grasp the destiny of our country&#39;s development and progress. In your own hands, turn your great dreams into a brilliant reality. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;General Secretary Xi Jinping pointed out: &quot;To carry forward the spirit of patriotism, we must regard patriotic education as an eternal theme.&quot; Carry out patriotic education among all people in accordance with the law, cultivate and enhance feelings for the Chinese nation and the great motherland, Inherit the national spirit, strengthen the national concept, strengthen and unite all patriotic forces, and make patriotism become the firm belief, spiritual strength and conscious action of all the people, which is better for motivating and mobilizing all the people to work hard and move forward courageously, and contribute to the comprehensive construction of the country. It is of great and far-reaching significance to unite and work hard to build a modern socialist country and comprehensively promote the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation. Promoting and protecting patriotic education through the rule of law and further forming legal norms that the whole society can follow will help better promote the spirit of patriotism and improve the quality and effectiveness of patriotic education through the rule of law. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Patriotism is the most natural and simple emotion of the Chinese people. To strengthen patriotism education in the new era, we must adhere to the guidance of Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, adhere to the unity of patriotism, love for the party, and love for socialism, focus on safeguarding national unity and ethnic unity, and build a comprehensive building of socialist modernization. Strengthening the country and realizing the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation as a distinct theme, focusing on cultivating new people of the era who will take on the responsibility of national rejuvenation, focusing on cultivating patriotism, sharpening the ambition to strengthen the country, and practicing acts of serving the country, so as to gather great strength for the construction of a strong country and national rejuvenation. It is necessary to follow the main contents, responsibilities and tasks, implementation measures and support guarantees specified in the Patriotism Education Law, and implement them conscientiously in combination with specific realities to ensure the normalization of patriotic education, let the spirit of patriotism firmly take root in people&#39;s hearts, and transform patriotic enthusiasm into new The struggle practice of the times. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;On our new journey, our future is bright, but the road ahead will not be smooth sailing. Patriotism has always been the spiritual force that firmly unites the Chinese nation. Let us unite more closely around the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping as the core, adhere to the guidance of Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, fully implement the spirit of the 20th National Congress of the Party, thoroughly study and implement Xi Jinping Cultural Thought, and educate with patriotism The enactment and implementation of the law serve as an opportunity to strengthen patriotism education, carry forward the spirit of patriotism, build a common spiritual home for the Chinese nation, continuously strengthen the spiritual bond of unity and the spiritual motivation of self-improvement, and successfully promote the historical cause of building a strong country and national rejuvenation. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Thu, 26 Oct 2023 06:26:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>