<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>People&#39;s Daily</title><description> People&#39;s Daily full text RSS. Get more full text RSS: https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://www.people.com.cn/ <item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 全面推进美丽中国建设 健全自然垄断环节监管体制机制]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/08/nw.D110000renmrb_20231108_1-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 8, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;■Building Beautiful China is an important goal in building a modern socialist country in an all-round way. It is necessary to anchor the basic realization of the goal of Beautiful China in 2035. , continue to advance the prevention and control of pollution, accelerate the green transformation of development methods, enhance the diversity, stability, and sustainability of ecosystems, secure the bottom line of safety, improve the security system, and promote the fundamental improvement of the ecological environment. The state-owned capital operation budget is an important part of the national budget system. It is necessary to improve the state-owned capital operation budget system, expand the scope of implementation, strengthen functions and effects, improve revenue and expenditure management, and improve fund efficiency. It is necessary to improve the supervision system and mechanism of natural monopoly links, strengthen institutional design, improve the supervision system, enhance supervision capabilities, enhance the state-owned economy&#39;s control over natural monopoly links, better meet the needs of building a modern infrastructure system, and better protect national security. It is necessary to better serve and support public decision-making, strengthen the supervision and management of experts&#39; participation in public decision-making, improve systems and mechanisms, standardize process standards, strengthen whole-process management, and create an environment for experts to participate in public decision-making that makes full use of their talents, is full of vitality, and has integrity. Ecological environment zoning management and control plays a fundamental role in the ecological environment source prevention system. It is necessary to strengthen top-level design and improve the institutional system, with the goal of ensuring ecological functions and improving environmental quality, and promote the realization of differentiated and precise management and control of the ecological environment by region&lt;/P>; &lt;P>;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 7 The third meeting of the Deepening Reform Committee reviewed and approved the &quot;Opinions on Comprehensively Promoting the Construction of Beautiful China&quot;, &quot;Opinions on Further Improving the State-owned Capital Management Budget System&quot;, &quot;Implementation Opinions on Improving the Supervision System and Mechanism of Natural Monopoly Links&quot;, &quot;Opinions on Further Improving the State-owned Capital Management Budget System&quot;, &quot;Guiding Opinions on Strengthening the Supervision and Management of Expert Participation in Public Decision-making&quot; and &quot;Guiding Opinions on Strengthening Zoning Management and Control of Ecological Environment&quot;. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;When presiding over the meeting, Xi Jinping emphasized that building a beautiful China is an important goal of comprehensively building a modern socialist country. It is necessary to anchor the basic realization of the goal of beautiful China in 2035, continue to advance pollution prevention and control, and accelerate the green development model. Transform, enhance the diversity, stability, and sustainability of the ecosystem, secure the bottom line of safety, improve the security system, and promote the fundamental improvement of the ecological environment. The state-owned capital operation budget is an important part of the national budget system. It is necessary to improve the state-owned capital operation budget system, expand the scope of implementation, strengthen functions and effects, improve revenue and expenditure management, and improve fund efficiency. It is necessary to improve the supervision system and mechanism of natural monopoly links, strengthen institutional design, improve the supervision system, enhance supervision capabilities, enhance the state-owned economy&#39;s control over natural monopoly links, better meet the needs of building a modern infrastructure system, and better protect national security. It is necessary to better serve and support public decision-making, strengthen the supervision and management of experts&#39; participation in public decision-making, improve systems and mechanisms, standardize process standards, strengthen whole-process management, and create an environment for experts to participate in public decision-making that makes full use of their talents, is full of vitality, and has integrity. Ecological environment zoning management and control plays a fundamental role in the ecological environment source prevention system. It is necessary to strengthen top-level design, improve the institutional system, and promote the realization of differentiated and precise management and control of the ecological environment by region with the goal of ensuring ecological functions and improving environmental quality. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Li Qiang, Wang Huning and Cai Qi, members of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and deputy directors of the Central Commission for Comprehensive Deepening Reforms, attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The meeting pointed out that since the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, my country&#39;s ecological civilization construction has undergone historic, turning and overall changes from theory to practice. It must be based on the new needs of high-quality economic and social development, the people&#39;s The public has new expectations for the improvement of the ecological environment, intensify efforts to solve prominent ecological environment problems, focus on the construction of ecological civilization systems, give full play to the leading role of pioneer exploration and demonstration, carry out nationwide actions, promote local and overall coordination, and treat symptoms and root causes. Connectivity, current and long-term integration. It is necessary to strengthen organizational leadership, combine local actual classification policies, district governance, refined construction, and promote the goal of Beautiful China to become reality step by step through specific actions. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The meeting emphasized that the budget work reflects the will of the party and the country, and it is necessary to uphold and strengthen the leadership of the party, give full play to the institutional advantages of concentrating efforts on major tasks, focus on promoting the optimization and structural adjustment of the state-owned economic layout, and promote the relationship between state-owned capital and Concentrate on important industries and key areas of national security and the lifeline of the national economy, concentrate on public services, emergency response capabilities, public welfare fields related to the national economy and people&#39;s livelihood, and concentrate on forward-looking strategic emerging industries to better serve the construction of a new development pattern and promote high quality develop. We must always adhere to the idea of ​​&quot;living a tight life&quot;, strengthen the scientific coordination and rational allocation of financial resources, reasonably determine the scale of budget revenue and expenditure, make overall plans to ensure and improve people&#39;s livelihood, and put an end to extravagance and waste. It is necessary to adhere to the statutory budget, strengthen budget constraints, promote budget performance management, and give full play to the supervisory role of the National People&#39;s Congress. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The meeting pointed out that network links in industries such as electricity, oil and gas, and railways have natural monopoly attributes and are key areas of my country’s state-owned economic layout. It is necessary to improve the regulatory system, strengthen regulatory capacity building, focus on strengthening the supervision of the natural monopoly link in the implementation of major national strategies and planning tasks, the fulfillment of national security responsibilities, the fulfillment of social responsibilities, business scope and business behavior, and promote the natural monopoly link. Enterprises focus on their main responsibilities and businesses, increase state-owned capital investment in network infrastructure, and improve the security and reliability of backbone networks. It is necessary to supervise the scope of monopolistic and competitive businesses carried out in natural monopoly links to prevent the use of monopoly advantages from extending to upstream and downstream competitive links. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The meeting emphasized that experts are important intellectual resources for promoting reform and development. It is necessary to strengthen the political guidance of the expert team, improve policy guarantees and incentive measures for experts to participate in public decision-making, and fully mobilize the enthusiasm and initiative of experts. It is necessary to establish and improve the entire process and full-chain management system from expert selection to assessment and supervision, improve the institutional norms for experts to participate in public decision-making by field and category, clarify the responsibilities, rights, obligations and corresponding responsibilities of experts participating in public decision-making, and encourage These experts actively provide advice and suggestions for the party and government&#39;s scientific decision-making. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The meeting pointed out that to strengthen ecological environment zoning management and control, it is necessary to implement the main functional zone strategy, connect land spatial planning and use control, focus on regional and river basin outstanding ecological and environmental issues, improve the ecological environment zoning management and control plan, and establish Zoning and classification management and control strategies from problem identification to solutions. It is necessary to implement the main responsibilities of local party committees and governments at all levels, use the results of ecological environment zoning management and control, serve the implementation of major national and local development strategies, and scientifically guide various development, protection and construction activities. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Members of the Central Committee for Comprehensively Deepening Reforms attended the meeting, and responsible comrades from relevant departments of the central government and state agencies attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 10月货物贸易进出口总值增速转正（新数据 新看点）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/08/nw.D110000renmrb_20231108_2-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 08, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;This newspaper, Beijing, November 7th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporters Du Haitao and Luo Shanshan) The General Administration of Customs released data on the 7th It shows: my country’s total import and export value of goods trade in October was 3.54 trillion yuan, with the monthly growth rate turning from the recent year-on-year decline to an increase of 0.9%, and the positive trend of import and export has been further consolidated. In the first ten months, the total import and export value of my country&#39;s goods trade was 34.32 trillion yuan. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In the first 10 months, my country&#39;s general trade imports and exports increased and their proportion increased. Imports and exports were 22.26 trillion yuan, an increase of 1.8%, accounting for 64.9% of my country&#39;s total foreign trade value, an increase of 1.1 percentage points over the same period last year. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;In the first 10 months, the export of mechanical and electrical products was 11.43 trillion yuan, an increase of 2.8%; the total import and export to the countries jointly building the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; was 15.96 trillion yuan, an increase of 3.2%, and the largest trading partner ASEAN Imports and exports increased by 0.9%, imports and exports to Central and Eastern European countries increased by 2.7%, imports and exports to the five Central Asian countries increased by 34.8%, imports from the European Union and the United States increased by 5.1% and 0.2% respectively; imports and exports of private enterprises reached 18.24 trillion yuan, an increase of 6.2%. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The latest results of the China Customs Trade Prosperity Statistics Survey show that the proportion of companies that are optimistic about future imports and exports has increased, and the positive development trend of my country&#39;s foreign trade has further emerged. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;According to reports, the current accumulation of positive factors in my country&#39;s foreign trade field has increased, driving import and export growth in October year-on-year. Experts said that as my country&#39;s policy of stabilizing the economy and stabilizing foreign trade continues to release dividends, consumption has picked up significantly, key manufacturing industries are expected to improve, and policy support and corporate efforts have formed an effective synergy, foreign trade is expected to continue the overall stable development momentum. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 让互联网更好造福世界各国人民]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/08/nw.D110000renmrb_20231108_3-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 08, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;In November 2014, the first World Internet Conference was held in Wuzhen, Zhejiang. In his congratulatory message to the conference, President Xi Jinping emphasized that “China is willing to work together with all countries in the world to deepen international cooperation based on the principles of mutual respect and mutual trust, respect network sovereignty, maintain network security, and jointly build a peaceful, secure, open, and cooperative network. space, and establish a multilateral, democratic, and transparent international Internet governance system.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Wuzhen Summit of the World Internet Conference is the largest and highest-level Internet conference held in China, and is also an unprecedented summit meeting in the world&#39;s Internet field. Since 2014, every year, political dignitaries and Internet elites from all over the world gather in Wuzhen, the permanent venue, to discuss win-win cooperation in global cyberspace. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Thousand-year-old ancient town, digital civilization, history and future complement each other here. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The wind is just right for sailing. On November 8, the 2023 World Internet Conference Wuzhen Summit opened. With ten years of accumulation, the World Internet Conference has built consensus, built a platform, and promoted the concept of building a community with a shared future in cyberspace to be deeply rooted in the hearts of the people. Fruitful results have continued to emerge, and win-win cooperation has steadily advanced, contributing wisdom and solutions to promote Internet development and governance to the world. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The concept of building a community with a shared future in cyberspace has been widely recognized and responded positively to by the international community&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping pointed out that “all countries should strengthen communication, expand consensus, and deepen Cooperate and jointly build a community with a shared future in cyberspace&quot; and &quot;promote the construction of a more fair and reasonable, open and inclusive, safe and stable cyberspace, and full of vitality, so that the Internet can better benefit people all over the world.&quot; &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Currently, more than half of the countries and regions in the world use Beidou, and more and more people’s lives are becoming more convenient, safer, more efficient, and more accurate because of Beidou. Beidou has entered the standard system of international organizations such as civil aviation, maritime affairs, and mobile communications, and is accelerating its integration into the international industrial system. In November 2022, during the Wuzhen Summit of the World Internet Conference, the &quot;Working Together to Build a Community of Shared Future in Cyberspace&quot; release and display event was held, including 12 cases including &quot;Beidou System Serving the World and Benefiting Humanity - Working Together to Build a Community of Shared Future in Space-Time Network&quot; Selected. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Connecting the World&quot;, &quot;European Union Cross-border Flow of Scientific Research Data Practice&quot;, &quot;Asian Digital Art Exhibition&quot;...the emergence of many excellent cases reflects the increasing implementation of the concept of building a community with a shared future in cyberspace around the world. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Wuzhen Summit witnessed the proposal and deepening of the concept of building a community with a shared future in cyberspace, which has become increasingly popular. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Building a community with a shared future in cyberspace reflects a profound understanding of the development laws of human society in the information age, and has received widespread recognition and positive response from the international community. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From concept documents to action initiatives to practical cases, ideological consensus gradually turned into concrete actions. Relying on the Wuzhen Summit of the World Internet Conference, the beautiful picture of countries jointly seeking global Internet development and building a community with a shared future in cyberspace is clearly visible:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2017, at the 4th World Internet Conference, China, Egypt, Laos, Saudi Arabia, Serbia, Thailand, Turkey, the United Arab Emirates and other countries jointly launched the &quot;Belt and Road&quot; Digital Economy International Cooperation Initiative. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2019, the World Internet Conference Organizing Committee released the concept document &quot;Working Together to Build a Community with a Shared Future in Cyberspace&quot;, which provides an in-depth explanation of the historical background, basic principles, practical paths and governance structure of the concept of building a community with a shared future in cyberspace. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In 2020, the World Internet Conference Organizing Committee released the &quot;Action Initiative to Work Together to Build a Community with a Shared Future in Cyberspace&quot; to further transform the concept of building a community with a shared future in cyberspace into practical actions. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;………&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The more you practice, the better your knowledge will advance; the deeper your knowledge, the more your practice will reach you. Today, the World Internet Conference has entered its tenth year and continues to explore the answers of the times to jointly build a community with a shared future in cyberspace. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Build a better platform for international exchange and cooperation in cyberspace&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Everything can be achieved if we work together as one. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The World Internet Conference itself has also continued to reform its mechanisms in order to better build an international exchange and cooperation platform in cyberspace. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“The establishment of the international organization of the World Internet Conference is an important measure to conform to the development trend of the information age and deepen international exchanges and cooperation in cyberspace.”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On July 12, 2022, President Xi Jinping Send a congratulatory letter to the establishment of the international organization of the World Internet Conference. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From an annual international conference to an international organization with permanent institutions, the World Internet Conference has achieved a qualitative leap. Since its establishment, the international organization of the World Internet Conference has attracted more than 120 members from the United Kingdom, France, Germany, the United States, Australia, South Korea, Japan, India, etc. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;When a new organization is established, new practical explorations follow. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“Through digital cooperation and technological innovation, technology can empower thousands of industries and create more opportunities for business sectors in various countries.” “To promote digital cooperation, there is an urgent need to bridge the digital divide and establish and improve international digital cooperation. Mechanisms, norms of ethics and morals, etc. to take action”...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In midsummer, in the land of Qilu, the discussion of opinions is as hot as the scorching sun. In June this year, the Nishan Dialogue on Digital Civilization of the World Internet Conference with the theme of &quot;The Era of Artificial Intelligence: Building a Digital World of Exchange, Mutual Learning, and Inclusion&quot; opened in Qufu, Jining, Shandong Province. This is the first time the World Internet Conference has been held since the establishment of the international organization Thematic activities. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Nishan Dialogue on Digital Civilization is a representative of many new practices of the international organizations of the World Internet Conference. After the establishment of the World Internet Conference International Organization, it has continuously innovated its operating mechanism, enriched members&#39; rights and interests, served member development, carried out various conference activities such as member symposiums, member activity days, etc., and explored various thematic activities. In addition, the international organization of the World Internet Conference also actively follows up on new developments in global rules in related fields around hot topics such as artificial intelligence and data governance. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A flying bridge, Guanshan is not far away. In recent years, more and more international exchange activities have been held in China, and together with the World Internet Conference, we have built a collaborative platform for building a community with a shared future in cyberspace. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China International Digital Products Expo, China International Software Expo, World Robot Conference, World Artificial Intelligence Conference... one after another &quot;Eastern Promise&quot; set up by China allows the international community to share innovative achievements in cyberspace. . &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;China Internet Governance Forum, Sino-British Internet Roundtable, Sino-German Internet Economic Dialogue, China-Africa Internet Development and Cooperation Forum... international platforms for dialogue, exchange and cooperation, for the open sharing of global cyberspace, We have made important contributions to mutual benefit and win-win results. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the World Internet Conference plays an increasingly important role as a communication and collaboration platform, a closely connected &quot;circle of friends&quot; in global cyberspace has become increasingly active. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Promote digital civilization to benefit people all over the world&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the highlight of the Wuzhen Summit of the World Internet Conference every year, the &quot;Light of the Internet&quot; Expo has become a leading new global Internet The vane of technological development. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since 2014, the World Internet Conference has focused on promoting the integration of data and reality and using new momentum to promote new development. Not only the &quot;Light of the Internet&quot; Expo, but also important events such as the release of the world&#39;s leading Internet scientific and technological achievements and the &quot;Direct to Wuzhen&quot; global Internet competition have promoted the integration of mobile Internet, cloud computing, big data, artificial intelligence, etc. with various industries, creating a strong foundation for enhancing the Global economic development provides new impetus. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taking the World Internet Conference as an opportunity, as a major country in the digital economy, China is also actively promoting broader and deeper cooperation in the digital economy among countries, so that the results of Internet development can benefit people of all countries. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In December 2017, President Xi Jinping said in his congratulatory letter to the Fourth World Internet Conference: &quot;China hopes to use its own efforts to promote all countries in the world to ride the express train of the development of the Internet and digital economy.&quot;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;China’s actions are consistent and firm: In Southeast Asia, Chinese companies help build ASEAN’s first 5G smart hospital and promote the intelligent transformation of service processes; in Latin America, China, Brazil, Ecuador and other countries use digital technology to innovate Cooperate to help protect the Amazon rainforest ecosystem and marine ecological environment; in Africa, China and the International Telecommunication Union have cooperated to launch technical assistance and training projects to help build a &quot;digital Uganda&quot;...&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;From the construction of information infrastructure, From the digital transformation of society to the application of new technologies such as 5G and the Internet of Things, China is actively committed to narrowing the global digital divide and sharing the development opportunities of the times with the world. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;We know each other no matter how far we are, but we are still neighbors thousands of miles away. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In his congratulatory letter to the Wuzhen Summit of the 2021 World Internet Conference, President Xi Jinping emphasized that China is willing to work with all countries in the world to jointly shoulder the historical responsibility for the progress of mankind, stimulate the vitality of the digital economy, and enhance the effectiveness of digital government , optimize the digital social environment, build a digital cooperation pattern, build a solid digital security barrier, let digital civilization benefit people of all countries, and promote the construction of a community with a shared future for mankind. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The beauty of beauty is shared by all. In the information age, the Internet carries human dreams and is related to people&#39;s well-being. Looking forward to the future, the World Internet Conference will always adhere to &quot;high starting point planning, high-standard construction, and high-level advancement&quot;, and is committed to building a global Internet shared platform for consultation, joint construction, actively creating a new pattern of international cooperation in cyberspace, and continuing to write a new chapter in global Internet development and development. A new chapter in governance. &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 李强同澳大利亚总理阿尔巴尼斯会谈]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/08/nw.D110000renmrb_20231108_4-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 08, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http: //paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/2023-11/08/01/rmrb2023110801p35_b.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;On the morning of November 7, Premier Li Qiang of the State Council held talks at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing with Prime Minister Albanese of Australia, who was in China for an official visit. Before the talks, Li Qiang held a welcoming ceremony for Albanese in the North Hall of the Great Hall of the People. &lt;BR/>;Photo by Xinhua News Agency reporter Liu Bin&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 7th&amp;nbsp ;&amp;nbsp;On the morning of November 7, Premier Li Qiang held talks at the Great Hall of the People with Australian Prime Minister Albanese, who was in China for an official visit. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Li Qiang said that President Xi Jinping held a fruitful meeting with Mr. Prime Minister to provide strategic guidance for the development of China-Australia relations in the new era. China is willing to work with Australia to further strengthen dialogue and communication, deepen political mutual trust, and properly handle differences in the spirit of mutual respect and mutual understanding, so that cooperation will continue to become the mainstream of China-Australia relations and win-win results will be reflected in all areas of cooperation between the two sides. , promote the sustained and steady development of the China-Australia comprehensive strategic partnership and create more benefits for the people of the two countries. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Li Qiang pointed out that China-Australia cooperation has great potential. China is willing to work with Australia to follow economic laws and adhere to market principles, consolidate and strengthen cooperation in traditional fields such as energy and mining, and expand green development, digital economy, technological innovation, Cooperate in emerging fields such as the health industry, avoid politicizing and security-oriented economic and trade issues, achieve win-win development, and promote regional prosperity. China is willing to work with Australia to promote exchanges and cooperation in education, culture and tourism, local areas, youth and other fields, and further facilitate personnel exchanges between the two sides, so that China-Australia friendship will continue to be deeply rooted in the hearts of the two countries. &amp;nbsp;&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Albanese said that since Prime Minister Whitlam’s visit to China 50 years ago, Australia-China relations have made great progress and brought great benefits to the people of both countries. China is Australia&#39;s important partner, and Australia-China relations should not be defined by differences. Australia adheres to the one-China policy and is willing to enhance mutual understanding with China, deepen cooperation in trade, investment, science and technology, people-to-people and cultural exchanges, properly manage differences through communication and dialogue, and jointly respond to global challenges such as climate change, food security, and transnational organized crime. Maintain regional and world peace and prosperity, and promote the development of Australia-China comprehensive strategic partnership in a positive, stable and constructive direction. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Before the talks, Li Qiang held a welcoming ceremony for Albanese in the North Hall of the Great Hall of the People. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Wu Zhenglong participated in the above activities. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;During Albanese&#39;s visit to China, the two sides issued the &quot;Joint Outcome Statement of the Annual Meeting between the Chinese and Australian Prime Ministers&quot;. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 赵乐际会见越南共产党代表团]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/08/nw.D110000renmrb_20231108_5-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 08, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Xinhua News Agency, Beijing, November 7&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and Chairman of the Standing Committee of the National People&#39;s Congress Zhao Leji On the 7th, he met in Beijing with a delegation led by Tran Kim Sui, member of the Political Bureau of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of Vietnam, member of the Secretariat of the Central Committee, and director of the Central Inspection Commission. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Zhao Leji said that under the strategic guidance of General Secretary Xi Jinping and General Secretary Nguyen Phu Trong, China-Vietnam relations have always maintained a good momentum of development. This year marks the 15th anniversary of the establishment of a comprehensive strategic cooperative partnership between China and Vietnam. China is willing to work with Vietnam to implement the important consensus reached by the top leaders of the two parties, deepen practical cooperation in various fields, and push the relations between China and Vietnam between the two parties and the two countries to a new level in the new era. The National People&#39;s Congress of China is willing to intensify exchanges at all levels with the National Assembly of Vietnam, share experience in state governance, and make positive contributions to building a China-Vietnam community with a shared future. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Chen Jinxiu said that Vietnam is willing to work with China to implement the important consensus reached by the top leaders of both sides, strengthen the exchange of experiences on party and state governance concepts, further promote party building, and consolidate the people’s trust in the party, government and society. the trust and support of the socialist system. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 坚持以习近平文化思想为引领 开创新时代宣传思想文化工作新局面]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/08/nw.D110000renmrb_20231108_6-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 8, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;Our newspaper, Beijing, November 7th&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;(Reporter Zhang Shuo) Symposium on Studying and Implementing Xi Jinping’s Cultural Thought 6 It was held in Beijing on the same day. Cai Qi, member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and secretary of the Secretariat of the CPC Central Committee, attended and delivered a speech. He emphasized that we must deeply understand the decisive significance of the &quot;two establishments&quot;, resolutely achieve the &quot;two maintenances&quot;, adhere to the guidance of Xi Jinping&#39;s cultural thoughts, create a new situation in propaganda and ideological and cultural work in the new era, and comprehensively promote the construction of a strong country and national rejuvenation. Weiye provides strong ideological guarantee, strong spiritual power, and favorable cultural conditions. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cai Qi said that Xi Jinping’s cultural thoughts were formed and continuously enriched and developed in the great practice of building socialist culture with Chinese characteristics in the new era. It is a theoretical summary of the practical experience in building party leadership culture in the new era. This important thought profoundly answers fundamental questions such as what flag to raise, what path to take, what principles to adhere to, and what goals to achieve in my country&#39;s cultural construction in the new era. It enriches and develops Marxist cultural theory and promotes ideological and cultural development for the new era and new journey. It provides a scientific guide for action to work and shoulder new cultural missions, and contributes Chinese wisdom to creating a new form of human civilization and leading the development and progress of world civilization. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cai Qi said that Xi Jinping’s cultural thoughts are broad and profound. They not only have profound views, strategic planning, and scientific deployment, but also teach us the correct stance and effective methods. It is necessary to comprehensively study and understand, not only accurately understand the important concepts and formulations, but also strengthen the systematic and holistic grasp, thoroughly understand the basic spirit, understand the core essence, clarify the practical requirements, and achieve understanding and integration. We must deeply understand the major innovative perspectives, scientific methodology and strategic arrangements for cultural construction contained in this important thought, and deeply understand that this important thought is an evolving, open, scientific and systematic system of thought that will surely evolve with practice. In-depth and continuous enrichment and development. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Cai Qi said that learning and implementing Xi Jinping’s cultural thoughts must emphasize both learning and practice, and work hard on deepening theoretical arming, improving the ability to guide public opinion, and improving the construction of innovative spiritual civilization. We should work hard to promote cultural prosperity, work hard to enhance the effectiveness of international communication, and work hard to prevent and resolve ideological risks, and effectively implement this important idea into all aspects and the entire process of publicity, ideological and cultural work. The propaganda, ideological and cultural front must regard the study, research and interpretation of Xi Jinping’s cultural thoughts as an important political task, pay close attention to study and training, organize and carry out theoretical research, continue to strengthen propaganda and interpretation, and continue to lead to in-depth study. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;Li Shulei, member of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and director of the Propaganda Department of the CPC Central Committee, presided over the meeting. State Councilor Chen Yiqin attended the meeting. &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;The main responsible comrades of the State Administration of Radio and Television, Xinhua News Agency, Shanghai Municipal Party Committee Propaganda Department, Guangdong Provincial Party Committee Propaganda Department, Xinjiang Uygur Autonomous Region Party Committee Propaganda Department and some experts and scholars made speeches. The meeting was attended by responsible comrades of the central publicity and cultural units, main responsible comrades of the Propaganda Department of the Party Committees of various provinces, autonomous regions and municipalities and the Xinjiang Production and Construction Corps, and relevant experts and scholars in the ideological and cultural circles. &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[01版要闻 - 中国新发展  世界新机遇（进博会观察）]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/08/nw.D110000renmrb_20231108_7-01.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;Wednesday, November 08, 2023&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;p>;President Xi Jinping sent a letter to the 6th China International Import Expo and pointed out: “I hope that the CIIE will speed up the improvement and build a new development pattern. Window function to provide new opportunities for the world with China&#39;s new development; give full play to its role as a platform to promote high-level opening up, making China&#39;s big market a big market shared by the world; better provide international public goods and services shared by the world, and help promote the construction of openness Shape the world economy and let win-win cooperation benefit the world.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meet at CIIE and share the future. Walking at the CIIE, you can see the wonderful exhibits on display one by one, the mutually beneficial and win-win signings and cooperation, and the forum activities with in-depth exchanges. You can feel the continuous release of the spillover effect of the CIIE. More and more new products, new technologies, and new services are making their debut, driving China&#39;s industrial and consumption upgrades, boosting high-quality development, and injecting new momentum into the world economy. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the CIIE as a window, China is taking a more open and confident attitude to benefit the world through win-win cooperation. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;The dividends of openness continue to be released, and win-win cooperation benefits the world&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The first place for new products, the first choice for cutting-edge technology, and the first place for innovative services, the CIIE has Develop into an international public good shared by the world. At this CIIE, the area of ​​cutting-edge science and technology exhibitions and consumer-related exhibitions increased by 30% compared with the previous session, with more than 400 new products, technologies, and services on display. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Opening up is the only way to achieve high-quality development. The CIIE continues to release the dividends of opening up, smoothes the domestic circulation, connects the domestic and international dual circulations, and becomes an important platform for global companies to deeply explore the Chinese market. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At the General Medical booth, nearly 30 innovative and intelligent products attracted people&#39;s attention; at the Michelin booth, a variety of racing tires using new technologies attracted many professional visitors; at the Pacific Alpaca Home Textile Group booth, Yangtuo The camel hair snow jacket became a topic of discussion among the audience. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Analog is a new friend at this year’s CIIE. Although it participated in the exhibition for the first time, it won a 300-square-meter booth in the technical equipment exhibition area and brought edge intelligence, digital factory, automobile, digital The latest technologies and products in medical and other fields. Cai Zhenyu, Industrial Marketing Director of Analog Devices China, said: &quot;The China International Import Expo will give companies the opportunity to strengthen exchanges and cooperation with customers and bring more market opportunities to companies.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;New development in China, new opportunities in the world . In the next five years, China&#39;s import and export volume of trade in goods and services is expected to exceed US$32 trillion and US$5 trillion respectively. With the help of the CIIE platform, more and more high-quality global products have been transformed from exhibits into commodities, sharing the opportunities in China&#39;s ultra-large-scale market. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The exhibits are splendid and there are many first-time exhibitions. &quot;This is the first time that the company has participated in the exhibition and has brought some brand-new products.&quot; said a relevant person in charge of the home furnishing brand Tempur-Pedic. &quot;Next, we will open more physical stores to allow Chinese consumers to experience better health products.&quot;&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;The new hydrogen fuel cell heat exchanger, the world’s first actively powered prosthetic knee joint, precise diagnosis and treatment solutions for serious diseases based on molecular imaging technology... The CIIE helps precise docking of trade procurement, and more exhibitors As investors, more and more companies are investing in China. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Taking advantage of the spillover effect of the CIIE, Danone has achieved fruitful results. A number of Chinese local research results from Shanghai Danone Open Research Center have gradually entered the market and spread to the world. &quot;We will continue to increase investment in China, continue to accelerate localization development, and use the open platform of the CIIE to bring more &#39;Created in China, Made in China&#39; products and services to global consumers.&quot; Danone relevant person in charge Xie Weibo explain. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;Strengthen innovation cooperation and promote industrial transformation and upgrading&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the enterprise exhibition area of ​​this CIIE, innovation, professionalism, green and other characteristics are particularly prominent. Focusing on high-quality development, the area of ​​energy, low-carbon and environmental protection technology, crop seed industry and other special areas increased by 30% compared with the previous session; the upgraded and expanded innovation incubation area attracted about 300 projects to participate in the exhibition, building a centralized display platform for global start-ups. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Technological innovation is an important engine for promoting high-quality development. With the help of the CIIE, more advanced technology equipment and high-end parts have entered the Chinese market. All parties have strengthened innovation cooperation, shared development opportunities, and assisted industrial transformation and upgrading. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The absolute articulated arm measuring machine can swing up and down and adjust the angle just like a human arm, enabling portable measurement of large equipment; an ultra-high-precision three-dimensional coordinate measuring machine with a maximum accuracy of 0.28 microns... …In the technology equipment exhibition area of ​​the CIIE, the digital information technology solutions displayed by Hexagon attracted many inquiries from domestic companies. &quot;China&#39;s industrial upgrading has huge potential. We look forward to using the CIIE as a platform to strengthen innovation cooperation with partners and jointly promote the digital and intelligent transformation of the industry.&quot; said Sun Jiangzhao, the relevant person in charge of Hexagon. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“As an enterprise in the cold chain logistics business sector of the supply and marketing cooperative system, every time we come to the CIIE, we can expand our international horizons and enhance our development momentum. By exchanging cutting-edge information on industry development and introducing advanced technologies and services , our innovation-driven development capabilities are stronger, and we have more motivation to make our main business bigger and stronger.&quot; Yang Zhihua, general manager of China Supply and Marketing Cold Chain Logistics Co., Ltd., a subsidiary of China Supply and Marketing Group, said that the company will continue to give full play to the advantages of the supply and marketing cooperative system&#39;s logistics and distribution system , accelerate scientific and technological innovation, rely on China-Europe freight trains to introduce more affordable, high-quality and safer products, and enrich consumers&#39; choices. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Green is the foundation for high-quality development. In the automobile exhibition area, Toyota Motor&#39;s hydrogen fuel cell system for commercial vehicles became a hot spot for inquiries from merchants. &quot;China is accelerating green development and bringing new market opportunities. We will join hands with more Chinese companies to embrace new green opportunities and help achieve the &#39;double carbon&#39; goal.&quot; Xu Yiming, Director of Marketing and Public Relations Department of Toyota Motor (China) Investment Co., Ltd. explain. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;strong>;New products, new technologies, and new services enter the market to meet new demands for quality life&lt;/strong>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;This CIIE will optimize and upgrade the health and elderly care area, beverages The exhibition area of ​​wine, fashion, health food and other sectors increased by 30% compared with the previous session. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meeting the people’s growing needs for a better life is the starting point and foothold of high-quality development. With the help of the CIIE platform, more and more new products, new technologies, and new services have entered the Chinese market, enriching the choices of domestic consumers and helping to meet new demands for quality life. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Crystal cups from the Czech Republic, unicorn fruits from Ecuador, &quot;sweet bread&quot; pineapples from Benin, handicrafts from Bangladesh... Many special products at the CIIE attract people to &quot;check in&quot; for the experience. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On the first day of the CIIE, Pinduoduo held a special live broadcast to bring goods. &quot;Pinduoduo is a beneficiary of the &#39;CIIE Effect&#39; and an amplifier of the &#39;CIIE Effect&#39;. Through live broadcasts, we hope that more consumers will feel the atmosphere of the CIIE and buy the same good things as the CIIE without leaving home. Click here Brighten a better life.&quot; Hou Kaidi, Vice President of Pinduoduo, said that in the past five years, Pinduoduo has relied on the China International Import Expo and other events to attract hundreds of thousands of high-quality overseas merchants to further meet consumers&#39; diversified and quality shopping needs. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At this year’s CIIE, New Zealand’s a2 Milk Company, an old friend of the CIIE, released a new series of infant formula milk powder products, attracting many consumers to learn about it on the spot. &quot;The CIIE has established a platform for global dairy industry peers to work together and stimulate new vitality in the industry&#39;s innovation and development. Keeping up with changes in consumer demand and complying with the trend of consumption upgrades, we will continue to increase investment in scientific research, vigorously promote the high-quality development of the dairy industry, and Bringing more nutritious, healthy and high-quality dairy products to consumers,&quot; said Li Xiao, the person in charge of a2 Milk Company. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the in-depth implementation of the Healthy China strategy, people’s health needs have become more diverse, bringing market opportunities to more companies. &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;全自动细胞工作站、主动式航空温控集装箱、生物制药场景整体解决方案……在医疗器械及医药保健展区，盈康一生向消费者展示了重要数智场景和20余项创新成果。 “通过进博会大舞台，我们继续加大科技创新，推出更多优质的健康产品和服务，更好满足人们对高品质医疗卫生服务的需求。”盈康一生相关负责人龚雯雯说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;进博会上，跨国消费健康企业赫力昂带来多款全球首发和中国首发产品。 “我们将携手合作伙伴，共享优质资源，深化科技创新，推出更多个性化的健康解决方案。”赫力昂相关负责人顾海英说。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;进博会“6天+365天”常年展示交易平台发展至今，已经拓展至60家，让消费者不出国门就能体验到全球好货，让更多高品质供给助力高品质生活。 &lt;/p>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 何立峰在香港国际金融领袖投资峰会上发表视频致辞]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/08/nw.D110000renmrb_20231108_1-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月08日星期三&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;新华社香港11月7日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;香港国际金融领袖投资峰会6—8日在香港举行，中共中央政治局委员、国务院副总理何立峰发表视频致辞。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;何立峰指出，习近平主席高度重视香港发展。中央政府完全支持香港长期保持独特地位和优势，巩固国际金融、航运、贸易中心地位。回归祖国以来，香港金融业国际竞争力和全球影响力日益展现出强大韧性与活力，国际金融中心地位更加稳固，对国家发展作出了重要而独特的贡献。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;何立峰强调，中国共产党第二十次全国代表大会擘画了全面建设社会主义现代化国家的宏伟蓝图，描绘了香港长期繁荣稳定的美好未来。希望香港充分发挥优势和特点，着力加强自身建设，主动适应市场变化，继续保持国际化特色，巩固提升在国际金融领域地位，深化同各国各地区更加开放、更加密切的交往合作，更好融入国家发展大局，在以中国式现代化全面推进中华民族伟大复兴的历史进程中作出更大贡献。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;何立峰指出，刚刚结束的中央金融工作会议强调，要巩固提升香港国际金融中心地位。这既是中央政府对香港国际金融中心地位的高度肯定，也是对香港开创金融高质量发展新局面、实现新飞跃寄予的厚望。希望香港金融界抓住机遇，开拓进取，推动香港国际金融中心不断迈上新台阶。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 坚持和发展新时代“枫桥经验”  提升矛盾纠纷预防化解法治化水平]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/08/nw.D110000renmrb_20231108_2-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月08日星期三&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报北京11月7日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者亓玉昆）纪念毛泽东同志批示学习推广“枫桥经验”60周年暨习近平总书记指示坚持发展“枫桥经验”20周年大会6日在京召开。中共中央政治局委员、中央政法委书记陈文清在会上强调，要坚持以习近平新时代中国特色社会主义思想为指导，全面贯彻习近平法治思想，坚持和发展新时代“枫桥经验”，提升矛盾纠纷预防化解法治化水平，为强国建设、民族复兴伟业创造更加安全稳定的社会环境。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;陈文清指出，习近平总书记亲切会见了全国“枫桥式工作法”入选单位代表，充分体现了以习近平同志为核心的党中央对坚持和发展新时代“枫桥经验”的高度重视，对奋战在基层一线同志们的亲切关怀和殷切期望。要把习近平总书记的亲切关怀转化为坚持和发展新时代“枫桥经验”的强大动力，更好地肩负起党和人民赋予的职责使命。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;陈文清强调，要牢牢把握新时代“枫桥经验”的科学内涵和实践要求，坚持和贯彻党的群众路线，依靠基层组织和广大群众，立足于预防、调解、法治、基层，做到预防在前、调解优先、运用法治、就地解决，实现“小事不出村、大事不出镇、矛盾不上交”。要发挥党的领导政治优势，从健全制度、落实责任、搭建平台、科技支撑入手，不断开创工作新局面。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;王小洪主持大会，吴政隆、张军、应勇出席。&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 国务院二〇二三年度省级政府安全生产和消防工作考核巡查启动]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/08/nw.D110000renmrb_20231108_3-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月08日星期三&lt;/div>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;本报北京11月7日电&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;（记者刘温馨）记者从应急管理部获悉：国务院2023年度省级政府安全生产和消防工作考核巡查近日启动。由国务院安委会有关成员单位负责人带队的20个考核巡查组陆续进驻31个省级政府和新疆生产建设兵团，对2023年度安全生产和消防工作开展考核巡查。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;据了解，此次考核巡查自11月初开始，到11月底结束，是党的二十大后首次组织实施，也是首次与地方党政领导班子和领导干部高质量发展政绩考核衔接，对于推动各方面更好统筹发展和安全具有重要意义。考核巡查工作将聚焦习近平总书记重要指示批示精神和党中央国务院决策部署学习贯彻情况、安全生产责任落实情况、重大事故隐患专项排查整治2023行动和全国城镇燃气安全专项整治等重大专项行动组织实施情况、基层末梢抓工作落实情况等，全面客观检验安全生产和消防工作实效，督促推动各级党委政府和有关部门压紧压实责任，坚持问题导向，突出重点环节，采取切实有效措施，着力补短板、强弱项，坚决防范遏制重特大事故，以高水平安全服务高质量发展，以新安全格局保障新发展格局。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;据介绍，考核巡查组将综合运用听取汇报、调阅材料、个别谈话、走访问询、受理举报、实地检查等方式开展工作，并延伸考核巡查2个市级政府，在全省（区、市）范围内开展明查暗访。此外，进驻期间，各考核巡查组将通过分省设立举报电话、电子邮箱和信访邮箱等方式接收来电来信和网络举报，坚持严的基调，切实推动解决人民群众关心关注的安全生产和消防问题，坚决查处安全生产和消防安全重大问题隐患，精准高效务实完成考核巡查工作。 &lt;/P>;&lt;P>;根据有关工作安排，在完成省级政府考核巡查后，还将陆续对39个国务院安委会成员单位开展安全生产工作考核。 &lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;Get more RSS:&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https:// feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[02版要闻 - 图片报道]]></title><link/><![CDATA[http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/html/2023-11/08/nw.D110000renmrb_20231108_4-02.htm]]><description> &lt;div>;2023年11月08日星期三&lt;/div>; &lt;TABLE width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;TBODY>;&lt;TR>;&lt;TD align=&quot;center&quot;>;&lt;IMG width=&quot;100%&quot; src=&quot;http://paper.people.com.cn/rmrb/images/1/20231108/1699387732781_1.jpg&quot;>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>; &lt;TR>;&lt;TD>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;/TD>;&lt;/TR>;&lt;/TBODY>;&lt;/TABLE>; &lt;!--enpcontent-->;&lt;P>;11月7日，甘肃省张掖市湿地公园风光旖旎，秀美如画。近年来，当地践行绿水青山就是金山银山理念，持续推进生态保护修复，天更蓝、水更清、山更绿，环境更优美。&lt;/P>;&lt;P>;王子豪摄（影像中国）&lt;/P>;&lt;!--/enpcontent-->; &lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Wed, 08 Nov 2023 05:56:05 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>