<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>路透社</title><description>路透社全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://reuters.com <item><title><![CDATA[OAS names mediators for Guatemala conflict that threatens transfer of power]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/guatemala-politics/oas-names-mediators-for-guatemala-conflict-that-threatens-transfer-of-power-idUSKBN31701R]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07T22:45:29Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;美洲国家组织 (OAS) 于周六任命了代表，将领导其在危地马拉官员和根据社交媒体网站 X 上发布的声明，街头抗议者寻求将权力有序移交给当选总统贝尔纳多·阿雷瓦洛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美洲国家组织负责人路易斯·阿尔马格罗此前于周五晚些时候表示，他接受了危地马拉政府的邀请要求在国家“不同部门之间达成共识”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌拉圭前国防部长路易斯·罗萨迪拉和美洲国家组织权利与公平部长马里卡门·普拉塔将率领此次访问。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;周六发布的文件称，“上述代表团将寻求与该国社会和政治局势的主要参与者会面，并提出具体建议。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这些建议将它补充说，其目的是让危地马拉政府“采取紧急政治决定，从而有效解决目前正在发展的社会抗议的主题问题”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;本周前往&lt;a href=&quot;/world/americas/guatemala-protests-intensify-demanding-prosecutor-resignations-2023-10-05/&quot;>;危地马拉街头&lt;/a>;，要求被指控工作的强大高级检察官辞职破坏阿雷瓦洛上任的能力。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;罗萨迪拉和普拉塔将“尽早”前往危地马拉城，美洲国家组织驻危地马拉办事处代表迭戈·帕斯 (Diego Paz) 也将与他们一起前往危地马拉城。阿雷瓦洛于 8 月以压倒性优势当选，但自那以后，总检察长康苏埃洛·波拉斯加大了力度，取消阿雷瓦洛的反腐败塞米拉运动党的资格，并下令突击搜查选举当局的办公室，夺取选票。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;波拉斯办公室声称六年前该党的注册存在违法行为，但她的调查是在阿雷瓦洛在六月的第一轮投票中出人意料地获得第二名之后才启动的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;司法部长被美国政府指控腐败。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周末期间，抗议活动已蔓延至中美洲人口最多国家的 60 多个地点，由土著团体、学生、教师和民众领导。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;作为过渡进程所采取步骤的一部分，危地马拉政府周六表示，它为民选当局团队设立了办公室，以“了解不同的机构并促进团队之间的沟通过程。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h2>;相关图库：&lt;/h2>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PJT2WNIKORJE7HXED6YB52Q6BQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;在危地马拉危地马拉城，人们游行要求有权势的高级检察官辞职，这些检察官被指控破坏当选总统贝尔纳多·阿雷瓦洛的就职能力2023 年 10 月 7 日。REUTERS/Josue Decavele&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/4AAALVN4LROABN356G4AXMTIUQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;在危地马拉危地马拉城，人们参加抗议活动，要求有权有势的高级检察官辞职，这些检察官被指控破坏当选总统贝尔纳多·阿雷瓦洛的就职能力2023 年 10 月 7 日。REUTERS/Josue Decavele&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YGPOLYYNJJKQJOVLU3P5JGSA5U.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;在危地马拉危地马拉城，人们参加抗议活动，要求有权有势的高级检察官辞职，这些检察官被指控破坏当选总统贝尔纳多·阿雷瓦洛的就职能力2023 年 10 月 7 日。REUTERS/Josue Decavele&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/P2IVJTSXVPMHH7554IAXD46HU.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;一名示威者在公共部大楼被封锁期间举起危地马拉国旗，要求被指控破坏当选总统贝尔纳多·阿雷瓦洛的强大高级检察官辞职2023 年 10 月 6 日在危地马拉危地马拉城就职。REUTERS/Josue Decavele/档案照片&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 06:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Aisha Wahab: author of vetoed California bill to ban caste discrimination]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/usa-caste-discrimination-senator/aisha-wahab-author-of-vetoed-california-bill-to-ban-caste-discrimination-idUSKBN3170J7]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07T21:54:46Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;州参议员 Aisha Wahab 撰写&lt;a href=&quot;https://reut.rs/3F5TEcv&quot; target=&quot;_blank &quot;>;该法案被州长加文·纽瑟姆 (Gavin Newsom) 否决，&lt;/a>; 该法案将使加州成为美国第一个明确禁止种姓歧视的州。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;瓦哈卜 (Wahab) 称该法案是“保护人们免受长期种姓歧视”的一种方式。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在否决该法案时，纽瑟姆称其“没有必要”，他认为，由于现有法律已经禁止血统歧视，因此不需要明确针对种姓歧视制定单独的立法。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;瓦哈卜于 2022 年当选加州参议员，据她的网站称，她将自己定位为一名立法者，旨在减少经济不平等并加强老年人、妇女、儿童和工薪家庭的安全网。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;瓦哈卜本人在年轻时就失去了父母，因此被安置在寄养家庭。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她于 2018 年当选海沃德市议会议员，使瓦哈卜成为第一位当选美国公职的阿富汗裔美国女性&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;虽然瓦哈卜的禁止种姓歧视法案赢得了多个人权组织的支持并获得通过，但她遭到了那些认为该法案会侮辱整个少数群体（主要是南亚人）的人的强烈反对。和印度教徒 - 在美国。纽瑟姆的否决标志着她和美国反种姓歧视活动人士的挫折。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://reut.rs/3Z9yjXE&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;种姓制度&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; a>; 是世界上最古老的严格社会分层形式之一。它可以追溯到几千年前，允许上层种姓享有许多特权，但压制下层种姓。达利特社区处于印度教种姓制度的最低层。成员被视为“贱民”。印度在 70 多年前就宣布种姓歧视为非法。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个问题对于印度裔美国人和印度教徒来说尤为重要，尤其是随着多年来越来越多的印度人和其他南亚人移居美国，尤其是加利福尼亚州以及该州的硅谷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国歧视法禁止血统歧视，但没有明确禁止种姓歧视。瓦哈卜的法案在加州获得通过，纽瑟姆否决了这一法案，该法案将种姓作为受保护阶级添加到该州现有的反歧视法中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;反对种姓歧视的活动人士表示，种姓歧视与种族主义等其他形式的歧视没有什么不同。加州该法案的反对者表示，由于美国法律已经禁止血统歧视，此类立法只会对整个社区造成大范围的污名化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;瓦哈布表示，她在提出该法案后就面临着威胁。法案，将其视为扩大实现美国梦的机会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“该法案涉及工人权利、妇女权利和公民权利。该法案旨在确保所有人都能实现美国梦那些追求它的人，”她在她的网站上谈到该法案时说道。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[California bill veto is setback in North American fight against caste discrimination]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/usa-caste-discrimination-recent-steps/factbox-california-bill-veto-is-setback-in-north-american-fight-against-caste-discrimination-idUSKBN3170JI]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07T22:12:56Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;周六加利福尼亚州州长加文·纽瑟姆&lt;a href=&quot;https://reut.rs/3F5TEcv&quot; target=&quot; _blank&quot;>;否决了州立法者最近通过的一项明确禁止种姓歧视的法案，理由是现有法律已经禁止血统歧视，这使得该法案“没有必要”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纽瑟姆的否决标志着罕见的但今年在北美势头强劲的反种姓歧视运动却遭遇了相应的挫折。如果该法案签署成为法律，加利福尼亚州将成为美国第一个明确禁止种姓歧视的州。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个问题对于南亚侨民，特别是印度和印度教社区来说很重要。种姓制度是世界上最古老的严格社会分层形式之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以下是北美各地最近为打击种姓歧视而采取的政策措施的一些示例：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2 月，西雅图成为&lt;a href=&quot;https://reut.rs/3EzHh8a&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;美国第一个禁止种姓歧视的城市&lt;/a>;，当地议会投票决定将种姓纳入该市的反歧视法。&lt;/a>; p>;&lt;p>;三月份，多伦多学校董事会成为&lt;a href=&quot;https://reut.rs/3FdHtuC&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;加拿大第一个&lt;/a>;承认该市存在种姓歧视的学校董事会学校，并要求省级人权机构帮助建立解决该问题的框架。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;9 月，加利福尼亚州弗雷斯诺成为&lt;a href=&quot;https://reut.rs/46xjSAs&quot; 目标=&quot;_blank&quot;>;美国第二座城市&lt;/a>;在市议会一致投票后禁止种姓歧视。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;去年，加州州立大学成为美国第一所将种姓列为受保护的大学系统其反歧视政策类别。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022 年末，布朗大学成为&lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/3PcmJaR&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;第一所常春藤盟校&lt;/ a>; 在将种姓纳入其非歧视政策时，增加官方的种姓保护。哈佛大学随后将种姓作为受保护阶层纳入其非歧视和反骚扰政策。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加州禁止种姓歧视的法案&lt;a href=&quot;https://reut.rs/3qQD3G4&quot; target= “_blank&quot;>;由阿富汗裔美国人、民主党州参议员艾莎·瓦哈布于三月提出&lt;/a>;并撰写。其早期版本在进行修订之前已通过州参议院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;修订后的版本已于 &lt;a href=&quot;https://reut.rs/3Rh2gEs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; 获得加利福尼亚州议会通过>;8 月底&lt;/a>;，州参议院于 9 月初以几乎一致的投票结果通过了该法案，之后该法案被纽瑟姆否决。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 06:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[California governor vetoes bill to ban caste discrimination]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/usa-caste-discrimination/california-governor-vetoes-bill-to-ban-caste-discrimination-idUSKBN3170IS]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07T21:08:10Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CU2WFA5MOZLDNIX2SVSNVZKTM4。 jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;加利福尼亚州州长 Gavin Newsom 于 2023 年 5 月 2 日在美国加利福尼亚州比佛利山庄举行的 2023 年米尔肯研究所全球会议上发表讲话. REUTERS/Mike Blake/档案照片&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;周六加州州长加文·纽瑟姆&lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/3rEBrj7&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;否决了&lt;/a >; 州立法机关最近通过了一项禁止种姓歧视的法案，称不需要为此制定单独的立法，因为现有法律已经禁止血统歧视。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如果纽瑟姆签署该法案，加州将成为美国有史以来第一个明确禁止种姓歧视的州。纽瑟姆的否决对于一直倡导该立法的活动人士来说是一个巨大的挫折。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国的歧视法禁止血统歧视，尽管它们没有明确提及种姓。加州的立法针对南亚和印度教移民社区的种姓制度，将种姓作为受保护阶层添加到该州现有的反歧视法中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该法案&lt;a href=&quot;https://reut.rs /3qQD3G4&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;由阿富汗裔美国人、民主党州参议员艾莎·瓦哈卜 (Aisha Wahab) 于 3 月份提出&lt;/a>;并撰写。它的早期版本在进行修订之前已通过了州参议院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;修订后的版本将种姓列为“祖先”，而不是作为一个单独的类别，并于&lt;a href=&quot;获得了加利福尼亚州议会的通过。 https://reut.rs/3Rh2gEs&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;8 月下旬&lt;/a>;，并于 9 月初由州参议院几乎一致投票通过。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该法案将种姓定义为“种姓”反对种姓歧视的活动人士表示，种姓歧视与种族主义等其他形式的歧视没有什么不同，因此应该被取缔。加州该法案的反对者表示，由于美国法律已经禁止血统歧视，此类立法就变得毫无意义，只会对整个社区（主要是印度教徒和南亚人）造成污名化。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在纽瑟姆否决之前，北美反对种姓制度的运动近几个月来愈发活跃。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;今年早些时候，西雅图成为&lt;a href=&quot;https://reut.rs/3xGwHJ6 &quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;美国第一个在市议会投票后禁止种姓歧视的城市&lt;/a>;，多伦多学校董事会成为&lt;a href=&quot;https://reut.rs/3FdHtuC&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; >;加拿大第一个&lt;/a>;承认该市学校存在种姓歧视。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上个月，在加利福尼亚州，弗雷斯诺成为美国第二个城市&lt;a href=&quot;https://reut .rs/46q2JJ5&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;在市议会一致投票后禁止种姓歧视&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这个问题对于印度裔和印度教徒的美国人尤其重要。随着越来越多的印度人和南亚人移居美国，特别是加利福尼亚和硅谷，美国的一些&lt;a href=&quot;/business/sustainable-business/caste-california-tech-giants-confront-ancient-indian-hierarchy- 2022-08-15/&quot;>;最大的科技公司&lt;/a>;也不得不面对种姓歧视问题。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多美国科技公司也由印度裔领导人领导，例如Alphabet&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GOOGL.O&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(GOOGL.O)&lt;/a>; 微软首席执行官 Sundar Pichai &lt;a href=&quot;https:// www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MSFT.O&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(MSFT.O)&lt;/a>; 首席执行官 Satya Nadella 和 IBM &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets /companies/IBM.N&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(IBM.N)&lt;/a>; 首席执行官 Arvind Krishna。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://reut.rs/3Z9yjXE&quot; 目标=&quot;_blank&quot;>;种姓制度&lt;/a>;是世界上最古老的严格社会分层形式之一。它可以追溯到几千年前，允许上层种姓享有许多特权，但压制下层种姓。达利特社区处于印度教种姓制度的最低层。成员被视为“贱民”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度 70 多年前就宣布种姓歧视为非法，但近年来的多项研究表明，偏见仍然存在。 &lt;a href=&quot;https://bit.ly/3lYybf0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;一项研究&lt;/a>;发现，来自低种姓的人在高薪工作中所占比例不足。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;达利特人仍然面临着印度各地普遍存在虐待行为，他们向上社会流动的尝试有时会遭到暴力镇压。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;印度国内外关于种姓制度的争论充满争议，并与宗教交织在一起。有人说，现在歧视已经很少见了，尤其是在印度以外的地区。近年来，印度政府为印度顶尖大学的低种姓学生保留席位的政策帮助许多科技工作在西方落地。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 05:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US House“s Scalise, Jordan locked in two-way speaker race, for now]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/usa-congress-speaker/us-houses-scalise-jordan-locked-in-two-way-speaker-race-for-now-idUSKBN3170IU]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07T21:11:42Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;美国众议院第二号共和党人史蒂夫·斯卡利斯 (Steve Scalise) 和该党领袖吉姆·乔丹 (Jim Jordan)保守派正在两方&lt;a href=&quot;/world/us/republicans-scalise-jordan-trump-eye-us-house-speaker-role-2023-10-05/&quot;>;争夺众议院领导权&lt;/a>; 在凯文·麦卡锡 (Kevin McCarthy) 历史性地被罢黜后，选举也尚未尘埃落定。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;来自路易斯安那州的议员斯卡利斯 (Scalise) 采取了更传统的方式登上最高层 &lt;a href=&quot;/world /us/money-matters-republicans-scalise-jordan-vie-us-house-speaker-2023-10-06/&quot;>;通过筹集资金&lt;/a>;并在党内建立关系，而乔丹则在右翼煽动者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乔丹是前总统唐纳德·特朗普的主要捍卫者，而唐纳德·特朗普仍然是共和党的重要人物。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;特朗普是 2024 年共和党总统候选人的领跑者提名，&lt;a href=&quot;/world/us/trump-may-meet-with-house-republicans-leadership-race-us-media-2023-10-05/&quot;>;支持乔丹担任众议院议长&lt;/a>;星期五。但它能承载多少重量还有待观察。在 1 月份麦卡锡为议长木槌进行的旷日持久的争夺中，一些共和党人忽视了特朗普要求团结的呼吁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;截至周五，斯卡利斯和乔丹都从众议院 221 名共和党人中获得了大约二十打的支持。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;共和党人定于周三在闭门会议上选出领导人，不过他们可能需要一段时间才能确定候选人。保守派共和党研究委员会主席凯文·赫恩(Kevin Hern)预计也将参选，其他候选人仍可能浮出水面。众议员帕特里克·麦克亨利目前临时担任该职位。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;无论谁获胜，都必须谈判一项资金协议，以使政府在 11 月 17 日的最后期限之后保持开放，并监督对民主党总统乔·拜登的弹劾调查。说的是没有根据的。议长还必须决定是否支持更多的乌克兰援助，而许多普通共和党人反对这一点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;众议院全体投票选出议长。共和党在众议院以 221 比 212 占多数，如果反对党民主党团结一致，只能腾出四票。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;57 岁的斯卡利斯自 2014 年以来一直当选众议院领导职务，并被视为麦卡锡的继承人显而易见。去年，他是共和党的第二大筹款人，这可能有助于他竞选党魁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2017 年 6 月，一名在社交媒体上批评共和党的男子开枪射杀了斯卡利斯和其他议员，斯卡利斯身受重伤。当时他们正在为一场慈善棒球比赛进行练习。三个月后他回到众议院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;8 月，这位路易斯安那州议员宣布他正在寻求多发性骨髓瘤（一种血癌）的治疗。斯卡利斯于 9 月返回国会大厦，并表示自己的健康状况足以担任议长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;斯卡利斯因 2002 年作为州议员向一个与前库尔德有联系的白人至上主义组织发表的演讲而受到批评。三K党领袖大卫·杜克。斯卡利斯表示，他对这个错误感到遗憾。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;斯卡利斯的一名助手表示，自从宣布参选以来，他一直在“不间断”地与其他成员通电话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;斯卡利斯在选举中面临着一个强大的挑战者。约旦。来自俄亥俄州的议员乔丹担任众议院司法委员会主席，该委员会是拜登弹劾调查的三个核心小组之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他有很大的动力，但他显然仍然是失败者，”一位熟悉竞选的消息人士称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乔丹是特朗普努力破坏他在 2020 年大选中输给民主党人乔·拜登的努力的直言不讳的支持者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位前大学摔跤教练是特朗普的竞选团队之一。他是保守派众议院自由核心小组的创始人，过去曾与自己党内的成员发生过争执，最引人注目的是，他是一小群强硬派的一员，他们在 2015 年向共和党议长约翰·博纳施压，迫使其辞职。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; 59 岁的乔丹是党领导层的局外人。他在 2018 年的领导力挑战中输给了麦卡锡，但最终成为了亲密盟友。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乔丹教练的摔跤手在 2018 年表示，他知道队医在骚扰他们。他否认对此知情。&lt;/p>;&lt;h2>;相关图库：&lt;/h2>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/FC37NIDPG5KMBP4GKQHNBYYOJE.jpg &quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;美国众议院多数党领袖史蒂夫·斯卡利斯 (Steve Scalise) 于 2023 年 7 月 12 日在华盛顿国会山发表讲话。 REUTERS/Evelyn Hockstein/档案照片&lt;/small>; &lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SSNVV6NZRFPM3FKYXBIAUFVV6Y.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999 ;&quot;>;2023 年 9 月 28 日，俄亥俄州共和党众议员吉姆·乔丹 (Jim Jordan) 在华盛顿举行的美国总统乔·拜登弹劾调查听证会上发表讲话。REUTERS/Jim Bourg/档案照片&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr >;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt; br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 05:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel“s Netanyahu vows “mighty vengeance“ against Hamas]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/israel-palestinians-netanyahu/israels-netanyahu-vows-mighty-vengeance-against-hamas-idUSKBN3170HR]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07T19:35:15Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;在巴勒斯坦激进运动周六发动突然袭击后，以色列总理本杰明·内塔尼亚胡誓言对哈马斯进行“强力报复”，杀害了 150 多名以色列人并俘虏了大量俘虏。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在简短的视频讲话中，他表示哈马斯将对俘虏的福祉负责，并表示以色列将与任何伤害他们的人算账.&lt;/p>;&lt;h2>;相关图库：&lt;/h2>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/FKALUGCAWVOPVMZPFEAGEJ3D54.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt; div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;2023 年 7 月 5 日，以色列总理本杰明·内塔尼亚胡在以色列里雄莱锡安市附近的帕尔马希姆空军基地发表声明。REUTERS/Amir Cohen&lt;/small>;&lt; /div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/JCD7HSDT3RKEHNQSBJAQF5CKWQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999; &quot;>;2023 年 7 月 5 日，以色列总理本杰明·内塔尼亚胡坐在黑鹰直升机上访问以色列里雄莱锡安市附近的帕尔马希姆空军基地。REUTERS/Amir Cohen&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src= &quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/M7J2GM6S25MIBEZDELWEYSDRJI.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;以色列总理本杰明·内塔尼亚胡2023 年 7 月 5 日，他在参观以色列里雄莱锡安市附近的帕尔马希姆空军基地时散步。路透社/Amir Cohen&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 03:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Ecuador removes, investigates security officials after killings of suspects in candidate assassination]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/ecuador-violence/ecuador-removes-investigates-security-officials-after-killings-of-suspects-in-candidate-assassination-idUSKBN3170BU]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07T19:40:41Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/DYZCQDQXXFJNPNEE2A2TIQP6OY。 jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;厄瓜多尔总统候选人费尔南多·比亚维森西奥 (Fernando Villavicencio) 于 2023 年 8 月 9 日在厄瓜多尔基多举行的竞选集会上发表讲话。 REUTERS/Karen Toro/档案照片&lt;/小>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;厄瓜多尔总统吉列尔莫·拉索周六宣布，在七名被控谋杀总统候选人费尔南多·比亚维森西奥的囚犯被杀害后，两名官员、监狱长和警察调查部门负责人被免职。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周五，六名囚犯在滨海监狱被杀，周六，另一名囚犯在基多监狱被杀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一名监狱官员负责这六名囚犯所在的监狱。根据总统的声明，被杀者已被拘留接受审讯。拉索还下令转移与比亚维森西奥谋杀案有关的六名囚犯，以确保他们的安全。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;近年来，厄瓜多尔的暴力事件急剧增加，政府将其归咎于贩毒团伙，最近的杀戮似乎凸显了违法行为的加剧.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;厄瓜多尔总检察长办公室周六早些时候表示，该办公室还对该国监狱机构展开了调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;检察官表示，他们发起调查是因为该机构 SNAI 没有出于安全原因，执行一项待定命令，移交周五在滨海监狱被杀的六名囚犯。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;比亚维森西奥 (Villavicencio) 是一位揭露腐败和有组织犯罪的著名记者，他在 8 月离开一场竞选活动时被枪杀。警方当天逮捕了六人，并杀死了一名嫌疑人。另外七名嫌疑人后来被捕。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拉索的官方社交媒体账户称，周六他正在与安全内阁开会，并取消了即将前往韩国的旅行，以“解决监狱系统的危机”。政府此前曾承诺查明谋杀比亚维森西奥的知识分子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;比亚维森西奥的职业生涯建立在揭露政治家和商界领袖的腐败之上，在他去世之前，他曾谴责阿尔巴尼亚黑手党和洛斯乔内罗斯的领导人内政部长周五表示，警方对比亚维森西奥被杀事件的调查报告已经准备就绪。该报告尚未公开。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;第二轮决选将于 10 月 15 日举行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两位候选人，商业继承人丹尼尔·诺博亚 (Daniel Noboa)，在民意调查中以微弱优势领先，政治分析师阿尔弗雷多·埃斯皮诺萨 (Alfredo Espinosa) 表示，嫌疑人被杀不太可能影响第二轮投票意向。然而，埃斯皮诺萨说，明确谁对比亚维森西奥的谋杀案负责，尤其是如果发现一名政客参与其中，可能会导致“该国的伦理​​和道德动摇”。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 03:55:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel vows “mighty vengeance“ after deadliest day for 50 years]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/israel-palestinians/israel-vows-mighty-vengeance-after-deadliest-day-for-50-years-idUSKBN31701K]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07T19:52:57Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;视频控件 src=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;周六（10 月 7 日），巴勒斯坦伊斯兰组织哈马斯发动突然袭击，枪手越境进入以色列，并从加沙发射了一连串火箭弹，随后发生爆炸震动加沙地带，烟雾和灰尘遍布整个城市。&lt;/small>; &lt;/div>;&lt;p>;巴勒斯坦组织&lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/what-is-palestinian-group-hamas-2023-10-07/&quot;>;哈马斯&lt;/a>;的枪手在以色列境内横行周六，以色列发生了 50 年前赎罪日战争以来最严重的暴力事件，造成 200 多人死亡，人质逃离。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以色列以这是其报复性袭击最具破坏性的日子之一。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总理本杰明·内塔尼亚胡表示：“我们将为这个黑色的日子进行强有力的报复。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“哈马斯发动了一场残酷而邪恶的战争“我们将赢得这场战争，但代价太沉重，难以承受。” “哈马斯想要谋杀我们所有人。这是一个在家中、在床上谋杀母亲和儿童的敌人。一个绑架老人、儿童和少女的敌人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哈马斯领导人伊斯梅尔·哈尼亚 (Ismail Haniyeh) 说从加沙开始的袭击将蔓延到约旦河西岸和耶路撒冷。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是我们的敌人、其士兵和定居者遭受失败和羞辱的早晨，”他在一次演讲中说。 “发生的事情揭示了我们准备工作的伟大。今天发生的事情揭示了敌人的弱点。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/gunmen-homes-captives-abducted-gaza- left-israelis-shock-2023-10-07/&quot;>;以色列平民的尸体遍布以色列南部加沙附近斯德洛特的街道上，周围都是碎玻璃。一女一男的尸体躺在汽车的前座上。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我走出去，看到大量恐怖分子、平民的尸体，汽车被炸毁。里面是尸体的海洋。”斯德洛特沿路以及其他地方，都有大量尸体，”来自斯德洛特的什洛米说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;惊恐的以色列人被困在安全室里，通过电话在电视直播中讲述了他们的困境。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;”他们刚刚又进来了，请派人帮忙。”一位名叫多林（Dorin）的妇女在加沙附近的基布兹尼尔奥兹（Nir Oz）告诉以色列 N12 新闻。 “我丈夫把门关着......他们正在发射子弹。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;埃丝特·博罗乔夫(Esther Borochov)在一场遭到枪手袭击的狂欢舞会上逃离，她告诉路透社，她是在车里装死才得以幸存。司机试图帮助她逃跑后遭到近距离射击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我无法移动我的腿，”她在医院告诉路透社。 “士兵们来了，把我们带到了灌木丛中。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在加沙，以色列报复性袭击击中的一座高层塔楼冒出黑烟和橙色火焰，直冲夜空。成群结队的哀悼者抬着刚刚被杀的武装分子的尸体穿过街道，尸体裹着绿色的哈马斯旗帜。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加沙的死伤者被送往摇摇欲坠、人满为患的医院，医疗用品和设备严重短缺。卫生部表示，已有 232 人死亡，至少 1,700 人受伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;除了急速驶向空袭现场的救护车外，街道上空无一人。以色列切断电源，城市陷入黑暗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以美国为首的西方国家，&lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/world-reacts-surprise-attack-by-hamas -israel-2023-10-07/&quot;>;谴责巴勒斯坦的袭击&lt;/a>;并承诺支持以色列。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;总统乔·拜登在白宫表示，以色列有权“全面保卫自己”停止”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们永远不会让她回来。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;整个中东地区爆发了支持哈马斯的示威活动，以色列和美国国旗被点燃，游行者在伊拉克、黎巴嫩、叙利亚和也门挥舞着巴勒斯坦国旗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哈马斯的袭击受到伊朗和伊朗的黎巴嫩盟友真主党的公开赞扬。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六夜幕降临时，以色列南部，居民们还没有得到警报，可以离开他们从凌晨起就躲藏起来的避难所。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“事情还没有结束，因为（军队）还没有说基布兹已经安全了”恐怖分子”，丹尼·拉哈明（Dani Rahamim）在避难所通过电话告诉路透社，他当时仍然躲在纳哈尔奥兹（Nahal Oz）靠近加沙围栏的避难所。枪声已经平息，但仍能听到定期爆炸声。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哈马斯表示，周六晚上，它向特拉维夫发射了 150 枚火箭弹，以报复以色列的空袭，该空袭摧毁了一栋高层建筑，造成更多人员伤亡。超过 100 间公寓。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哈马斯副首领萨利赫·阿鲁里 (Saleh al-Arouri) 告诉半岛电视台，该组织扣押了大量以色列俘虏，其中包括高级官员。他说，哈马斯有足够的俘虏，可以让以色列释放其监狱中的所有巴勒斯坦人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以色列军方证实，以色列人被关押在加沙。一名军方发言人表示，以色列可以动员多达数十万预备役人员，并做好在北部战线对抗黎巴嫩真主党组织的战争准备。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;主张摧毁以色列的哈马斯表示，这次袭击的原因是据称，这是以色列对约旦河西岸、耶路撒冷的巴勒斯坦人和以色列监狱中的巴勒斯坦人的升级袭击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这是结束地球上最后占领的最伟大战斗的一天，”哈马斯军事指挥官穆罕默德戴伊夫在哈马斯媒体广播中宣布行动开始，并呼吁各地巴勒斯坦人进行战斗。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;自武装分子夺取加沙控制权以来，加沙已因哈马斯和以色列之间的四场战争和无数小冲突而遭受破坏。 2007 年，以色列境内的暴力场面是前所未有的，甚至在过去几十年的巴勒斯坦起义最激烈的时期也是如此。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以色列完全措手不及，这被人们感叹为这是历史上最严重的情报失误，这对一个自诩对武装分子进行密集渗透和监控的国家来说是一个震惊。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在加沙地带，230 万巴勒斯坦人在以色列的封锁下生活了 16 年居民们因担心未来几天的战争而争先恐后地购买物资。 Some evacuated their homes and headed for shelters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Scores of Palestinians were killed and hundreds wounded in clashes at the border into Israel, where fighters captured the crossing point and tore down fences. Some of those dead were civilians, among crowds that attempted to cross into Israel through the damaged gates.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;We are afraid,&quot; a Palestinian woman, Amal Abu Daqqa, told Reuters as she left her house in Khan Younis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The escalation comes against a backdrop of surging violence between Israel and Palestinian militants in the Israeli occupied West Bank, where a Palestinian authority exercises limited self-rule, opposed by Hamas that wants Israel destroyed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the West Bank, there were clashes in several locations on Saturday, with stone throwing youths confronting Israeli troops.包括一名 13 岁男孩在内的四名巴勒斯坦人被杀。 Palestinian factions called a general strike for Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Israel itself has been experiencing internal political upheaval, with the most right-wing government in its history attempting to overhaul the judiciary.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, Washington has been trying to strike a deal that would &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/islamic-jihad-chief-denounces-normalisation-talks-with-israel-2023-10-06/&quot;>;normalise ties&lt;/a>; between Israel and Saudi Arabia, seen by Israelis as the biggest prize yet in their decades-long for Arab recognition. Palestinians fear any such deal could sell out their future dreams of an independent state.&lt;/p>;&lt;h2>;Related Galleries:&lt;/h2>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/53YHMG3OUBJVNGMUKU4TLRANWQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Rockets are fired towards Israel from the northern Gaza Strip, as seen from Ashkelon, southern Israel October 7, 2023. REUTERS/Amir Cohen&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/XMW475TJQVCH7N5F4T3E7WQRHE.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;A view of an ambulance hit by an Israeli strike, after Hamas gunmen launched a surprise attack against Israel, in the southern Gaza Strip, October 7, 2023. REUTERS/Ibraheem Abu Mustafa - RC2NN3AC3OAB&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/I6Y6L7PHUJFNNDRS2C36B5G5IU.JPG&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Palestinians break into the Israeli side of Israel-Gaza border fence after gunmen infiltrated areas of southern Israel, October 7, 2023. REUTERS/Mohammed Fayq Abu Mostafa NO RESALES.没有档案。 TPX IMAGES OF THE DAY&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/R5JRCLQP6FKQDKITX6RW5G5L5Y.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Smoke and flames billow after Israeli forces struck a high-rise tower in Gaza City, October 7, 2023. REUTERS/Mohammed Salem&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/FQ2JMPM4DFNJBO34A4ME5WANKY.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Israeli soldiers stand near a vehicle with the dead body of a man who was killed following a mass-infiltration by Hamas gunmen from the Gaza Strip, in Sderot, southern Israel October 7. REUTERS/Ammar Awad&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PAMY5OOLE5JDFCWFJZHKDTYURQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Rockets are fired by Palestinian militants into Israel, in Gaza City October 7. REUTERS/Mohammed Salem&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2L5PS52D4RM3JMD5PCS5IJ5QLE.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;A man wearing a Jewish prayer shawl looks out of the damaged entrance way to a building, as rockets are launched from the Gaza Strip, in Ashkelon, southern Israel October 7. REUTERS/Ammar Awad&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YMFECLDX4ZMBZPERCWPMM6IFCQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;A man runs on a road as fire burns after rockets were launched from the Gaza Strip, in Ashkelon, Israel October 7. REUTERS/Amir Cohen&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 03:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“Sea of bodies“ in Israel, scores dead in Gaza as shock Hamas attack unleashes war]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/israel-palestinians/sea-of-bodies-in-israel-scores-dead-in-gaza-as-shock-hamas-attack-unleashes-war-idUSKBN31701K]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07T18:33:09Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;video controls src=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Palestinian Islamist group Hamas launched the biggest attack on Israel in years on Saturday, killing more than 20 people and wounding hundreds in a surprise assault that combined gunmen crossing into Israel with a barrage of rockets fired from Gaza. This report contains graphic images. Lucy Fielder has more.&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Gunmen from the Palestinian group &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/what-is-palestinian-group-hamas-2023-10-07/&quot;>;Hamas&lt;/a>; rampaged through Israeli towns on Saturday killing and capturing scores of civilians and soldiers in a surprise assault, met by Israel with massive retaliatory air strikes that killed scores in the Gaza Strip.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The worst attack on Israel for decades unleashed a war that both sides vowed to escalate.据报道，以色列境内 20 多个地点发生的枪战至少造成 200 名以色列人死亡、1,100 人受伤。 In Gaza, health officials reported more than 230 people killed and 1,600 wounded.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Our enemy will pay a price the type of which it has never known,&quot; Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu said. &quot;We are in a war and we will win it&quot;.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hamas leader Ismail Haniyeh said the assault that had begun in Gaza would spread to the West Bank and Jerusalem.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;This was the morning of defeat and humiliation upon our enemy, its soldiers and its settlers,&quot; he said in a speech. &quot;What happened reveals the greatness of our preparation. What happened today reveals the weakness of the enemy.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Sderot, in southern Israel near Gaza, &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/gunmen-homes-captives-abducted-gaza-leave-israelis-shock-2023-10-07/&quot;>;bodies of Israeli civilians&lt;/a>; lay strewn across a highway, surrounded by broken glass.一名女子和一名男子四肢摊开，倒在汽车前座上，死亡。 A military vehicle drove past the bodies of another woman and a man in a pool of blood behind another car.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;I went out, I saw loads of bodies of terrorists, civilians, cars shot up. A sea of bodies, inside Sderot along the road, other places, loads of bodies,&quot; said Shlomi from Sderot.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Terrified Israelis, barricaded into safe rooms, recounted their plight by phone on live TV.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;They just came in again, please send help,&quot; a woman identified as Dorin told Israel&#39;s N12 News from Nir Oz, a kibbutz near Gaza. &quot;My husband is holding the door closed ... They are firing rounds of bullets.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Esther Borochov, who fled a dance rave party attacked by the gunmen, told Reuters she survived by playing dead in a car after the driver trying to help her escape was shot point blank.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;I couldn&#39;t move my legs,&quot; she told Reuters at the hospital. &quot;Soldiers came and took us away to the bushes.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Gaza, black smoke and orange flames billowed into the evening sky from a high rise tower hit by an Israeli retaliatory strike. Crowds of mourners carried the bodies of freshly killed militants through the streets, wrapped in green Hamas flags.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gaza&#39;s dead and wounded were carried into crumbling and overcrowded hospitals with severe shortages of medical supplies and equipment. The health ministry said 232 people had been killed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Streets were deserted apart from ambulances racing to the scenes of air strikes. Israel cut the power, plunging the city into darkness.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;By nightfall on Saturday in southern Israel, residents had yet to be given the all-clear to leave the shelters where they had hidden from the gunmen since the early hours.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;It&#39;s not over because the (army) hasn&#39;t said the kibbutz is clear of terrorists,&quot; Dani Rahamim told Reuters by telephone from the shelter where he was still hiding in Nahal Oz, close to the Gaza fence. Gunfire had subsided but regular explosions could still be heard.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hamas said it fired a volley of 150 rockets towards Tel Aviv on Saturday evening in retaliation for an Israeli air strike that took down a high rise building with more than 100 apartments.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hamas deputy chief Saleh al-Arouri told Al Jazeera that the group was holding a big number of Israeli captives, including senior officials. He said Hamas had enough captives to make Israel free all Palestinians in its jails.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Israeli military confirmed Israelis were being held in Gaza. A military spokesman said Israel could mobilise up to hundreds of thousands of reservists and was also prepared for war on its northern front against Lebanon&#39;s Hezbollah group.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hamas, which advocates Israel&#39;s destruction, said the attack was driven by what it said were Israel&#39;s escalated attacks on Palestinians in the West Bank, Jerusalem and against Palestinians in Israeli prisons.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;This is the day of the greatest battle to end the last occupation on earth,&quot; Hamas military commander Mohammad Deif said, announcing the start of the operation in a broadcast on Hamas media and calling on Palestinians everywhere to fight.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hamas has since fought four wars against Israel since seizing control of Gaza in 2007. But the scenes of violence inside Israel itself were unlike anything seen since the suicide bombings of the Palestinian Intifada uprising two decades ago.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;That Israel was caught completely off guard was lamented as one of the worst intelligence failures in its history, a shock to a nation that boasts of its intensive infiltration and monitoring of militants.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Gaza, a narrow strip where 2.3 million Palestinians have lived under an Israeli blockade for 16 years, residents rushed to buy supplies in anticipation of days of war ahead. Some evacuated their homes and headed for shelters.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Scores of Palestinians were killed and hundreds wounded in clashes at the border into Israel, where fighters captured the crossing point and tore down fences. Some of those dead were civilians, among crowds that attempted to cross into Israel through the damaged gates.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;We are afraid,&quot; Palestinian woman, Amal Abu Daqqa, told Reuters as she left her house in Khan Younis.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Western countries, led by the United States, &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/world-reacts-surprise-attack-by-hamas-israel-2023-10-07/&quot;>;denounced the Palestinian attack&lt;/a>; and pledged support for Israel.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;I made clear to Prime Minister Netanyahu that we stand ready to offer all appropriate means of support to the Government and people of Israel,&quot; US President Joe Biden said in a statement issued after the two men spoke on a call.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Israel has a right to defend itself and its people. The United States warns against any other party hostile to Israel seeking advantage in this situation,&quot; Biden added.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Across the Middle East, there were demonstrations in support of Hamas, with Israeli and US flags set on fire and marchers waving Palestinian flags in Iraq, Lebanon, Syria and Yemen.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Hamas attack was openly praised by Iran and by Hezbollah, Iran&#39;s Lebanese allies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;UN Middle East peace envoy Tor Wennesland condemned the attacks on Israel, warning in a statement: &quot;This is a dangerous precipice, and I appeal to all to pull back from the brink.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The escalation comes against a backdrop of surging violence between Israel and Palestinian militants in the Israeli occupied West Bank, where a Palestinian authority exercises limited self-rule, opposed by Hamas that wants Israel destroyed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the West Bank, there were clashes in several locations on Saturday, with stone throwing youths confronting Israeli troops.包括一名 13 岁男孩在内的四名巴勒斯坦人被杀。 Palestinian factions called a general strike for Sunday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Israel itself has been experiencing internal political upheaval, with the most right-wing government in its history attempting to overhaul the judiciary.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meanwhile, Washington has been trying to strike a deal that would &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/islamic-jihad-chief-denounces-normalisation-talks-with-israel-2023-10-06/&quot;>;normalise ties&lt;/a>; between Israel and Saudi Arabia, seen by Israelis as the biggest prize yet in their decades-long for Arab recognition. Palestinians fear any such deal could sell out their future dreams of an independent state.&lt;/p>;&lt;h2>;Related Galleries:&lt;/h2>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/HGLKYIX33ZPJVM5FP3CLBKNQ5Y.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Smoke and flames billow after Israeli forces struck a high-rise tower in Gaza City, October 7, 2023. REUTERS/Mohammed Salem&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/OHFKGCVG6FJWZJZAAJ34IWMMPM.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;A rocket is fired from Gaza toward Israel, in Gaza, October 7, 2023. REUTERS/Ibraheem Abu Mustafa&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/5GD327P2CVP33EDHZUA7YKLTAA.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Smoke rises following Israeli strikes in Gaza, October 7, 2023. REUTERS/Mohammed Salem&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/M4PH2XIBEJOEHFMZK3T7B5ZHFQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Smoke rises from the Israeli side after Palestinian Hamas gunmen infiltrated areas of southern Israel, as seen from Gaza, October 7, 2023. REUTERS/Mohammed Salem&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YMFECLDX4ZMBZPERCWPMM6IFCQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;A man runs on a road as fire burns after rockets were launched from the Gaza Strip, in Ashkelon, Israel October 7, 2023. REUTERS/Amir Cohen&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/24BRTM4BWBN5BGKV44KVZDM62A.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;The body of a motorist lies on a road following a mass-infiltration by Hamas gunmen from the Gaza Strip, in Sderot, southern Israel October 7. REUTERS/Ammar Awad&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/QGBQCSS5FNKDZHDNHINHWHO3MU.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Israeli soldiers work to secure residential areas following a mass-infiltration by Hamas gunmen from the Gaza Strip, in Sderot, southern Israel October 7. REUTERS/Ammar Awad&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZYKDVV6DANLAPDMCKHKIJVFZDM.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Smoke rises following Israeli strikes in Gaza, October 7, 2023. REUTERS/Mohammed Salem&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/6CV7PVUGMVKQLK2BHBO573RFKQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Israeli police inspect a car that has a Palestinian licence plate on it, following a mass-infiltration by Hamas gunmen from the Gaza Strip, in Sderot, southern Israel October 7, 2023. REUTERS/Ammar Awad&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/GRQVMLLYCNIHPP3FDZFMH7I6TE.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Smoke is seen in the Rehovot area as rockets are launched from the Gaza Strip, in Israel October 7. REUTERS/Ilan Rosenberg&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/HTBBGH4QGFJETDP2JEJKAQ7ZMM.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Palestinian militants ride an Israeli military vehicle that was seized by gunmen who infiltrated areas of southern Israel, in the northern Gaza Strip October 7, 2023. REUTERS/Ahmed Zakot&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/H2CTYOL6DZLCNDYB7BR4QORGI4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Israel&#39;s Iron Dome anti-missile system intercepts rockets launched from the Gaza Strip, as seen from Ashkelon in southern Israel October 7, 2023. REUTERS/Ammar Awad&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CIPEUFXXDRILJL3F277WPF6PPA.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Israeli security personnel and members of the media take shelter as a siren sounds while rockets are launched from the Gaza Strip, in Mevaseret Zion, Israel October 7, 2023. REUTERS/Ronen Zvulun&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PAMY5OOLE5JDFCWFJZHKDTYURQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Rockets are fired by Palestinian militants into Israel, in Gaza City October 7. REUTERS/Mohammed Salem&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YCJNRONVINJ7JNXWLDLJ7RRXEQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;A building is ablaze following rocket attacks from the Gaza Strip, in Tel Aviv, Israel October 7. REUTERS/Itai Ron&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WTRVI5UGKVJAPFSRNP54RFD54Q.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Israelis take cover in a bomb shelter as rockets are launched from the Gaza Strip, in Rishon Lezion, Israel October 7, 2023. REUTERS/Hadas Parush &lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2L5PS52D4RM3JMD5PCS5IJ5QLE.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;A man wearing a Jewish prayer shawl looks out of the damaged entrance way to a building, as rockets are launched from the Gaza Strip, in Ashkelon, southern Israel October 7. REUTERS/Ammar Awad&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/FFWOOUCYZRP6VAKYLEEEPBZZEI.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;A Palestinian man takes a selfie in front of a burning Israeli military vehicle after it was hit by Palestinian gunmen who infiltrated areas of southern Israel, at the Israeli side of Israel-Gaza border, October 7, 2023. REUTERS/Yasser Qudih&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/SX2DW4GHXNNPVOPSDB4CLZ67SQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;An aerial view shows vehicles on fire as rockets are launched from the Gaza Strip, in Ashkelon, southern Israel October 7, 2023. REUTERS/Ilan Rosenberg&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/VDW6WUSOPZNAFMSG357E2TYIHA.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Israeli security personnel walk near the body of a dead man, as Hamas launches a surprise attack from the Gaza Strip, near Ashkelon, southern Israel October 7, 2023. REUTERS/Ammar Awad&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CBR4C3PRWRMHXJS3X23DS5BMM4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Palestinians react as an Israeli military vehicle burns after it was hit by Palestinian gunmen who infiltrated areas of southern Israel, at the Israeli side of Israel-Gaza border, October 7, 2023. REUTERS/Mohammed Fayq Abu Mostafa&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/TF3S4BF525K3HNUX2DOY5CPQ2E.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;The bodies of people, some of them elderly, lie on a street after they were killed during a mass-infiltration by Hamas gunmen from the Gaza Strip, in Sderot, southern Israel October 7, 2023. REUTERS/Ammar Awad&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/EQHSZWFJI5ORXD7SRQ7LMNY44I.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Palestinians break into the Israeli side of Israel-Gaza border fence after gunmen infiltrated areas of southern Israel, October 7. REUTERS/Mohammed Fayq Abu Mostafa&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WP3GUWNZ7ZO7BCNV5INGOVYNUE.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Palestinians celebrate as they ride on an Israeli military vehicle that was seized by Palestinian gunmen who infiltrated areas of southern Israel, in the southern Gaza Strip October 7, 2023. REUTERS/Bassam Masoud&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/OQP3K7UF3VNB7JWZY7DSUN6PQA.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Rockets are fired by Palestinian militants into Israel, in Gaza City October 7, 2023. REUTERS/Ibraheem Abu Mustafa&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CMVLT3KBI5OQ7FPJVFTXU4F6CI.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;An Israeli war jet is seen as rocket barrages are launched from the Gaza Strip, in Ashdod, Israel October 7. REUTERS/Ammar Awad&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/S7SICJQR2FKVLMLNECCCWMCHTI.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;An emergency personnel works to extinguish the fire after rockets are launched from the Gaza Strip, as seen from the city of Ashkelon, Israel October 7. REUTERS/Amir Cohen&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/APYEJBPDSJNPLEBGZUNVMVVZ2Q.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Rockets are fired by Palestinian militants into Israel, in Gaza October 7, 2023. REUTERS/Ibraheem Abu Mustafa&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 02:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Biden offers Israel support, faces criticism on Iran at home after Hamas attack]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/israel-palestinians-biden/biden-offers-israel-support-faces-criticism-on-iran-at-home-after-hamas-attack-idUSKBN3170BY]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07T17:58:41Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/RR2C2CRQKVKR3JHYXMHQGD2NKY.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;US President Joe Biden speaks about the September Jobs Report and National Manufacturing Day in the Roosevelt room at the White House in Washington, US, October 6, 2023. REUTERS/Leah Millis&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;US President Joe Biden offered Israel on Saturday &quot;all appropriate means of support&quot; after &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/sirens-warning-incoming-rockets-sound-around-gaza-near-tel-aviv-2023-10-07/&quot;>;a deadly attack&lt;/a>; from Palestinian militant group Hamas and warned &quot;any other party hostile to Israel&quot; not to seek advantage.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The attack from the Iran-backed Islamist group erupted amid efforts by Biden and his team to negotiate a landmark normalization agreement between foes Israel and Saudi Arabia and a US-Saudi defense pact.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Biden spoke by phone to Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu on Saturday to offer US support, with scenes of violence playing out on American news networks. The two leaders have had strained relations but &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/biden-netanyahu-discuss-saudi-normalization-iran-2023-09-20/&quot;>;met in New York&lt;/a>; last month in a show of solidarity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;I made clear to Prime Minister Netanyahu that we stand ready to offer all appropriate means of support to the government and people of Israel,&quot; Biden said in a statement issued after their call.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Biden also issued a blunt warning.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Israel has a right to defend itself and its people. The United States warns against any other party hostile to Israel seeking advantage in this situation,&quot; he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The violence came as Washington was in disarray: Republicans are looking for a successor to ousted Speaker Kevin McCarthy of the House of Representatives, and a budget showdown looms with Biden and his Democrats that could lead to a government shutdown in about 40 days.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Biden&#39;s choice to be US ambassador to Israel, former Treasury Secretary Jack Lew, has yet to be confirmed by the US Senate.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Biden was briefed early on Saturday about the events in Israel and White House officials worked through the night monitoring them, an official said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Republicans seeking to oust Biden in the 2024 presidential election were quick to criticize his handling of the situation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Iran has helped fund this war against Israel, and Joe Biden&#39;s policies that have gone easy on Iran has helped to fill their coffers. Israel is now paying the price for those policies,&quot; said Florida Governor Ron DeSantis, a Republican running for his party&#39;s presidential nomination.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;DeSantis appeared to be referring to a &lt;a href=&quot;/world/us-allows-6-billion-transfer-part-iran-prisoner-swap-2023-09-11/&quot;>;prisoner swap deal&lt;/a>; the Biden administration arranged with Iran last month. Under the deal, the United States waived sanctions to allow the transfer of $6 billion in Iranian funds from South Korea to Qatar, a step needed to carry out the US-Iran prisoner swap.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A Biden administration official said not a dollar of the $6 billion has been spent yet. The money is intended solely for humanitarian purposes.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;I can&#39;t comment on 2024 because of the Hatch Act. But I can clarify the facts: Not a single cent from these funds has been spent, and when it is spent, it can only be spent on things like food and medicine for the Iranian people,&quot; said White House National Security Council spokesperson Adriene Watson.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Hatch Act prohibits White House officials from engaging in political activity.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The impact of the Hamas attack on the US-Israel-Saudi normalization negotiations was unclear. White House Middle East envoy Brett McGurk was in Saudi Arabia a month ago talking to officials, including Palestinians, about normalization.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The United States has been insistent any agreement include some Israeli concessions to the Palestinians, but what those would be remained a subject of negotiations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Reuters &lt;a href=&quot;/world/us-saudi-defence-pact-tied-israel-deal-palestinian-demands-put-aside-2023-09-29/&quot;>;reported last month&lt;/a>; that Saudi Arabia is determined to secure a military pact requiring the United States to defend the kingdom in return for opening ties with Israel, and will not hold up a deal even if Israel does not offer major concessions to Palestinians in their bid for statehood.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Palestinian President Mahmoud Abbas has said any bargain must recognize the Palestinian right to a state within the 1967 borders, including East Jerusalem, and must stop Israeli settlement building.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Netanyahu has said Palestinians should not have a veto over any peacemaking deal.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 02:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Turkey says it killed 58 Kurdish militants in northern Syria]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/turkey-security-syria/turkey-says-it-killed-58-kurdish-militants-in-northern-syria-idUSKBN317034]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-10-07T17:13:27Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/EZUW5ODVBNLO3B6E6QVYRI4I2U.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Smoke rises from Syria&#39;s Kurdish-controlled northeast city of Qamishli, Syria October 5, 2023. REUTERS/Orhan Qereman&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Turkish forces have killed 58 Kurdish militants in northern Syria in overnight attacks on militant targets, the Defence Ministry said on Saturday, as conflict in the region escalated nearly a week after a &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/explosion-heard-turkish-capital-media-report-2023-10-01/&quot;>;bomb attack&lt;/a>; in Ankara.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Turkey this week said all targets belonging to the outlawed Kurdistan Workers Party (PKK) militia and the Syrian Kurdish YPG militia were &quot;legitimate targets&quot; for its forces, after the PKK claimed responsibility for Sunday&#39;s bombing in Ankara which wounded two police officers and killed the two attackers.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Turkey said the attackers came from Syria. The US-backed Syrian Democratic Forces (SDF) - a coalition of rebel groups spearheaded by the YPG militia - denied this.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Since the bomb attack, Ankara has launched a &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/turkey-says-26-militants-neutralised-conflict-escalates-syria-2023-10-06/&quot;>;barrage of air strikes &lt;/a>;and ground-based attacks against militant targets in northern Syria and Iraq, while ramping up security operations at home.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Targets belonging to PKK/YPG terrorists in northern Syria&#39;s Euphrates Shield, Olive Branch, and Peace Spring operation areas were hit strongly all night long,&quot; the ministry said, referring to regions where Turkey has previously mounted incursions.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ministry said the operations, which it says are carried out under self-defence rights, had &quot;neutralised&quot; 58 militants in the region. Ankara typically uses the term &quot;neutralised&quot; to mean killed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Late on Friday, the ministry had said Turkey&#39;s military had conducted air strikes in northern Syria, destroying 15 militant targets where it said militants were believed to be.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Interior Minister Ali Yerlikaya said on Saturday that police in the eastern province of Van had captured six people suspected of PKK links and in preparation of an attack. Following the bomb attack, authorities have carried out raids and operations across the country, seizing dozens of people.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Speaking at his ruling AK Party&#39;s congress in Ankara on Saturday, President Tayyip Erdogan repeated his warning that Turkey &quot;may suddenly come one night&quot;, a term he has often used to target militants in Syria and Iraq.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;We will implement our strategy of ending terror at its root with determination, and hold the PKK, FETO, and Daesh to account over every drop of blood they have spilled,&quot; he said referring to the network of US-based cleric Fethullah Gulen whom Ankara accuses of orchestrating a failed coup attempt in 2016 (FETO), and the Islamic State.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Turkey lists the YPG as a terrorist organisation and says it is indistinguishable from the PKK, which has fought an insurgency against the Turkish state since 1984 in which more than 40,000 people have been killed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The United States and European Union deem the PKK a terrorist organisation, but not the YPG.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The YPG is at the heart of the SDF forces in the US-led coalition against Islamic State militants. US support for them has long caused tension with Turkey.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Underscoring the tension, the United States on Thursday &lt;a href=&quot;/world/turkish-officials-says-ground-operation-into-syria-an-option-after-bombing-2023-10-05/&quot;>;shot down&lt;/a>; an armed Turkish drone that was operating near its troops in Syria, the first time Washington has brought down an aircraft of NATO ally Turkey.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ankara and Washington held a series of calls following the incident, with Turkey saying non-conflict mechanisms with the parties on the ground would be improved, but vowing to continue hitting militants in Syria and Iraq.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Turkey, which has mounted several incursions into northern Syria against the YPG, has said a ground operation into Syria is an option it could consider.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 08 Oct 2023 01:25:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>