<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>路透社</title><description>路透社全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://reuters.com <item><title><![CDATA[Tens of thousands protest across Spain at proposed Catalan amnesty]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/spain-politics-protests/tens-of-thousands-protest-across-spain-at-proposed-catalan-amnesty-idUSKBN327063]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12T13:45:01Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;周日，西班牙各地数万人抗议代理总理佩德罗·桑切斯计划特赦加泰罗尼亚分离主义者换取连任支持。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;政府&lt;a href=&quot;/world/europe/spanish-socialists-reach-deal-with-catalan-junts-government-support-tve-2023- 11-09/&quot;>;周四与加泰罗尼亚分离主义政党 Junts 达成协议&lt;/a>;，其中包括通过一项有争议的法律，对因 2017 年加泰罗尼亚试图脱离西班牙而被定罪的人给予特赦。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该协议&lt;a href=&quot;/world/europe/down-not-out-spains-pm-sanchez-faces-countrys-ire-long-road-ahead-2023-11-10/&quot;>;向世界各地发出冲击波&lt;/a>;桑切斯的保守派反对者指责他为了自己的政治利益而将法治置于危险之中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在举行新的选举之前，我们不会闭嘴，”人民党 (PP) 领导人阿尔贝托 (Alberto)努涅斯·费乔 (Nunez Feijoo) 对挤满马德里太阳门广场的欢呼人群发表讲话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当局表示，马德里有 8 万人参加示威，而呼吁西班牙各城市举行抗议活动的人民党 (PP) 则称总人数接近 100 万人。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多人举着西班牙和欧盟旗帜，以及写有“尊重宪法”等口号的横幅。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他（桑切斯）背叛了共存、民主......他可以不要继续执政，”38 岁的银行家托马斯·佩雷斯 (Tomas Perez) 举着写着“桑切斯叛徒”的牌子说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“据我所知，许多投票支持社会党的人都感到非常失望，因为……桑切斯从未说过特赦将成为他计划的一部分。”64 岁的 Inmaculada Herranz Castro 说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据当局称，在巴塞罗那，当地警方称有 6,000 人示威，而格拉纳达和塞维利亚的示威人数分别达到 30,000 人和 50,000 人。马拉加、帕尔马和巴伦西亚等城市也发生了其他抗议活动。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;7 月 23 日的选举没有结果后，社会党花了数周时间与较小的政党进行谈判，其中包括极左纲领苏马尔、加泰罗尼亚、加利西亚和巴斯克民族主义政党。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;上周 Junts 和巴斯克民族主义党的确认支持，将使桑切斯在由 350 名议员组成的下议院在未来几天举行的投票中获得绝对多数。&lt; /p>;&lt;h2>;相关图库：&lt;/h2>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/IA52QX3MTRNBE7PD2DDDV2GUY.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>; &lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;人们举着旗帜参加人民党号召的抗议活动，反对西班牙社会主义者与加泰罗尼亚分离主义 Junts 党达成的政府支持协议，该协议涉及对人民的大赦参与加泰罗尼亚 2017 年独立申请失败，2023 年 11 月 12 日，西班牙马德里。REUTERS/Susana Vera&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing。 com/reuters/FLEBJ6IDV5JMBEDOFMN5RH7W3Q.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;西班牙反对党人民党领袖阿尔贝托·努涅斯·费乔 (Alberto Nunez Feijoo) 在人民党呼吁的抗议活动中受到支持者的欢迎2023 年 11 月 12 日，西班牙社会主义者在西班牙马德里与加泰罗尼亚分离主义 Junts 党达成一项寻求政府支持的协议，其中包括对参与加泰罗尼亚 2017 年独立申请失败的人员进行特赦。 REUTERS/Susana Vera&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>; &lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2QMV2ENZF5M63JZMDAZZUVFEVY.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;人物11 月，在西班牙马德里，西班牙社会党与加泰罗尼亚分离主义 Junts 党达成一项寻求政府支持的协议，其中包括对参与加泰罗尼亚 2017 年独立申请失败的人员进行大赦。 2023年12月12日。REUTERS/Susana Vera&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color :orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https ://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 21:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Senior Ukrainian officer coordinated Nord Stream attack: Washington Post]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/ukraine-crisis-nord-stream/senior-ukrainian-officer-coordinated-nord-stream-attack-washington-post-idUSKBN32705R]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12T13:06:01Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/IEQWPTQRJRIK5D74INDOI3LT4E。 jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;波罗的海北溪2号天然气管道未使用的管道在德国穆克兰港可见， 2022 年 9 月 30 日。路透社/Fabian Bimmer/档案照片&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;《华盛顿邮报》周六援引匿名消息人士的话报道，去年，一名乌克兰军官协调了对北溪天然气管道的袭击&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没有人对 2022 年 9 月发生的爆炸负责，这起爆炸发生在丹麦博恩霍尔姆岛附近，导致俄罗斯向欧洲输送天然气的系统的四分之三破裂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;没有人对 2022 年 9 月发生的爆炸负责。 p>;&lt;p>;华盛顿和北约称其为破坏行为，而莫斯科则称这是国际恐怖主义行为。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;曾在乌克兰军队特种部队服役的前情报官员罗曼·切尔文斯基(Roman Chervinsky)据《华盛顿邮报》报道，这是一个由六人组成的小组，但并未策划这次袭击。他否认参与其中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;乌克兰军方发言人告诉路透社，他“没有关于这一说法的信息”。乌克兰外交部和基辅国内安全部门 SBU 没有立即回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;该报还报道称，否认基辅在爆炸事件中所扮演角色的总统弗拉基米尔·泽伦斯基并不知情。的操作。泽伦斯基上周取代了乌克兰特种作战部队的负责人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;德国、丹麦和瑞典已对北溪爆炸展开调查，该爆炸导致大量甲烷泄漏到大气中，持续了数天。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;切尔文斯基目前因越权被捕，此前他曾在 2022 年试图说服一名俄罗斯飞行员叛逃到乌克兰，调查人员称这导致了俄罗斯对乌克兰空军基地的致命袭击。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;切尔文斯基直言不讳地批评泽伦斯基政府，他表示针对他的案件是出于政治动机，他在这次行动中是服从命令的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他当时的指挥官维克多·哈努什查克少将告诉乌克兰广播公司今年早些时候，媒体称高级军事领导层已经批准了引诱俄罗斯飞行员的阴谋。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;《华盛顿邮报》和德国《明镜周刊》合作报道并撰写了单独的故事，并同意同时发表.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[“True European“: Former top Czech diplomat Schwarzenberg dies]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/people-schwarzenberg/true-european-former-top-czech-diplomat-schwarzenberg-dies-idUSKBN32703I]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12T13:06:59Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;官员称，捷克前外交部长卡雷尔·施瓦岑贝格去世，他是该国后共产主义时代的领军人物之一周日说。他现年 85 岁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;施瓦岑贝格出生于捷克一个享有盛誉的家庭，在这位前持不同政见者于 1990 年赢得该国第一次自由选举后，他成为了朋友瓦茨拉夫·哈维尔 (Vaclav Havel) 的高级助手。 2007 年和 2013 年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他是欧洲更紧密一体化的坚定支持者，虽然他公开宣称是保守派，但他的吸引力延伸到了城市自由派团体和政治领域的年轻人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;施瓦岑贝格共同创立的瓦茨拉夫·哈维尔图书馆表示，施瓦岑贝格于周六去世，并称他是“爱国者和真正的欧洲人”。捷克媒体称他上周已被送往维也纳的医院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他是我生命中最重要、最善良的人之一，”施瓦岑贝格领导的 TOP09 党创始人米罗斯拉夫·卡劳塞克 (Miroslav Kalousek) 说道。社交媒体帖子中表示，一切都开始了。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“愿他安息，捷克共和国应该永远感谢他为捷克所做的一切。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;施瓦岑贝格他一生的大部分时间都在流亡中度过，因为他的家人是共产党在 1948 年政变中掌权的主要目标之一，没收了施瓦岑贝格的大量财产，其中包括主要位于该国南部靠近奥地利的城堡、森林和土地，他们在那里也有土地。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在奥地利流亡期间，他接管了家族的财产，还支持反共产主义人权运动，并赞助了一个收藏捷克违禁文学的图书馆。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;1989 年天鹅绒革命和平推翻了当时捷克斯洛伐克的共产党统治，施瓦岑贝格成为哈维尔的幕僚长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;捷克电视台引用他回国后的话说：“你不知道幸福一个人有什么时候可以再次回家。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外交部称他是两代外交官的灵感之源。和哈维尔一样，他讨厌闲聊，并会在回答有关世界错误的讨论时说：“好吧，我们该怎么办？”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他知道我们的自由和自由是多么不确定和脆弱。奥地利外交部长亚历山大·沙伦伯格 (Alexander Schallenberg) 在 X 上表示，施瓦岑贝格是民主和欧洲理念的“坚定倡导者”。 “他是一个最意义上的中欧人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;施瓦岑贝格于 2004 年成为参议员，然后帮助创立了 TOP09 党，该党现在是中右翼政府联盟的初级成员。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2013 年，他竞选总统，但输给了米洛斯·泽曼 (Milos Zeman)，后者是 1989 年后捷克政坛的另一位杰出人物，今年早些时候完成了第二个总统任期。&lt;/p>;&lt;h2>;相关画廊：&lt;/h2>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/AEUQJMZFCBNFLFDX5YYWACX55Y.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;2013 年 10 月 8 日，一名男子对着选举前的壁画做出手势，壁画描绘了 TOP09 政党主席卡雷尔·施瓦岑贝格 (Karel Schwarzenberg)，该壁画绘制在布拉格一栋废弃建筑上。路透社/David W Cerny（捷克共和国 - 标签：政治选举）/文件照片&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ZLOPCRH4ZBK4DN64OLVEKUUDQA.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;小样式=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;2013 年 9 月 24 日，TOP09 政党主席卡雷尔·施瓦岑贝格 (Karel Schwarzenberg) 抵达布拉格参加路透社峰会时站在电梯里。REUTERS/Petr Josek /资料照片&lt;/small>; &lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[King Charles, UK PM Sunak lead remembrance services after day of protests]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/britain-remembrance-day/king-charles-uk-pm-sunak-lead-remembrance-services-after-day-of-protests-idUSKBN3260ES]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12T13:13:09Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;周日，查尔斯国王和首相里希·苏纳克带领英国缅怀该国的战争死难者，力求有一天让社区团结起来在一次大规模的亲巴勒斯坦游行之后，极右翼反抗议者和警察之间发生了小规模冲突。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在伦敦市中心白厅的战争纪念碑纪念碑上举行的庄严仪式上，查尔斯、苏纳克和其他政治家和王室高级成员默哀两分钟，然后敬献花圈，以纪念在战争中丧生的人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周六，一年一度的纪念世界大战结束的停战日纪念活动超过&lt;a href =&quot;/world/huge-crowds-expected-london-pro-palestinian-rally-police-gear-trouble-2023-11-11/&quot;>;30万&lt;/a>;亲巴勒斯坦示威者在伦敦市中心游行，警方逮捕超过 120 人试图阻止极右反抗议者伏击主要集会。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在反对派政客指责内政部长苏埃拉·布雷弗曼 (Suella Braverman) 加剧游行前夕的紧张局势后，国防部格兰特·沙普斯部长表示，他不会使用她在批评警察的文章中使用的语言。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但他告诉 BBC，这篇文章表达了人们对警方是否对抗议者采取足够迅速的行动的担忧。被指控高喊反犹太口号或举着“例如带有纳粹十字记号的横幅”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我是说，我确实认为警方迅速采取行动非常重要，”他说。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;负责治安的布雷弗曼因上周使用一篇文章指责警方在对待抗议活动（尤其是亲巴勒斯坦游行）时采取“双重标准”，而受到反对派和本党议员的批评。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;反对党工党内政政策负责人伊薇特·库珀 (Yvette Cooper) 告诉天空新闻，布雷弗曼的行为旨在“故意在阵亡将士纪念周末前夕加剧紧张局势”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“她不应该一开始就一直在做这项工作，Rishi Sunak 让她这么做，而他太虚弱了，无能为力……我不知道她如何才能继续做这项工作。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;On周六，苏纳克谴责了暴力场面，他说：“纪念周末是我们作为一个国家聚集在一起并纪念那些为我们的自由而战和牺牲的人们的时刻。今天令人无法接受的场景不尊重他们的记忆。”&lt;/p>;&lt;h2>;相关图库：&lt;/h2>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/VUS3JUVAAZPRZBGNZD7E5CRHAI。 jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;英国国王查理三世、威尔士亲王威廉、爱丁堡公爵爱德华王子和长公主安妮参加国民服役2023 年 11 月 12 日在英国伦敦白厅纪念碑举行的纪念活动。Chris Jackson/Pool via REUTERS&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing .com/reuters/AQ5XEG4XZROI3DQSU5Y4JRIVU.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;英国国王查理三世于 11 月 12 日在英国伦敦白厅纪念碑参加国家纪念仪式，2023 年。Kin Cheung/Pool，来自 REUTERS&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2VCU262L7FI3RD45JB5YT24M34.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; >;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;英国国王查尔斯三世、威尔士亲王威廉、爱丁堡公爵爱德华王子和长公主安妮于 2019 年 12 月 17 日在和平纪念碑举行的国家纪念活动英国伦敦白厅，2023 年 11 月 12 日。Kin Cheung/Pool，来自 REUTERS&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/OF5WRUJQQFNZNEEQASN2XRKXEM .jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;英国首相里希·苏纳克和工党领袖凯尔·斯塔默在白厅纪念碑参加国家纪念仪式时手捧罂粟花圈英国伦敦，2023 年 11 月 12 日。Kin Cheung/Pool，来自 REUTERS&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/HTB3D43T5FLX5E7GSJLJQTIN7E。 jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;英国国王查尔斯于 2023 年 5 月 5 日在伦敦马尔堡宫举行的英联邦政府首脑会议上与首相里希·苏纳克握手，英格兰。克里斯·杰克逊/泳池来自路透社/档案照片&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 21:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Film crews became “collateral damage“ of Hollywood strikes]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/television-actors-strike-film-crew/film-crews-became-collateral-damage-of-hollywood-strikes-idUSKBN327054]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12T12:15:17Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/RTFT6H42QRMM3FKALVC3M337OQ。 jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;7 月 25 日，美国加利福尼亚州伯班克迪士尼影城外，美国演员工会联合会 (SAG-AFTRA) 演员和美国作家协会 (WGA) 的罢工标志等待着罢工，2023。路透社/迈克·布莱克&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;多伦多一名制片助理的收入因好莱坞罢工而枯竭，失去了住房，最终只能住在自己的车里。纽约的一位布景师在压力下失去了清醒。新墨西哥州的一名助理导演陷入深度抑郁并结束了自己的生命。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他们是数十万美国和加拿大影视剧组工作人员中的一员，他们因工会号召的罢工而失业长达 10 个月。演员和作家，留下了一系列被驱逐和家庭解体的痕迹。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在&lt;a href=&quot;/world/us/hollywood-writers-deal-may期间，剧组成员团结起来互相帮助，慈善机构也参与其中-set-template-talks-with-striking-actors-2023-09-27/&quot;>;作家罢工&lt;/a>;，从 5 月 2 日开始，到 9 月下旬结束，演员罢工从 7 月开始。演员们达成了初步&lt;a href=&quot;/business/media-telecom/striking-actors-reach-tentative-agreement-with-hollywood-studios-end-strike-2023-11-09/&quot;>;协议&lt;/a>;心理健康慈善机构 Behind the Scenes 的执行董事洛里·鲁宾斯坦 (Lori Rubinstein) 表示：“演员和编剧得到了大量宣传，但工作人员却是罢工的附带损害。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;船员失去了健康保险并闯入了退休金。据工会领导人、顾问和十几名工作人员称，他们眼睁睁地看着人际关系崩溃，变得孤立和沮丧，因为他们一个月又一个月没有工资，也失去了每周 70 小时的工作时间，创作出耗资数亿美元的节目。路透社采访的成员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据工作人员称，在过去 18 个月里，鲁宾斯坦为大约 1,000 名行业成员提供了心理健康急救培训课程，以防止在这个与药物滥用、工作狂和欺凌作斗争的行业中发生自杀事件。路透社采访的成员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他确实需要工作，”&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/name/nm5395991/&quot; target= 的母亲帕姆·罗森 (Pam ​​Rosen) 说&quot;_blank&quot;>;乔·布法利诺&lt;/a>;，32 岁，新墨西哥州有史以来最年轻的第一助理导演，因《丝绸之路》和《泰国洞穴救援》等电影而闻名，他在&lt;a href=&quot;https:// www.legacy.com/us/obituaries/abqjournal/name/joseph-bufalino-obituary?id=52876949&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;8 月17.&lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“在他去世时，他看不到未来，”罗森说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在加利福尼亚州，电影公司社会服务部负责人詹妮弗·豪尔赫(Jennifer Jorge)电视基金会 (MPTF) 和她的团队每周处理数百个电话，其中一些来自电影摄制组人员，他们谈到了自杀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“当有人难以每月还款时，当他们的汽车被收回时，当“他们面临被驱逐的境地，当他们自己或孩子没有食物时，会造成很大的心理困扰。”Jorge 说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;MPTF 已向工人提供了约 375 万美元的援助。加拿大亚足联慈善机构在收到大量请求后暂停了新的援助申请。娱乐社区基金已向加州、纽约和亚特兰大的工人发放了超过 1120 万美元的补助金。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在多伦多地区，一名剧组成员收留了睡在车里的制作助理.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“如果不是朋友们的好意，我早就死了，”制作助理肖恩说，他要求不要使用他的全名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一名工作人员，一名场地经理，重新拥有了他的货车。他的妻子也是一名电影工作者，靠托儿所来支付账单。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们通常有一个安全网，但由于今年我们个人经历的一切，安全网已经消失了，”说场景经理克里斯要求不要使用他的全名。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纽约布景师和道具师诺文·范·邓克 (Norvin Van Dunk) 长期以来一直在与抑郁和焦虑作斗争。在第一次罢工发生之前，他已经清醒了大约一年。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;即使有仍在工作的妻子和船员朋友的支持，他还是短暂地重新酗酒以应对不喝酒的压力。在职的。此后他恢复了清醒，去健身房、演奏音乐并照顾年幼的孩子。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纽约道具大师格温·罗奇和她的丈夫耗尽了毕生积蓄，并放弃了拥有一套房子的希望。她的失业救济金已经用完，她丈夫的失业救济金也即将用完。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我一生中从来没有想过要考虑接受福利或食品援助，”曾在一家慈善机构工作的罗奇说。餐厅和花店。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在阿尔伯克基，助理导演&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.imdb.com/name/nm3134370/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;Anthony Pelot&lt;/ a>;，37 岁，在布法利诺的片场工作了 14 年，他为失去最好的朋友而感到悲痛。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“毫无疑问，如果这些袭击没有发生，乔就会活着。今天，”佩洛特说道，他坐在罗森旁边的一家咖啡馆里，这家咖啡馆距离这两个朋友住的地方不远。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 20:25:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[In UN talks for a global plastic treaty, delegates to face off over production limits]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/un-plastics-treaty/in-un-talks-for-a-global-plastic-treaty-delegates-to-face-off-over-production-limits-idUSKBN327022]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12T11:30:49Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;随着世界各国本周进入另一轮谈判，讨论制定首个遏制塑料污染的条约，官员们正在准备就是否限制塑料生产量或仅关注废物管理进行艰难的谈判。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;正在制定一份名为“零草案”的文件，其中列出了需要考虑的可能政策和行动参与谈判的官员表示，参加在肯尼亚内罗毕举行的为期一周的会议的各国代表将讨论将哪些选项纳入到 2024 年底最终成为具有法律约束力的条约中。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “我们正处于这一进程的关键时刻，”谈判观察员、国际环境法中心执行律师戴维·阿祖莱 (David Azoulay) 表示。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;目前全球的产量约为 4 亿吨。根据联合国环境规划署的数据，每年产生大量塑料垃圾，其中不到 10% 被回收利用，导致垃圾填埋场堵塞，海洋遭到破坏。由于通常也生产塑料的石油公司在能源转型过程中寻找新的收入来源，从化石燃料转向塑料，因此产量将在未来十年激增。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;如今，大约 98% 的塑料根据联合国环境规划署的说法，一次性塑料（如瓶子或包装）是从化石燃料中提取的。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;欧盟和包括日本、加拿大和肯尼亚在内的数十个国家呼吁 -条约中包含“具有约束力的条款”，旨在减少石化产品的原始塑料聚合物的生产和使用，并消除或限制有问题的塑料，例如 PVC 和其他含有有毒成分的塑料。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这一立场遭到了塑料协会的反对。工业界以及沙特阿拉伯等石油和石化出口国希望看到塑料的使用继续下去。他们认为，该条约应重点关注塑料的回收和再利用，有时在谈判中称为塑料供应的“循环”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沙特阿拉伯在本周谈判前提交的一份文件中表示，根本原因是塑料的回收和再利用。塑料污染的根源在于“废物管理效率低下”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国最初希望制定一项由国家计划组成的条约来控制塑料，但近几个月来已经修改了立场。美国国务院发言人在给路透社的一份声明中表示，现在认为，虽然该条约仍应以国家计划为基础，但这些计划应反映全球商定的减少塑料污染的目标，这些目标“有意义且可行”。&lt;/p >;&lt;p>;国际化学协会理事会发言人马修·卡斯特纳 (Matthew Kastner) 表示，国际化学协会理事会希望该条约纳入“加速塑料循环经济”的措施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“塑料协议应重点关注终止塑料制品卡斯特纳在一份声明中对路透社表示：“对于石油、天然气和石化产品生产商和出口商来说，强有力的条约是一种责任，可能会限制化石燃料的销售，”卡斯特纳在一份声明中告诉路透社。国际污染物消除网络协调员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沙特阿拉伯和其他生产国正在“推行一种‘自下而上’的方法，让各个国家对塑料和化学品的清理、健康和环境成本负责，同时让化石燃料和塑料工业摆脱了困境，”比勒说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;各国还将讨论该条约是否应该为塑料生产中的化学品使用制定透明度标准。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但在此之前他们可以在实质性问题上开展工作时，代表们需要解决程序性异议，这些异议在 6 月份减缓了谈判进程，当时沙特阿拉伯表示决定应由大多数国家而不是协商一致通过。达成共识将允许一个国家阻止该条约的通过。大多数其他国家不支持干预。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;沙特代表团没有立即回应置评请求。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;环保组织表示，他们希望本周的会谈能够重点讨论该条约的实质内容，并超越阻碍进展的程序性讨论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们需要对全球塑料经济进行彻底的重新思考，不能因脱轨策略和错误解决方案而陷入困境，”环境调查局的克里斯蒂娜迪克森说.&lt;/p>;&lt;h2>;相关图库：&lt;/h2>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/DM7DMH3WEFM53BEZCE7YCXYL5U.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt; div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;2020 年东京奥运会。当参赛者为比赛热身时，一个装有垃圾的塑料袋漂浮在水面上。 REUTERS/Carlos Barria&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/GR5OMNNBEBO5XCVLHX7PDSWAXY.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt; Small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;2022 年 3 月 1 日，美国纽约曼哈顿区的联合国总部大楼，上面有联合国标志。REUTERS/Carlo Allegri/档案照片&lt;/小>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 19:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel offers Gaza hospital evacuation for babies but fighting rages on]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/israel-palestinians/israel-offers-gaza-hospital-evacuation-for-babies-but-fighting-rages-on-idUSKBN3260F4]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12T11:34:36Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;视频控件 src=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;巴勒斯坦官员表示，周六（11 月 11 日）加沙最大的医院燃料耗尽后，两名婴儿死亡，数十人面临危险，而以色列则表示已准备好从该机构撤离婴儿。艾玛·杰勒 (Emma Jehle) 制作了这份报告。&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;以色列军队表示已准备好从加沙 &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/al-shifa-gazas-largest-hospital- 撤离婴儿headers-2023-11-10/&quot;>;周日最大的医院&lt;/a>;，但巴勒斯坦官员表示，里面的人仍然被困，两名新生儿死亡，数十人因附近激烈战斗而面临停电危险。&lt;/p>; &lt;p>;加沙北部的希法医院和其他医院是以色列长达一个月的消灭哈马斯和解救武装分子人质战争的焦点，但它们几乎无法照顾病人。每天都有更多的人因以色列的猛烈轰炸而受伤。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加沙卫生部发言人阿什拉夫·齐德拉 (Ashraf Al-Qidra) 在最大的医院 Al-Shifa 内部发表讲话时告诉路透社，以色列的炮火并非一夜之间直接袭击该医院，但“令人恐惧”以色列首席军事发言人、海军少将丹尼尔·哈加里周六表示，以色列军方将应医院工作人员的要求帮助从医院撤离婴儿。 Al-Qidra 表示，共有 45 名婴儿，其中两人已经死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当被问及疏散情况时，Al-Qidra 表示：“我们尚未获悉有任何机制可以将婴儿转移到指定地点。”更安全的医院。到目前为止，我们正在祈祷他们的安全，不要失去更多人。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在加沙地带北部 Beit Lahiya 的印度尼西亚医院 Mosab Subeih，一名男婴 Mosab Subeih，一名被以色列导弹击中的房屋被赶了过来。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他的头部直接受伤，正在流血，我们没有进行手术，”一名正在治疗的医护人员说道。由于电源被切断，他使用手动复苏器。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴勒斯坦红新月会表示，加沙北部圣城的另一家医院的医务人员正在努力照顾那些缺乏药品、食物和水的人。 .&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“圣城医院在过去 6 至 7 天内与世隔绝。进不去，出不去”，红十字国际联合会发言人托马索·德拉·隆加 (Tommaso Della Longa)新月协会告诉路透社。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加沙地带南部汗尤尼斯纳赛尔医院的医生穆罕默德·坎迪尔 (Mohammad Qandil) 表示，希法也无法救治新伤员，他与那里的同事保持着联系。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“希法医院现在无法工作，任何人都不允许进入，任何人都不允许出去，如果你在加沙地区受伤或受伤，我们的救护车无法将你疏散到希法医院，因此，希法医院现在已经停止服务。”他告诉路透社。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;周日，以色列表示，人们可以从加沙北部的三家医院（包括希法医院）的其中一个出口安全撤离。医院院长穆罕默德·阿布·塞尔梅亚 (Mohammad Abu Selmeyah) 告诉阿拉伯电视台，没有安全通道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着加沙各地的人道主义局势恶化，其边境当局表示，进入埃及的拉法过境点将于周日对外国护照持有者重新开放。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;据以色列官员称，自以色列一个多月前向哈马斯宣战以来，武装分子在以色列南部肆虐，造成约 1,200 人死亡，并劫持了 200 多人质，之后进入加沙的援助非常少。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;巴勒斯坦官员周五表示，自那时以来，已有 11,078 名加沙居民在空袭和炮击中丧生，其中约 40% 是儿童。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;疾病正在学校和其他避难所的疏散人员中蔓延，国际援助机构称，他们仅靠少量食物和水生存。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一些国家已开始通过降落伞提供援助；约旦表示，周日早些时候已向野战医院空投了第二批物资。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;哈马斯表示，已完全或部分摧毁了加沙地带的 160 多个以色列军事目标，其中包括超过 27 辆坦克和车辆。过去 48 小时。以色列军方发言人表示，哈马斯已经失去了对加沙北部的控制。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在周六晚间的新闻发布会上，以色列总理本杰明·内塔尼亚胡宣布又有五名以色列士兵在加沙死亡。以色列军方表示，自地面行动开始以来，已有 46 人死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;居民表示，加沙北部海岸的沙蒂难民营周围的战斗加剧。以色列军方表示，已击毙那里的多名武装分子，并呼吁平民利用四个小时的暂停时间向南部撤离。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;54 岁的贾米拉在加沙城内表示，她和家人可以听到 700 米外街道上坦克行驶的轰鸣声。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“白天，人们试图寻找面包和水等必需品，而到了晚上，人们试图生存，”她在电话中说道。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们整个晚上都听到爆炸声，有时我们可以看出其中一些爆炸是抵抗战士和以色列军队之间的交火。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这位六个孩子的母亲说，她的家人不敢离开。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们在南方听到很多爆炸声，而且没有食物。那里的情况似乎与我们这里的情况没有什么不同，”她说.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴勒斯坦卫生官员表示，以色列周日对汗尤尼斯的一所房屋进行空袭，造成 13 人死亡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;以色列表示，医生、患者和数千名撤离人员都受到了影响。在&lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/gazas-centuries-war-brief-history-2023-10-30/&quot;>;加沙&lt;/a>;北部的医院避难的人必须离开，这样它才能摧毁它所说的一切他们的下方和周围是哈马斯指挥中心。哈马斯否认以这种方式使用医院。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Al Shifa 工作人员告诉路透社，持续轰炸已超过 24 小时。 Most hospital staff and people sheltering there had left, but 500 patients remained.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The World Health Organisation expressed &quot;grave concern&quot; for the safety of everyone trapped there by the fighting and said it had lost communications with its contacts in the hospital.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Israel&#39;s three major TV news channels said on Saturday there was some progress toward a deal to free hostages held by Hamas in Gaza but there was little sign of one on Sunday. They did not cite any named sources and there was no public comment from Hamas or Israel on the reports.&lt;/p>;&lt;h2>;Related Galleries:&lt;/h2>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/BO2RTHFZSBNQNAYOEPI4ZJ67DA.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;A Palestinian child wounded in Israeli strikes waits to receive treatment at Nasser hospital in Khan Younis in the southern Gaza Strip November 12, 2023. REUTERS/Mohammed Salem&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/IUSA7TPSBVO7LPZW25XK77LVUY.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;A Palestinian child wounded in Israeli strikes amid the ongoing conflict between Israel and Palestinian group Hamas waits to receive treatment at Nasser hospital in Khan Younis in the southern Gaza Strip November 12, 2023. REUTERS/Mohammed Salem&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2T3DUMUUGVIIJBE355D7ISXRZ4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Palestinians wounded in Israeli strikes are assisted out of an ambulance to receive treatment at Nasser hospital in Khan Younis in the southern Gaza Strip November 12, 2023. REUTERS/Mohammed Salem&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CVJ6CWUL6ROE3HNYQ3UJGU2ZXY.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Smoke rises as displaced Palestinians take shelter at Al Shifa hospital, amid the ongoing conflict between Hamas and Israel, in Gaza City, November 8, 2023. REUTERS/Doaa Rouqa/File Photo&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WGEQBHIMHZIOHAYE6GX5PNHY5U.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;A Palestinian reacts at the site of an Israeli strike on a house belonging to Fojo family in Rafah in the southern Gaza Strip November 11, 2023. REUTERS/Hatem Khaled &lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/6EJSOIAHXFOAXKJ4HJIVXDZICA.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Israeli soldiers take a position inside the Gaza Strip, amid the ongoing ground operation of the Israeli army against Palestinian Islamist group Hamas, according to the Israeli Defense Forces (IDF), in this handout picture obtained by Reuters on November 11, 2023. Israeli Defense Forces/Handout via REUTERS &lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YSHYATQTCFJWNGVZV2SXUGVZLY.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Israeli soldiers operate inside the Gaza Strip, amid the ongoing ground operation of the Israeli army against Palestinian Islamist group Hamas, according to the Israeli Defense Forces (IDF), in this handout picture obtained by Reuters on November 11, 2023. Israeli Defense Forces/Handout via REUTERS &lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/DSPONO5HIZJ7RJ3X5P2I4IAA2A.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;A girl is assisted as Palestinians search for casualties at the site of an Israeli strike on a house, in Rafah in the southern Gaza Strip November 11, 2023. REUTERS/Hatem Khaled &lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/3SASITWRMFPZJMT6L5M7N2TFZ4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Smoke rises over Gaza as seen from southern Israel, amid the ongoing conflict between Israel and the Palestinian group Hamas, November 11, 2023. REUTERS/Alexander Ermochenko&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 19:55:02 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[World War Two veterans eye 80th anniversary of D-Day as Europe salutes war dead]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/remembrance-day-normandy/ww2-veterans-eye-80th-anniversary-of-d-day-as-europe-salutes-war-dead-idUSKBN32703A]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12T11:16:00Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;English soldier Ken Hay was trapped behind German lines and captured while on night patrol in 1944, days after joining the Allied invasion of Normandy, a turning point in World War Two.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The ambush near the bitterly contested &quot;Hill 112&quot; came during weeks of fighting after the largest seaborne assault in history, which began the liberation of France from Nazi German occupation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Thirty of us went out, 16 including my brother got back, five of us got captured and nine got killed,&quot; Hay said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As many nations around the world commemorate last century&#39;s wars and other conflicts during a weekend of remembrance, preparations are already under way to mark next year&#39;s 80th anniversary of the D-Day landings and the Battle of Normandy.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Born in the English county of Essex, Hay took part in the early reinforcements of Juno Beach, which had been stormed under Canadian command on D-Day, June 6. He is now an active ambassador for the nearby British Normandy Memorial, overlooking Gold Beach in the UK sector.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Until two years ago, Britain was alone among allies on the Western front in not having a dedicated Normandy memorial.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;An elegant rectangular colonnade now sits on former farmland chosen by veterans themselves at Ver-sur-Mer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In total, 22,440 servicemen and two servicewomen of more than 30 nationalities who died under British command between June 6 and Aug. 31, 1944, are commemorated on 160 stone columns, as well as a ceremonial wall for those who perished on D-Day itself.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The 30-million-pound ($37 million) memorial was financed by fines levied on banks by the British government, as well as private donations.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hay, 98, is helping raise funds for an educational pavilion in time for next year&#39;s 80th anniversary, likely to be attended by Britain&#39;s King Charles III and French President Emmanuel Macron.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;With the average age of a dwindling number of veterans also 98, it will be the last major chance to gather some of those who helped their fallen comrades push back the Western front.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Unusually, the memorial is laid out by date of death.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The fact that names are presented chronologically means you get an understanding of how the battle unfolded: the days that are particularly fierce,&quot; said operations manager Sacha Marsac.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;When a whole unit is lost on the same day, their names are all next to each other.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Neatly carved rows of names, ranks and ages can only hint at the personal stories. 4 名 16 岁的年轻人可能夸大了自己的年龄，在 18 岁之前服役。大多数人几乎不知道自己 20 多岁。 The oldest: merchant seaman Thomas Hardwyre Milligan, 64.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Soldiers promoted unusually young, like a major of only 28, hint at heavy losses as their superiors were killed.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;One name is honoured with special insignia.西德尼·贝茨下士多次用轻机枪向德军关键阵地发起冲锋，最终因伤重而死，因此被追授英国维多利亚十字勋章，以表彰其“至高无上的英勇”。 He was 23.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A separate monument honours French civilians.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Veterans like Hay refuse to call themselves heroes, deferring to those who fell in battle. Yet many suffered hardship, injury and separation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;I joined at the age of 17 in 1943, but they wouldn&#39;t call me [to serve] until I was 17-and-a-half; they said I was too young to die,&quot; Hay said in a recent interview.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;For six days after capture, he and fellow prisoners were hauled in a cattle wagon to Stalag VIII-D prison camp, now in the Czech Republic. Later he was sent to work in a Polish coal mine.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Then, in early 1945, began a three-month march westwards as German captors moved their prisoners ahead of the advancing Soviet army.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a forest near Regensburg, Germany, guns approached from the West and the German commanding officer accepted the war was over.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;That was April 20. From Jan. 23, we had done 1,000 miles,&quot; Hay said. &quot;I&#39;ve got a good pair of feet.&quot;($1 = 0.8182 pounds)&lt;/p>;&lt;h2>;Related Galleries:&lt;/h2>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/OWVQR3IV7ZLCVMR4YUMVTK2FHM.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Veteran Ken Hay, 98, an ambassador for the British Normandy Memorial who reinforced Juno Beach and took part in the Battle of Normandy in 1944, is seen at the Royal International Air Tattoo, in Fairford, Britain on July 14, 2023. REUTERS/Tim Hepher/File Photo&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/ROEWXXPNLVO2XEORS7BDKG7U7E.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Columns commemorating some of the 22,442 who died under British command between D-Day and the end of the Battle of Normandy are displayed at the British Normandy Memorial, in Ver-sur-Mer, France, July 30, 2023. REUTERS/Tim Hepher&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/5GBBB5YVNZIRVPIBPZIHO7POBE.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;People visit the new British Normandy Memorial at Ver-sur-Mer, after an official opening ceremony on the 77th anniversary of D-Day, France, June 6, 2021. REUTERS/Stephane Mahe/Pool&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/33ICCD2WKVPJ3ABXLNT3EOWKKQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;A general view of the veteran parade during the National Service of Remembrance at The Cenotaph in London, Britian November 12, 2023. Every year, members of the British Royal family join politicians, veterans and members of the public to remember those who have died in combat. Chris Jackson/Pool via REUTERS&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/RF7MQCJC3FKPHAWBLMZOYNZULI.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Veterans attend the National Service of Remembrance at The Cenotaph on Whitehall in London, Britian November 12, 2023. Chris Jackson/Pool via REUTERS&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/FLQRG2AICNMFDKAWMCRRDHSMHM.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;A formal gun salute fires as part of a National Service of Remembrance, in Whitehall, Westminster, London Britain November 12, 2023. REUTERS/Hannah McKay&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/A53ZDTQCCRKXRATHIBPDHOXK3E.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;British Prime Minister Rishi Sunak and former Prime Ministers Liz Truss, Boris Johnson, Theresa May, James Cameron, Gordon Brown, Tony Blair and John Major attend the annual Remembrance Sunday ceremony at the Cenotaph, in Whitehall, London Britain November 12, 2023. REUTERS/Toby Melville/Pool&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/57IYJ6AC45LO7F7UHVTEBHIDSY.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Spouses of former and current Britain&#39;s prime ministers Cherie Blair, Akshata Murty, Philip May, Norma Major, Sarah Brown and Hugh O&#39;Leary attend National Service of Remembrance at The Cenotaph on Whitehall in London, Britian November 12, 2023. Henry Nicholls/Pool via REUTERS&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/6X7QPVGEVFMZPGBHS2IENVCEXI.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;A man lays poppies on the Tomb of the Unknown Soldier following a ceremony at the National War Memorial on Remembrance Day in Ottawa, Ontario, Canada November 11, 2023. REUTERS/Blair Gable&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/PD4OBURBJBJZ5GK6SGZAUC3D4Y.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Canada&#39;s Prime Minister Justin Trudeau lays a wreath during a ceremony at the National War Memorial on Remembrance Day in Ottawa, Ontario, Canada November 11, 2023. REUTERS/Blair Gable&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/GG3BIOHQ5JMURGLWEOT5ZG5YOU.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;French President Emmanuel Macron lays a wreath during a ceremony at the Tomb of the Unknown Soldier at the Arc de Triomphe in Paris, France on November 11, 2023, as part of commemorations marking the 105th anniversary of the November 11, 1918 Armistice, ending World War I (WWI). MOHAMMED BADRA/Pool via REUTERS&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/22UL6BELHBJS5BVJJXIQNHDTZQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Chelsea Pensioner Arthur Teasdale, 93, gestures on the day of the National Service of Remembrance, in Whitehall, Westminster, London, Britain November 12, 2023. REUTERS/Hannah McKay&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/VIOGTMECHFKM7E5Z3Y4MQMQICU.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Names of some of the 22,442 who died under British command between D-Day and the end of the Battle of Normandy are displayed at the British Normandy Memorial, in Ver-sur-Mer, France, July 30, 2023. REUTERS/Tim Hepher/File Photo&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 19:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel offers to evacuate babies from crippled Gaza hospital]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/israel-palestinians/israel-offers-to-evacuate-babies-from-crippled-gaza-hospital-idUSKBN3260F4]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12T08:53:46Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;video controls src=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Palestinian officials said two babies had died and dozens more were at risk after fuel ran out at Gaza&#39;s largest hospital on Saturday (November 11), while Israel said it was ready to evacuate babies from the facility. Emma Jehle produced this report.&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Israel&#39;s military said it was ready to evacuate babies from Gaza&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/al-shifa-gazas-largest-hospital-headlines-2023-11-10/&quot;>;largest hospital&lt;/a>; on Sunday, where Palestinian officials said two newborns died and dozens more were at risk after fuel ran out amid intense fighting in the area.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the humanitarian situation worsened, Gaza&#39;s border authority said the Rafah crossing into Egypt would reopen on Sunday for foreign passport holders. Jordan also air-dropped more aid into a field hospital in the enclave.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hamas said it had completely or partially destroyed more than 160 Israeli military targets in Gaza, including more than 27 tanks and vehicles in the past 48 hours. An Israeli military spokesperson said Hamas had lost control of northern Gaza.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At a news conference late on Saturday, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu announced the deaths of five more Israeli soldiers in Gaza. The Israeli military said 46 had been killed since its ground operations there began.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Israel said rockets were still being fired from Gaza into southern Israel, where it has said about 1,200 people were killed and more than 200 taken hostage by Hamas last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Palestinian officials said on Friday that 11,078 Gaza residents had been killed in air and artillery strikes since Oct. 7, around 40% of them children.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Israel&#39;s three major TV news channels, without citing named sources, said there was some progress toward a deal to free hostages held by Hamas in Gaza.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Netanyahu said he would not discuss details of any possible deal, which according to N12 News would involve 50 to 100 women, children and elderly being released in stages during a three to five day pause in fighting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the reports, Israel would release women and minor Palestinian prisoners and consider letting fuel in to Gaza, while reserving the right to resume fighting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Tel Aviv, thousands joined a rally to support families of the hostages.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gaza residents said Israeli troops, who went to war to eliminate Hamas after its deadly cross-border assault on Oct. 7, had &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/israel-targets-hamas-tunnels-new-phase-gaza-war-2023-11-07/&quot;>;clashed with&lt;/a>; Hamas gunmen overnight in and around Gaza City where the Al Shifa hospital, Gaza&#39;s largest, is located.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ashraf Al-Qidra, who represents the health ministry in &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/what-is-palestinian-group-hamas-2023-10-30/&quot;>;Hamas-controlled&lt;/a>; Gaza, said the hospital had ceased functioning since Saturday, after it ran out of fuel. He said two babies had died in an incubator as a result.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;We are using all and primitive means to try not to lose more lives,&quot; Al-Qidra told Reuters. &quot;But unless a solution is found to provide us with fuel or electricity the patients and injured are at risk of death.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Israel&#39;s chief military spokesperson, Rear Admiral Daniel Hagari, said the Israeli military would help evacuate babies from the hospital, at the request of the staff at Al Shifa. Al-Qidra had said there were 45 babies in total.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Asked about the evacuations, Al-Qidra said: &quot;We have not been informed about any mechanism to get the babies out to a safer hospital. So far we are praying for their safety and not to lose more of them.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Earlier, the World Health Organisation expressed &quot;grave concern&quot; for the safety of everyone trapped in the hospital by the fighting and said it had lost communications with its contacts there.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Israel has said doctors, patients and thousands of evacuees who have taken refuge at hospitals in northern &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/gazas-centuries-war-brief-history-2023-10-30/&quot;>;Gaza&lt;/a>; must leave so it can tackle Hamas gunmen who it says have placed command centres under and around them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hamas denies using hospitals this way. Medical staff say patients could die if they are moved and Palestinian officials say Israeli fire makes it dangerous for others to leave.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Israeli Agriculture Minister Avi Dichter called the evacuations &quot;Gaza&#39;s Nakba&quot; - a reference to &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/palestinians-leaving-besieged-gaza-city-fear-new-nakba-2023-11-09/&quot;>;mass dispossessions&lt;/a>; of Palestinians after Israel was founded in 1948.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Operationally there&#39;s no way to conduct a war the way the IDF (Israel Defense Forces) wants to conduct it inside Gaza territories,&quot; Dichter said. &quot;I don&#39;t know how it will end.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Al Shifa staff told Reuters there had been continuous bombardment for more than 24 hours. Most hospital staff and people sheltering there had left, but 500 patients remained.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The military wing of Hamas ally Islamic Jihad, the Al-Quds Brigades, said it was &quot;engaged in violent clashes in the vicinity of Al Shifa Medical Complex, Al Nasr neighbourhood, and Al Shati camp in Gaza.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Al Nasr is home to several major hospitals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Israel said earlier it had killed what it called a Hamas &quot;terrorist&quot; who it said had prevented the evacuation of another hospital in the north, which Palestinian officials have said is out of service and surrounded by tanks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In London, at least 300,000 pro-Palestinian &lt;a href=&quot;/world/huge-crowds-expected-london-pro-palestinian-rally-police-gear-trouble-2023-11-11/&quot;>;demonstrators&lt;/a>; marched and police arrested over 120 people as they sought to stop far-right counter-protesters ambushing the rally. Over 20,000 people joined a pro-Palestinian rally in &lt;a href=&quot;/world/more-than-20000-people-join-pro-palestinian-rally-brussels-2023-11-11/&quot;>;Brussels&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meeting in Saudi Arabia, Muslim and Arab countries called for an &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/saudi-arabia-host-extraordinary-joint-islamic-arab-summit-riyadh-saturday-2023-11-10/&quot;>;immediate end&lt;/a>; to military operations in Gaza, rejecting Israel&#39;s justification of self-defence. A communique issued at the summit urged the International Criminal Court to investigate &quot;war crimes and crimes against humanity that Israel is committing.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;h2>;Related Galleries:&lt;/h2>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/BO2RTHFZSBNQNAYOEPI4ZJ67DA.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;A Palestinian child wounded in Israeli strikes waits to receive treatment at Nasser hospital in Khan Younis in the southern Gaza Strip November 12, 2023. REUTERS/Mohammed Salem&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/IUSA7TPSBVO7LPZW25XK77LVUY.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;A Palestinian child wounded in Israeli strikes amid the ongoing conflict between Israel and Palestinian group Hamas waits to receive treatment at Nasser hospital in Khan Younis in the southern Gaza Strip November 12, 2023. REUTERS/Mohammed Salem&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/2T3DUMUUGVIIJBE355D7ISXRZ4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Palestinians wounded in Israeli strikes are assisted out of an ambulance to receive treatment at Nasser hospital in Khan Younis in the southern Gaza Strip November 12, 2023. REUTERS/Mohammed Salem&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CVJ6CWUL6ROE3HNYQ3UJGU2ZXY.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Smoke rises as displaced Palestinians take shelter at Al Shifa hospital, amid the ongoing conflict between Hamas and Israel, in Gaza City, November 8, 2023. REUTERS/Doaa Rouqa/File Photo&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WGEQBHIMHZIOHAYE6GX5PNHY5U.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;A Palestinian reacts at the site of an Israeli strike on a house belonging to Fojo family in Rafah in the southern Gaza Strip November 11, 2023. REUTERS/Hatem Khaled &lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/6EJSOIAHXFOAXKJ4HJIVXDZICA.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Israeli soldiers take a position inside the Gaza Strip, amid the ongoing ground operation of the Israeli army against Palestinian Islamist group Hamas, according to the Israeli Defense Forces (IDF), in this handout picture obtained by Reuters on November 11, 2023. Israeli Defense Forces/Handout via REUTERS &lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YSHYATQTCFJWNGVZV2SXUGVZLY.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Israeli soldiers operate inside the Gaza Strip, amid the ongoing ground operation of the Israeli army against Palestinian Islamist group Hamas, according to the Israeli Defense Forces (IDF), in this handout picture obtained by Reuters on November 11, 2023. Israeli Defense Forces/Handout via REUTERS &lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/DSPONO5HIZJ7RJ3X5P2I4IAA2A.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;A girl is assisted as Palestinians search for casualties at the site of an Israeli strike on a house, in Rafah in the southern Gaza Strip November 11, 2023. REUTERS/Hatem Khaled &lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/3SASITWRMFPZJMT6L5M7N2TFZ4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Smoke rises over Gaza as seen from southern Israel, amid the ongoing conflict between Israel and the Palestinian group Hamas, November 11, 2023. REUTERS/Alexander Ermochenko&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 16:55:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel says it“s ready to evacuate babies from Gaza hospital as fighting rages]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/israel-palestinians/israel-offers-to-evacuate-babies-from-main-gaza-hospital-amid-fierce-fighting-idUSKBN3260F4]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-12T04:07:20Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;video controls src=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Palestinian officials said two babies had died and dozens more were at risk after fuel ran out at Gaza&#39;s largest hospital on Saturday (November 11), while Israel said it was ready to evacuate babies from the facility. Emma Jehle produced this report.&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Israel&#39;s military said it was ready to evacuate babies from Gaza&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/al-shifa-gazas-largest-hospital-headlines-2023-11-10/&quot;>;largest hospital&lt;/a>; on Sunday, where Palestinian officials said two newborns died and dozens more were at risk after fuel ran out amid intense fighting in the area.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the humanitarian situation worsened, Gaza&#39;s border authority said the Rafah crossing into Egypt would reopen on Sunday for foreign passport holders after closing on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hamas said it had completely or partially destroyed more than 160 Israeli military targets in Gaza, including more than 25 vehicles in the past 48 hours. An Israeli military spokesperson said Hamas had lost control of northern Gaza.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At a news conference late on Saturday, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu announced the deaths of five more Israeli soldiers in Gaza. The Israeli military said 46 had been killed since its ground operations there began.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Israel said rockets were still being fired from Gaza into southern Israel, where it has said about 1,200 people were killed and more than 200 taken hostage by Hamas last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Palestinian officials said on Friday that 11,078 Gaza residents had been killed in air and artillery strikes since Oct. 7, around 40% of them children.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Israel&#39;s three major TV news channels, without citing named sources, said there was some progress toward a deal to free hostages held by Hamas in Gaza.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Netanyahu said he would not discuss details of any possible deal, which according to N12 News would involve 50 to 100 women, children and elderly being released in stages during a three to five day pause in fighting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the reports, Israel would release women and minor Palestinian prisoners and consider letting fuel in to Gaza, while reserving the right to resume fighting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Tel Aviv, thousands joined a rally to support families of the hostages.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gaza residents said Israeli troops, who went to war to eliminate Hamas after its deadly cross-border assault on Oct. 7, had been &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/israel-targets-hamas-tunnels-new-phase-gaza-war-2023-11-07/&quot;>;clashing with&lt;/a>; Hamas gunmen all night in and around Gaza City where the Al Shifa hospital, Gaza&#39;s largest, is located.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ashraf Al-Qidra, who represents the health ministry in &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/what-is-palestinian-group-hamas-2023-10-30/&quot;>;Hamas-controlled&lt;/a>; Gaza, said the hospital suspended operations after fuel ran out.他说，两名婴儿因此死在保温箱中。 He said there were 45 babies in total.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said Israeli shelling killed a patient in intensive care and that Israeli snipers on rooftops fired into the medical complex from time to time, limiting people&#39;s ability to move.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The World Health Organisation expressed &quot;grave concern&quot; for the safety of everyone trapped in the hospital by the fighting and said it had lost communications with its contacts there.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Israel&#39;s chief military spokesperson, Rear Admiral Daniel Hagari, said the Israeli military would help evacuate babies from the hospital, at the request of the staff at Al Shifa.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Muhammad Abu Salmiya, the hospital&#39;s director, told Al Jazeera TV, that protecting patients was the priority.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;We contacted the Red Cross and informed them we ran out of water, oxygen, fuel, and everything,&quot; Abu Salmiya said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The premature babies, patients of the intensive care, and even wounded people couldn&#39;t survive with the lack of electricity... If the occupation forces want to evacuate the wounded people to any place in the world that is safer than the Gaza Strip, we are not against that.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Israel has said doctors, patients and thousands of evacuees who have taken refuge at hospitals in northern &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/gazas-centuries-war-brief-history-2023-10-30/&quot;>;Gaza&lt;/a>; must leave so it can tackle Hamas gunmen who it says have placed command centres under and around them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hamas denies using hospitals this way. Medical staff say patients could die if they are moved and Palestinian officials say Israeli fire makes it dangerous for others to leave.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Israeli Agriculture Minister Avi Dichter called the evacuations &quot;Gaza&#39;s Nakba&quot; - a reference to &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/palestinians-leaving-besieged-gaza-city-fear-new-nakba-2023-11-09/&quot;>;mass dispossessions&lt;/a>; of Palestinians after Israel was founded in 1948.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Operationally there&#39;s no way to conduct a war the way the IDF (Israel Defense Forces) wants to conduct it inside Gaza territories,&quot; Dichter said. &quot;I don&#39;t know how it will end.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ahmed al-Mokhallalati, a senior plastic surgeon at Al Shifa, told Reuters there had been continuous bombardment for more than 24 hours. He said most hospital staff and people sheltering there had left, but 500 patients remained.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;It&#39;s totally a war zone. It&#39;s a totally scary atmosphere here in the hospital,&quot; he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The military wing of Hamas ally Islamic Jihad, the Al-Quds Brigades, said it was &quot;engaged in violent clashes in the vicinity of Al Shifa Medical Complex, Al Nasr neighbourhood, and Al Shati camp in Gaza.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Al Nasr is home to several major hospitals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Israel said earlier it had killed what it called a Hamas &quot;terrorist&quot; who it said had prevented the evacuation of another hospital in the north, which Palestinian officials have said is out of service and surrounded by tanks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It said Ahmed Siam was killed along with other militants while hiding in the Al Buraq school. Palestinian officials told Reuters on Friday at least 25 Palestinians had been killed in an Israeli strike at the school, which was packed with evacuees.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In London, at least 300,000 pro-Palestinian &lt;a href=&quot;/world/huge-crowds-expected-london-pro-palestinian-rally-police-gear-trouble-2023-11-11/&quot;>;demonstrators&lt;/a>; marched and police arrested over 120 people as they sought to stop far-right counter-protesters ambushing the rally. Over 20,000 people joined a pro-Palestinian rally in &lt;a href=&quot;/world/more-than-20000-people-join-pro-palestinian-rally-brussels-2023-11-11/&quot;>;Brussels&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meeting in Saudi Arabia, Muslim and Arab countries called for an &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/saudi-arabia-host-extraordinary-joint-islamic-arab-summit-riyadh-saturday-2023-11-10/&quot;>;immediate end&lt;/a>; to military operations in Gaza, rejecting Israel&#39;s justification of self-defence. A communique issued at the summit urged the International Criminal Court to investigate &quot;war crimes and crimes against humanity that Israel is committing.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;h2>;Related Galleries:&lt;/h2>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/6EJSOIAHXFOAXKJ4HJIVXDZICA.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Israeli soldiers take a position inside the Gaza Strip, amid the ongoing ground operation of the Israeli army against Palestinian Islamist group Hamas, according to the Israeli Defense Forces (IDF), in this handout picture obtained by Reuters on November 11, 2023. Israeli Defense Forces/Handout via REUTERS &lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CVJ6CWUL6ROE3HNYQ3UJGU2ZXY.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Smoke rises as displaced Palestinians take shelter at Al Shifa hospital, amid the ongoing conflict between Hamas and Israel, in Gaza City, November 8, 2023. REUTERS/Doaa Rouqa/File Photo&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WGEQBHIMHZIOHAYE6GX5PNHY5U.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;A Palestinian reacts at the site of an Israeli strike on a house belonging to Fojo family in Rafah in the southern Gaza Strip November 11, 2023. REUTERS/Hatem Khaled &lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YSHYATQTCFJWNGVZV2SXUGVZLY.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Israeli soldiers operate inside the Gaza Strip, amid the ongoing ground operation of the Israeli army against Palestinian Islamist group Hamas, according to the Israeli Defense Forces (IDF), in this handout picture obtained by Reuters on November 11, 2023. Israeli Defense Forces/Handout via REUTERS &lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/DSPONO5HIZJ7RJ3X5P2I4IAA2A.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;A girl is assisted as Palestinians search for casualties at the site of an Israeli strike on a house, in Rafah in the southern Gaza Strip November 11, 2023. REUTERS/Hatem Khaled &lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/3SASITWRMFPZJMT6L5M7N2TFZ4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Smoke rises over Gaza as seen from southern Israel, amid the ongoing conflict between Israel and the Palestinian group Hamas, November 11, 2023. REUTERS/Alexander Ermochenko&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Israel says it“s ready to evacuate babies from Gaza hospital as fighting rages]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/israel-palestinians/as-fighting-rages-israel-says-ready-to-evacuate-babies-from-gazas-main-hospital-idUSKBN3260F4]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-11-11T23:41:15Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;Israel&#39;s military said it was ready to evacuate babies from Gaza&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/al-shifa-gazas-largest-hospital-headlines-2023-11-10/&quot;>;largest hospital&lt;/a>; on Sunday, where Palestinian officials said two newborns died and dozens more were at risk after fuel ran out amid intense fighting in the area.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;As the humanitarian situation worsened, Gaza&#39;s border authority said the Rafah crossing into Egypt would reopen on Sunday for foreign passport holders after closing on Friday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hamas said it had completely or partially destroyed more than 160 Israeli military targets in Gaza, including more than 25 vehicles in the past 48 hours. An Israeli military spokesperson said Hamas had lost control of northern Gaza.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At a news conference late on Saturday, Israeli Prime Minister Benjamin Netanyahu announced the deaths of five more Israeli soldiers in Gaza. The Israeli military said 46 had been killed since its ground operations there began.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Israel&#39;s three major TV news channels, without citing named sources, said there was some progress toward a deal to free hostages held by Hamas in Gaza.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Netanyahu said he would not discuss details of any possible deal, which according to N12 News would involve 50 to 100 women, children and elderly being released in stages during a three to five day pause in fighting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;According to the reports, Israel would release women and minor Palestinian prisoners from its jails and consider letting fuel in to Gaza, while reserving the right to resume fighting after the deal.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;When we have something concrete to say then we will update the families and bring it to the government,&quot; Netanyahu said. &quot;Until then silence would be best.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Tel Aviv, thousands joined a rally to support families of the hostages.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Gaza residents said Israeli troops, who went to war to eliminate Hamas after its bloody cross-border assault on Oct. 7, had been &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/israel-targets-hamas-tunnels-new-phase-gaza-war-2023-11-07/&quot;>;clashing with&lt;/a>; Hamas gunmen all night in and around Gaza City where the Al Shifa hospital, Gaza&#39;s largest, is located.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ashraf Al-Qidra, who represents the health ministry in &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/what-is-palestinian-group-hamas-2023-10-30/&quot;>;Hamas-controlled&lt;/a>; Gaza, said the hospital suspended operations after fuel ran out.他说，两名婴儿因此死在保温箱中。 He said there were 45 babies in total.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He said Israeli shelling killed a patient in intensive care and that Israeli snipers on rooftops fired into the medical complex from time to time, limiting people&#39;s ability to move.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;We are besieged inside the Al Shifa Medical Complex, and the (Israeli) occupation has targeted most of the buildings inside,&quot; he told Reuters by phone.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Colonel Moshe Tetro, head of coordination and liaison at COGAT, the Israeli defence ministry body handling civil affairs in Gaza, said there had been clashes but added: &quot;There is no shooting at the hospital and there is no siege.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Israel&#39;s chief military spokesperson, Rear Admiral Daniel Hagari, said the Israeli military would help evacuate babies from the hospital.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The staff of the Shifa hospital has requested that tomorrow we help the babies in the pediatric department to get to a safer hospital. We will provide the assistance needed,&quot; he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Israel has said doctors, patients and thousands of evacuees who have taken refuge at hospitals in northern &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/gazas-centuries-war-brief-history-2023-10-30/&quot;>;Gaza&lt;/a>; must leave so it can tackle Hamas gunmen who it says have placed command centres under and around them.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Hamas denies using hospitals this way. Medical staff say patients could die if they are moved and Palestinian officials say Israeli fire makes it dangerous for others to leave.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Israeli Agriculture Minister Avi Dichter was asked by N12 about images of Gaza residents evacuating south and whether that was a goal of the war, or only temporary.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;He described the situation as being &quot;Gaza&#39;s Nakba&quot; - a reference to &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/palestinians-leaving-besieged-gaza-city-fear-new-nakba-2023-11-09/&quot;>;mass dispossessions&lt;/a>; of Palestinians after Israel was founded in 1948.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Operationally there&#39;s no way to conduct a war the way the IDF (Israel Defense Forces) wants to conduct it inside Gaza territories while the masses are between the tanks and soldiers,&quot; Dichter said. &quot;I don&#39;t know how it will end.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Ahmed al-Mokhallalati, a senior plastic surgeon at Al Shifa, told Reuters there had been continuous bombardment for more than 24 hours. He said most hospital staff and people sheltering there had left, but 500 patients remained.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;It&#39;s totally a war zone. It&#39;s a totally scary atmosphere here in the hospital,&quot; he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The military wing of Hamas ally Islamic Jihad, the Al-Quds Brigades, said it was &quot;engaged in violent clashes in the vicinity of Al Shifa Medical Complex, Al Nasr neighbourhood, and Al Shati camp in Gaza.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Al Nasr is home to several major hospitals.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Israel said earlier it had killed what it called a Hamas &quot;terrorist&quot; who it said had prevented the evacuation of another hospital in the north, which Palestinian officials have said is out of service and surrounded by tanks.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;It said Ahmed Siam was killed along with other militants while hiding in the Al Buraq school. Palestinian officials told Reuters on Friday at least 25 Palestinians had been killed in an Israeli strike at the school, which was packed with evacuees.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Israel said rockets were still being fired from Gaza into southern Israel, where it has said about 1,200 people were killed and more than 200 taken hostage by Hamas last month.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Palestinian officials said on Friday that 11,078 Gaza residents had been killed in air and artillery strikes since Oct. 7, around 40% of them children.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Israel said it had increased the number of places in which it said it would stop firing for several hours at a time so Gazans could move south, and a military spokesperson said the last three days had seen the evacuation of at least 150,000 people.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In London, at least 300,000 pro-Palestinian &lt;a href=&quot;/world/huge-crowds-expected-london-pro-palestinian-rally-police-gear-trouble-2023-11-11/&quot;>;demonstrators&lt;/a>; marched and police arrested over 120 people as they sought to stop far-right counter-protesters ambushing the rally. Over 20,000 people joined a pro-Palestinian rally in &lt;a href=&quot;/world/more-than-20000-people-join-pro-palestinian-rally-brussels-2023-11-11/&quot;>;Brussels&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Meeting in Saudi Arabia, Muslim and Arab countries called for an &lt;a href=&quot;/world/middle-east/saudi-arabia-host-extraordinary-joint-islamic-arab-summit-riyadh-saturday-2023-11-10/&quot;>;immediate end&lt;/a>; to military operations in Gaza, rejecting Israel&#39;s justification of self-defence.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;(This story has been refiled to fix a typo in &#39;newborns&#39; in paragraph 1)&lt;/p>;&lt;h2>;Related Galleries:&lt;/h2>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/6EJSOIAHXFOAXKJ4HJIVXDZICA.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Israeli soldiers take a position inside the Gaza Strip, amid the ongoing ground operation of the Israeli army against Palestinian Islamist group Hamas, according to the Israeli Defense Forces (IDF), in this handout picture obtained by Reuters on November 11, 2023. Israeli Defense Forces/Handout via REUTERS &lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/CVJ6CWUL6ROE3HNYQ3UJGU2ZXY.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Smoke rises as displaced Palestinians take shelter at Al Shifa hospital, amid the ongoing conflict between Hamas and Israel, in Gaza City, November 8, 2023. REUTERS/Doaa Rouqa/File Photo&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WGEQBHIMHZIOHAYE6GX5PNHY5U.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;A Palestinian reacts at the site of an Israeli strike on a house belonging to Fojo family in Rafah in the southern Gaza Strip November 11, 2023. REUTERS/Hatem Khaled &lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/YSHYATQTCFJWNGVZV2SXUGVZLY.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Israeli soldiers operate inside the Gaza Strip, amid the ongoing ground operation of the Israeli army against Palestinian Islamist group Hamas, according to the Israeli Defense Forces (IDF), in this handout picture obtained by Reuters on November 11, 2023. Israeli Defense Forces/Handout via REUTERS &lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/DSPONO5HIZJ7RJ3X5P2I4IAA2A.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;A girl is assisted as Palestinians search for casualties at the site of an Israeli strike on a house, in Rafah in the southern Gaza Strip November 11, 2023. REUTERS/Hatem Khaled &lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/3SASITWRMFPZJMT6L5M7N2TFZ4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Smoke rises over Gaza as seen from southern Israel, amid the ongoing conflict between Israel and the Palestinian group Hamas, November 11, 2023. REUTERS/Alexander Ermochenko&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Sun, 12 Nov 2023 07:55:03 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>