<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>路透社</title><description>路透社全文RSS。获取更多全文RSS：https://feedx.net</description><link/> http://reuters.com <item><title><![CDATA[Biden, Brazil“s Lula focus on dangers to democracy, aim to advance workers“ rights]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/un-assembly-usa-brazil/biden-brazils-lula-focus-on-dangers-to-democracy-aim-to-advance-workers-rights-idUSKBN30Q0MX]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20T18:28:23Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;美国总统乔·拜登和巴西总统路易斯·伊纳西奥·卢拉·达席尔瓦强调了他们对支持民主的共同承诺，发起了一项周三的倡议旨在促进劳动人民的权利，这是两位领导人的主要焦点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登和卢拉在联合国大会高级别会议期间举行的双边会议上发表讲话，强调了体面工作、良好工资以及确保工人从社会广泛开展的数字和绿色能源转型中受益的重要性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“西半球最大的两个民主国家正在捍卫世界各地的人权，拜登告诉卢拉。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国-巴西工人权利伙伴关系将作为一项双边倡议开始，但两国将鼓励其他国家及时加入，拜登政府高级官员表示，但没有透露其他可能的参与者。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卢拉警告说，世界各地的民主国家正受到威胁，他表示，加强工人权利至关重要，并表示新举措将有助于“激发人们的热情”。 “为工薪家庭带来希望”，同时加深两国之间的关系。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“这不仅仅是另一项双边关系。我们在这里建立的是一种信仰关系，也是美国与巴西之间平等伙伴关系的新时代，”他说，并补充道，“贫困和不平等不符合任何人的利益。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登和卢拉在第二次面对面会议开始时交换了有关体面工作重要性的个人故事。这次会议恰逢 &lt;a href=&quot;/business/autos-transportation/canadian-union-says-negotiations-with-ford- are-continuing-2023-09-19/&quot;>;12,700 名美国汽车工人联合会成员罢工&lt;/a>;反对福特&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/FN&quot; target=&quot;_blank &quot;>;(FN)&lt;/a>;，通用汽车&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GM.N&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(GM.N)&lt;/a>;和克莱斯勒母公司 Stellantis &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/STLAM.MI&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(STLAM.MI)&lt;/a>; 敦促他们提高薪酬和&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;卢拉指出，他的教育仅包括职业培训，并且他在一家工厂工作了 27 年。他说，他的劳工部长周二会见了罢工工人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p >;“我认为这对我们来说是一个黄金时刻，也是我们未来的可能性，”他说。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登呼吁罢工工人获得与汽车制造商一致的“创纪录的合同” ”最近的结果，引用了美国财政部最近的一份报告，该报告显示了工会化的重要性以及它如何改善经济成果。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当&lt;a href=&quot;/world/us/biden-meet-brazils-lula- talk-climate-democracy-2023-02-10/&quot;>;卢拉二月份在白宫拜访了拜登&lt;/a>;，两位领导人都高度关注气候危机，并承诺加快采取措施保护亚马逊以及争取和推进民主价值观的必要性。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一位不愿透露姓名的美国高级官员表示，该倡议将解决强迫劳动和童工问题、清洁能源和数字经济对工人的影响转型、零工经济以及工作场所对妇女、LGBTQ+ 人群以及少数种族和族裔的歧视。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两位领导人计划在 20 国集团主要经济体等多边论坛上提出这些问题，巴西将在这些论坛上提出这些问题。巴西政府在一份声明中表示，该倡议旨在“让私营部门合作伙伴参与创新方法，在关键生产链中创造体面就业机会”。 ，打击工作场所的歧视并促进多样性，”声明称。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这次会议是美国试图加强与巴西关系的努力的一部分，巴西一直寻求与中国保持密切关系其主要贸易伙伴，尽管北京和华盛顿之间的紧张局势急剧加剧。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;另一名官员表示，华盛顿非常明确地表达了对中国侵犯人权、经济行为和军事扩张的担忧，并将与巴西就这些问题进行对话。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这位不愿透露姓名的官员补充说，与中国和其他国家建立关系是巴西的主权。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;一位官员补充道，预计两位领导人还将讨论海地日益严重的人道主义危机，以及肯尼亚提出的领导多国部队支持改善安全的提议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴西可以发挥重要作用这位官员补充道，让中国和其他联合国安理会成员国了解参与海地事务的重要性。&lt;/p>;&lt;h2>;相关图库：&lt;/h2>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east- 2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/5CDBT6LEZFINXLZ26TFX3IXNKY.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;美国总统乔·拜登在会议期间与巴西总统路易斯·伊纳西奥·卢拉·达席尔瓦交谈2023 年 9 月 20 日在美国纽约举行的第 78 届联合国大会期间。REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2. images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/K5AB7QTEKBJ5PA7I6IJJE24ZXI.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;美国总统乔·拜登在场外会议期间向巴西总统路易斯·伊纳西奥·卢拉·达席尔瓦致意第 78 届联合国大会，美国纽约，2023 年 9 月 20 日。 REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing .com/reuters/7U2RRWHMFJMWTLJHH7WVBSYEXI.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;美国总统乔·拜登在与巴西总统路易斯·伊纳西奥·卢拉·达席尔瓦及其代表团会晤时听取了关于2023 年 9 月 20 日，第 78 届联合国大会在美国纽约举行。REUTERS/Kevin Lamarque&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images. arcpublishing.com/reuters/EB2WOGA2EZP23GMKORMASHVYRE.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;美国总统乔·拜登和巴西总统路易斯·伊纳西奥·卢拉·达席尔瓦走下白宫的柱廊，美国华盛顿，2023 年 2 月 10 日。Andrew Caballero-Reynolds/Pool via REUTERS/File Photo&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href= &quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; 样式=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 02:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[UAW, Detroit Three in standoff as wider strike looms]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/autos-labor-uaw/uaw-detroit-three-in-standoff-as-wider-strike-looms-idUSKBN30Q03B]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20T18:29:52Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;视频控件 src=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;/video>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;尽管底特律三大汽车制造商面临美国汽车工人联合会单独协调罢工可能升级的情况，但福特周二晚间与加拿大工会达成了初步协议，美国汽车行业避免了更多痛苦。朱利安·萨特思韦特 (Julian Satterthwaite) 报道。&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;周三，底特律三大汽车制造商和美国汽车工人联合会在劳资谈判中仍存在很大分歧，距离工会取得重大进展或升级罢工的最后期限还不到 48 小时。新的停工。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在福特&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies”之后的第二天，协调罢工的第六天，工会代表和公司管理层继续进行会谈/FN&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(FN)&lt;/a>; 避免了加拿大工人的罢工。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但几乎没有迹象表明取得了重大进展，底特律汽车制造商越来越直言不讳地拒绝 UAW 的要求：包括加薪 40%、每周工作 32 小时以及结束新员工工资较低的分层工资结构。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“基本现实是，UAW 的要求可以用一个词来描述——站不住脚的，”通用汽车总裁马克罗伊斯周三在底特律自由报发表的一篇评论文章中表示。 “过去已经清楚地表明，罢工中没有人会获胜。我们提供了创纪录的报价。这是事实。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;UAW 对福特、通用汽车发起了罢工&lt;a href=&quot;https上周，://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GM.N&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(GM.N)&lt;/a>; 和 Stellantis 分别瞄准了两家公司的一家美国组装厂。这些罢工已导致密歇根州、俄亥俄州和密苏里州的工厂停产，这些工厂生产福特野马、吉普牧马人和雪佛兰科罗拉多以及其他受欢迎的车型。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国汽车工人联合会表示，将宣布对更多美国工厂进行罢工。如果在美国东部时间中午（格林尼治标准时间 1600）之前与汽车制造商的谈判没有取得重大进展，则周五。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;谈判中最大的问题是工人的加薪和福利水平。三大汽车制造商提议在其拟议交易的 4-1/2 年期限内加薪 20%，尽管这只是 UAW 要求的到 2027 年的一半。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;UAW 工人也希望结束他们说，分层工资结构在新员工和老员工之间造成了巨大差距，迫使一些人&lt;a href=&quot;/world/us/ohio-to-michigan-highway-us-auto-workers-drive-solidarity-2023- 09-20/&quot;>;做两份工作&lt;/a>;以维持收支平衡。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;大约 12,700 名工人因 UAW 的&lt;a href=&quot;/business/autos-transportation/canadian -union-says-negotiations-with-ford-are-continuing-2023-09-19/&quot;>;协调美国在三巨头工作的 146,000 名工会成员中采取的行动&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; “我们不是在玩。我们对此很认真。”24 岁的维克多·霍洛威 (Victor Holloway) 来自密歇根州韦斯特兰，自 2021 年以来一直在密歇根州韦恩的福特工厂工作。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;通用汽车表示，其位于堪萨斯州费尔法克斯的工厂正在闲置周三，由于附近的密苏里州罢工导致零部件短缺，该汽车工厂的 2,000 名小时工将暂时休假。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;分析师预计，工厂将生产利润更高的皮卡，例如如果罢工继续下去，福特的 F-150、通用汽车的雪佛兰索罗德和 Stellantis 的 Ram 将成为下一个罢工目标。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;福特在周二晚间达成了最后一刻的协议，以避免其加拿大工厂发生罢工。代表约 5,600 名加拿大汽车工人的 Unifor 一直威胁说，如果未达成协议，将在该国的所有三个福特工厂举行罢工。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这项为期三年的协议仍有待 Unifor 批准。福特加拿大部门在一份声明中表示，该公司不会透露暂定交易的细节。 Unifor 寻求提高工资和养老金，以及向电动汽车过渡的支持以及福特的额外投资承诺。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;加拿大工会现在将转而与通用汽车和 Stellantis 敲定交易。在福特谈判继续进行期间，这些最后期限被延长。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;福特周二表示，正在为美国进一步停工制定应急计划，包括计划运送让福特汽车继续行驶的零部件，特别是让急救人员留在路上以及其他基本服务的运行。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;福特表示，它继续与美国汽车工人联合会进行谈判，重点是达成一项奖励员工并允许公司投资和发展的协议。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; Stellantis 周三表示，由于俄亥俄州托莱多吉普车组装厂发生罢工，该公司将暂时解雇俄亥俄州 68 名员工，并预计印第安纳州另外 300 名工人将被暂时解雇。 Stellantis 预计印第安纳州科科莫的 Kokomo Transmission 和 Kokomo Casting 也会采取类似行动，预计将影响另外 300 名员工。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;146,000 名 UAW 汽车工人的全面罢工可能会导致美国年化增长率小幅拖累 0.2%如果罢工行动持续一个月，本季度的国内生产总值&lt;a href=&quot;/business/autos-transportation/auto-strike-could-be-speed-bump-hard-driven-us-economy-2023-09- 15/&quot;>;RSM 估计&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;白宫表示，美国总统乔·拜登周三佩戴红领带，以声援 UAW 工人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;拜登已站在一边与美国汽车工人联合会合作，并呼吁汽车制造商向罢工工人做出更多让步，但他的&lt;a href=&quot;/business/autos-transportation/sidelined-uaw-strikes-biden-white-house-talks-economic-aid-2023-09- 19/&quot;>;消息人士告诉路透社，由于缺乏引导谈判的法律权力，政府一直陷入困境&lt;/a>;，并且正在努力找出美国汽车工人联合会主席肖恩·费恩的谈判策略。&lt;/p>;&lt;h2>;相关画廊： &lt;/h2>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/JL6CY42BONJIFNQBBWUBQ74ICM.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999 ;&quot;>;2023 年 9 月 19 日，罢工的美国汽车工人联合会成员在美国俄亥俄州托莱多的 Stellantis Jeep 工厂外举行纠察。REUTERS/Rebecca Cook/File Photo&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront -us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/OFCB7HY4ZZJ37LPEUUDAR72HWM.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;罢工美国汽车工人联合会成员 Candis Holmes 在福特外的纠察队位于美国密歇根州韦恩的密歇根装配厂，2023 年 9 月 19 日。REUTERS/Rebecca Cook/File Photo&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing。 com/reuters/R6OQJDSNXJNKRNTU2X3P42F43I.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;奥克维尔装配厂的墙上可以看到福特标志，UNIFOR 的工人们正在附近参加批准投票，2016 年 11 月 6 日于加拿大安大略省奥克维尔。 REUTERS/Chris Helgren&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WHTLQRI6URJ2BG2WMW6RRB4NRE .jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;2023 年 5 月 26 日，鸟瞰图显示加拿大安大略省奥克维尔的福特奥克维尔装配厂最近生产的车辆。 REUTERS/Carlos Osorio /文件照片&lt;/小>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 02:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Azerbaijani leader sends Karabakh Armenians and Armenia message of cooperation and peace]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/armenia-azerbaijan-aliyev/azerbaijani-leader-sends-karabakh-armenians-and-armenia-message-of-cooperation-and-peace-idUSKBN30Q1S9]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20T18:51:35Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;阿塞拜疆总统伊尔哈姆·阿利耶夫周三向分离的纳戈尔诺-卡拉巴赫地区的亚美尼亚人和邻国亚美尼亚提出了合作前景他的部队&lt;a href=&quot;/world/us-calls-azerbaijan-halt-karabakh-attack-Russia-urges-return-ceasefire-2023-09-20/&quot;>;控制飞地后实现和解与共同发展。 &lt;/a>;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他在电视讲话中表示，阿塞拜疆已恢复对其领土的完全主权，现在希望整合卡拉巴赫人口，将该地区变成“天堂”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他表示阿塞拜疆对卡拉巴赫的亚美尼亚人民没有任何反对意见——“他们是我们的公民”——而只是反对他们的“犯罪”分裂主义领导层。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他的话似乎旨在回应亚美尼亚领导人关于巴库计划“种族清洗”的指控“卡拉巴赫有 12 万亚美尼亚人口，更广泛地说，巴库和埃里温之间数十年的公开敌对和不信任。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;许多阿塞拜疆人在 20 世纪 90 年代初逃离该地区后希望返回该地区，当时亚美尼亚人占领了该地区。在一场与苏联解体以及亚美尼亚和阿塞拜疆独立相关的战争中控制纳戈尔诺-卡拉巴赫。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;数千名亚美尼亚语使用者担心未来可能会发生什么，早些时候聚集在斯捷潘纳克特机场，卡拉巴赫的首都被阿塞拜疆称为汉肯迪，而其他人则在俄罗斯维和人员的庇护下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿塞拜疆表示，阿塞拜疆重视亚美尼亚这一事实，因为纳戈尔诺-卡拉巴赫三十年来一直依赖亚美尼亚的支持，但亚美尼亚并没有寻求干预。参与了巴库的军事行动，但仍保持“警惕”。他说，这改善了和平谈判的前景。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;巴库坚称亚美尼亚在纳戈尔诺-卡拉巴赫保留军队，违反了 2020 年战争后达成的停火协议，其中阿塞拜疆收回了纳戈尔诺-卡拉巴赫的大片土地。以及卡拉巴赫亚美尼亚人的山区飞地周围。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;埃里温否认了这一点，但阿利耶夫表示阿塞拜疆军队发现了 100 辆亚美尼亚坦克和装甲车。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;他说他的士兵已经履行了这一义务在迫使分离主义当局投降的 24 小时攻势中避免伤害卡拉巴赫平民和民用基础设施。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;一名分离主义亚美尼亚人权官员周三表示，至少 200 人被杀，战斗中有400多人受伤。这位官员说，死者中有十人是平民，其中五人是儿童。路透社无法核实这些数字。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿塞拜疆在 2020 年取得的进展让亚美尼亚几乎没有选择帮助卡拉巴赫保卫自己，新的权力平衡为两个邻国之间的新和平谈判奠定了基础。跨境战斗零星爆发。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;阿利耶夫表示，阿塞拜疆重新控制纳戈尔诺-卡拉巴赫不仅将消除长期的和平障碍，而且为这三个国家加强合作与发展铺平道路包括格鲁吉亚在内的南高加索地区。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;亚美尼亚总理尼科尔·帕辛扬本月表示，俄罗斯因乌克兰战争而分心，正在逐步减少对该地区的参与。克里姆林宫否认了这一点，称俄罗斯“不会去任何地方”，并将继续作为&lt;a href=&quot;/world/kremlin-rejects-armenian-pms-suggestion-that-Russia-is-quitting-south-caucasus-2023-09 -05/&quot;>;安全保证人&lt;/a>;。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 02:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Fed leaves interest rates unchanged, sees tighter policy through 2024]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/usa-fed/fed-leaves-interest-rates-unchanged-sees-tighter-policy-through-2024-idUSKBN30Q0QQ]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20T18:51:17Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/BDL3ET27EZPSPDW2SBDCWR7ULU。 jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;2018 年 8 月 22 日，一名骑自行车的人经过美国华盛顿特区的美联储大楼。REUTERS/Chris Wattie/档案照片&lt;/小>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;美联储周三维持利率稳定，但加强了鹰派立场，预计年底前将再次加息，货币政策在2024年之前将显着收紧，远超此前预期。&lt;/正如他们在 6 月份所做的那样，美联储政策制定者的中值仍然认为央行基准隔夜利率今年将在 5.50%-5.75% 范围内达到峰值，仅比当前范围高出四分之一个百分点。&lt; /p>;&lt;p>;但从那时起，美联储更新的季度预测显示，与 6 月会议上预期的降息幅度相比，2024 年利率仅下降半个百分点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;随着联邦基金的实施到2024年底，利率将降至5.1%，2025年底将降至3.9%，央行的主要通胀指标预计将在今年年底降至3.3%，明年降至2.5%，到2025年降至2.2%。 2025 年底。美联储预计 2026 年通胀率将回到 2% 的目标，这比一些官员预期的日期要晚。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联邦利率制定机构“通胀仍然较高”公开市场委员会 (FOMC) 在一份政策声明中表示，其中包括将经济和就业增长强于先前预测的预测，并明确考虑“软着陆”的前景。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;金融市场普遍预期，美联储将维持利率不变。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但投资者也一直指望美联储明年大幅降息，这一预期因显示 19 名官员中有 10 名认为明年政策利率将保持在 5% 以上的预测而蒙上阴影&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;声明和预测发布后，面对长期较高的货币政策立场，债券收益率走高，两年期国债收益率升至2007年以来的最高水平。股市最初走弱，而美元兑一篮子主要货币抹去了当天的跌幅。联邦基金期货显示交易者下调了对美联储未来降息的预期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;新的预测包括对经济增长的大幅上调：在早些时候的预测中预计今年经济增长将疲弱至 0.4% 后，美联储目前预计 2023 年经济将增长 2.1%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;预计今年失业率将稳定在 3.8% 左右，到年底将升至 4.1%，这是对经济增长可能性的信任票遏制了自 20 世纪 80 年代以来最严重的通胀爆发，但没有出现重大失业。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但这些预测也威胁到企业和家庭，他们可能面临比美联储激进政策期间已经承受的信贷条件更紧缩和更高的借贷成本。为期两年的遏制通胀之战，在最新预测中体现了“长期走高”的理念。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美联储声明发表后，经济学家认为央行官员更有信心他们能够在不造成更广泛经济痛苦的情况下抑制通胀。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“他们对 2024 年经济增长的上调和对失业率的下调所传达的信息清楚地表明，美联储已经调高了对软着陆的预期惠誉评级美国经济主管 Olu Sonola 表示：“尽管长期利率较高，但美联储的预测让一些观察人士措手不及，尤其是考虑到经济增速比想象的要慢的新观点。”通胀压力下降。预测公司 Inflation Insights 的奥迈尔·谢里夫 (Omair Sharif) 表示，考虑到美联储的前景，货币政策前景出现鹰派转变并不奇怪，同时补充说，在谈到官员的前景时，“对劳动力市场的看法异常乐观，对劳动力市场的看法同样奇怪地悲观”。今年的核心通胀。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美联储声明在为期两天的会议后获得一致通过，标志着新任美联储理事阿德里安娜·库格勒 (Adriana Kugler) 首次登上央行决策舞台。&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 02:55:04 +0800</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[US appeals judge, 96, suspended in rare clash over fitness]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/usa-court-newman-investigation/us-appeals-judge-96-suspended-in-rare-clash-over-fitness-idUSKBN30Q19T]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20T14:09:33Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;华盛顿（路透社）-美国联邦巡回上诉法院周三暂停法官 Pauline Newman 审理新案件关于这位 96 岁法学家担任法官的心理能力的冲突日益加深。&lt;/p>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://static.reuters.com/resources/r/?m=02&amp;d=20230920&amp;t= 2&amp;i=1645293566&amp;r=LYNXMPEJ8J0MS&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;美国联邦巡回上诉法院的美国巡回法官 Pauline Newman 出现在一张未注明日期的照片中。美国联邦巡回上诉法院/路透社的讲义&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;华盛顿特区法院的法官委员会一致表示，纽曼未能配合对其健康状况的调查，并禁止她参加至少一年内不得审理新案件，或者直到她参加法院命令的体检。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;“我们敏锐地意识到，这对于纽曼法官堪称典范且传奇的职业生涯来说并不合适，”该委员会说，但补充说，当“本法院的法官不再有能力履行其司法职责时，它别无选择。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;这种公开且有争议的关于能力的内部争议在法院是极不寻常的。联邦司法机构。纽曼援引两名医生的意见为自己的健康状况进行了辩护，并向华盛顿一家单独的法院提起诉讼，寻求转移或停止调查。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;纽曼的律师格雷格·多林表示，该委员会“忽视了数据或信息”或与其预定目标和结果不一致的意见”，并且法官将对这一命令提出质疑，并继续在法庭上坚持她的主张。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联邦巡回法院的代表拒绝发表评论。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; >;&lt;p>;纽曼是专利法领域备受尊敬的人物和著名的异议者，1984 年被罗纳德·里根总统任命为专注于专利的联邦巡回法院法官，也是美国最年长的在职联邦法官。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;她的案件引发了有关美国老龄化联邦司法机构的敏感问题，该机构的成员被任命为终身法官，可以被弹劾，但不能被迫退休。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联邦法官的平均年龄最近达到了 69 岁的历史新高。 ，根据哈佛医学院弗朗西斯·沉 (Francis Shen) 2020 年在《俄亥俄州法律杂志》上发表的一项研究。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;联邦巡回法院首席法官金伯利·摩尔 (Kimberly Moore) 在 4 月份公开的命令中表示，纽曼表现出认知和认知障碍的迹象。 &lt;/p>;&lt;p>;根据 8 月份公布的文件，法庭工作人员还描述了纽曼的“记忆丧失、混乱、偏执和愤怒的咆哮”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>; p>;&lt;p>;纽曼的律师长期以来一直主张纽曼自己的法院不应主持能力调查。他们在周三公开的一份文件中表示，调查她健康状况的委员会“只对一件事感兴趣——通过行使原始权力让纽曼法官远离法官席。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;美国巡回法官纽曼在美国第五巡回上诉法院的朋友伊迪丝·琼斯 (Edith Jones) 称联邦巡回法庭“本质上存在偏见”，并表示她希望司法机构的国家政策制定机构“司法会议中的负责方”能够介入。&lt;/ p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 02:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Colorado police face trial over death of Elijah McClain]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/usa-race-colorado/colorado-police-face-trial-over-death-of-elijah-mcclain-idUSKBN30Q1C3]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20T18:14:07Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;开庭陈词将于周三开始，这是针对 2019 年黑人伊利亚·麦克莱恩 (Elijah McClain) 死亡案的三项审判中的第一项当科罗拉多州警方与他对峙时，他并没有被怀疑有任何犯罪，将他掐住脖子，并打电话给医护人员，医护人员给了他过量的镇静剂。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;23 岁的麦克莱恩当时正从丹佛的一家便利店步行回家。 2019 年 8 月 24 日，他在奥罗拉 (Aurora) 郊区，当时他因行为可疑而被警方拦下。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;在选拔过程中选出的 12 名陪审员和两名候补陪审员中没有黑人陪审员从周五开始。首次审判涉及奥罗拉市警官兰迪·罗德玛 (Randy Roedema) 和前警官杰森·罗森布拉特 (Jason Rosenblatt)，他们均被指控犯有过失杀人、刑事过失杀人和其他指控。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两人均不不认罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;警察掐住麦克莱恩的脖子后，医护人员给他注射了强效镇静剂氯胺酮，然后心脏骤停，几天后在医院死亡。所有涉及的警察和护理人员都是白人。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2020 年，乔治·弗洛伊德 (George Floyd) 在明尼阿波利斯一名白人警察的膝盖下被杀，麦克莱恩案引起了全国关注，该事件引发了整个夏天的全球抗议活动。非裔美国人和其他少数族裔受到美国执法部门的制裁。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;当地检察官起初拒绝对麦克莱恩的死亡提出指控。但公众的强烈抗议促使科罗拉多州州长命令州总检察长审查此案。 2021 年 9 月，也就是凶杀案发生两年后，大陪审团在一份 32 项起诉书中指控了三名警察和两名护理人员。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;2022 年 9 月修订后的尸检报告得出结论，麦克莱恩死于氯胺酮过量。法医病理学家最初得出麦克莱恩死因“未确定”的结论，并在后来的报告中写道，他在 2019 年尸检期间获得的“信息不足”。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;警察佩戴的随身摄像机，可以听到麦克莱恩抽泣着恳求：“我无法呼吸，请停下来。我正要回家。”&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;科罗拉多州总检察长还确定奥罗拉警察局经常违反规定被指控掐住麦克莱恩脖子的奥罗拉警官内森·伍德亚德 (Nathan Woodyard) 将于 10 月份因同样的指控单独接受审判。他已表示自己无罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;两名给麦克莱恩注射氯胺酮的护理人员计划于 11 月以同样的罪名接受联合审判。两人均不不认罪。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;罗森布拉特于 2020 年被解雇，原因是罗森布拉特在一条短信中对三名警察在麦克莱恩遇害现场拍摄的一张嘲笑照片做出了“哈哈”的回应。另外两名警官和护理人员已被停薪停职，等待审判结果。摆拍照片的两名警察被解雇，第三名警察在采取任何纪律处分之前辞职。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥罗拉市于 2021 年 11 月同意向麦克莱恩的家人支付 1500 万美元，以和解民权诉讼.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;奥罗拉市议会聘请的一个独立小组发现，拦截麦克莱恩的警官没有明显理由怀疑正在实施犯罪，而且警方对此事的初步内部调查存在缺陷。&lt;/p>; &lt;h2>;相关图库：&lt;/h2>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/AATISH3UNBMXDO5MGBIDF6F3SI.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;小样式=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;兰迪·罗德玛 (Randy Roedema) 是奥罗拉 (Aurora) 的三名警察之一，另外还有两名护理人员，因伊利亚·麦克莱恩 (Elijah McClain) 的死亡而被刑事指控。 伊利亚·麦克莱恩 (Elijah McClain) 是一名黑人，于 2019 年被制服并注射镇静剂后死亡。亚当斯县司法中心于 2022 年 4 月 15 日在美国科罗拉多州布莱顿举行状态听证会。REUTERS/Kevin Mohatt&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images .arcpublishing.com/reuters/2H3BS5DBVVOW7DPFGV366ZQKQM.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Peter Cichuniec，除了三名奥罗拉警察之外的两名护理人员之一，被指控造成死亡2022 年 4 月 15 日，美国科罗拉多州布莱顿举行状态听证会后，黑人男子伊利亚·麦克莱恩 (Elijah McClain) 于 2019 年被制服并注射镇静剂后死亡，在武装保安的护送下，他在亚当斯县司法中心外。凯文·莫哈特&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/DWP25HTHXFLVBMMAYXUUCXAU.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;小样式=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;伊利亚·麦克莱恩 (Elijah McClain) 于 2019 年被制服并注射镇静剂后在警方拘留期间死亡，谢妮·麦克莱恩 (Sheneen McClain) 在被告身份听证会结束后站在亚当斯县司法中心外2022 年 4 月 15 日，她的儿子在美国科罗拉多州布莱顿去世。路透社/Kevin Mohatt&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 02:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[VIEW Fed leaves rates unchanged, sees tighter policy through 2024]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/usa-fed-instant/fed-leaves-rates-unchanged-sees-tighter-policy-through-2024-idUSKBN30Q1QQ]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20T18:20:18Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;美联储&lt;a href=&quot;/markets/rates-bonds/fed-projections-show-if- Soft-landing-is-new-baseline-or-baseless-2023-09-20/&quot;>;周三维持利率稳定&lt;/a>;，但加强了鹰派立场，预计年底前进一步加息到 2024 年，货币政策将显着收紧，远超此前预期。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;与 6 月份一样，美联储政策制定者中位数仍预计央行基准隔夜利率今年将在 5.50%-5.75% 范围内见顶，仅比当前区间高四分之一个百分点。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;但从那时起，美联储更新的季度预测显示，与会议上预期的降息幅度相比，2024 年利率仅下降半个百分点六月。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;市场反应：&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;股票：标准普尔 500 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.SPX&quot; target=&quot;_blank &quot;>;(.SPX)&lt;/a>; 下跌 3.43 点，即 0.08%，至 0.4,440.52 债券：美国 10 年期国债收益率最新下跌 1.6 个基点，至 4.35%。&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;外汇： dollar index trimmed losses after the rate decision, was last flat at 105.11.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;COMMENTS:&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;It was actually a good bit more hawkish than I thought it was going to be. It&#39;s definitely higher for longer, and I just don&#39;t think those kinds of metrics were expected.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;You&#39;re not going to get relief on rates anytime soon, and so that means that interest costs are going to remain elevated, probably for longer than people expected.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Previously, the Fed had seemingly signaled a commitment to being aggressive, potentially even again raising interest rates multiple times before the end of this year to continue efforts to drive down inflation. While they still very well may follow through with that before the end of this year, this week&#39;s announcement indicates that the Fed may believe that the best course of action, for now, is to continue monitoring the economy, and the effects of previous hikes, to determine if and when additional rate hikes are necessary.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;The decision not to raise rates at present will likely have impacts across the credit markets. In the mortgage market, for instance, consumers who have been holding off may begin to be motivated by the announcement to consider making the home purchase they have been waiting on.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Consumers who have credit cards will also likely see some short-term benefits by this announcement. This is because when the Fed announces an interest rate increase, credit card interest rates typically follow shortly thereafter, which may result in larger minimum monthly payments for credit card holders. While the decision not to raise interest rates this time round mitigates that for now, more interest rate increases may be on the horizon. For that reason, it&#39;s a good idea for consumers to continue to maintain balances that are in alignment with what they know they will be able to make payments on each month, and take into consideration the possibility of further interest rate increases and how those payments may change as a result.&quot;&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 02:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[S&P, Dow rise as yields slip ahead of Fed rate verdict]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/usa-stocks/wall-street-loses-ground-after-fed-pauses-rates-says-they-will-stay-higher-for-longer-idUSKBN30Q0PR]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20T16:03:55Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/WZMNOP5YCBLOPK4YBVKGMFVVVM.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Traders work on the floor of the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) in New York City, US, September 11, 2023. REUTERS/Brendan McDermid/File Photo&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;The S&amp;amp;P 500 and the Dow gained on Wednesday as Treasury yields pulled back ahead of a likely pause in the Federal Reserve&#39;s policy tightening campaign, though concerns over rates staying higher for longer kept investor sentiment in check.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The US central bank is expected to maintain its key rate in the range of 5.25%-5.50% as it concludes its meeting at 2 pm ET, with investors focused on Fed economic &lt;a href=&quot;/markets/rates-bonds/fed-projections-show-if-soft-landing-is-new-baseline-or-baseless-2023-09-20/&quot;>;projections&lt;/a>; and Chair Jerome Powell&#39;s comments for clues on the outlook for rates and inflation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Recent economic data has signaled an easing in core inflation, fuelling bets interest rates could have peaked, but a surge in oil prices has clouded the outlook for headline inflation, providing the Fed room to keep rates higher for longer.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Reinforcing the likelihood of a Fed pause, US Treasury yields retreated from their 2007 highs hit in the previous session.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;However, megacap growth stocks including Alphabet &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/GOOGL.O&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(GOOGL.O)&lt;/a>;, Microsoft &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MSFT.O&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(MSFT.O)&lt;/a>; and Apple &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AAPL.O&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(AAPL.O)&lt;/a>; lost between 0.7% and 1.6%, weighing on the communication services &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.SPLRCL&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(.SPLRCL)&lt;/a>; and information technology &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.SPLRCT&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(.SPLRCT)&lt;/a>; sectors. The tech-heavy Nasdaq &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.IXIC&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(.IXIC)&lt;/a>; also gave up its early gains.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Concerns remain that the Fed is clearly holding policy at what would be considered to be a restrictive level,&quot; said Mark Luschini, chief investment strategist at Janney Montgomery Scott.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Everybody is watching for any kind of evidence that would suggest that the traction from tight monetary policy is inflicting damage on the economy.&quot;&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Financial markets have priced in a 99% chance the Fed will pause rates on Wednesday and a near 71% likelihood the central bank will keep them unchanged in November, according to CME&#39;s FedWatch tool.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In another sign of new market entrants failing to hold on to their strong gains on debut, &lt;a href=&quot;/markets/us/instacart-stock-subdued-debut-enthusiasm-loses-steam-2023-09-20/&quot;>;Instacart&lt;/a>; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/CART.O&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(CART.O)&lt;/a>; lost 5.5% while Arm Holdings was down 4.4%.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Investors are now looking forward to marketing automation company Klaviyo&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/KVYO.N&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(KVYO.N)&lt;/a>; debut on the New York Stock Exchange, with the stock last indicated to open between $36 and $38.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Boston-based company had secured a &lt;a href=&quot;/markets/deals/klaviyo-prices-ipo-above-range-raise-576-mln-sources-2023-09-19/&quot;>;valuation of $9.2 billion&lt;/a>; in its initial public offering after pricing the shares above their indicated range.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;At 11:47 am ET, the Dow Jones Industrial Average &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.DJI&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(.DJI)&lt;/a>; was up 190.38 points, or 0.55%, at 34,708.11, the S&amp;amp;P 500 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.SPX&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(.SPX)&lt;/a>; was up 7.87 points, or 0.18%, at 4,451.82, and the Nasdaq Composite &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/quote/.IXIC&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(.IXIC)&lt;/a>; was down 24.00 points, or 0.18%, at 13,654.18.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pinterest &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/PINS.N&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(PINS.N)&lt;/a>; added 4.3% as Citigroup upgraded the image-sharing platform to &quot;buy&quot; from &quot;neutral&quot; and as the firm announced a share buyback of up to $1 billion.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Coty &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/COTY.N&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(COTY.N)&lt;/a>; added 5.1% after the CoverGirl parent raised its annual like-for-like sales forecast.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Advancing issues outnumbered decliners by a 3.58-to-1 ratio on the NYSE and a 1.59-to-1 ratio on the Nasdaq.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The S&amp;amp;P index recorded 10 new 52-week highs and four new lows, while the Nasdaq recorded 33 new highs and 140 new lows.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 02:25:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[US employers to see biggest healthcare cost jump in a decade in 2024]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/usa-health-insurance/us-employers-to-see-biggest-healthcare-cost-jump-in-a-decade-in-2024-idUSKBN30Q1NU]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20T17:26:59Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/M5NX723BRVP4TNEMXGYRQ6H34I.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;Pharmaceutical tablets and capsules are arranged in the shape of a US dollar sign on a table in this picture illustration taken in Ljubljana August 20, 2014. Picture taken August 20. REUTERS/Srdjan Zivulovic/File Photo&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;US employers are bracing for the largest increase in health insurance costs in a decade next year, according forecasts from healthcare consultants, but workers may be somewhat spared this time around in a tight labor market.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Benefit consultants from Mercer, Aon &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/AON.N&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(AON.N)&lt;/a>; and Willis Towers Watson &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/WTW.O&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(WTW.O)&lt;/a>; see employer healthcare costs jumping 5.4% to 8.5% in 2024 due to medical inflation, soaring demand for costly weight-loss drugs and wider availability of high-priced gene therapies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;A survey conducted by Mercer, a unit of Marsh McLennan &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/MMC.N&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(MMC.N)&lt;/a>;, found over two thirds of employers either do not plan to shift any cost increase to their staff or will pass on less than the expected rise in 2024.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;They don&#39;t want to add more financial stress on employees who are also coping with inflation, especially in this time where they&#39;re really relying on their health benefits as a way to keep employees working for them,&quot; said Beth Umland, Mercer&#39;s director of health &amp; benefits research.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;US consumer prices &lt;a href=&quot;/markets/us/us-consumer-prices-accelerate-august-gasoline-2023-09-13/&quot;>;accelerated&lt;/a>; 3.7% in the 12 months through August, down from a peak of 9.1% in June last year. However, medical cost increases usually lag general inflation as contracts between insurers and hospitals for the prices of procedures are signed months or even a year in advance.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Benefit consultants help design insurance plans for medium and large employers. About two-thirds of US workers receive benefits through such plans. Insurers UnitedHealth &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/UNH.N&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(UNH.N)&lt;/a>;, Centene &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/CNC.N&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(CNC.N)&lt;/a>;, Cigna &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/CI.N&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(CI.N)&lt;/a>; and Elevance &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/ELV.N&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(ELV.N)&lt;/a>;, which manage employer insurance plans, declined to comment for this story.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Of its projected 8.5% increase in employer healthcare costs for next year, Aon anticipates 1 percentage point coming from weight-loss drugs alone.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Sales of Novo Nordisk&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/NOVOb.CO&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(NOVOb.CO)&lt;/a>; Wegovy, which is approved to treat obesity, as well as &quot;off-label&quot; use of similar diabetes drugs including Novo&#39;s Ozempic and Eli Lilly&#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reuters.com/markets/companies/LLY.N&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;(LLY.N)&lt;/a>; Mounjaro for weight loss have surged in demand in the last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Roughly half a dozen gene therapies have been approved in the United States over the past year, most costing over $1 million. Gene therapy treatment of just one employee could significantly raise costs for a company, consultants said.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Employers will increasingly use artificial intelligence to help cut administrative staff expenses as they look for ways to mitigate rising costs, all the consultants said, adding that there will be increased scrutiny on coverage for expensive therapies.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Companies and insurers are also identifying less expensive hospital networks for certain procedures.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;Employees are given incentive that says if you go here, you pay less,&quot; said Janet Faircloth, senior vice president of Aon&#39;s health innovation team.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 01:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[South Africa to host US-Africa trade summit despite Russia spat]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/usa-safrica/south-africa-to-host-us-africa-trade-summit-despite-russia-spat-idUSKBN30Q1P3]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20T17:44:54Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;img src=&quot;https://cloudfront-us-east-2.images.arcpublishing.com/reuters/7E7MZ7MX5ZK2NH7VMSVMLA3HEQ.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot;>;&lt;div>;&lt;small style=&quot;color: #999;&quot;>;US Trade Representative Katherine Tai testifies before a Senate Finance Committee hearing on President Biden&#39;s trade policy agenda on Capitol Hill in Washington, US, March 31, 2022. REUTERS/Jonathan Ernst/File Photo&lt;/small>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;South Africa will host a US-Africa trade summit in November despite an earlier call by US lawmakers for the event to be moved over what they said was the country&#39;s deepening military relationship with Russia.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;South Africa&#39;s economic hub, Johannesburg, will host the US-sub-Saharan Africa Trade and Economic Cooperation Forum from Nov. 2 to 4, US and South African officials said in a joint statement on Wednesday.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The meeting will discuss the future of the African Growth and Opportunity Act (AGOA), Washington&#39;s flagship trade programme for the continent, which grants tariff-free access to the US market and is due to expire on Sept. 30, 2025.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;As President Biden has said, the future is Africa,&quot; United States Trade Representative Katherine Tai said in the statement. Tai said she looked forward to visiting South Africa to &quot;discuss opportunities to make AGOA more transformative&quot;.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the wake of Russia&#39;s February 2022 invasion of Ukraine, US and European officials have attempted to rally opposition to Moscow&#39;s actions among African governments. Most African states, however, have shied away from taking sides.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Despite Pretoria&#39;s declared neutrality, perceived close ties between Russia and South Africa, an important US trading partner in Africa, have ruffled feathers Washington.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In a &lt;a href=&quot;/world/us-lawmakers-call-safrica-lose-summit-over-russia-ties-2023-06-13/&quot;>;June letter&lt;/a>;, leading members of the US House of Representatives and the US Senate asked the Biden administration to choose another location for the US-Africa trade meeting.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Pointing to South Africa&#39;s joint naval operations with China and Russia in February, and plans to host Russian President Vladimir Putin at a BRICS bloc summit, they also suggested South Africa&#39;s trade benefits under AGOA could be revoked.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The lawmakers appeared to back up an &lt;a href=&quot;/world/us-envoy-says-russian-ship-picked-up-arms-south-africa-2023-05-11/&quot;>;explosive accusation&lt;/a>; by the US ambassador to South Africa that a Russian vessel under sanctions collected weapons at a South African naval base last year.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In the end, Putin, who is wanted under an International Criminal Court warrant on charges of war crimes in Ukraine, did not travel to the September BRICS summit. And a South African investigation into the purported arms delivery stated that the accusation was unfounded.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In Wednesday&#39;s statement, Ebrahim Patel, South Africa&#39;s trade minister, attempted to turn the page on the incident, calling for AGOA to be extended.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;&quot;An extension of AGOA beyond 2025 will promote inward investment in Africa and provide benefits to both the United States and African countries,&quot; he said.&lt;/p>;&lt;br>;&lt;hr>;&lt;div>;获取更多RSS：&lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.net&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.net&lt;/a>; &lt;br>;&lt;a href=&quot;https://feedx.best&quot; style=&quot;color:orange&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;https://feedx.best&lt;/a>;&lt;br>;&lt;/div>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 01:55:04 +0800</pubDate> </item><item><title><![CDATA[Houston sued over program setting aside public contracts for minorities]]></title><link/><![CDATA[https://reuters.com/article/usa-race-houston/houston-sued-over-program-setting-aside-public-contracts-for-minorities-idUSKBN30Q1PC]]><description> &lt;div>;&lt;i>;2023-09-20T17:50:13Z&lt;/i>;&lt;/div>;&lt;p>;A white married couple that owns two landscaping companies has sued Houston, claiming that the city&#39;s requirement that certain government contracts be set aside for minority-owned businesses runs afoul of the US Constitution.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The two businesses owned by Jerry and Theresa Thompson in a &lt;a href=&quot;https://pacificlegal.org/wp-content/uploads/2023/09/2023.09.19-01-PLF-Complaint.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;complaint&lt;/a>; filed in federal court in Houston on Tuesday said the city&#39;s program violates their constitutional rights to equal protection. The city has said that the four-decade-old program ensures that historically disenfranchised people have an opportunity to participate in lucrative government contracting, and fosters a more competitive economic environment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The lawsuit is the latest to challenge affirmative action programs since the US Supreme Court in June &lt;a href=&quot;/legal/us-supreme-court-strikes-down-university-race-conscious-admissions-policies-2023-06-29/&quot;>;struck down race-conscious policies&lt;/a>; in college student admissions in rulings involving Harvard University and the University of North Carolina. The suit was filed on the same day that an anti-affirmative action group &lt;a href=&quot;/world/us/us-anti-affirmative-action-group-challenges-west-point-admissions-policy-2023-09-19/&quot;>;sued the US Military Academy&lt;/a>; at West Point, claiming the Army school&#39;s affirmative action practices unconstitutionally discriminate against white applicants.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;Under Houston&#39;s program, the city sets annual numerical goals for awarding different types of contracts to businesses owned by minorities. Between July 2021 and June 2022, about 24% of professional service contracts and about 14% of construction contracts were awarded to minority-owned businesses, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.houstontx.gov/obo/reports/FY2022-Annual-MWSBE-Report.pdf&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;>;according to the city&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The office of Houston Mayor Sylvester Turner, a Democrat, did not immediately respond to a request for comment.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The lawsuit said one of the Thompson businesses currently has a five-year contract with the city worth $1.3 million, but is required to subcontract 11% of the total value, or $143,000, to a minority-owned business.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The Thompsons are represented by the conservative Pacific Legal Foundation, which said that racial set-asides feed into stereotypes that some racial groups cannot succeed without government help.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The lawsuit also alleges that Houston failed to explain how its contracting program is tailored to remedy past discrimination. The Supreme Court previously has said affirmative action programs can be deemed unlawful without such an explanation.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;The June Supreme Court ruling, while directly affecting only higher education, is expected to bolster legal challenges to various government programs and corporate &lt;a href=&quot;/legal/affirmative-action-ruling-could-place-target-us-corporate-diversity-programs-2023-06-30/&quot;>;workforce diversity initiatives&lt;/a>;.&lt;/p>;&lt;p>;In July, a federal judge in Tennessee cited the decision in ruling that the US Small Business Administration could not assume that minority business owners were &quot;socially disadvantaged,&quot; &lt;a href=&quot;/legal/government/sba-accused-sidestepping-court-ruling-race-conscious-program-2023-09-18/&quot;>;making them eligible&lt;/a>; to bid on certain government contracts, without requiring them to provide any evidence beyond their race.&lt;/p>;</description><pubDate> Thu, 21 Sep 2023 01:55:04 +0800</pubDate></item></channel></rss>